PENNY: Previously
on The Magicians...
Hey, would you break up with me
if I told you that I've never
been happier in my entire life?
ELIOT: You wished
my boyfriend away.
MARGO: Boyfriend?
Other people aren't
supposed to get between us.
(GRUNTS)
PENNY: This is the most
pathetic loser dream ever.
This is all in your
head. I'm in your head.
Marina didn't betray my mom.
She cleaned up her mess.
JULIA: But you know who
has a ton of new stuff? Marina.
HANNAH: Run.
JULIA: Hannah! Help!
There are good
people out there, Julia.
People trying to learn about the
world and make it a better place.
I need a key to unlock
the door to Fillory.
PENNY: Let's see this button.
(GASPS)
(GASPING)
Where the hell am I?
Hi.
I come in peace.
Do you talk?
Haven't seen you
around here before.
First-timer. From?
Not here. You?
Hmm, nice try, psychic.
Gonna need to get to
know a girl a little better
before she lets you go
running around up there.
Yeah, I wasn't. You
were, but it's okay.
Maybe we got off
on the wrong foot.
I'm Eve. Penny.
Do you live here? Mmm-hmm.
Born and raised.
I'm actually kind of the
Welcome Committee.
I keep track of the fountains.
I felt you come through.
Please, tell me that I can help
you get where you need to go.
Okay, where are we, exactly?
The Neitherlands.
And that is...
The Neitherlands are
sort of the place between
all other places.
It's how you get
from "A" to "B."
Which fountain did
you come out of?
Over there. Earth. Ooh.
You know, we don't get
too many of you guys,
but when you come, you always
have the most interesting magic.
So, tell me, what
brought you here?
Hmm?
I've pretty much seen it
all. Enchanted capes, rings.
This one guy, uh, he rode
a sled pulled by flying...
What do you call them?
Not zebra. Reindeer.
Santa Claus? Yeah.
You know him? He's
a really nice guy, right?
Yeah. No. What?
No, I didn't have anything
like that. Just a button.
That's new. Can I see it?
(GRUNTS)
God damn it.
Oh, my God.
(EXHALES)
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING IN OTHER LANGUAGE)
What?
I need your help
to fix the hyperdrive
and get a message to my friends.
I can help you if you
help me find my dragons.
Let's do it.
Let's find your
dragons, and I...
Oh, hey, look. I respect
the shit out of you both,
and you are leaders, and
you're people, and I'm a feminist...
If you would just shut
up for two seconds,
this sex dream would pass
the Bechdel test, Quentin.
God.
(PENNY LAUGHS)
Nice dream, loser.
Why do you ruin
everything in my life?
(GASPS)
Alice.
I just talked to Penny.
Wait, what? Where is
he? What happened?
It's not what it looks like.
I mean, it looks like a
grade-A nerd-boy wet dream,
and I want... God, I
want to make fun of you,
but the more I consider it,
you might be
some kind of savant.
Look. Where have you been?
So, wait. I was
making out with who?
Uh, nobody.
You said I was there
making out with someone.
No. Yes. Not...
I mean, not that it's important.
It was, sort of... Julia. Julia.
Your lifelong crush.
Dreams are weird.
People are naked,
and animals are
smoking cigarettes.
I... Look. Here's
what's important.
You've been gone for six weeks.
No, I've been gone six hours.
Shit.
Where are you, anyway?
The Neitherlands.
I thought it might
be some Fillory shit.
I mean, it sounds
familiar, but...
It's, like, fountains
and plazas up the ass,
and then the fountains,
they all go to different worlds.
I'll check the books
when I wake up.
Man, the one time I need you
to know this Comic-Con shit.
Why don't you just jump
back into the Earth fountain?
'Cause I'm lost.
There's three
moons here, Quentin.
My internal compass is
having a grand mal seizure.
Okay, so, why don't
you just travel back here?
If you can Inception
me from there...
I can't aim.
If I try to travel back,
I could end up dead.
Look. I need your help.
What do we know about
these Neitherlands?
I don't remember them
from the Fillory books.
There's not much.
In The Wandering
Dune, Jane and Rupert
meet this talking dromedary
named Cameltoes.
No. Seriously?
Amazing. It was 1943.
It wasn't a dirty thing
to say back then.
Anyway, he talks about
a world between worlds,
and then he
vanishes, and that's it.
I might know somebody
who can help us,
who's traveled.
You've never
mentioned that before.
We've never been
this desperate before.
Okay, so we're all in agreement.
We should ask the lizard man.
What?
The lizard man over there.
MARGO: Eliot. Honey,
what are you on?
Some pinks, a green,
and a tab of something
called "Chocolate Sunshine."
I really like the name.
Do you like the name?
Uh. (CLEARS THROAT)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
Maybe I shouldn't
have had that green.
Maybe you should get
checked out at the infirmary.
(LAUGHS) That's nonsense.
Me strong like bull.
Let's go on a quest.
Uh, you two go talk
to Alice's whatever.
Eliot, honey, maybe you and
I should go upstairs and rest.
Wait, wait, wait.
Are my eyes open,
or closed right now?
Oh, my God.
How about now?
Shit.
(BRANCHES CRACKING)
Over there. Come on, let's go.
Whoa!
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Shit. Uh, coming!
Don't worry. It's only me.
I was just checking the Free
Trader app to see if you'd imploded.
I kept that offline.
Uh, so, what do I call you?
Like, "Richard" or,
um, "Failstaff" or...
Richard, though
some of the others
might prefer their log-in names.
Hey, when was the
last time you unplugged?
It's been a while.
But, I mean, when
was the last time
I had actual friends to discuss
Gödel, Escher, Bach with?
But listen. The portals are gonna
take me a couple hours to calculate
if you want to, you
know, straighten up.
Thank God.
Listen, do you mind
if we commandeer
the guest room for the project?
Um...
What project? A-ha.
You and Asmodeus will learn
more once you've leveled up.
The next 12 spells. No mistakes.
Wow.
The... Um...
The, um, "Spellbinder"?
I mean, it was right there.
Mmm.
Yeah, because it's a
binder filled with spells.
(CHANTING SPELL)
(EXHALES)
Hi.
You must be Vicious
Circe. I'm Silver.
(LAUGHS)
(SQUEALS) (SIGHS)
Hi. JULIA: Bender.
Thanks for having me.
I'm extremely happy finally
to meet you face-to-face.
I've taken the liberty of
writing a cooperative variation
on the spell I
sent you last week.
Menolly. Finally, in
person. (BOTH CHUCKLE)
How you feeling?
So good.
I am danked as
shit right now, girl.
The perks of chemo
just keep rolling in.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Hi.
Asmodeus is the last one.
She's actually just coming from
uptown, but rush hour, you know.
Hi. Asmodeus.
Welcome.
You two know each other.
Obviously, I didn't realize
that you two had history,
um, and I don't
want to dismiss it,
but we are running out of time
here, and we need both of you.
Okay?
Of course.
I've never been
to Chicago before.
This isn't Chicago,
it's the 'burbs.
We should make this fast. Maybe
you can wait outside while I run in.
Come on, Vix, when are you
gonna tell me who we're here to see?
What's the big secret?
Just let me do the talking.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Jesus, it's like the
TARDIS in here.
What kind of magic
are these people using?
Thibadeau's Planar Compression.
It's really not a big deal.
Alice, whose house
is this, exactly?
Alice.
Hi, Dad.
DANIEL: Come, come, come, come.
So glad you guys could
make it for the Veneralia,
the Roman festival of Venus.
Did Alice tell you I
study historical magic?
We celebrate all the
Roman holidays around here.
Jesus Christ, how
come you didn't tell me
we were coming
to see your parents?
Because I knew you'd make a
big deal out of it and act like this.
Well, I... So, they're Travelers?
Amongst other things?
No, my mom just
knows a Traveler.
Look, it's complicated.
Just let me handle it.
DANIEL: Really hope you
can come for the Saturnalia.
Much less tame
than this old thing.
Right. This is a
little tame. Hmm.
Dad, I need to talk to Mom,
like, now. It's important.
Well, after a frolic, she'll
usually head for the tepidarium.
Can you please
just call it "the bath"?
Nonsense. This is my domus.
I shall call it what I please.
Ugh.
Okay, look. Distract my dad.
I'll be 30 minutes, tops.
Please?
So, dating my daughter?
Let's have a
little fatherly chat.
(PEOPLE MOANING)
I can't believe I gave up
tickets to Hamilton for this.
Um, sorry you
have to do your job.
Ugh, story of my life.
Anyway, there's
nothing wrong with him.
Really? Nothing at all?
Well, he has a
massive drug problem,
but at least he's
medicating, hmm?
Thank you. Hmm.
You, on the other hand, appear
to require medical intervention.
What?
(GLASS SHATTERS) (GASPS)
(LAUGHING)
That was me?
Yep.
Something's draining
her chi, her life force.
Or someone.
So, okay, I know that this is
embarrassing, but trust me, dying is worse.
Have you engaged in any
unprotected rituals of any kind?
(WHISPERS) Be honest.
(GROANS) God.
That son of a bitch.
They're chanting something.
Look, we should get started.
We have a lot of
spells to get through.
You know, first, I
just want to be clear.
Richard might be about
forgiveness, but I'm sure as shit not.
Look, I'm sorry you and your
mom had a shitty relationship,
but not a day goes
by where I don't
feel terrible about
what happened to her.
I did not cause her death, okay?
I only wish that I
could've stopped it.
I'm just trying to
make up for my past,
just like you.
Did she suffer?
She said she loved you.
Yeah, I know she did.
So, are we gonna
do this, or what?
Whoa.
William. You're late.
I'm what? Who are you?
You always ask
the same questions.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You never do. I'm a
member of The Order,
the keepers of the
libraries of the Neitherlands,
the greatest repository
of knowledge, full stop.
Any idea who the motherfuckers
in the hoods are that
are trying to kill me?
The locals used to work
for us in a custodial function,
but labor relations have
become somewhat strained of late.
We had to ban them
from the libraries.
They've been thoroughly cursed,
so they can't use the fountains,
but that hasn't stopped them
from finding other employment,
some with a
particularly nasty entity.
The Beast?
Well, he has many names.
Look, this is all great,
but I'm just trying to get
back to the Earth fountain.
Can you show me where it is?
I suppose I could
order you a map,
but it'd have to come
from another branch.
Great, let's do that.
Inter-library loans typically
take two to four weeks to process.
Are you kidding? That's
two years on my world.
Then, I'm afraid we are limited
to the resources of this branch.
Follow me.
STEPHANIE: Alice?
Hi, Mom.
Alice.
Fine.
Stephanie.
You know how I feel about "Mom."
I just... I have an important
question to ask you.
Sure.
Push past everything you left on
the table the last time we spoke.
I'm sure you've
forgotten all about it.
Oh, my God.
You're really not gonna
let that go, are you?
Because we haven't
finished discussing it.
It was six months ago.
Look, I just...
Mom... Stephanie,
I don't see the point
in talking about it.
We don't agree on it,
and we're never going to.
Well, because you act like
there's something wrong with me.
No, I just think it's weird that
you're not at all curious about
what happened to Charlie.
It's not gonna bring him back,
so I don't want to know.
Which is a perfectly
reasonable position
in spite of how you judge me.
Fine. Okay, fine.
Okay, I don't need
that patronizing tone.
Then what do you want from me?
How about... Hmm...
(CLICKS TONGUE)
You admit that your
mother is a human being,
because you act like
you're the only one
who has a right to feel.
No, I don't.
I just...
Okay.
I think we're done talking.
This conversation has
worn me out entirely.
Excuse me.
Every second I spend
in this place, ugh,
I just feel like I'm being
pulled back into this
version of me when I was, like, 12
and furious and invisible and mute.
Ugh, she just fucking
does that to me.
Well, I'm sure being cooped
up in your old room helps.
It's like going back
in time to 2004.
The Garden State soundtrack.
Hey, that was cool
when it came out.
The Joy of Sex?
Is that Stephanie?
My dad.
He meant well.
But my mom made him give
me the version from the '70s,
because she thinks that kids
should know what pubic hair looks like.
Jesus Christ.
I can't imagine what you must
be thinking of me right now.
It's cool. I'm, like, really
into damaged chicks.
Like Julia?
Alice, I don't know what
you think Julia and I were,
but the truth is, we
weren't anything.
We were two kids
who tested well,
got placed together,
and I got a crush,
because that's
how hormones work,
and she didn't,
and I got over it,
and the end.
I'm kind of new to this whole
thing, if you hadn't guessed.
All my past
relationships were, like,
you know, at a party.
"Can we just do this
standing up?" kind of thing.
Well, the fact that you could
want to have sex with anyone
after living in this house
is pretty impressive.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Thanks.
So, what's the deal with this
Traveler? Why can't we just ask?
I mean...
Okay, so...
My mom knows this Traveler
from another world, Joe.
Joe? Yeah.
Apparently, his actual name
is impossible to pronounce.
Anyway, it's kind
of a touchy subject,
and I think that it's best
that when I talk to my mom,
my dad's not around.
Why? Is she sleeping with Joe?
And your dad doesn't know?
Alice, they were having
a sex party when we showed up.
Look, I know it
sounds ridiculous,
but my parents are weird
and possessive,
and they just have to
do everything together.
Look, when I was 10,
my dad caught my
mom having an affair,
and he threatened
to commit suicide.
Oh, my God.
He said he had to go extreme
just to get her
attention, which...
He was psychotic,
but he wasn't wrong.
I think he would have done
it if she hadn't come around.
Well...
Now I kind of feel like
a dick for making fun
of your Garden State soundtrack.
Total dick. (CHUCKLES)
Now you have to help me.
(GIGGLES)
(WIND WHOOSHING AND WHISTLING)
(WHISTLING STOPS) (SIGHS)
I think that was one
of your memories.
Yeah.
Antarctica. Jesus.
What brought you there?
Brakebills.
So, what happened?
I mean, why'd you leave?
They found out my deal,
and it was either stay
and get brain-wiped, or jet.
I was heading to New York.
I was coming to kill Marina.
Well, then what happened?
I met Richard,
and he convinced
me Marina could wait,
and invited me to join
the Free Trader Beowulf,
which sounded...
I don't know, maybe, better than
death or jail, so... (LAUGHS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Uh, everything okay in there?
RICHARD: Yeah. All good.
I know 100 ways to break in.
We have four spells
left. Let's just finish, okay?
Then they have to let
us in on their project.
Just a little further.
Wait a minute. I
know these people.
LIBRARIAN: Well,
every book is here.
All the books ever written,
all the books never written,
all the books of all the
people who ever lived.
This is my book.
Yo.
Why are there all these
flowers and shit on the cover?
People who read their
books often discover
they don't like the
main character,
and are rarely happy
with how it ends.
Ah. Here it is.
Wait, "Martin"? That's...
That's one of the Fillory kids.
Okay, is there anything
in there about The Beast?
I'm sorry. I can't
lend you this.
Not without a library card.
Of course, you can't.
You know, shit like this is
why people hate librarians.
(COPIER WHIRRING)
What are you doing?
Here's what would happen if
you did what you're thinking.
You'd try to steal
this book by force,
we'd fight, you'd lose,
but you'd rip out several pages
before I banished
you from the library.
This way, no books get hurt.
(GRUNTS)
Fuck.
I hate this place.
We always have so
much left over. Oh, here.
You have to try this. Mmm.
Filleted goat penis. Mmm.
Promotes virility, hmm?
That's very
thoughtful of you, Dad.
Oh.
So, Daniel, uh, you were saying
that your discipline
is in historical magic.
Indeed. Ah, the
Romans still fascinate me.
In fact, I'm about to
publish my third volume
on illusion work of
the Collis Aventinus.
Oh, could I see it?
Well, it's still in galleys,
but I suppose I
could show you...
Oh, great. Uh,
that sounds great.
Could we... Which...
Let's go now.
But you haven't even
touched your penis.
You know what? I had
a ton of it yesterday.
You said that it was this way.
Yeah, yeah. Uh, well...
Stephanie, I was wrong,
and you were right,
and I promise to be a
better daughter in the future.
Right about what?
I couldn't possibly
know how you feel,
other than that you feel deeply,
and you are your own person,
and you're the only one who
knows how to deal with your stuff,
and it was wrong
of me to presume.
Was that really
so tough, sweetie?
Look, I know this
is a tricky subject,
but my friend's
life is in danger,
and I need to talk
to you about Joe.
Joe. Oh, I love Joe!
(GRUNTS)
Would you hand me that
minced parrot, please?
Wait. I don't understand. I thought
you wouldn't want Dad to hear.
Why on Earth not?
Because it could
destroy your marriage.
What? Your father loves Joe.
I don't understand. I thought
you were hiding him from him.
Nope. Alice, you make
me sound so melodramatic.
(SIGHS)
Fine, yes, sure.
At first, yeah, your father
was a touch sensitive,
but then he figured out
that Joe could
work for both of us.
So, now he's our third,
you know, in a sort of
polyamorous triad sense.
So, you and Joe and... Yeah.
Joe's anatomy is adaptable.
He's like a Swiss Army knife.
He's good for every occasion.
So, whatever do
you want with Joe?
I need his help.
Oh, sweetie.
I'm sure Quentin
will understand.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
You see two of you, too, right?
Okay, good. This stuff is
finally starting to wear off.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Margo.
Uh, I can explain.
Explain this, you dick!
Hi. I'm Eliot.
So, what's up? How can I help?
Please know I'm a certified
therapist at home as well as here.
You can trust me completely.
No, no, no.
Like I said, our friend is
trapped in the Neitherlands.
Acquaintance. That
place is the worst.
So confusing.
Not to mention those fountains.
Completely unpredictable.
Wait, so, you know your
way around the Neitherlands?
Could you, like, draw us a map?
Yeah, I guess. Of what I know.
It's not gonna do
your friend any good
if he's very far from
the Earth fountain,
although, I might have
something that could help with that.
ALICE: Great. What?
It's a beacon.
You cast it here, and the fountain
for this world lights up there.
Okay, so how do we cast it?
Well, there are some
specific requirements,
sexually speaking.
Wait. It's sex magic?
All magic where I'm
from is sex magic.
Thought you knew that.
I could perform it
with you if you'd prefer.
I'm a heck of a pinch hitter.
I think we've got this.
All right, suit yourself.
I sense a nice connection between
your genitals. You should be fine.
You just need
some blood, a globe,
a few candles
bound with twine. Oh!
And you both have to
climax at the same time.
That gonna be a problem?
No. Well...
What?
I'm sorry.
We need the
spell to work, right?
I can't believe I'm
letting your boyfriend
talk to my boyfriend
about how to...
Ugh.
Is this the...
That's the deal.
STEPHANIE: Although, I must say,
this one seems like
an awful lot of work.
Who? Quentin?
You're complicated.
You need somebody
who gets that about you.
Maybe several people.
Don't take this the
wrong way, Mom,
but shut the fuck up, okay?
We'll talk when
you're less cranky.
(SALSA MUSIC PLAYING)
Cheers.
Darling.
Are you okay?
No.
I'm not okay, you dick.
You stole my life force.
I'm sorry.
Uh, there was a tiny
hole in the casting.
I've corrected it.
Won't happen again.
Shouldn't have happened at all.
I begged you to stay.
Margo, I needed you.
You broke my heart.
The only way I could repair it
was to create my golem of you.
A golem of Margo.
A Margolem.
MARGO: You selfish prick.
You put my life at risk,
so you could have a
realistic-looking sex doll?
No, no, no. I... I
wanted a relationship.
Margo,
I love you.
And sometimes the only
thing that we do is spoon and...
Ugh.
You're gross.
I'm taking the Margolem,
and I'm going to destroy it,
and I hope no one
ever spoons you again.
(ELIOT LAUGHS)
(SNIFFING DEEPLY)
What?
What are you doing? (SNORTS)
Nothing.
I brought you to support
me while I fight with my ex,
not do lines with a golem.
Oh, I'm sorry. I thought this
is how we support each other.
Is there something you
want to say to me, Eliot?
No. What is there to say?
I like your golem.
Life is a unicorn shitting
rainbows of candy.
I'll, um...
I'll deal with the
Margolem myself.
Just go home, Eliot.
(RELAXING MUSIC PLAYING)
QUENTIN: You have
the most beautiful hair.
And your eyes are, like,
the perfect shade of blue.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
And you're also smart.
Okay, okay.
It kind of feels like you're
trying to do a thing here.
I was told that women like it
when you compliment
them. (SIGHS)
Yeah, but that has
to feel real, you know?
Since when is that an issue?
What is that supposed to mean?
Nothing.
Apparently, you can't,
you know, with me.
Not that you've ever
said that to my face.
Yeah, well, maybe you
should pay better attention
when we're having sex.
I thought I was.
I don't think that
I've ever paid
that much attention
to anything in my life,
and little did I know that you
were so incredibly convincing.
But isn't that what you
want, Quentin, huh?
To feel like you're
perfect at it every time?
No, not if I'm not. I want...
How am I supposed to get better
if you won't tell me
if I'm doing it wrong?
So, have you, like, ever
come when we're together?
Yes. Lots of times.
I mean it.
It's just, sometimes...
Sometimes it's not that easy.
You know, like
when we were foxes.
Well, I'm sorry I'm not a fox.
(GROANS)
Well, there goes the mood.
(LAUGHS)
Voilà.
Reverse entropy.
Spell number 12, done and done.
Hard to believe something
so kludgy even works.
(CHUCKLES) (KNOCK AT DOOR)
Perfect timing. Pizza.
A large half veggie,
half meat. Thank you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Kady.
Did you see that?
Okay, what just happened?
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Déjà vu. Uh-huh.
A large half veggie, half meat.
Thank you.
Okay, what the fuck is going on?
Could it be the entropy spell?
No.
No, this is time magic,
much more power involved.
Well, if we didn't
cast it, who did?
MAN: Yeah!
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
MAN: We did it!
Okay.
Sit. Let's talk.
You've leveled up. It's time.
No pun intended. (CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
Not to state the obvious,
but we are pushing
the boundaries of what
is magically possible.
We are working our way up
to the energetic glass ceiling,
so we can shatter it.
You say that like it's possible.
It is.
Well, not according
to Brakebills.
No, the glass ceiling is
"explode and turn into
a niffin," or something.
You can't just keep ramping.
Brakebills was right. If you
go by Brakebills' methods.
We have a whole new methodology.
Yeah, but why? I mean,
what are you trying to do?
And don't just
say "good things."
You're talking about
massive nuclear power.
You're right. It's
personal. Yeah.
We are the best
Magicians we know.
Silver can literally
fly to the moon.
But Menolly is dying,
and we can't cure her.
Bender's trying to stay
off the ledge every day.
His meds have stopped working.
And you?
Eight years ago, I
was a drug addict,
and I left my son in a hot car.
And he was eight months old.
My life was destroyed.
Jesus.
You're doing time magic
to change what you did.
Yeah, but only a
fluke natural-born
time witch could do
something like that.
Now, I have done all
the research there is,
and one day,
I realized I was
looking at it wrong.
We don't have the energy, but
it's not that we need to generate it,
because somebody already has it.
We just need them,
and they can give us
inexhaustible,
unimaginable power.
That's no one.
That's the Source.
That's the place
it all comes from,
how people used to get shit done
when they needed
a fucking miracle.
The divine. You're trying to...
Summon a god.
Your fave.
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry.
Can we really talk, baby?
I think Professor Lipson
could have been wrong about me.
I think something
might really be broken.
What the fuck?
Oh, Jesus. There she is.
She has a bad
habit of walking off,
although when she does,
it's nice to be reminded
I have a great ass.
I thought you were
going to destroy her.
Oh, I was, but then I thought
I'd keep her around
a little longer.
She might come in handy.
What were you two talking about?
Nothing.
Got these for you, bitch.
Aw.
Thanks, bitch.
We need a chaser.
What did you do?
Hmm?
(DOOR OPENS)
So, I'm a dick.
I'm insecure, and I suck.
So, if we could just give
this another go, I'll even...
I don't know. I'll
be more fox-like
if that's what you want.
I don't want that.
I don't get it, Alice. I'm
not amazing at magic,
and apparently, I'm
pretty patchy at this.
(SIGHS)
Why are you even with me?
Because I like you.
A lot. And I don't know why.
I just really, really do.
In the weirdest way.
I don't think we're supposed to
like people for what they're good at.
I think that's
something we make up
to torture ourselves.
What about what we're bad at?
You're not bad at sex.
Okay, I'm just bad at
asking for what I want.
It's embarrassing.
It's me, Vix. I know.
I know. I know.
And I love you.
And so, as far as I'm concerned,
you know, let's just do this.
Oh.
Okay. Me, too.
You.
Maybe just kiss me?
No. Here.
Bite me.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Oh, Quentin, you girly
fanboy piece of shit. You did it.
There he is!
Get him! Come on!
(BOTH MOANING)
(WIND WHOOSHING) PENNY: Whoa.
(ALICE AND QUENTIN PANTING)
Welcome back.