QUENTIN: Previously
on The Magicians...
Children of Earth have been making
a mess of things here for some time.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(MARGO GASPING)
(MARGO SCREAMING)
I'm your Queen!
I demand that this trial/peasant
uprising be dismissed.
Josh Hoberman, class of '16.
Come with me if
you want to live.
It has begun.
Sorry.
JULIA: Is that cocaine?
It's the excretion of a
very rare magical creature.
But, yes, you will
have to snort it.
What creature?
JULIA: A fairy?
And I can't see her because
I've never made a fairy deal?
My daughter's dead
because of them.
You need to talk
to Irene's fairy.
My name is Skye.
Fen, what is it?
What do you see?
FEN: It's her, it's Skye.
Oh, God, they cut off her leg.
JULIA: That's what
the powder is made of.
(MOUTHING)
Weren't you supposed
to report to the Underworld
branch of the Library anyway?
Yeah, and I burned
my body to avoid that.
(PANTING) Did you...
Okay, come on.
Alice, are you working
with the Library?
(YELLING)
Maybe we should've waited at
the mirror for a little while longer.
I mean, maybe they survived
somehow. They didn't.
Ask her.
Harriet and Victoria
were in the bridge.
I'm pretty sure both
mirrors shattered.
Oh, my God. No.
There's your answer.
Where's your bag?
I need the Truth Key.
To see Penny, if
he made it back.
All right.
You found the Fourth Key?
(SOFT FLUTTERING)
Here we go.
Okay. It's in code.
Mmm.
Be careful with that.
(BREATHING HEAVILY) Penny?
This looks familiar.
You know what? No.
Not till you tell me what
you were doing in the Library.
I was finishing something.
Grand Unified Theory of Magic.
I needed information.
Penny!
Funny, 'cause there
is no magic to unify.
Just let me see it again.
No.
I... I know what it is.
Music.
Music?
Medieval music.
(SIGHS)
Here.
Just give it a minute, okay?
(MEDIEVAL MELODY PLAYING)
Sure you're playing
it right? Yes, I'm sure.
Then you're an idiot.
Back then the scale
didn't start at C.
So that's an A.
What?
No, I just didn't
know that you had...
Well, me and music go way back.
It's what my mom took
her clothes off to for money.
And save the
judgment. She was good.
And she liked it. And it
paid for piano lessons.
(MEDIEVAL MELODY PLAYING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
What? Where'd it go?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
What the hell?
ALICE: Where did all
these people come from?
Who are they?
I don't recognize them.
What time is it, y'all?
Todd.
Yeah, it's time for the one,
the only King of Party O'Clock!
(ALL CHEERING)
(SINGING) Can't wait for the
time When I could shed my skin
You can't read my mind
But if you're wondering
I'm somebody else,
you ain't met me before
I'll put my real face on
Open the door
Wham, bam, here I am
Demon of the glitter and glam
Yes, catch your breath
Got you eating out of my hand
Wham, thank you, ma'am
Now I'm here, the party is on
Wow, check me out
Don't know what
you got till it's gone
Guys, what took you so long?
Pump the beat through my veins
Ain't no stopping me now
Wham, bam, thank you, ma'am
Now I'm here, the party is on
Wow, check us out
Don't know what
you got till it's gone
Need it up, need it up
Turn the freakin' music up Gone
I think we've found Hell.
(ALL CHEERING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
Whatever this is,
I don't have time.
Where's the door?
Really?
(CROWD CHATTERING)
QUENTIN: All the
clocks say 4:20.
Well, it's not hell for Josh.
Why would the book send us here?
Where are we? Guys.
Great to see you.
Seriously, it's been too long.
Little word of advice, this is
a no-rules zone, except one.
You gotta be the vibe.
And the vibe is fun-in-the-sun,
and you can't throw
shade, capisce?
I have no idea
what you just said.
(MUSIC STOPS)
Good to see you, uh...
Where are we, exactly?
And why are they doing that?
Okay, guys.
(CHUCKLES) Guys, it's
okay. It's okay, all right?
(MUMBLES)
What Joshster was telling you,
it's all good in the
New World Order,
but one rule, okay?
(MUSIC RESUMES)
Have a blast, or adiós.
(CROWD CHATTERING)
How do we "adiós,"
Todd? There's no door.
True, but the trade-off...
Is this.
Holy shit.
Yeah, we're not just
partying 'cause it's fun.
Uh-uh.
We're tearing it up 'cause
magic is back, my babies.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah, it is.
Whoo-hoo.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
How? I...
Two words. "Who cares?"
(WHOOSHES)
Oh, my gosh, this
feels... (EXHALES)
(WHOOSHING)
(ALL CHEERING)
That bone saw.
The smith who forged it
must've been a monster.
Fen, I did a whole line
of that fairy coke shit.
All right? We've gotta help.
We can't. Excuse me?
I agree that what's being
done to the fairies is awful,
but they are evil, and I told you
what they did to me, my daughter.
And Julia, they
can't be enslaved.
They can do magic.
Yeah, but that was in Fillory.
You know, it's
obviously different here.
Maybe... Maybe
they're different.
And I can see them
without making a deal.
How?
(INDISTINCT CHANTING)
What the fuck-me hell?
You've been found guilty.
By a marsupial in
a wig and a robe.
PICKWICK: The judge
you requested for trial.
The Wombat? "Wombat"?
Jesus, Tick, I said "combat."
We wanted trial by combat.
That is not, as you would
say, "a thing" in Fillory.
Why do you think we went in
with Bingle, a mute swordsman?
If we'd known it
was a wombat judge,
we would've hired
a wombat lawyer.
There is some good news.
You are free...
To choose the manner
of your execution.
Tick.
I don't mean to sound snappish,
but what part of that
news is remotely good?
It's an honor only bestowed upon
the greatest of deposed monarchs.
Let's see.
The serrated spoon...
Don't pick that one.
The steep climb up
Fire Ant Mountain.
I'd pick the
serrated spoon first.
The Infinite Waterfall.
The Stone Crush.
Wait.
"Infinite Waterfall"?
It's quite horrid, and
wet. (CHUCKLES)
Right.
But which death on your
little list takes the longest?
The one with the
word "infinite" in it.
Right? Right.
A lot of time to...
Think on our royal
sins and repent.
Plan on how best to...
Meet death... Gracefully.
As desired then.
You will plummet through freezing
waters against walls of razor rocks,
so you bleed out or drown,
or if you're lucky,
just starve to death.
I really don't think we
could've picked a better option.
(ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(EXHALES) Feels really good.
There's something
very wrong here.
None of my locator
spells are working.
I... I don't know where we are.
How about I just
blow a hole in the wall?
Sure, go ahead, but...
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
The only magic
that works here is...
Party tricks. ALICE: Yeah.
Look, we're on the quest.
So maybe there's a clue
in what we can and can't do.
What we can't do is sit
around here getting blitzed
on never-ending scotch.
It's cognac, actually.
Easy. You, easy.
For all I know, this is you. Me?
Yeah, doing shit for your
Library buddies to slow us down.
QUENTIN: Okay,
hey, you know what?
We're all pretty raw, so
why don't we have a drink?
(MUSIC STOPS)
ALICE: Wait a minute.
QUENTIN: Whoa, whoa, whoa...
ALICE: Uh... No, no, no, no, no.
(GRUNTING)
(MUTTERS)
QUENTIN: No,
no, no, no. I'm not...
(SINGING) Ha... Ha...
Happy birthday to you
BOTH: Happy birthday, dear...
Fun and amazing party hounds
Happy birthday to you
You
(ALL CHEERING)
(MUSIC RESUMES)
There's Josh.
We have to figure this out now.
We can't do it here.
We gotta get him alone.
ALICE: I can get him upstairs.
Somebody has to stay
here and put on a show
so that they don't pick
up on any bad vibes.
Okay. You take the nerd.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
I got these bozos.
I can thank good ol' Mom.
Ah.
Here. Here, I...
(GASPS) Who are you?
How can you see me?
I'm Julia.
You've probably
seen me with Irene?
You're Skye.
My... My friend Fen,
she told me about you,
about what happened to your leg.
I'm sorry, I'm very busy.
You clean their homes,
you cook their food,
and they take your leg
and grind it into powder
to snort so they
can do magic tricks.
I wanna help you
get out of here.
No.
No, this is the way.
We can't do magic.
We're helpless.
The McAllistairs,
they protect us.
No, the McAllistairs use
you. And they hurt you.
Mrs. McAllistair will
be angry if I'm late.
I'm told that fairies
can do magic.
If that's true, if I
can show you that,
it proves that the
McAllistairs have lied to you.
About everything.
Meet me in the lab as
soon as you can get away.
Deal?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(JAZZ PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) Got my new gown
Got my hair...
Wait.
Wrong key. Try E.
It's in A.
We like it in E.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
That's... An excellent
idea. (CHUCKLES)
Thank you.
I always felt a connection.
Especially when
you'd glare at me
like you were trying to kill me.
I always thought
you were annoying.
Which turns out to
be my power move.
Yeah, just not today.
(SIGHS)
Got my new gown
Got my hair down
All I need, oh
Is the boy
Got my silk net
Got my heart set
Got my five yards Of
beaded crêpe de chine on
Now all I need's a
strong arm to lean on
If he'll just appear
We'll use this big town
For a toy
And if
He'll say
My darling, I'm yours
I'll throw away
My silk nets
Yes, and every bead
All I really need
Is the boy
Ugh!
Ugh.
Is this a thing
you guys are into?
I'm not judging,
it's just a little high school.
Oh, my God.
Is that the book?
Not here.
All right, of course.
It's not even our piano.
It's just a part of all this.
I don't know what you
guys are babbling about.
I had it moved up here
so I could rehearse.
Hence the reason
it's in my room.
This isn't your room.
Yeah, Josh, you're a Naturalist.
This is not even your house.
(SCOFFS)
That's pretty much all
you know about me, right?
Where am I from?
Where'd I go to undergrad?
When is the last time we
actually saw each other?
A couple of weeks ago? I...
Exactly. I texted, I called.
Over and over, to try to get back
with you guys and go on the quest.
Go ahead, check your phones.
I got one reply, from Julia.
Then nada from any of you.
And that's pretty much all
you think about me, right?
(EXHALES)
Got my new gown
Got my hair down
All I need now
Is the boy
Got my silk net...
Ventriloquist act. Nice trick.
Is that even your
voice down there?
Brava.
You really contacted a lot.
Sorry, we were just so...
Narcissistically up
your own asses?
Look, you ditched us
in Fillory, so it's not...
Not the same.
That was cowardice.
Not indifference.
Look, it's fine. It's fine.
Because we don't really know
each other, and now we don't need to.
Quest is over. Magic is back.
Okay, great, well,
then just magic yourself
out of those ropes.
(SCOFFS)
(GRUNTS) That is weird.
Josh, I know you're a smart guy.
And you want to
believe that this is real
because it feels so good,
but this isn't life, okay?
And I'm worried the longer you
stay here, the less you'll want to leave.
Look, he wants to stay. Fine.
Just tell us how you got
here so we can get out.
Leave us.
(ELIOT SIGHS)
(SIGHING) All right.
Good, good, good,
good, good, good, good.
You pickpocketed the key?
I did...
Not.
Wait till it gets
dark, that's better.
Let me stop you right there.
I will not be
helping you escape.
In fact, I will not be
helping you with anything,
ever again. Wait, what?
You're the worst.
The absolute worst
rulers Fillory has ever had.
Oh, come on. Martin Chatwin?
All of you. Children of Earth.
The divine prank of
Ember and Umber's.
And you know
what's truly infuriating?
How you always really
believe you have the right.
Look, we didn't
make the rules here.
We don't even like them.
Good, as they no longer
need to be followed.
No magic means no
more idiotic Earth rulers,
and I get my Kingdom back.
Your Kingdom?
I ran Fillory for years.
(SCOFFS)
Tick.
Maybe we can just
take a beat, okay?
If there's something
that we did or didn't do,
or missed or fucked up,
don't you think after everything
that we have been
through, you couldn't just,
I don't know, maybe talk to us?
I refuse to beg for what
I have waited to seize.
Now is the time.
Muntjac, we are going
to the Infinite Waterfall.
As soon as we reach
the Point of No Return,
we'll put them in a
lifeboat and let the rapids
carry them over the edge.
And then finally
have a free Fillory
of, for, and by
Fillorians like us.
What do you say?
Allies?
(LAUGHS)
Her too?
Does everybody hate us?
All right, you've got us
guarded and locked down here.
You might as well
just undo these.
I shall...
Not! (LAUGHING)
Okay, the "not"
thing is kind of arch.
How is this not a terrible idea?
Fen, whatever they did,
they don't deserve to...
I mean, nobody deserves to...
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
Mrs. McAllistair is dining.
I have one hour. (DOOR CLOSES)
Uh...
Okay, um, we
won't push too hard.
I just want to see
what you can do.
So after I couldn't find Kady, I
called and called and called...
Okay, we suck. Got it.
Next?
I went back to Bacchus'.
Party was still raging.
But no matter how hard
I hit the pharmaceuticals,
I couldn't shake the fact that I
was ditched hard by you guys.
Which wasn't exactly unfamiliar.
And, can you untie me?
You've made your point
and I can't feel my thumbs.
It's a life theme
for me, I guess.
You know, my brother got
us tickets to that concert.
Turned out to be the last
one Bowie did in the U.S.
I saw it.
It was amazing, wasn't it?
It's what I heard
from my brother,
who ditched me
to take Ann Posner.
And even after they got back
and told me how great it was,
and that Bowie went into
the middle of the crowd
to do Under Pressure, I
didn't feel as bad as I should've
because I was just like,
"This is what happens.
"This is what's
always gonna happen."
Can we just get back to
the part of how you got here?
(MUFFLED MUSIC PLAYING)
Todd? What's up, brother?
Not my dick. I gotta crash.
Hey, uh...
Let you in on a little secret?
(WHISPERS INDISTINCTLY)
Get the fuck out.
(CHUCKLES)
Okay... One, if I'm tripping,
keep me on a molly drip.
Two, who else knows?
Three, how?
(MUSIC PLAYING)
One, you are not tripping.
Two, everyone who needs to know.
And three...
(CHUCKLES)
QUENTIN: Wait,
Todd has the Fifth Key?
It's one of them. I'm not sure.
Well, let's get it.
Well...
The Key...
Isn't the key to what
we're getting up to here.
Okay, but that's
pretty important.
I need to tell my
friends. Are they here?
And sorry, but how can magic be
back if you have one of the keys?
(MUSIC STOPS)
And why are they...
Yes, we lived it.
Uh, have a blast or...
Adiós. ALL: Adiós.
That wasn't maybe a
clue all this was fake?
It's not fake. It's
just different, okay?
Magic comes
back, it's a little off.
Things always evolve.
(SINGING CONTINUES)
for a toy
And if he'll say
My darling I'm
yours, I'll throw away
My silk net, yes
(MUSIC STOPS)
Look, have you seen anybody
else you know other than Todd?
Have you been outside?
I mean, these guys are great.
And I'll get a campus
tour as soon as...
Josh, this is not Brakebills.
And this Todd, very
un-Todd. (SCOFFS)
The real Todd isn't creepily
bossy with a prancing army
that turns psycho the...
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING) Oh, no.
Okay, Josh, the quest
brought us here for a reason,
and it's not to party to
death for Todd's pleasure.
Wait, that's it.
QUENTIN: What's it?
(CROWD SHOUTING OUTSIDE)
Why Todd isn't Todd.
I think... (POUNDING ON DOOR)
Shit.
QUENTIN: Okay, look, we
have been total dicks to you,
and I swear to you, we
are gonna make it up to you,
but you have to buy us some time
so that we can figure this out.
Figure it out or don't,
but if you're right,
and this is my own private
Idaho, I want you out of it.
(ALL SHOUTING)
(FUNK MUSIC PLAYING)
Let's hustle.
(ALL CHEERING)
Ready?
It's okay.
Again.
One, two, three.
(SIGHS)
This is silly.
Maybe you're teaching it wrong.
I've never seen a fairy do all
that Magician-y finger bending.
They are magic.
They don't have to access it.
They just get right to
the ruining-your-life part.
Okay.
Here. Give me your hand.
Imagine a flower growing
out of the palm of your hand.
But don't picture
it in your head.
Picture it here.
In the real world.
(SINGING) You
might not ever get rich
But let me tell you It's
better than digging a ditch
Wait, Todd's a
what? A traumesser.
It's from German folktales.
It's a demon who creates a pocket
world where all your fantasies come true,
and then feeds
off your happiness.
So, it's a joy junkie?
Yeah, and it created
all this to mainline Josh.
Who just happens
to look like Todd?
It's also a shape-shifter.
But how would it find
the Fifth Key and why?
And, why would it hide it?
ALICE: I don't know.
It's not malevolent.
Well, for demons.
Okay, so the demon
had the Fifth Key here.
The book brought us here, so the...
The key has still gotta be here, right?
(SIGHS) Ugh, boy,
not working in E.
What? No, just the... The song.
Not Todd has a fetish for... E.
The Fifth Key.
But from A.
(NOTE PLAYING)
(EXHALES)
Wait, wait. No fingers.
Sometimes bad shit happens.
Give it a sec.
See if it tells us what it is.
Honey, you don't
have to listen to Tick.
You can just do your own thing.
Turn around, head
home, relax, whatevs.
(BOAT RUMBLING)
(EXHALES) Nothing.
Maybe Tick was right about us.
I mean, what really
gave us the right?
Hey, we didn't make the world.
It was baked by fucking
goat-meat nutjobs,
so of course it's insane.
And of course we're insane for
thinking we can make it better.
But you know what? What?
We did.
For a hot minute, we did.
When?
Right after you and
Idri sealed that deal.
And he turned into a rat?
I said "one hot minute."
I meant, literally one perfect
minute on this god-fucked rock.
(LAUGHS)
And we can do it
again. We made it better.
I mean, come on. (SIGHS)
We've pretty much
only ever had each other.
And that's gotten us through
pretty much everything.
Mmm-hmm. I mean, everything.
Everything.
(CHUCKLES) Well,
whatever happens,
thank you for giving us the
time where we can finally
just speak with no
bullshit, and I can just say...
I love you, Margo.
I know.
We've reached the
point of no return.
Please stop so we
can cast them off.
Please. Stop.
Please?
I order you to
stop, this moment.
I am your king.
Stop right now.
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
(WHIMPERS)
(GASPS)
My first Royal Proclamation.
Scuttle all ships
that can think.
Write that down!
I don't suppose
you'd stop for me?
(GASPS)
Ah.
Fuck this.
(BUZZING)
Holy shit.
(GASPS)
(RATTLING)
The necklace.
It kills them when
they use magic.
How could I not... Your eyes.
Julia.
The magic you just did.
You didn't use your hands.
How?
I think I'm leveling up.
(SINGING) Working
at the car wash
Working at the car wash Yeah
Come on down and sing it with me
Car wash
Car wash, yeah
(CHEERING AND WHOOPING)
MAN: Dude, I'm new here, okay?
I don't know
where the coffee is.
I don't even know if
there is coffee here.
Penny.
Wait, you hear him
too? Inside your head?
Yeah, me too. Penny, Penny!
Wait, Kady?
Oh, my God, Penny,
where are you?
I'm... I'm in the
Underworld Library.
Where are you? How
am I hearing you?
I don't know, but
we can all hear you.
Yeah, can you... Can
you hear all of us?
Am I hallucinating?
Um... If you are, so am I.
Eliot, Margo? ELIOT: Quentin?
Penny? What's going on?
Uh... Okay, it's the Fifth Key.
That must be what it does.
It... It links us all up.
Guys, I'm sure this is important,
but I almost killed somebody.
And then somehow
froze her in time.
And I'm not sure
what to do next.
So just give me a sec.
Hi.
Well, we're chained to a boat
about to go over a waterfall.
Yeah, complete with
lacerating rocks, so...
Oh, shit, the
Infinite Waterfall.
Not helping... Wait,
you guys have magic.
Can you stop this boat?
No, it's not that kind of magic.
Great, well, enjoy our
death screams, I guess.
Hey, everybody out of my head.
Josh... Oh, wait, wait,
wait, wait, I think...
Look, look, we go
back to Brakebills.
And then we get the
Time Key, and we reverse...
No, no, no, we can't
go through the door.
Why?
QUENTIN: Because we
are all listening to each other.
We're speaking to each
other. All eight of us.
That...
That's what it is, it's unity.
Uh... The quest brought us to
a world made for the Quester
who always feels left behind.
The key... The key
needs us to work together.
Oh, bullshit!
(MUSIC STOPS)
You know, everything was
great until you guys got here,
so just go. Wait, who's that?
Perfect, thank you, Penny.
You know what? Fuck the rule.
No, Josh, Josh,
just calm down, I...
And fuck you!
(CROWD MURMURING)
(GRUNTING)
No, no. No!
Okay, everybody, listen.
We have to save Josh and
convince him to come back with us.
No idea what
you're talking about.
All right, well, we've got
some life-and-death stakes
of our own over here.
Yes, we're all fucked in
our own way, like always.
But if we do not do this,
then the quest is done.
Okay, we have to work
together and we have to do it now.
All right, it's gonna sound
weird, but just go with me.
You're gonna hear music,
and we're gonna make sure
that everyone knows the words,
but every single
one of us has to sing.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
God, I hate you.
JOSH: Stop! No.
No! No, stop, stop!
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
(PUNCHES LANDING)
(SCATTING)
(SINGING) Pressure
pushing down on me
Pressing down on
you No man ask for
Under pressure
That burns a building
down Splits a family in two
Puts people on streets
(SCATTING)
Julia?
That's the terror of knowing
What this world is about
Watching some good friends
Screaming, "Let me out!"
Pray tomorrow takes me higher
Pressure on people
People on streets
(SCATTING)
Okay
Chippin' around
Kick my brains around the floor
These are the days It
never rains but it pours
(SCATTING)
People on streets
It's the terror of knowing
What this world is about
Watching some good friends
Screaming let me out
Pray tomorrow takes me higher
Higher high
Pressure on people
People on streets
God damn it, Penny.
Turned away from
it all like a blind man
Sat on a fence but it don't work
Keep coming up with love
But it's so slashed and torn
Why
Why Why (SCREAMING)
Love love love love love
Insanity laughs Under
pressure we're cracking
Can't we give ourselves
one more chance
Why can't we give love
That one more chance
Why can't we give
love Give love, give love
Give love, give love, give love
Give love, give love
'Cause love's such
an old-fashioned word
And love dares you
To care for
The people on the
edge of the night
And love dares you
To change our way Of
caring about ourselves
This is our last dance
This is ourselves
Under pressure
Pressure
(CHAINS CLINKING)
Bowie fan?
Margo fan.
Well, he said you'd ace it.
Who said... What?
The only one I'd do this for.
To be honest, it
was kind of a pain.
Nothing personal, Josh,
but after a couple of weeks,
I started having doubts
whether your friends would come
or actually be worthy.
Right, so this was all a test?
Everything's just
a test. Right, Pen?
Penny?
Penny, can you hear me?
QUENTIN: Eliot, Margo?
Wait, why can't we hear
each other anymore?
I don't mean to be rude, but
pigging out on Josh's dream world
has left me a little gassy.
I need a little
me-time at the ashram.
So...
Auf Weidersen. Congratulations.
Schnell, schnell.
You can just feel the boring.
Thank God. (SIGHS)
Wait, where is the Truth Key?
Is it gone?
Just needed to borrow it.
Hey, guys.
(SIGHS)
Josh. You never called me back.
The old me was a dick that way.
(PAPER RUSTLING)
Really?
I missed a lot, didn't I?
Yep.