Previously on "The Magicians..."
Children of Earth have been making a
mess of things here for some time.
I demand that this trial/peasant
uprising be dismissed.
Josh Hoberman, class of '16.
Come with me if you want to live.
It has begun.
Sorry.
Is that cocaine?
It's the excretion of a very
rare magical creature.
But yes, you will have to snort it.
- What creature?
- A fairy?
And I can't see her because
I've never made a fairy deal?
My daughter's dead because of them.
You need to talk to Irene's fairy.
My name is Skye.
Fen, what is it? What do you see?
It's her, it's Skye.
Oh, God, they cut off her leg.
That's what the powder is made of.
_
Weren't you supposed to
report to the Underworld
branch of the Library anyway?
Yeah, and I burned my body
to avoid that.
Did you...
Okay, come on.
Alice, are you working with the Library?
Maybe we should've waited at the
mirror for a little while longer.
- I mean, maybe they survived somehow.
- They didn't.
Ask her.
Harriet and Victoria were in the bridge.
I'm pretty sure both mirrors shattered.
Oh, my God. No.
There's your answer.
Where's your bag?
I need the Truth Key.
To see Penny, if he made it back.
All right.
You found The Fourth Key?
Here we go.
Okay. It's in code.
Be careful with that.
Penny?
- This looks familiar.
- You know what?
No.
Not till you tell me what you
were doing in the Library.
I was finishing something.
Grand Unified Theory of Magic.
I needed information.
Penny!
Funny, 'cause there is
no magic to unify.
Just let me see it again.
No.
I... I know what it is.
Music.
Music?
Medieval music.
Here.
Just give it a minute, okay?
- Sure you're playing it right?
- Yes, I'm sure.
Then you're an idiot.
Back then the scale didn't start at C.
So that's an A.
What?
No, I just didn't know that you had...
Well, me and music go way back.
It's what my mom took her
clothes off to for money.
And save the judgment. She was good.
And she liked it.
And it paid for piano lessons.
What? Where'd it go?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
What the hell?
Where did these people come from?
Who are they?
- I don't recognize them.
- What time is it, y'all?
Todd.
Yeah, it's time for the one, the only
King of Party O'Clock!
♪ Can't wait for the time
when I could shed my skin ♪
♪ You can't read my mind,
but if you're wondering ♪
♪ I'm somebody else,
you ain't met me before ♪
♪ I'll put my real face on ♪
♪ Open the door ♪
♪ Wham, bam, here I am ♪
♪ Demon of the glitter and glam ♪
♪ Yes, catch your breath ♪
♪ Got you eating out of my hand ♪
♪ Wham, thank you, ma'am ♪
♪ Now I'm here, the party is on ♪
♪ Wow, check me out ♪
♪ Don't know what you got
till it's gone ♪
Guys, what took you so long?
♪ Pump the beat through my veins
♪ Ain't no stopping me now ♪
♪ Wham, bam, thank you, ma'am ♪
♪ Now I'm here, the party is on ♪
♪ Wow, check us out ♪
♪ Don't know what you got
till it's gone ♪
♪ Need it up, Need it up ♪
♪ Turn the freakin' music up, Gone ♪
I think we found hell.
Whatever this is, I don't have time.
Where's the door?
Really?
All the clocks say 4:20.
Well, it's not hell for Josh.
Why would the book send us here?
Where are we?
Guys.
Great to see you.
Seriously, it's been too long.
Little word of advice,
this is a no-rules zone,
except one...
You gotta be the vibe.
And the vibe is fun-in-the-sun, and
you can't throw shade, capisce?
I have no idea what you just said.
Good to see you, uh...
Where are we, exactly?
And why are they doing that?
Okay, guys.
Guys, it's okay. It's okay, all right?
What Joshster was telling you,
it's all good in the New World Order,
but one rule, okay?
Have a blast, or adios.
How do we "adios," Todd?
There's no door.
True, but the trade-off...
Is this.
Holy shit.
Yeah, we're not just
partying 'cause it's fun.
We're tearing it up 'cause
magic is back, my babies.
Yeah, it is.
Whoo-hoo.
How? I...
Two words... who cares?
Oh, my gosh, this feels...
That bone saw, the smith who forged it
must've been a monster.
Fen, I did a whole line of
that fairy coke shit.
All right? We've gotta help.
- We can't.
- Excuse me?
I agreed that what's being
done to the fairies is awful,
but they are evil, and I told
you what they did to me,
my daughter.
And Julia, they can't be enslaved.
They can do magic.
Yeah, but that was in Fillory.
You know, it's obviously different here.
Maybe... maybe they're different.
And I can see them
without making a deal.
How?
What the fuck me hell?
You've been found guilty.
By a marsupial in a wig and a robe.
The judge you requested for trial.
- The Wombat?
- Wombat?
Jesus, Tick, I said combat.
We wanted trial by combat.
That is not, as you would say,
"a thing" in Fillory.
Why do you think we went in
with Bingle, a mute swordsman?
If we'd known it was a wombat judge,
we would've hired a wombat lawyer.
There is some good news.
You are free...
to choose the manner of your execution.
Tick.
I don't mean to sound snappish,
but what part of that news
is remotely good?
It's an honor only bestowed upon
the greatest of deposed monarchs.
Let's see.
The serrated spoon......
Don't pick that one.
The steep climb up Fire Ant Mountain.
I'd pick
the serrated spoon first.
The Infinite Waterfall. The Stone Crush.
Wait.
Infinite Waterfall?
It's quite horrid, and wet.
Right.
But which death on your
little list takes the longest?
The one with the word "infinite" in it.
- Right?
- Right.
A lot of time to...
Think on our royal sins and repent.
Plan on how best to...
Meet death...
gracefully.
As desired then.
You will plummet through freezing waters
against walls of razor rocks,
so you bleed out or drown,
or if you're lucky,
just starve to death.
I really don't think we could've
picked a better option.
Feels really good.
There's something very wrong here.
None of my locator spells are working.
I... I don't know where we are.
How about I just blow
a hole in the wall?
Sure, go ahead, but...
The only magic that works here is...
- Party tricks.
- Yeah.
Look, we're on the Quest.
So maybe there's a clue
in what we can and can't do.
What we can't do is sit
around here getting blitzed
on never-ending scotch.
It's cognac, actually.
- Easy.
- You, easy.
- For all I know, this is you.
- Me?
Yeah, doing shit
for your Library buddies
- to slow us down.
- Okay, hey, you know what?
We're all pretty raw,
so why don't we have a drink?
Wait a bit. Wh...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, take it e...
Ah. No, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no. I'm not...
♪ Ha... ha... happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear... ♪
♪ Fun and amazing party hounds ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ You ♪
There's Josh.
We have to figure this out now.
- We can't do it here.
- We gotta get him alone.
I can get him upstairs.
Somebody has to stay here
and put on a show
so that they don't pick up
on any bad vibes.
Okay. You take the nerd.
I got these bozos.
I can thank good ol' mom.
Here. Here, I...
Who are you?
How can you see me?
I'm Julia.
You've probably seen me with Irene?
You're Skye.
Um, my... my friend Fen,
she told me about you,
about what happened with your leg.
I'm sorry, I'm very busy.
You clean their homes,
you cook their food,
and they take your leg
and grind it into powder
to snort so they can do magic tricks.
I wanna help you get out of here.
No.
No, this is the way.
We can't do magic.
We're helpless.
The McAllistairs, they protect us.
No, the McAllistairs use you.
And they hurt you.
Mrs. McAllistair
will be angry if I'm late.
I'm told that fairies can do magic.
If that's true, if I can show you that,
it proves that the McAllistairs
have lied to you.
About everything.
Meet me in the lab as soon
as you can get away.
Deal?
♪ Got my new gown ♪
♪ Got my hair... ♪
Wait.
Wrong key. Try E.
It's in A.
We like it in E.
That's... an excellent idea.
Thank you.
I always felt a connection.
Especially when you'd glare at me
like you were trying to kill me.
I always thought you were annoying.
Which turns out to be my power move.
Yeah, just not today.
♪ Got my new gown ♪
♪ Got my hair down ♪
♪ All I need, oh ♪
♪ Is the boy ♪
♪ Got my silk net ♪
♪ Got my heart set ♪
♪ Got my five yards
of beaded crêpe De chine on ♪
♪ Now all I need's
a strong arm to lean on ♪
♪ If he'll just appear ♪
♪ We'll use this big town ♪
♪ For a toy ♪
♪ And if ♪
♪ He'll say ♪
♪ My darling, I'm yours ♪
♪ I'll throw away ♪
♪ My silk nets ♪
♪ Yes, and every bead ♪
♪ All I really need ♪
♪ Is the boy ♪
Is this a thing you guys are into?
I'm not judging,
it's just a little high school.
Oh, my God.
Is that the book?
Not here.
All right, of course.
It's not even our piano.
It's just a part of all this.
I don't know what you
guys are babbling about.
I had it moved up here
so I could rehearse.
Hence the reason it's in my room.
This isn't your room.
Yeah, Josh, you're a Naturalist.
This is not even your house.
That's pretty much all you
know about me, right?
Where am I from?
Where'd I go to undergrad?
When is the last time
we actually saw each other?
A couple of weeks ago? I...
Exactly. I texted, I called.
Over and over, to try to get
back with you guys
and go on the Quest.
Go ahead, check your phones.
I got one reply, from Julia.
Then Nada from any of you.
And that's pretty much all
you think about me, right?
♪ Got my new gown ♪
♪ Got my hair down ♪
♪ All I need now ♪
♪ Is the boy ♪
♪ Got my silk net... ♪
Ventriloquist act. Nice trick.
Is that even your voice down there?
Brava.
You really contacted a lot.
Um, uh, sorry, we were just so...
Narcissistically up your own asses?
Look, you ditched us
in Fillory, so it's not...
Not the same. That was cowardice.
Not indifference.
Look, it's fine. It's fine.
Because we don't really know each
other, and now we don't need to.
Quest is over. Magic is back.
Okay, great, well,
then just magic yourself
out of those ropes.
That is weird.
Josh, I know you're a smart guy.
And you want to believe
that this is real
because it feels so good,
but this isn't life, okay?
And I'm worried the longer you stay
here, the less you'll want to leave.
Look, he wants to stay. Fine.
Just tell us how you got here
so we can get out.
Leave us.
All right.
Good, good, good,
good, good, good, good.
You pickpocketed the key?
I did...
not.
Wait till it gets dark, that's better.
Let me stop you right there.
I will not be helping you escape.
In fact, I will not be
helping you with anything,
- ever again.
- Wait, what?
You're the worst.
The absolute worst rulers
Fillory has ever had.
Oh, come on. Martin Chatwin?
All of you. Children of Earth.
The divine prank of Ember and Umber's.
And you know what's truly infuriating?
How you always really believe
you have the right.
Look, we didn't make the rules here.
We don't even like them.
Good, as they no longer need
to be followed.
No magic means no more
idiotic Earth rulers,
and I get my Kingdom back.
Your Kingdom?
I ran Fillory for years.
Tick.
Maybe we can just take a beat, okay?
If there's something that
we did or didn't do,
or missed or fucked up,
don't you think after everything
that we have been through,
you couldn't just,
I don't know, maybe talk to us?
I refuse to beg for what
I have waited to seize.
Now is the time.
Muntjac,
we are going to the Infinite Waterfall.
As soon as we reach
the point of no return,
we'll put them in a lifeboat
and let the rapids
carry them over the edge.
And then finally have a free Fillory
of, for, and by Fillorians like us.
What do you say?
Allies?
Her too?
Does everybody hate us?
All right, you've got us
guarded and locked down here.
You might as well just undo these.
I shall...
not.
Okay, the "not" thing is kind of arch.
How is this not a terrible idea?
Fen, whatever they did,
they don't deserve to...
I mean, nobody deserves to...
Mrs. McAllistair is dining.
I have one hour.
Uh, okay, um, we won't push too hard.
I just want to see what you can do.
So after I couldn't find Kady,
I called and called and called...
Okay, we suck. Got it.
Next?
I went back to Bacchus'.
Party was still raging.
But no matter how hard
I hit the pharmaceuticals,
I couldn't shake the fact
that I was ditched hard
by you guys.
Which wasn't exactly unfamiliar.
And, can you untie me?
You've made your point
and I can't feel my thumbs.
It's a life theme for me, I guess.
You know, my brother got us
tickets to that concert.
Turned out to be the last one
Bowie did in the U.S.
- I saw it.
- It was amazing, wasn't it?
Is what I heard from my brother,
who ditched me to take Ann Posner.
And even after they got back
and told me how great it was,
and that Bowie went
into the middle of the crowd
to do "Under Pressure,"
I didn't feel as bad as I should've
because I was just like,
"This is what happens.
This is what's always gonna happen."
Can we just get back to the
part of how you got here?
- Todd?
- What's up, brother?
Not my dick. I gotta crash.
Hey, uh...
Let you in on a little secret?
Get the fuck out.
Okay... one, if I'm tripping,
keep me on a molly drip.
Two, who else knows?
Three, how?
- Ooh.
- One, you are not tripping.
Two, everyone who needs to know.
And three...
Wait, Todd has the Fifth Key?
It's one of them. I'm not sure.
Well, let's get it.
Well...
The key
isn't the key to what
we're getting up to here.
Okay, but that's pretty important.
I need to tell my friends.
Are they here?
And sorry, but how can magic be back
if you have one of the keys?
And why are they...
Yes, we lived it.
Uh, have a blast or... all: Adios.
That wasn't maybe a clue
all this was fake?
It's not fake.
It's just different, okay?
Magic comes back, it's a little off.
Things always evolve.
♪ For a toy ♪
♪ And if he'll say ♪
♪ My darling I'm yours,
I'll throw away ♪
♪ My silk net, yes ♪
Look, have you seen anybody
else you know other than Todd?
- Have you been outside?
- I mean, these guys are great.
And I'll get a campus tour as soon as...
Josh, this is not Brakebills.
And this Todd, very un-Todd.
The real Todd isn't creepily
bossy with a prancing army
that turns psycho the m...
Oh, no.
Okay, Josh, the quest
brought us here for a reason,
and it's not to party to death
for Todd's pleasure.
Wait, that's it.
- What's it?
- Why Todd isn't Todd.
I think...
Shit.
Okay, look, we have been
total dicks to you,
and I swear to you,
we are gonna make it up to you,
but you have to buy us some time
so that we can figure this out.
Figure it out or don't,
but if you're right,
and this is my own private Idaho,
I want you out of it.
Let's hustle.
Ready?
Okay.
It's okay.
Again.
One, two, three.
This is silly.
Maybe you're teaching it wrong.
I've never seen a fairy do all
that Magician-y finger bending.
They are magic.
They don't have to access it.
They just get right to
the ruining-your-life part.
Okay.
Here. Give me your hand.
Imagine a flower growing out
of the palm of your hand.
But don't picture it in your head.
Picture it here.
In the real world.
♪ You might not ever get rich ♪
♪ But let me tell you, it's
better than digging a ditch ♪
- Wait, Todd's a what?
- A traumesser.
It's from German folk tales.
It's a demon who creates a pocket world
where all your fantasies come true,
and then feeds off your happiness.
So, it's a joy junkie?
Yeah, and it created all this
to mainline Josh.
Who just happens to look like Todd?
It's also a shape-shifter.
But how would it find
the Fifth Key and why?
- And, why would it hide it?
- I don't know.
It's not malevolent. Well, for demons.
Okay, so the demon
had the Fifth Key here.
The book brought us here, so the...
the key is still gotta be here, right?
Ugh, boy, not working in E.
- What?
- Uh, just the... the song.
- Not Todd has a fetish for...
- E.
- The Fifth Key.
- But from A.
Wait, wait. No fingers.
Sometimes bad shit happens.
Give it a sec.
See if it tells us what it is.
Honey, you don't have to listen to Tick.
You can just do your own thing.
Turn around, head home, relax, whatevs.
Nothing.
Maybe Tick was right about us.
I mean, what really gave us the right?
Hey, we didn't make the world.
It was baked by fucking
goat-meat nut-jobs,
so of course it's insane.
And of course we're insane for
thinking we can make it better.
- But you know what?
- What?
We did.
- For a hot minute, we did.
- When?
Right after you
and Idri sealed that deal.
And he turned into a rat?
I said "one hot minute."
I meant, literally one perfect minute
on this god-fucked rock.
And we can do it again.
We made it better.
I mean, come on.
We've pretty much
only ever had each other.
And that's gotten us through
pretty much everything.
I mean, everything.
Everything.
Well, whatever happens,
thank you for giving us
the time where we can finally
just speak with no bullshit,
and I can just say,
I love you, Margo.
I know.
We've reached the point of no return.
Please stop so we can cast them off.
Please. Stop.
Please?
I order you to stop, this moment.
I am your king.
Stop right now.
My first Royal Proclamation...
Scuttle all ships that can think.
Write that down.
I don't suppose you'd stop for me?
Fuck this.
Holy shit.
The necklace.
It kills them when they use magic.
- How could I not...
- Your eyes.
Julia. The magic you just did.
You didn't use your hands.
How?
I think I'm leveling up.
♪ Working at the car wash ♪
♪ Working at the car wash, Yeah ♪
♪ Come on down and sing it with me ♪
♪ Car wash ♪
♪ Car wash, yeah ♪
Dude, I'm new here, okay? I
don't know where the coffee is.
I don't even know
if there is coffee here.
Penny.
- Wait, you hear him too?
- Inside your head? Yeah, me too.
Penny, Penny!
Wait, Kady?
Oh, my God, Penny, where are you?
I'm... I'm in the Underworld Library.
Where are you? How am I hearing you?
I don't know, but we can all hear you.
Yeah, can you... can you hear all of us?
- Am I hallucinating?
- If you are, so am I.
Um...
- Eliot, Margo?
- Quentin?
Penny? What's going on?
Uh, okay, it's the Fifth Key;
that must be what it does.
It... it links us all up.
Guys, I'm sure this is important,
but I almost killed somebody.
And then somehow froze her in time.
And I'm not sure what to do next.
So just give me a sec. Hi.
Well, we're chained to a boat
about to go over a waterfall.
Yeah, complete
with lacerating rocks, so...
Oh, shit, the Infinite Waterfall.
Not helping...
wait, you guys have magic.
Can you stop this boat?
No, it's not that kind of magic.
Great, well, enjoy
our death screams, I guess.
Hey, everybody out of my head.
Josh... oh, wait, wait,
wait, wait, I think, um...
Look, look, we go back to Brakebills.
And then we get the Time
Key, and we reverse...
No, no, we can't go through the door.
Why?
Because we are all
listening to each other.
We're speaking to each other.
All eight of us. That...
That's what it is, it's unity. Uh...
The Quest brought us to a world
made for the Quester
who always feels left behind. The key...
The key needs us to work together.
- Um...
- Oh, bullshit!
You know, everything was great
until you guys got here,
- so just go.
- Wait, who's that?
Perfect, thank you, Penny.
You know what? Fuck the rule.
No, Josh, uh, Josh, just calm down, I...
And fuck you!
Wah!
Ah, no, no.
Okay, everybody, listen.
Um, we have to save Josh
and convince him to come back with us.
No idea what you're talking about.
All right, well, we've got
some life and death stakes
of our own over here.
Yes, we're all fucked
in our own way, like always.
But if we do not do this,
then the Quest is done.
Okay, we have to work together
and we have to do it now.
All right, it's gonna sound weird,
but just go with me.
You're gonna hear music,
and I'm gonna make sure that
everyone knows the words,
but every single one of us has to sing.
God, I hate you.
Ah, stop! Ugh, no.
No, stop, stop!
♪ Mm bu Ba De ♪
♪ Um bum Ba De ♪
♪ Bu bu bum Ba De De ♪
♪ Pressure pushing down on me ♪
♪ Pressing down on you, No man ask for ♪
♪ Under pressure ♪
♪ That brings a building down,
Splits a family in two ♪
♪ Puts people on streets ♪
♪ Um Ba Ba be, Um Ba Ba be ♪
♪ Bi De da, Di De da ♪
Julia?
♪ That's the terror of knowing ♪
♪ What this world is about ♪
♪ Watching some good friends ♪
♪ Screaming let me out ♪
♪ Pray tomorrow gets me higher ♪
♪ Pressure on people,
People on streets ♪
♪ De De dum ♪
♪ Ba da da da bum ♪
♪ Okay ♪
♪ Chippin' around ♪
♪ Kick my brains around the floor ♪
♪ These are the days
it never rains but it pours ♪
♪ Ee doo doe De ma ♪
♪ Ee da Ba Ba Ba ♪
♪ Do bum, beh lap ♪
♪ People on streets ♪
♪ Ee da Dee da deh ♪
♪ Ee da Dee da Dee da Dee da ♪
♪ It's the terror of knowing
what this world is about ♪
♪ Watching some good friends ♪
♪ Screaming let me out ♪
♪ Pray tomorrow takes me higher ♪
♪ Higher high ♪
♪ Pressure on people,
People on streets ♪
God damn it, Penny.
♪ Turned away from it all
like a blind man ♪
♪ Sat on a fence but it don't work ♪
♪ Keep coming up with love ♪
♪ But it's so slashed and torn ♪
♪ Why ♪
♪ Why, Why ♪
♪ Love love love love love ♪
♪ Insanity laughs
under pressure we're cracking ♪
♪ Can't we give ourselves
one more chance ♪
♪ Why can't we give love
that one more chance ♪
Give love give love ♪
♪ Give love give love, Give love ♪
♪ Give love give love ♪
♪ 'Cause love's such
an old-fashioned word ♪
♪ And love dares you ♪
♪ To care for ♪
♪ The people on the ♪
♪ Edge of the night ♪
♪ And love dares you ♪
♪ To change our way of ♪
♪ Caring about ourselves ♪
♪ This is our last dance ♪
♪ This is ourselves ♪
♪ Under pressure ♪
♪ Pressure ♪
Bowie fan?
Margo fan.
Well, he said you'd ace it.
Who said... what?
The only one I'd do this for.
To be honest, it was kind of a pain.
Nothing personal, Josh,
but after a couple of weeks,
I started having doubts whether
your friends would come
or actually be worthy.
Right, so this was all a test?
Everything's just a test. Right, Pen?
Penny?
- Penny, can you hear me?
- Eliot, Margo?
Wait, why can't we hear
each other anymore?
I don't mean to be rude,
but pigging out on Josh's dream world
has left me a little gassy.
I need a little me time at the ashram.
So...
Auf Weidersen. Congratulations.
Schnell, schnell.
You can just feel the boring.
Thank God.
Wait, where is the Truth Key?
Is it gone?
Just needed to borrow it.
Hey, guys.
Josh. You never called me back.
The old me was a dick that way.
Really?
- I missed a lot, didn't I?
Yep.