Previously on The Magicians...
On Earth, barely any time has
passed, while here, it's been 300 years.
High King Fen and
Josh the Fresh Prince
were overthrown 300 years ago.
The Dark King reigns.
Glory to his rule.
So, tell me. Did you happen
to bring any food with you?
A monster rode you around for
months while he murdered people.
And then one of your
closest friends died.
The surges are getting worse.
I'm just saying, this is the type of
thing I should be using my magic to fix.
The apocalypse is happening,
but you won't accept my
help because I'm a woman?
Quite right.
My name is Professor Adiyodi.
It's not a voice. It's
more like a signal.
I'm gonna take down my
wards so you can show me.
Professor?
This building. It's missing.
Do you know what kind of skills
it would take to steal a building
with Level Five wards?
I miss him every day, too.
No one gets to tell
you how to grieve, Alice.
If you need to do something
crazy to get through it,
do something crazy, okay?
Quentin?
Where am I?
Where are my pants?
If this is a dream, which
it seems like it's a dream,
shouldn't knowing it's
a dream wake me up?
Unless it's a lucid dream,
like that episode of Voyager.
Or I've been kidnapped by aliens
who are trying to get secrets out of me
like that other
episode of Voyager.
Is something wrong?
No. It's just you sound like
someone I used to know.
I feel like I'm supposed to
be helping you with something.
Is that weird?
No, it isn't weird at all.
You're right. This
is a crazy dream.
See, this belonged to my
friend, and I can't read it.
But you can.
And you're supposed to tell me
what it says, and then you'll wake up.
What language is it in?
I was hoping you knew.
I've never seen it before.
What? Sorry.
If it was Elvish or Klingon...
This is a really weird dream.
Do you have a car? Can
you take me to Taco Bell?
Where the hell is
that Portal Tree?
You are doing such a great job.
Will you promise me something?
Mmm? When this is all
over, we can still be friends?
No.
Whoa.
This isn't real.
Eliot. Hey!
Hey. How are you
talking right now?
I'm dead, not rude.
You're a ghost. Am I?
Sorry. It's hard to be mad.
I was a terrible High King.
Or that's what a lot of
people screamed at me,
and a lot of strangers
screaming at you can't be wrong.
Right. Anyhoo, they hung me.
"Fen out, bitches."
For what it's worth, I am sorry
that I wasn't here to save you.
It's okay. Really.
The last I heard, you were
still possessed by The Monster.
And I figured if they did save
you, you'd probably be off drinking.
Honestly, I was counting on
Margo to save me. Or Quentin.
Or Alice, or Penny,
or Julia or Dean Fogg.
But I know the man I married.
Too well, it seems.
Oh, no, look at your sad face.
Don't be hard on
yourself. I'm already dead.
It's not like you can do some
kind of magic to turn back time.
Wait. Unless... Can you?
Eliot, if you can save
me, you have to do it.
Buzzards are coming
soon to peck out my eyes.
My poor dead eyes!
Okay, fine. Jesus. Oh, God!
Chill.
Yikes.
Eliot!
Which one of you beefy twats
built a Magician-proof dungeon?
All right, let's brute
force this mother.
Oh, my God.
My friends, if you're reading
this, it's because I'm dead.
Or I escaped and forgot
to get rid of this letter.
But probably the
first one. R.I.P. me.
We knew something
had gone right on your end
when magic came
back stronger than ever.
But then we didn't
hear from you.
- News from the Northern Marsh.
- What about our friends?
Have any of the messenger
bunnies returned?
Not as of yet.
The rabbits believe the connection
between our world and yours
has been disturbed somehow.
They're refusing to
come out of their burrows,
no matter how many
cigarettes we offer them.
Days turned into months
with no word from anyone
and no way for us
to return to Earth.
Her languorousness Abigail advises
we send our armies to the Northern Marsh
to investigate the
reports of these creatures.
The locals called
them "the Takers."
Look, man, I may be drowning my sorrows
in fried chicken, but I'm not an idiot.
We're in over our heads.
That's why we need to
get a message to Margo.
We spent so much time
trying to get you back
that we didn't see the real
problem right in front of us.
The people rose up against us.
On the count of
three, we charge.
But I don't have a weapon.
You are the weapon.
I'm just saying, you have two.
One, two, three, charge!
It did not go well for us.
Like a dope, I had done some renovations
and made the dungeon Magician-proof.
Oops.
Margo, I hope it's
you who finds this.
And I hope you
understand, I did it all for you.
Goodbye.
Did your pig visitor
tell you about the nature
of this apocalyptic
whatever-the-hell
that's coming to kill us all?
No, but Magicians are blowing
themselves up all over the place.
So many that civilians
have caught on. I think...
There's too much
goddamn magic. Yes, I know.
Some surges come and go
and hardly anyone notices.
And sometimes it's a clusterfuck
of catastrophe and death.
I'm trying to find a pattern.
Why some surges and not others?
Well, if you'd had a
proper Brakebills education,
you'd know the answer.
Circumstances, dear.
The phase of the moon,
the nearest body of water.
You must factor them
all into your casting.
Even us filthy hedges
know about circumstances.
The trick is
certain circumstances
make casting easier.
Others make them
much more difficult.
Some of the surges must be lining up
with particularly favorable circumstances.
Is there any way
to predict them,
so we can warn
people in advance?
I may know someone
who can help you.
Professor Ex.
Wait. Like the X-Men?
No. She's my ex-lover.
I like calling her that
because she hates it.
She's a genius at metamath.
Do you feel that? A surge.
Damn it.
That was Professor Ex's
classroom blowing up.
I picked a hell of a
week to quit drinking.
I asked around.
Nobody knows who
stole the Book Depository.
Did you ask David
Copperfield? Yeah.
Oh.
But a job this big, somebody
should have seen it.
All right, look,
my brain is fried,
so I either need to get some sleep
or to fry it some more, recreationally.
Well, club soda is as crazy
as I get these days, so...
Casual sex then?
Good night, Pete.
Good night, boss.
Your friend is like if
cocaine was a person.
Well, it's a hedge bar.
That description fits
half the people here.
Not you.
What am I?
A Mossad assassin
undercover as a lumberjack?
And you play bass in a
J-pop hard metal cover band?
Close. K-pop.
Yu-jin.
Kady.
Mmm, good morning.
Is it?
Yeah, I know what you mean.
I haven't had a night
like that in a while.
I'll just, um... Pants.
Uh, if you want to
hang sometime or, heh...
You know, I'm just
gonna stop talking.
I'm just...
Call... Call me.
Finally getting that GED?
Have some respect.
I'm a professor.
Oh. "Chapter Seven,
Travelling Against Your Will"?
That sounds like a problem.
One of my students
was hearing this signal,
and when I listened
to it, I just travelled.
No idea where, no idea why.
And none of this can explain it.
So, just don't listen
to the signal again?
Wow. Thank you. Shut up.
Except now I
hear it all the time.
This, here, helps
quiet down a bit, but...
It's kind of terrifying to lose
control of yourself like that. Yeah.
Are you okay?
You know, hangover remedies
are kind of a specialty of mine.
I remember.
No judgment or
anything, but I thought...
I'm sober.
Well, I was. Almost a year.
And here I am, and my head
feels like it's gonna explode.
And if I remembered
deciding to have that first drink,
I would tell you why I did it.
You're human. Dust yourself off.
Maybe keep searching for leads
on that vanishing Book
Depository or whatever.
What?
That library branch
that got heisted.
You spent all day
yesterday looking for it.
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
Are you sure you're
just hungover?
Did you get my tacos?
I got one of
everything they had.
Whose house is this? My mom's.
Where is she?
She's at a sex... She's camping.
This is a really long dream.
Mmm-hmm.
Hey. Oh, God.
What? Oh, hi.
Um, look, I need help
with a metamath problem.
The professor who specializes
in it at Brakebills blew herself up,
so I figured, next
best thing, right?
Yeah, you know,
now's not a good time.
My cousin's here from Canada,
and, well, he's Canadian,
so, anyway, I've got to go.
Alice.
That's... That's Quentin.
What the hell did you do?
Hello.
Oh, shit.
So, what do you say?
Wanna go back in time,
save my friends, and un-fuck
history for old times' sake?
If I change anything,
it could undo every sacrifice
we've all made to stop The Beast.
Why did you build a workshop
full of time travel gadgets
if you aren't
willing to use them?
The lesson that I've learned from
a life of trying to change the past is,
well, you almost always
make things worse.
Speaking of, where is
my little Volunteer Tomato?
Volunteer, um...
Quentin, my dear.
He died saving me.
Saving everybody.
Stiff upper lip, hey?
Positively British of you.
Someone's gotta
keep it together.
Is that what you
think you're doing?
Back when Quentin first came
to Fillory in the very first timeline,
he was running from grief.
His best friend had
died, tragically. Julia.
You.
A victim of your own vices.
I was worried that I was
taking advantage of him,
of his sorrow.
So the first change I
made was to save you.
To see if he would
still answer Fillory's call,
and he did.
And then he died.
Thirty-nine times.
I'd hoped this time
would be different.
It still could be.
You saved him 39
times. Why not 40?
Because he won.
If you took away his sacrifice,
you'd lose everything
that it brought you.
Your life, and the lives
of everyone around you.
Same with your friends
Josh and... Was it "Flen"?
It was not.
You have to let
go of the past, Eliot.
Let the dead stay dead.
Time is a
motherfucker, isn't it?
Ah. Tea's ready.
Oh, shit.
Why are you staring
at me? Because...
Holy shit. You look
like somebody I know.
My friend Julia.
Her grandma.
Yeah. Okay. Great.
Um, you know, I actually
have to talk to Alice,
so maybe you could go
play with rocks or something.
So, you built a
golem out of living clay
and used the book of Quentin's
life to fill it with his memories?
It's not so crazy.
And then you animated the
whole thing with his essence?
No, it's just a tiny grain of Q's soul
that I pulled from the Underworld.
You wouldn't help
me with a seance,
and then you go and do this?
Well, I knew it was
risky, but it worked.
But it didn't.
That is not the Quentin
you knew. That's...
How could you do
something like this?
I found this in Q's
stuff at Brakebills.
What is this?
I don't know. It's in a
language I've never seen before.
It could be a letter, or a diary
or a project he was working on.
I thought maybe he
left it for me to find.
So you built the version of
Q that could read this for you.
Right, but... He's
12, so he can't.
Get rid of it.
Put back the piece of Q's essence
that you stole and let him be at rest.
It's not that simple.
The spell keeps the golem alive
until he completes the
task I brought him here to do.
So the spell can never be finished
'cause he can't read Q's letter.
This was so insanely selfish.
I can't sleep. I can
barely breathe. I...
I needed to fix something,
finish something for him.
Yeah, well, you fucked up.
Maybe if we can figure
out how, we can fix it,
and you can put back the piece
of Quentin's soul where it belongs.
I'm glad you called. Last
night was a bit of a blur.
I was hoping for
a second chance.
Kind of a blur for me,
too. Which is why I called.
See, I'm sober.
I don't remember
drinking last night,
but I've got gaps in my
memory, and not just last night.
I can't remember things
that happened days ago.
What are you saying?
I want to know if
you can explain.
You want to know
if I drugged you?
I left you my number. I... I
showed up for a second date.
Which is big for me, since I
am terrified of settling down.
Oh, maybe I took a chance on you
because you remind me of my cousin
who I've been obsessed
with since we were 13.
Yes, my first cousin.
But our moms are twins,
so genetically my half-sister.
Which makes it worse.
Why am I saying all this?
Because I truthie-d your drink.
You drugged me to
see if I drugged you?
You are insane. But I swear,
whatever happened to you, I didn't do it.
I mean, I did some
stuff to you. On you.
I mean with you.
The... The sex stuff.
Because you asked, for the
record. God, fucking truth serums.
Wait, wait. Kady. Kady.
Um...
I got to my building
this morning
and I couldn't remember
which apartment was mine.
I thought, "Hey, crazy night."
But seems like, if your memory
was changed, so was mine.
I need to know why.
If the beheading didn't kill Josh,
the room service would have.
I'll take your complaint
to the manager.
Eliot?
Just in time. The
cell is Margo-proof,
and when the Dark King gets
back from his Summer Palace,
I'm gonna be executed.
What's that?
The contents of Jane
Chatwin's garage,
which we will use to
take back our kingdom.
My kingdom. But sure.
What is this? "Permanence,
for men and women."
Ugh.
God, could you ask first?
Says this will protect us
from timey-wimey whatever,
so we can change the past and
not erase ourselves in the future.
Clutch.
What's that?
A smoker. Beekeepers use
them to calm down their hives.
So that's super-applicable
to our current situation.
Wait.
Josh would never shut up about
the Royal Bees of Whitespire.
They make all the honey
for the castle's kitchens.
And they're talking bees.
Okay, all you have to do
is get the bees to deliver a
message to Josh in the past,
and then smoke them out.
Huh.
Time bees.
Hello there, bees.
Time bees activated.
I'm not sure it feels like we
changed the past. At least, not yet.
What are you doing?
There used to
be a letter in here.
Huh.
It's Fen's.
High King Fen here,
giving you an update on
life in Castle Whitespire.
Babadook hats and open-toed
shoes are the style this season.
Ooh, hey, Josh, hey.
Get in my Insta Story.
Uh, no. There is
no Insta on Fillory.
But... And so this is...
I have three bars.
We're on a different
planet. That's not even...
How do you have three bars?
This is... Whose phone is that?
The time bees.
- Oh, God, do you hear that?
- Well played, sister.
Oh, they're saying something.
Fen, I'm allergic to bees!
Or maybe not.
Oh, Josh! Please help me!
Oh! No! I'm being killed!
So many bees!
Did Josh say he was allergic?
Right.
That's why Josh would
never shut up about the bees.
Oops.
I had a friend who
used to do that.
Once he got to the
end of his favorite book,
he'd go back to
the beginning again.
Endings are the worst part.
Characters grow up, they
move on, some of them die.
It feels like...
Your best friend in the whole
world has abandoned you.
I've had this conversation
before. So have I.
The therapist my mom sends
me to says I have transition anxiety.
As if it's too much to ask
that nothing ever change.
Well, your real friends won't
abandon you. That will never change.
Or my best friend will start dating
skeevy guys who smoke and spit
and she'll forget
I ever existed.
You're just gonna have
to trust me on this one,
but the skeevy guys thing
is just a phase.
She needs you just as
much as you need her.
Excuse me.
Well, I tried to find a flaw
in the casting, but I couldn't.
It's him.
It's Q.
The one I knew at that age.
But the spell...
I've been doing a lot of
reading on circumstances.
Not all of them are
astrological. Some of them...
Are inside you.
I think you did
that spell perfectly.
Your brain might have asked
for the version of Q
that could read his letter,
but your internal circumstances
asked for something different.
Maybe you need to ask
him a different question.
What's that?
A History of Fillory,
from the Royal Library.
What does it say?
"After the Fresh Prince was stung to
death by a swarm of honey-drunk assassins,
"High King Fen..." My God,
she listened to the bees.
"She sent an army of soldiers
to hunt down the Dark King.
"A massive manhunt
"that was viewed as tyrannical
overreach by the people of Fillory.
"She was overthrown
and executed.
"The Takers invaded,
the Dark King still rose."
So that's it then?
In... In what conceivable
universe is that it?
I'm just saying we're doing all of
this to save a man you ostensibly love,
who died of a bee sting because
you forgot he was allergic.
What is your fucking point?
I was gone. You were alone,
and you hate being alone,
and so you grabbed the first
dick that crossed your desk,
and now you're having
a hard time letting go.
You think I should let
go of our friends' lives?
I think you have a textbook
case of cock-blindness.
You are Margo the Destroyer,
not Margo the Pining Girlfriend.
I'm gonna let
your bullshit slide
on account of you so recently being
possessed by a homicidal monster.
But I'm not changing my plan.
Okay. Okay.
Go for it.
All right.
Wait.
I recognize these.
The first time Jane
came to Fillory by herself,
she was homesick
and missed her brothers.
A forest crone gave
her these stamps.
Put them on a letter, address it
to whoever, wherever, whenever,
and it gets to them.
This could be our chance.
I can just tell Josh
how to fix things.
Find an envelope, address
it to Josh Hoberman,
Castle Whitespire,
before he was killed by bees.
Dear Josh, hello from your
friends 300 years in the future.
The bad news is we
can't come back to get you.
The good news, if you
do exactly what I say,
you won't be
overthrown and executed.
Uh, Fen? You're
gonna want to see this.
Those reports
you've been ignoring
about an invasion of creatures
in the Northern Marsh?
Stop ignoring them.
Send an army. Today.
I told you we should have.
Just shush. Summon the guards!
Everyone, we did it.
We scared the Takers back to
wherever the hell they came from.
Go us!
And somehow,
when we fix the past,
I hope we can see
each other again.
Love, Margo.
The letter disappeared the
moment I closed the mailbox.
It worked.
Josh and Fen did a banishment
spell to scare off the Takers,
they thought.
Then the creatures came back
and killed Josh and Fen
and everyone in Whitespire.
Don't say anything.
Okay, it's working.
So, how does a homemade psychic
amplifier help if I'm not a psychic?
Lowers the bar just enough for the two
of you to be able to connect your minds.
We're both missing memories.
If we combine the ones we have,
it might be enough
to give us an answer.
Huh.
So, it's like, uh,
memory VR. No.
Are you sure about this?
I'm sure I need to know
what happened to me.
You? Same.
Don't touch.
Hands together, please.
So, where should we start?
Last night. The bar.
Your friend is like if
cocaine was a person.
Well, it's a hedge bar.
That description fits
half the people here.
Not you.
Oh... Come on. This
is totally memory VR.
Shh.
Now what?
A Mossad assassin
undercover as a lumberjack?
Now we watch.
You play bass in a J-pop
hard metal cover band?
I can look away.
You clearly already remember it.
I don't know.
No drugs slipped into our
drinks, no head injuries.
Whatever happened to us,
it seems like we both forgot.
Oh, what the hell?
Stop! What are you doing?
Kady, uh, I know
that looked bad.
What the hell was that? What,
some kind of memory spell?
I mean, it looked like it, but I
don't know. I don't remember.
Well, what the hell do you remember
then? Why were you at the bar?
To drink to. To...
To meet a friend. Who?
A Hedge I know from
my first safe house.
Show me.
That's my friend. She's...
The woman that Pete left with.
What are you? What, some
kind of Manchurian Candidate?
A sleeper agent that gets activated
to attack women in their bedrooms?
This doesn't make any
sense. What's on the card?
I can't make it out. Damn it.
I know what's on the card. How?
You put your phone number on it.
Oh, Kady, wait...
So show me who you really are.
Someone sent you to
erase my memory. Who?
I have no idea.
I never do. I
get a job, I do it.
And when it's over, I
make sure I don't remember.
You walk around having no
idea what you do for a living?
Why would I want
that on my conscience?
Because that's what
a conscience is for.
To keep you from
doing fucked-up shit.
The world is painful.
That's not gonna change.
So I use whatever crutch
I have to to keep going.
Point is, you can take
the shiv from my throat,
because I can't rat out
someone I don't remember.
Well, my friend's a psychic.
Why don't I have him root around
and see what you do
and don't remember?
Then you don't leave
me much choice, Kady.
No! Damn it!
Who sent you?
What the hell happened?
I don't know. He just...
He self-destructed.
He's gone.
Telling them to kill the
Dark King was a bust.
Same with going
after the Takers.
We need a new plan. We
only have two stamps left.
One stamp. After your last
letter to Josh, I had an idea.
I gave it a shot. It didn't
work, so... one stamp.
And you didn't tell me?
I'm not your subject.
I'm your friend.
Fine. Then what would
you tell Josh to do?
Run to the nearest dive
and drink himself to death?
Yes. I would run away.
Because you try to save your
friends and they die anyway.
You can't stop the Takers and
you can't stop the Dark King.
And if we don't focus on getting
you out, you're gonna get decapitated.
Fillory is fucked
because it always is,
and I don't get why you
keep trying to fix something
that wants to be broken.
It may be broken,
but it's my home.
It hasn't been your
home for 300 years.
You are right about one
thing. I have gone soft.
I've been telling myself that if I
can just keep Josh from dying,
somehow I can get him
and my kingdom back.
But that's not possible. Is it?
What are you telling him?
I told him he
needs to stay here.
He can use the information
from this history book
to fight the Dark
King and the Takers
wherever they show
up for the rest of his life.
I told him goodbye.
I'm not dreaming, am I?
I ask because it's
been like a full day,
and if you sleep for that
long it's 'cause you're dead.
I had this friend who
I loved very much,
and he died.
And I didn't get to say goodbye.
And I honestly don't know how
I'm gonna go on without him.
And he gave me this
gift I can never repay.
What was the gift?
His life.
He gave it up for mine.
I brought you here
'cause I wanted closure.
You know, I just...
I wanted to fix something
or finish something for him.
But the letter I showed
you, you couldn't read it, so...
You're skipping to the
beginning of the book.
What?
I can't help you because
you don't want me to.
Because then your
friend's story is over.
My dad says when I get sad
about something that's gonna end...
I should just imagine this is
the first page in a new book.
The gift your friend gave you,
it wasn't his life.
It was yours.
That story just started.
What?
I shouldn't be surprised
that even at age 12,
Quentin Coldwater is still
the smartest person I know.
I'm feeling tired.
Really tired.
Hey, do you want to see a trick?
Sure.
That was cool. Yeah.
There's just one more thing
I wanted to say.
Goodbye, Quentin.
He's gone.
Are you okay?
I'm sorry he couldn't give
you the answer you wanted.
No. He did.
Maybe I can still help
you with your problem.
My dad had a friend with a really rare
discipline, predicting circumstances.
They lost touch years
ago, but she wrote this.
If anyone can find the pattern
you're looking for, it'll be her.
Thanks.
I don't remember any of it.
The Book Depository, the mystery
woman who apparently wiped my memory.
All I know is what
you told me, which...
Isn't enough to
do anything with.
Somebody's out there with
enough power to steal a building,
paranoid enough to send mind-wiping
sleeper agent assassins after you.
It's not nothing.
Well, I need a drink.
Sorry. Insensitive.
I'll show myself out.
How are you feeling?
And I thought that if I took on
more power and more responsibility,
that I'd want heroin less.
But the truth is, when
I thought I'd relapsed,
I wasn't disappointed.
I wasn't mad at myself.
I was relieved.
It gave me permission
to relapse some more.
Trying to lead the hedges,
it's only gonna get harder.
And I'm not sure I can
do it without a crutch.
Which maybe means
I shouldn't do it at all.
Hey... No.
You never quite get used to the
smell of Fillorian plumbing, do you?
Josh. You're alive.
Thanks to you.
I got your letter.
Right. The letter.
I did exactly what you said.
I went to the Clock Dwarf,
brought him a ham sandwich
and told him to send
me forward 300 years.
Just you?
No. Fen came, too.
And Tick, and Rafe and a few
guys from my bowling league.
I started a bowling league.
And about a dozen other people.
Nobody cool wanted to stay in the
past once they knew what was coming.
I can't believe it.
Look behind the stone.
I hid it there before I left.
Margo, thank you.
May I present the government
of High King Margo in exile.
Let's get out of here
before we all get killed.
Hey, Margo.