Previously,
on "The Magicians"...
On Earth, barely any time
has passed,
while here, it's been 300 years.
High King Fen
and Josh the Fresh Prince
were overthrown 300 years ago.
The Dark King reigns.
Glory to his rule.
So, tell me, did you happen
to bring any food with you?
A monster
rode you around for months
while he murdered people,
and then one
of your closest friends died.
The surges are getting worse.
I'm just saying,
this is the type of thing
I should be using my magic
to fix.
The apocalypse is happening,
but you won't accept my help
because I'm a woman?
Quite right.
My name is Professor Adiyodi.
It's not a voice.
It's more like a signal.
I'm gonna take down my wards
so you can show me.
Professor?
This building, it's missing.
Do you know what
kind of skills it would take
to steal a building
with level five wards?
I miss him every day too.
No one gets to tell you
how to grieve, Alice.
If you need to do
something crazy
to get through it...
do something crazy, okay?
Quentin?
Where am I?
Where are my pants?
If this is a dream...
Which it seems like
it's a dream...
Shouldn't knowing it's a dream
wake me up?
Unless it's a lucid dream
like that episode of "Voyager."
Or I've been kidnapped by aliens
who are trying
to get secrets out of me,
like that other episode
of "Voyager."
- Something wrong?
- No.
It's just, you sound
like someone I used to know.
I feel like...
I'm supposed to be helping you
with something.
Is that weird?
No, it isn't weird at all.
You're right.
This is a crazy dream.
See, this belonged to my friend,
and I can't read it.
But you can,
and you're supposed to tell me
what it says
and then you'll wake up.
What language is it in?
I was hoping you knew.
I've never seen it before.
What?
Sorry.
If it was Elvish or Klingon...
This is a really weird dream.
Do you have a car?
Can you take me to Taco Bell?
Where the hell is that
portal tree?
You are doing such a great job.
Will you promise me something?
When this is all over...
we can still be friends?
Meh.
No!
Whoa.
This isn't real.
Eliot! Hey!
Hey.
How are you talking right now?
I'm dead, not rude.
- Oh, you're a ghost.
- Am I?
- Sorry.
- It's hard to be mad.
I was a terrible High King.
Or that's what a lot
of people screamed at me,
and a lot of strangers
screaming at you
can't be wrong.
Right.
Anyhoo, they hung me.
Fen out, bitches.
For what it's worth,
I am sorry that I wasn't
here to save you.
It's okay, really.
The last I heard,
you were still possessed
by The Monster.
And I figured
if they did save you,
you'd probably be off drinking.
Honestly, I was counting
on Margo to save me.
Or Quentin or Alice or Penny
or Julia or Dean Fogg,
but I know the man I married.
Too well, it seems.
Oh, no, look at your sad face.
Don't be hard on yourself.
I'm already dead.
It's not like you can
do some kind of magic
to turn back time...
Wait, unless... can you?
Eliot, if you can save me,
you have to do it.
- The buzzards are coming soon...
- Wha...
- To peck out my eyes!
- My poor dead eyes!
- Okay, fine.
- Oh, God!
Jesus, ch... chill.
Oh, God!
Eliot!
Which one of you beefy twats
built a magician-proof dungeon?
All right,
let's brute-force this mother.
Oh, my God.
"My friends,
if you're reading this,
"it's because I'm dead
"or I escaped and forgot
to get rid of this letter,
"but probably the first one.
"R-I-P me.
"We knew something
had gone right on your end
"when magic came back
stronger than ever,
but then we didn't
hear from you."
- News from the Northern Marsh.
- What about our friends?
Have any of the messenger
bunnies returned?
Not as of yet.
The rabbits believe
the connection
between our world and yours
has been disturbed somehow.
They're refusing
to come out of their burrows
no matter how many cigarettes
we offer them.
"Days turned into months
with no word from anyone
and no way
for us to return to Earth."
Her languorousness Abigail
advises we send our armies
to the Northern Marsh
to investigate the reports
of these creatures.
The locals call them The Takers.
Look, man, I may be drowning
my sorrows in fried chicken,
but I'm not an idiot.
We're in over our heads.
That's why we need to get
a message to Margo.
"We spent so much time
trying to get you back
"that we didn't see
the real problem
"right in front of us.
The people rose up against us."
On the count of three,
we charge.
- I don't have a weapon.
- You are the weapon!
I'm just saying, you have two.
One, two, three, charge!
"It did not go well for us."
"Like a dope,
I had done some renovations
"and made the dungeon
magician-proof.
"Oops.
"Margo, I hope it's you
who finds this...
"And I hope you understand,
I did it all for you."
"Good-bye."
Did your pig visitor tell you
about the nature
of this apocalyptic
whatever-the-hell
that's coming to kill us all?
No, but magicians
are blowing themselves up
all over the place.
So many that civilians
have caught on.
I think...
There's too much goddamn magic.
Yes, I know.
Some surges come and go
and hardly anyone notices.
And sometimes it's a clusterfuck
of catastrophe and death.
I'm trying to find a pattern.
Why some surges and not others.
Well, if you'd had
a proper Brakebills education,
you'd know the answer.
Circumstances, dear.
The phase of the moon,
the nearest body of water.
You must factor them all
into your casting.
Even us filthy hedges
know about Circumstances.
Trick is, certain Circumstances
make casting easier.
Others make them
much more difficult.
Some of the surges
must be lining up
with particularly favorable
Circumstances.
Is there any way to predict them
so we can warn people
in advance?
I may know someone
who can help you.
Professor Ex.
Wait, like the X-Men?
No, she's my ex-lover.
I like calling her that
because she hates it.
She's a genius at metamath.
- Do you feel that?
- Surge.
Damn it.
That was Professor Ex's
classroom blowing up.
I picked a hell of a week
to quit drinking.
I asked around.
Nobody knows who stole
the Book Depository.
Did you ask David Copperfield?
Yeah.
Oh.
But a job this big,
somebody should have seen it.
All right, look.
My brain is fried, so...
I either need to get some sleep
or to fry it some more
recreationally.
Well, club soda is as crazy
as I get these days, so...
- Casual sex, then?
- Good-night, Pete.
Good-night, boss.
Your friend is like
if cocaine was a person.
Well, it's a hedge bar.
That description fits
half the people here.
Not you.
What am I?
A Mossad assassin
undercover as a lumberjack?
And you play bass
in a J-pop hard metal
cover band?
Close. K-pop.
Yu-jin.
Kady.
Oh, good morning.
Is it?
Yeah, I know what you mean.
Haven't had a night like that
in a while.
I'll just, um... pants.
Uh, if you, uh...
wanna hang sometime or...
You know,
I'm just gonna stop talking.
Yeah, I'll just, uh...
Um...
C-call me.
Finally getting that GED?
- Have some respect.
- I'm a professor.
Oh, "Chapter Seven:
Traveling Against Your Will."
That sounds like a problem.
One of my students
was hearing this signal,
and when I listened to it,
I just traveled.
No idea where, no idea why,
and none of this can explain it.
So just don't listen
to the signal again?
- Wow, thank you.
- Shut up.
Except now I hear it
all the time.
This here helps
quiet it down a bit, but...
It's kind of terrifying
to lose control of yourself
like that.
Yeah.
Are you okay?
You know,
hangover remedies are...
kind of a specialty of mine.
I remember.
No judgment or anything,
but I thought...
I'm sober.
Well, I was.
Almost a year, and here I am,
and my head feels
like it's gonna explode.
And if I remembered deciding
to have that first drink...
I would tell you why I did it.
- You're human.
- Dust yourself off.
Maybe keep searching for leads
on that vanishing
Book Depository or whatever.
What?
That library branch
that got heisted.
You spent all day yesterday
looking for it.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Are you sure
you're just hungover?
Did you get my tacos?
I got one
of everything they had.
- Whose house is this?
- My mom's.
Where is she?
She's at a sex... She's camping.
This is a really long dream.
Mm-hmm.
- Hey.
- Oh, God.
- What?
- Oh, hi.
Um, look, I need help
with a metamath problem.
The professor who specializes
in it at Brakebills
blew herself up, so I figured,
uh, next best thing, right?
Yeah, you know, uh,
now's not a good time.
My cousin's here from Canada
and, well, he's Canadian.
So anyway, I got to go.
Alice.
That's...
that's Quentin.
What the hell did you do?
Hello.
Shit.
So what do you say?
Wanna go back in time,
save my friends,
and unfuck history
for old times' sake?
If I change anything,
it could undo every sacrifice
we've all made
to stop The Beast.
Why did you build a workshop
full of time travel gadgets
if you aren't willing
to use them?
The lesson that I've learned
from a life of trying
to change the past
is, well, you almost always
make things worse.
Speaking of, where is my little
volunteer tomato?
Volunteer, um...
Quentin, my dear.
He died saving me.
Saving everybody.
Stiff upper lip, eh?
Positively British of you.
Someone's got to
keep it together.
Is that what you think
you're doing?
Back when Quentin
first came to Fillory
in the very first timeline,
he was running from grief.
His best friend
had died tragically.
Julia.
You.
A victim of your own vices.
I was worried that
I was taking advantage of him,
of his sorrow.
So the first change I made
was to save you
to see if he would
still answer Fillory's call.
And he did.
And then he died...
39 times.
I had hoped
this time would be different.
It still could be.
You saved him 39 times.
Why not 40?
Because he won.
If you took away his sacrifice,
you'd lose everything
that it bought you:
Your life and the lives
of everyone around you.
Same with your friends,
Josh and... was it Flen?
It was not.
You have to let go
of the past, Eliot.
Let the dead stay dead.
Time is a motherfucker,
isn't it?
Ah, tea is ready.
Oh, shit.
Why are you staring at me?
Because...
Holy shit.
You look like somebody I know.
My friend Julia...
her grandma.
Yeah, okay, great.
Um, you know, I actually
have to talk to Alice,
so maybe you could go
play with rocks or something.
So you built a golem
out of living clay
and used the book
of Quentin's life
to fill it with his memories?
It's not so crazy.
And then you animated
the whole thing
with his essence?
No, it's just a tiny grain
of Q's soul
that I pulled
from the Underworld.
You wouldn't help me
with a séance,
and then you go and do this?
Well, I... I knew it was risky,
but it worked.
But it didn't.
That is not the Quentin
you knew.
That's... how could you
do something like this?
I found this in Q's stuff
at Brakebills.
What is this?
I don't know.
It's in a language
I've never seen before.
It could be a... a letter
or a diary
or a project he was working on.
I thought maybe
he left it for me to find.
So you built the version of Q
that could read this for you.
Right, but...
He's 12, so he can't.
Get rid of it.
Put back the piece
of Q's essence that you stole
and let him be at rest.
It's not that simple.
The spell keeps the golem alive
until he completes the task
I brought him here to do.
So the spell
can never be finished
'cause he can't read Q's letter.
This was so insanely selfish.
I can't sleep.
I can barely breathe.
I... I needed to fix something,
finish something for him.
Yeah, well, you fucked up.
Maybe if we can figure out how,
we can fix it
and you can put back
the piece of Quentin's soul
where it belongs.
I'm glad you called.
Last night was a bit of a blur.
I was hoping
for a second chance.
Kind of a blur for me too...
- Mm.
- Which is why I called.
See, I'm sober.
I don't remember drinking
last night,
but I've got gaps in my memory,
and not just last night...
I can't remember things
that happened days ago.
What are you saying?
I want to know
if you can explain.
Wait, you want to know
if I drugged you?
I left you my number.
I... I showed up
for a second date,
which is big for me, since I am
terrified of settling down.
Oh, maybe I took a chance on you
because you remind me
of my cousin,
who I've been obsessed with
since we were 13.
Yes, my first cousin,
but our moms are twins.
So genetically my half-sister,
which makes it worse.
Why am I saying all this?
Because I "truthied" your drink.
You drugged me
to see if I drugged you?
You are insane.
But I swear,
whatever happened to you,
I didn't do it.
I... I mean,
I did some stuff to you.
O-on you. I mean, with you!
Th-the sex stuff!
Because you asked,
for the record.
God, fucking truth serums.
Wait, wait. Kady, Kady.
Um...
I got to my building
this morning,
and I couldn't remember
which apartment was mine.
I... I thought,
"Hey, crazy night."
But it seems like
if your memory was changed,
so was mine.
I need to know why.
If the beheading
didn't kill Josh,
the room service would have.
I'll take your complaint
to the manager.
Eliot?
Just in time.
The cell is Margo-proof,
and when the Dark King gets
back from his summer palace,
I'm gonna be executed.
What's that?
The contents
of Jane Chatwin's garage,
which we will use
to take back our kingdom.
My kingdom.
But sure.
What is this?
"Permanence,"
for men and women.
Ugh, God, could you ask first?
Says this will protect us
from timey-wimey-whatever.
So we can change the past
and not erase ourselves
in the future.
Clutch.
- What's that?
- A smoker.
Beekeepers use them
to calm down their hives.
So that's super applicable
to our current situation.
Wait.
Josh would never shut up
about the Royal Bees
of Whitespire.
They make all the honey
for the castle's kitchens.
And they're talking bees.
Okay, all you have to do
is get the bees to deliver
a message to Josh in the past
and then smoke them out.
Huh, time bees.
Hello, there, bees.
Time bees activated.
I'm not sure it feels like
we changed the past.
At least, not yet.
What are you doing?
There used to be a letter
in here.
Huh.
It's Fen's.
High King Fen here
giving you an update
on life in Castle Whitespire.
Babadook hats
and open-toed shoes
are the style this season.
Ooh, hey, Josh.
- Hey, get in my Insta story.
- Uh, no.
There is no Insta
on Fillory, Fen...
- But...
- So this is...
- I have three bars.
- We're on a different planet.
That's not even po...
How do you have three bars?
This is... what phone is this?
- The time bees.
- Oh, God, do you hear that?
Well played, sister.
Oh, they're saying something.
Fen, I'm allergic to bees!
Or maybe not.
- Oh, God!
- Please help me!
- Oh, God! Oh, God!
- I'm being killed...
by so many bees!
Did Josh say he was allergic?
Right.
That's why Josh would
never shut up about the bees.
Oops.
I had a friend
who used to do that.
Once he got to the end
of his favorite book,
he'd go back
to the beginning again.
Endings are the worst part.
Characters grow up,
they move on.
Some of them die.
It feels like...
Your best friend
in the whole world's
abandoned you.
I've had this
conversation before.
So have I.
The therapist my mom sends me to
says I have transition anxiety.
As if it's too much to ask
that nothing ever change.
Well, your real friends
won't abandon you.
That will never change.
My best friend will start
dating skeevy guys
who smoke and spit,
and she'll forget
I ever existed.
You're just gonna
have to trust me on this one,
but the "skeevy guys" thing?
It's just a phase.
She needs you just as much
as you need her.
Um, excuse me.
I tried to find a flaw
in the casting,
but I couldn't.
That's him.
It's Q.
The one I knew at that age.
But the spell...
I've been doing a lot
of reading on Circumstances.
Not all of them
are astrological.
- Some of them...
- Are inside you.
I think you did
that spell perfectly.
Your brain might have asked
for the version of Q
that could his letter, but...
your internal Circumstances
asked for something different.
Maybe you need to ask him
a different question.
What's that?
"A History of Fillory,"
from the Royal Library.
What does it say?
"After the Fresh Prince
was stung to death
"by a swarm
of honey-drunk assassins,
High King Fen... ".
My God, she listened
to the bees.
"She sent an army of soldiers
to hunt down the Dark King,
"a massive manhunt
that was viewed
"as tyrannical overreach
by the people of Fillory.
She was overthrown
and executed."
The Takers invaded,
the Dark King still rose.
So...
that's it, then?
I-in what conceivable
universe is that it?
I'm just saying,
we're doing all of this
to save a man
you ostensibly love
who died of a bee sting because
you forgot he was allergic.
What is your fucking point?
I was gone, you were alone...
And you hate being alone...
And so you grabbed the first
dick that crossed your desk,
and you're having a hard time
letting go.
You think I should let go
of our friends' lives?
I think you have a textbook case
of cock blindness.
You are Margo the Destroyer,
not Margo the Pining Girlfriend.
I'm gonna let
your bullshit slide
on account of you
so recently being possessed
by a homicidal monster...
But I'm not changing my plan.
Okay. Okay.
Go for it.
Wait.
I recognize these.
The first time Jane
came to Fillory by herself,
she was homesick
and missed her brothers.
A forest crone
gave her these stamps.
Put them on a letter,
address it whoever,
wherever, whenever,
and it gets to them.
This could be our chance.
I can just tell Josh
how to fix things.
Find an envelope!
Address it to "Josh Hoberman,
Castle Whitespire",
before he was killed by bees."
"Dear Josh,
hello from your friends
"300 years in the future.
"The bad news is,
we can't come back to get you.
"The good news:
If you do exactly what I say,
you won't be overthrown
and executed."
Uh, Fen, you're
gonna want to see this!
"Those reports
you've been ignoring
"about an invasion of creatures
"in the Northern Marsh?
Stop ignoring them.
Send an army, today."
- I told you we should have.
- Just shush!
Summon the guards!
Everyone, we did it!
We scared The Takers back
to wherever
the hell they came from.
Go us!
"And somehow,
when we fix the past..."
"I hope we can
see each other again.
Love, Margo."
The letter disappeared
the moment I closed the mailbox.
It worked.
Josh and Fen
did a banishment spell
to scare off The Takers...
they thought.
Then the creatures came back
and killed Josh and Fen
and everyone in Whitespire.
Don't say anything.
Okay, it's working.
So how does a homemade
psychic amplifier help
if I'm not a psychic?
Lowers the bar just enough
for the two of you to be able
to connect your minds.
We're both missing memories.
If we combine the ones we have,
it might be enough
to give us an answer.
Huh, so it's like,
uh, memory VR.
- No.
- So you're sure about this?
I'm sure I need to know
what happened to me.
You?
- Same.
- Don't touch.
Hands together, please.
So where should we start?
Last night, the bar.
Your friend is like
if cocaine was a person.
Well, it's a hedge bar.
That description fits
half the people here.
Not you.
Oh, come on,
this is totally memory VR.
Shh.
All right, now what?
A Mossad assassin
undercover as...
Now we watch.
And you...
play bass in a J-pop
hard metal cover band?
I could look away.
You clearly already remember it.
I don't know.
No drugs slipped
into our drinks,
no head injuries.
Whatever happened to us,
it seems like we both forgot.
Whoa, what the hell?
Stop! What are you doing?
Kady, I... I know
that looked bad.
What the hell was that?
What, some kind of memory spell?
I mean, it looked like it,
but I don't know.
I don't remember.
Well, what the hell
do you remember, then?
- Why were you at the bar?
- To drink.
T-to...
to meet a friend.
Who?
A... a hedge I know
from my first safe house.
Show me.
That's my friend. She's...
The woman that Pete left with.
What are you?
What, some kind
of Manchurian Candidate?
A sleeper agent
that gets activated
to attack women
in their bedrooms?
This doesn't make any sense.
What's on the card?
I-I can't make it out.
Damn it.
I know what's on the card.
How?
You put your
phone number on it...
Whoa, K-Kady, wait...
So show me who you really are.
Someone sent you
to erase my memory.
- Who?
- I have no idea.
I never do.
I get a job, I do it,
and when it's over,
I make sure I don't remember.
You walk around having no idea
what you do for a living?
Why would I want that
on my conscience?
Because that's
what a conscience is for,
to keep you from doing
fucked up shit.
- The world is painful.
- That's not gonna change.
So I use whatever crutch
I have to
to keep going.
The point is,
you can take the shiv
from my throat,
because I can't rat out someone
I don't remember.
Well, my friend's a psychic.
Why don't I have him root around
and see what you do
and don't remember?
Then you don't leave me
much choice, Kady.
Mortem.
No, no! Damn it!
Who sent... who sent you?
Who...
What the hell happened?
- I don't know.
- He just... self-destructed.
He's gone.
Telling them to kill
the Dark King was a bust.
Same with going after
The Takers.
We need a new plan.
We only have two stamps left.
One stamp.
After your last letter to Josh,
I had an idea.
I gave it a shot.
It didn't work, so...
one stamp.
And you didn't tell me?
I'm not your subject.
- I'm your friend.
- Fine.
Then what would you tell Josh
to do?
Run to the nearest dive
and drink himself to death?
Yes.
I would run away,
because you try
to save your friends
and they die anyway.
You can't stop The Takers,
and you can't stop
the Dark King.
And if we don't focus
on getting you out,
you're gonna get decapitated.
Fillory is fucked
because it always is,
and I don't get why you keep
trying to fix something
that wants to be broken.
It may be broken,
but it's my home.
It hasn't been your home
for 300 years.
You are right about one thing.
I have gone soft.
I've been telling myself
that if I can just keep Josh
from dying,
somehow I can get him
and my kingdom back.
But that's not possible, is it?
What are you telling him?
I told him
he needs to stay here.
He can use the information
from this history book
to fight the Dark King
and The Takers
wherever they show up
for the rest of his life.
I told him good-bye.
I'm not dreaming, am I?
I ask because it's been,
like, a full day,
and if you sleep for that long,
it's 'cause you're dead.
I had this friend...
who I loved very much...
And he died,
and I didn't get
to say good-bye.
And I honestly don't know
how I'm gonna go on without him.
And he gave me this gift
I can never repay.
What was the gift?
His life.
He gave it up for mine.
I brought you here
'cause I wanted closure.
You know, I just...
I wanted to...
fix something
or finish something for him.
But the letter I showed you,
you couldn't read it, so...
You're skipping
to the beginning of the book.
What?
I can't help you
because you don't want me to.
Because then your friend's
story is over.
My dad says
when I get sad about something
that's gonna end...
I should just imagine
this is the first page
in a new book.
The gift your friend gave you...
It wasn't his life.
It was yours.
That story just started.
What?
I just shouldn't be surprised
that, even at age 12,
Quentin Coldwater is still
the smartest person I know.
I'm feeling tired.
Really tired.
Hey, do you want to see a trick?
Sure.
- That was cool.
- Yeah.
There's just one more thing
I wanted to say.
I...
Good-bye, Quentin.
He's gone.
You okay?
I'm sorry he couldn't give you
the answer you wanted.
No, he did.
Maybe I can still help you
with your problem.
My dad had a friend with a...
really rare discipline,
predicting Circumstances.
They lost touch years ago,
but she wrote this.
If anyone can find the pattern
you're looking for,
it'll be her.
Thanks.
I don't remember any of it.
The Book Depository,
the mystery woman
who apparently wiped my memory.
All I know
is what you told me, which...
Isn't enough
to do anything with.
Somebody's out there
with enough power
to steal a building,
paranoid enough to send
mind-wiping sleeper agent
assassins after you...
It's not nothing.
Well, I need a drink.
Sorry. Insensitive.
I'll show myself out.
How are you feeling?
You know, I thought that
if I took on more power
and more responsibility...
that I'd want heroin less.
But the truth is,
when I thought I'd relapsed,
I wasn't disappointed.
Wasn't mad at myself.
I was relieved.
It gave me permission
to relapse some more.
And trying to lead the hedges,
it's only gonna get harder.
And I'm not sure I can do it
without a crutch.
Which maybe means
I shouldn't do it at all.
No, don't.
You never quite
get used to the smell
of Fillorian plumbing, do you?
Josh...
You're alive.
Thanks to you.
I got your letter.
Right.
- The letter.
- Did exactly what you said.
I went to the Clock Dwarf,
brought him a ham sandwich,
and told him to send me forward
300 years.
- Just you?
- No, Fen came too.
And Tick, and Rafe,
and a few guys
from my bowling league...
I started a bowling league...
And a dozen other people.
Nobody cool wanted
to stay in the past
once they knew what was coming.
I can't believe it.
Look behind the stone.
I hid it there before I left.
Margo, thank you.
May I present the government
of High King Margo in exile.
Let's get out of here
before we all get killed.