Previously on The Magicians...
We summoned some kind of
killer mothman from another world.
My friends, we got separated,
and I just... I can't let them
fight The Beast on their own.
You want me to come
to Fillory with you?
All right, so there might be
a solution here, a weapon.
It sounds like if
we could find it,
we could use it
to kill The Beast.
Payment is due.
Apparently, marriage
here is different.
I can never leave Fillory.
I have gifted you my bestowal.
When you are ready to
face The Beast, imbibe it.
We followed all the clues.
We thought that she was leading
us to her, we summoned her.
You know, I actually believed
Our Lady Underground chose me.
You may address me
as Reynard the Fox,
trickster of the faithful,
the pure of heart,
the very stupid.
Hi, Martin.
Wait. You know
how to deal with gods.
You know how to
fuck up their shit.
No.
I wanna make a deal. Let's.
Help!
Somebody!
There has got to
be someone in this
motherfuckin',
goddamn magical forest.
Hungry, I assume?
After all that being chased?
No, um, I'm not
being chased. Oh.
Usually they're being chased.
That I know of, no.
But you do need
some kind of help.
Uh, it's just where I come
from, there's a legend
about a witch with a
cottage made of candy.
Well, the cottage
is mostly wood.
And I'm more of a healer
and gardening enthusiast.
Okay. I need your help.
And you're offering...
Offering, I'm...
Gold is always good.
You would be helping the
next High King of Fillory.
Okay.
Then my discount rate. One vial.
Vial of what?
Were you dropped on your head
as a child? Your blood, dumb-dumb.
Oh, there you are.
We were so worried!
You're a...
God-powered.
So it's a little hard to
kill me at the moment.
Thank God.
I mean, you know...
Thank God, Alice.
I hesitated with The Beast. I
should've... It's... It's my fault.
No, it's not.
No, he's right.
It's Julia's fault.
No! Guys! She
was... She's not sane.
You think?
One small consolation is the
bitch is with The Beast right now,
and I can't really see
that going her way.
No. I... I'll explain
in a second. Um...
Can I have my blood back please?
Look, my friends. They're
fine. I don't need your...
No.
I took an hour out of my night.
You're in Fillory, Magician.
Be careful with strangers.
We only look whimsical.
Who was that?
Uh, a local.
Okay, fuckers, huddle up.
A zillion bucks says The
Beast comes back any minute.
So what's the plan?
We lost the blade. So
we need a new something.
Um, especially
while Alice is still...
Juiced up? ELIOT:
We should all juice up.
Like The Beast.
Wellspring smoothies, stat.
Ahh!
Shit.
Look, there's the
missing piece right there.
Oh, hey, I think I, uh... Yeah.
Gah! This is going great.
Let me try.
Wow, swallowin'
has its privileges.
Wow, it looks like...
A major drought's hit.
There's a bucket.
Oh, shit.
I knew The Beast came
here every day, but is it...
But is it even possible for him
to drain the
Wellspring that much?
Maybe he threw
something out of whack.
I vote we don't touch it,
on the grounds that
exploding Fillory wouldn't help.
Okay. We need a new plan.
What plan?
The Beast is gone, our squad
is a joke, what plan, exactly?
We'll figure it
out, we always do.
When it's a final to cheat on,
not when we're stuck
in some epic fantasy
that likes to behead its heroes
halfway through season one.
If we even are heroes.
We might be comic relief.
I thought you threw that out.
It's for emergencies.
Pass it around.
Okay. No Wellspring, no knife.
I have no idea what to do now.
So we are fucked without grease.
That sounds like us.
Must be a Monday.
Onward to glory.
Ah. Much better.
Why are, are we...
Oh, the food is
tremendous. Let's sit.
Are you familiar?
Word As Bond.
I assume the extra
bits enchant the blade
to kill me instantly in
the event I break it, eh?
Okay. Here's the deal...
You need to kill a god.
Thrilling.
So you need to
get near him. Tricky.
Yes. But you can help.
Hmm.
His name is Reynard the Fox.
A trickster of some sort, yes?
Oh. That will be a challenge.
Well, you don't really
have much choice, do you?
Oh, well aware, you
have that stylish little blade.
I sure do.
Yes.
That reminds me to
insist the terms of our deal
include said blade
reverting to me
at the moment of
Reynard's demise.
Agreed?
Almost.
First, for the duration
of our agreement,
you do not hurt or act
against me in any way.
Mmm, fine.
Quentin, all of them.
You lay a finger,
this will put this in
the base of your skull.
You're not what I expected.
Once Reynard is dead,
I put the knife
down. Yours to take.
So this Reynard's
still out there?
As far as she knows.
Yeah, it's why she needed the
knife, and why she needs The Beast.
Okay, I get it now,
but I also have to say
that is the dumbest thing
she could possibly have done.
Like I said, she's not sane
right now. I wouldn't be.
So what are we supposed to do?
Kill The Beast.
He's right. I know, it's awful.
But she chose to
double-cross us.
Look, I'm pissed, too, but
I would like to point out...
Okay, we don't have to
take a vote right this second.
Penny's right.
First things first.
We need to make a plan
to deal with The Beast.
Eliot! I thought for sure you...
Yeah. Me, too. Not yet.
Are you... Are you all right?
Um, I'll get everyone
something to eat.
That'd be amazing.
I think I like her.
I hope I like her.
Um, okay. This might
be something. Um...
So, there's a place
called the Armory.
Weapons?
Books.
Uh, so, Rupert Chatwin...
He realizes that back home
World War II is still raging.
And he tells Jane and
Martin that he is going.
He is going to go fight.
Before he does,
he spends all night
in the Armory, reading.
And, you know, like, whatever
he finds, it doesn't say,
but his next move is to petition
Ember and Umber, for strength.
I mean, what if he
found something.
What if he found a
spell or a piece of,
I don't know,
Fillorian battle magic,
that was so strong that
he couldn't do it without...
Without juice. Yeah.
Because the thing is,
this is December, 1944.
I mean, he shows up
right in the middle of the...
Battle of the Bulge?
Wait, are you saying
that Rupert's secretly...
I'm saying...
Maybe he found something
powerful enough to help.
Him win World War II?
Maybe.
Well, then I need the
Armory. Where is it?
Castle Whitespire.
Accessible to the King.
Oh.
Hey.
And if we can find the road,
there's, um, a carriage that
runs in a continuous circle,
also at the disposal
of the King. So...
Okay. Whitespire it is.
Come on, everybody, grab snacks.
Yeah. About that. My
hands are in a fucking box.
So, Chatwin's Torrent.
I know that one.
It's a healing river.
Can it reattach hands?
Maybe?
I'm going. I'll catch
you on the flip.
Wait, no. I don't think
you should be going alone.
I'll go.
Um, healing water.
We're going to battle.
I'll grab like a gallon.
You're wiping your own
ass. So figure that out.
Souvenir?
Barometer.
I thought I should pay
attention to see if it gets warm.
Oh. Hey, guys.
Hey! Over here!
Oh, my God. Those
horses are so beautiful.
Ah. Hey, what are you doing?
I just really love horses.
Come on.
You have got to be kidding me.
I know, those
horses were so rude.
I guess they're a tad literal.
- Yeah.
I'd call needing to see an
actual crown on my head
is pretty goddamn literal.
Look, it's not just
about the carriage.
They're not gonna
let us into Whitespire
until you've been
crowned High King. So.
So, we need to get you crowned.
Uh...
Okay, yeah.
Um, so, there's a specific
coronation place in the forest.
There are four kings and queens.
Yeah, you get to
pick the other three.
Do I get to be a king?
Unless you want
me to pick Penny?
So, okay.
So we get to the coronation spot
by crossing the Rainbow Bridge.
"Rainbow Bridge"? Like, where
family pets go when they die?
No, I mean, not that I know of.
No, it's called that because of
the flowers that are everywhere.
Oh.
Um, but there is,
of course, no map.
But I know Martin
found it with a spell.
Well, we could
always just ask around.
Or we could make like Martin.
He loves me. He loves me not.
He loves me. Let's go.
Uh, please know I
heard every loophole.
"Puts the knife down."
You really think you
have a fighting chance?
I think I'm gonna
give it my best.
Oh, this is going to be fun.
Nice of Reynard to pull so
many hearts out of chests.
It's distinctive.
Why do you suppose he does that?
He likes the taste.
Mm.
Brilliant, that's a laptop.
The things they come up with
when they don't have magic.
Yeah.
Like accounts that tweet
police scanner activity.
"Tweet"?
Birds have computer accounts?
Don't worry about it.
Mmm.
Wait a minute.
They found five bodies
at a house in Florida.
Missing a couple of hearts.
Okay. Just try to keep
people away for a minute.
Nicely. Mmm-hmm.
Hey. This seat taken?
Excuse me, sir, this is...
Won't be but a moment.
He's still in Richard's body.
Richard doesn't care, darling.
I fucking do.
Also, I guess we
came for not much.
On the contrary. We've
verified what attracts Reynard.
What? Witches doing rituals?
I mean, that's thousands
of people every day.
Not this type of ritual.
Come on.
So, what do I do?
Well, per the books, you
strip and jump in, I guess.
Here, I'll help you.
You'll need to help him
sew those back on his wrists.
Who are you?
I watch the river and assist
those who require its magic.
This guy is fuckin' weird.
Go on.
Right. Go, go.
You know, you're very beautiful.
Where're you from? Hmm?
Earth? I love women from Earth.
Is it supposed
to take this long?
No.
He may have drowned.
Are you kiddin'?
Why didn't you...
There we go.
Are you sure I can't
interest you in an elixir?
It's small-batch,
and very fresh.
No, thank you.
I have a tooth powder that I
think you are going to love.
You know what?
We're kind of in a hurry.
I understand. As you
wish. Pleasure to serve.
I think he wants a tip.
Twenty gold pieces is customary.
Okay, that sounds like a lot.
Well, this is Chatwin's Torrent.
We don't have...
There was nothing about
charging in the books.
Oh, you'd rather pay in labor?
I think three to five years...
Are you fucking kidding me?
You said none of this
before I went in the river.
Because I have manners.
Are you even officially
affiliated with the Torrent?
Penny, chill out.
It's kind of an amateur calling.
Oh, I see, yes, yes,
you're a con man.
No. Penny...
No! I know his type!
I've been ripped
off plenty of times
by smiling little snake
oil pricks like this dude.
Yes, all right.
Same in Detroit, same in
Mumbai, same in Fillory.
Okay.
Sorry, try it on the
next sap who needs
this natural resource
on public property.
Good luck.
I'm sorry. He gets touchy.
It's... It's not personal.
Um...
These are diamond.
What the hell is diamond?
Here.
When you meet one scammer,
you've met 'em all. Let's go.
Okay.
Okay, so this net...
This net you throw.
What sort of a
net catches a god?
Well, it's an obscure bit of
casting, but I assure you it works.
We'll just have to act
fast when the time comes.
It'll hold for a few seconds.
So...
I need a few items.
Okay, it might be better for
me to go alone for some of this.
Uh, can you drop
me at the playground?
I like to watch the little children
play. It's perfectly innocent.
El, we got your
note! Let's do this!
I call High Queen.
Hey, did it work?
Perfect. Lead the way.
It's fine. They're just healing.
Do you think he's
sleeping? Or dead?
I don't know. Should
we just go into the trunk?
Oh, pussies.
He looks dead.
I guess we're late.
Oh, dear.
I am the Knight of Crowns.
My apologies, I seem to have died
waiting for you aspirants to come.
You are aspirants?
I'm the High King of
Fillory. I took a blood test.
Excellent. Excellent.
It's an honor.
Can we have the crowns please?
Certainly. Honored to oblige.
Just as soon as
you pass the test.
Of course there's a test.
As you know,
only a Child of Earth can
wear the crown of the High King.
I will ask you a
series of questions,
designed to root out all
pretenders to the throne.
Only a true High King will
hold the answers in his heart.
Come at me.
What popular American television
program stars actor Tim Daly?
What the fuck?
He was on a lot of TV shows.
There is only one
correct answer.
Okay, give me the next question.
This hit single is performed
by offspring of
famous entertainers.
Dude, that is crazy vague.
You will receive a single hint.
Your hint is, "Beach Boys."
Hold On by Wilson Phillips.
That song is my jam.
Wait, all these questions
are from the '90s.
It's not the 1990s
on Earth right now?
No, it, it's 2017.
And it's Wings.
The Tim Daly show was Wings.
Of course you know that.
Okay, '90s?
Ask me something
about Patrick Swayze.
You know of Swayze?
Oh, jeez.
"Sorry about the
disruption, folks,
"but I always do the
last dance of the season.
"This year somebody
told me not to.
"So I'm gonna do my kind of
dancin' with a great partner,
"who's not only
a terrific dancer.
"Somebody who's taught me
"that there are people out there
"willing to stand
up for other people,
"no matter what it costs them.
"Somebody who's taught me
about the kind of person I wanna be.
"Miss Frances Houseman."
Oh...
Your Majesty.
The crowns of Fillory are yours.
So, I guess we just put 'em on?
No! God! Stop!
I mean, I just think we
should do a ceremony.
This is only gonna happen once.
We are becoming
kings and queens.
So it's important and
we should honor it.
Just, give me that.
Kneel, Eliot Waugh.
Would you just do it? It's
gonna be quick, I promise.
So, destiny is... It's bullshit.
But you are a High
King in your blood,
and somehow that
makes sense. You know?
And I just...
For what it's worth, I think
that you are going to be
a really good king.
Um...
So, um, I dub thee...
I don't know, would you say
you're, like, more brave or merciful?
I'd say I'm neither.
But I still plan to be a
spectacular monarch.
I hereby dub thee High
King Eliot the Spectacular.
Wow.
This feels as
natural as underwear.
Thank you.
By the power vested in me by...
I have no idea...
I do hereby crown
you High Queen Margo,
the Destroyer.
I mean that in the
best possible sense.
All hail. Everyone, clap.
I have known what you truly
are since the day we met.
Long may you reign.
I feel it's incumbent upon me to
promise never again
to betray you like I did.
I really, really am sorry.
I have some character
defects. I'm workin' on it.
Honestly.
I'm working on some, too.
Well, on that note,
I crown you
Queen Alice the Wise.
No, wait.
Since we're cleaning
slates and shit.
Give me.
Q.
I could start by
saying something cruel
yet totally hilarious about you.
Let's be real, you're
an easy target.
But that's... That's because
you're honest about what you love,
and underneath it
all, that's inspiring.
And I'm sorry, too.
Not about the sex, I don't
even really remember it.
But mostly my part in fucking up
something that was good for you.
Thanks, I think I fucked
it up just fine myself.
Now that we're ruling
a kingdom together,
I hope we can be
whatever we were again.
I guess you would
call that friends.
Let's go with that.
I hereby crown you
King Quentin the Moderately
Socially Maladjusted.
Scrunch down.
Yeah.
Royalty, bitches.
Okay.
Shit.
Hey, everything okay?
I'm going back to the Torrent.
You think that guy
did something to you?
'Cause you were a raging douche?
I'll sweet talk him, get him to fix
my hands, and I'll head to the castle.
Everything's under control.
Alice?
Apology accepted.
That was you apologizing
for what you did?
I just...
If we survive this, I hope
we can be friends still.
Look, I know it
might sound stupid,
but that's what I'm mad at you
for, and not the cheating part.
The part where what
you did made me lose you.
And you were a big
part of my life, Quentin.
You can never lose me, Alice.
I mean, you can avoid me,
and you can hate me and...
I don't hate you.
Well, you can't lose me. Sorry.
I can't stop thinking.
We're gonna find
this epic spell, great.
But I'm afraid I'm just gonna
freeze again when The
Beast is in front of me.
You're thinking about it wrong.
Cool under pressure
is not a talent.
It's a skill, and you
need to practice.
Come on.
We stood on a roof
together during the Trials
and you told me
that you were afraid
to see what you
were really capable of.
That was then. So let's
see what you can do now.
I'm not sure it'll help.
Then do it for me, hell.
I'm not gonna lie. I... I'm
dying to see what you can do.
I'm not a Naturalist.
You know the spell, we
all do. We just sucked at it.
Let's see what you can do now.
It feels...
It's just like breathing.
See? Nice.
So how do you feel now?
We're not getting back together.
Okay.
I've been wondering something.
Why didn't Reynard kill
you with your friends?
Why were you spared?
You weren't spared. Were you?
Look, let's not go there, okay?
You know, when I was a boy,
a man who was
meant to care for me
bent me over his desk
and had me over and over,
every time I was alone with him.
It helped me understand a truth.
You're powerful or you're weak.
If you're powerful,
you will survive.
So, what? You're
suggesting I just get over it?
Actually, yes.
How? Mutate?
Take over a world? Kill a
bunch of grad students 39 times?
You see, what you feel,
the haunted look in your eyes,
doesn't come from nowhere.
Then where does it come from?
In the center of your being,
there's a tiny beating heart.
What, you mean like my soul?
Part of it, yes.
The slimmest part.
But it holds specific power.
It's called a Shade.
Shade. Yeah.
It's what makes you feel
the pain will burn
you till there's nothing.
And, yes, it's
also there for love,
but let's be frank, darling,
you're more likely to
throw yourself off a bridge
than ever love again.
I felt that way.
And I knew it crippled me
when I needed to be strong.
As you do now.
You know...
I don't care for
people, as a rule.
But I like you.
You have promise.
With the right control,
you would be formidable.
Even a worthy collaborator.
I have plans. You
could be part of them.
If?
Do what I did. Sever your Shade.
Sever. Mmm.
It's not hard.
You'll feel better.
You'll feel happy. I
can show you how.
No, thank you.
Do let me know if
you change your mind.
Eliot!
The crown suits you. Of course.
Who are all these people?
The Pickwick family.
They'd been running things
till Children of Earth came.
Oh.
Your Highness.
Tick Pickwick of the Northern
Marsh Pickwicks, at your service.
The rest of the King's
Council will arrive shortly.
Great.
So glad you're here.
There are a few problems.
Uh, several problems that could
use your immediate attention.
Ah, um, okay. Great. We
should probably get started.
First, your Throne Room.
I'm afraid it's been locked a long
time. We're looking for the key.
That's fine. Uh, take
me straight to the Armory.
The Armory, Your Highnesses.
Well, this is underwhelming.
It's supposed to
be full of books.
Strategies for Trapping
Tomato-Eating Garden Fairies.
Yeah, no.
Someone took all
the battle magic.
It's not like The Beast is
coming to find us any second.
Wait, this is something.
It's a workbook on
spells. Serious ones.
Looks like battle magic. But
the actual spells aren't here.
Hmm. Like notes on
cake, but no actual recipes.
It's helpful.
Who wrote it?
Oh, my God.
What?
I know where we need to go.
Brakebills?
Hello? Mister, uh...
Mister...
Fuck!
Can I help you?
Hell, yes, you can.
These don't work.
Oh, by all means,
request a refund.
Very funny. You
did this on purpose.
Did what? Help an
ungrateful Child of Earth?
Look, I'll pay you
whatever you want. Okay?
I'm serious, okay?
I am friends with
the kings and queens.
You wanna be a duke,
great, I got you. I...
Actions have
consequences, Penny.
Even glib words spoken
in casual arrogance.
It's past time you learned.
Especially, given the
position you will occupy soon.
What position?
You know what? I've
done you a service.
No, no, look! Hey!
I'm sorry. Okay?
Please fix my hands.
Let's see, how do I put this in
a way that you will understand?
Ah. Go fuck yourself.
No, wait!
Fuck!
Hang on to this while I'm gone?
Oh.
You guys all packed?
Yeah.
El, thank you.
For what?
For taking one for the team to
the tune of the rest of my life?
I'm trying to see this
ruling thing as an adventure.
Apparently, we have
enemies to the north and south,
plus broken infrastructure,
and huge magic issues
thanks to The Beast
and his Wellspring addiction.
And do you know they don't
know what champagne is here?
I plan on inventing it.
I'd like to be known as
the "Champagne King."
It has a ring to it.
Right? Mmm-hmm.
I'm really looking forward
to drinking socially.
Like the French.
So, uh, in the books,
time doesn't exactly run the
same speed on Earth as in Fillory.
I mean, look,
sometimes it got screwy
when Jane and Martin
would go back and forth.
But not always.
It's gonna be fine, El.
Yeah. Yeah.
Or I'll just live out my days
waiting for my friends to return,
and die alone.
You know, it's considered
extremely disrespectful
to touch a king
without permission.
But, um, I think you should
probably hug me right now.
It'll also be okay if you just
gave my ass, like, a little squeeze.
Feel free to double-check
this before I get started.
Julia?
Why do you want to
help me with my Shade?
Without your Shade you'd
see a lot of things differently.
You'd be able to live, Julia.
Come here. Let me show you.
We're there.
Put it back.
It's okay. It's okay.
I need it.
Put it back now, Martin.
Suit yourself.
I understand why you're afraid.
You don't want to lose yourself.
But hear me on this.
Martyring yourself to your pain
isn't all it's advertised to be.
It'll destroy you.
There's no glory in that.
You might get Reynard. Yes.
But he'll still win.
Anyways.