QUENTIN: Previously
on The Magicians...
(SHRIEKS)
A zillion bucks says The
Beast comes back any minute.
So what's the plan?
QUENTIN: Right,
okay, so here's the thing,
I can't really touch the knife.
We need the power of a god.
I have gifted you my
bestowal. Imbibe it.
The more it burns,
the less time we have.
There's a spell that
seems strong enough.
These are my students. They
are in need of the Rhinemann Ultra.
BIGBY: No one but you can
be within 20 feet of the blast.
DEAN: Alice is going to take just
a few minutes to fully power up.
This is a cacodemon.
They'll grow much bigger.
Unleash these and, believe me,
they'll keep The Beast plenty busy.
(INAUDIBLE)
Do you know what a Niffin is?
No.
EMILY: It's when too much runs
through you. Only the magic is left.
Please fix my hands.
RIVER WATCHER: Go fuck yourself.
I think I can help.
(SIGHS) Wow. I owe you for real.
You could die if you don't
get clear of The Beast.
You think I don't know
how dangerous he is?
No. Not him. Us.
Yeah, do what you want with
him, but not until I get Reynard.
Well, we can't merely
summon him. A god can resist.
I don't give a shit
about getting him.
You should. I didn't summon him.
I didn't get raped by
him. I have no skin in this.
Reynard is targeting Hedges.
(GAGS)
(COUGHING)
Did you put some kind
of curse on the castle?
Did I?
The spell that won World War
II is called the Rhinemann Ultra?
It sounds like a
not-so-great beer.
Fine, it's a beer.
But it's a beer that we
can use to kill The Beast.
Meanwhile, Penny comes back
with cool, circa-1985 wrist chains.
Yeah, super cool how they
keep me from killing myself.
And then Dean Fogg gives
you all matching tramp stamps?
I thought tramp stamps were
supposed to be on our lower back.
(SIGHS) God, I feel like I
missed out on some crazy party
you'll be talking about
for the rest of your lives.
Say what you want, but we
brought back weapons and a plan.
What do you have
to show for yourself?
Ta-fucking-da!
Your royal accoutrements.
This is ceremony, people. And I
expect you to slather yourselves in it.
Thank you, Eliot.
I missed you all.
And I was bored.
Come, sit.
Is this really the
most important thing
we could be doing right now?
I mean, The Beast is still
out there, waiting for us, and...
The Beast can
wait for five minutes.
You are all Kings
and Queens of Fillory.
Well, almost all of you.
Just revel in your majesty
for one fucking second.
Be regal, miscreants.
Mmm...
(ECHOING) You're
such a stupid, stupid man.
I'm gonna kill
you in your sleep.
(WHISPERING)
Poison.
(ECHOING) El, you
okay? (SHUDDERS)
Totally fine. Why?
It's just... You went
away there for a minute.
Nonsense. I feel
great. Have a seat.
I'm kind of on a clock here.
So, we should talk strategy.
Yeah, we already
talked strategy.
So, we just need
to catch you up.
You've been planning without me?
Yeah. When we were on Earth.
What did you think we were doing?
(LAUGHING NERVOUSLY)
Eliot, we're not trying to exclude
you. You just weren't there.
No. No, I wasn't, was I?
Don't think I don't
see how this works.
You disappear. You come back.
Matching tattoos. And now
you're three-against-one.
I know exactly what
you're planning. Eliot...
Don't touch me.
Sweetie, you kind
of sound insane.
Do I?
Because I promise you, I will
not go down easily, oo-surpers.
Usurpers.
(SCOFFS) Whichever way
you're supposed to pronounce it.
What just happened?
He got like this on 'shrooms
once. I'll go talk to him.
(SIGHS)
QUENTIN: I just remembered
something that Julia said.
It's starting to
make a lot of sense.
You talked to that
bitch? Yes, he did.
It was a warning.
Something The Beast said.
Uh... God! Of course,
this makes sense!
Yeah, I mean, he'd want to
booby trap his kingdom, right?
Uh, so, apparently
he left curses behind.
Here, actually.
So, you think Eliot
might be cursed?
I mean, she was vague.
But, I mean... (SIGHS)
Did either of you notice
that Eliot started
acting strangely
once he took a
drink from the goblet?
I mean, it could be
poison or potion...
Okay, well we probably shouldn't
drink from ours, just to be safe.
Or maybe it was just some primo
Fillorian shit that went up his nose
and he's on the bad end of a trip,
because he's him. (CHUCKLES)
Did something happen to you?
Nope. Nothing.
I'm fine, Penny.
Oh.
Wait! And now you're doing it.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I mean like Eliot, you're
acting all tweaky and shit.
We're fine. We're fine.
Clearly.
Look, I think we can all agree
that we have a problem here.
Eliot.
He's High King. He's cursed.
We have no choice but...
We have to kill him. Exactly.
The thrones.
You're both cursed.
This is hard for you. I get
that. It's hard for us, too.
But it must be done.
For Fillory. For Fillory.
(WHISPERING)
But don't tell Quentin.
I'm going to have
to kill him, too.
Right after Margo.
PENNY: Margo!
Margo.
Margo! Margo! Margo! We
got a serious problem, okay?
I know. Eliot's cursed. No, no.
Not just Eliot. Alice
and Quentin, too.
Listen, whatever you do, do
not sit on your throne, okay?
(SIGHS) Fine.
Whatevs. I have a plan.
You gonna help me pick these?
What's this? An antidote?
Exactly. For the poison.
For the... What?
For the poison.
I have to drink it first or I
won't get Eliot to take it.
Jesus, you're acting like
this is your first regicide.
Also, it's not the
thrones that are cursed.
I sat on mine
and I'm totally fine.
You sat on your... Fuck!
Great! No, it's good. Okay.
Stop! This will be over soon.
I'll deal with Eliot,
and Alice and Q.
Are you... You're welcome.
Shit.
MARINA: So, this is
our little fox trap, huh?
Yeah.
So you wanna tell me where
you hooked up with your partner?
The Dirty Dozen?
Hmm. Uh...
Fillory.
(CHUCKLES)
Fine, don't tell me.
Listen, I'm here.
I want to help.
But that asshole seems like
severe psychic damage.
Look, I get it, okay?
But he knows a
spell to freeze a god.
I mean, you can't find that
at your local safe house.
Look, I've survived
this long on my instincts.
And every one of them is
telling me that he is bad news.
He's gonna turn on me.
Or you. Or both of us.
No, he can't. Okay, we have
an agreement. Word As Bond.
Oh, those are tough to break.
But if anyone could, it's
someone who could freeze a god.
MARTIN: Are you girls discussing
the nature of our agreement?
Marina was just asking.
Straightforward. I betray
her, she cuts me to the quick.
So, tell me, what happens after
the tenets of the agreement are met?
Why worry? You'll
be long gone by then.
So tell me. Are we ready?
Yeah.
(SINGING) A hunting we
will go A hunting we will go
We'll catch a fox and put him
in a box And then we'll let him go
What? Those are the lyrics.
(MARTIN WHISTLING TUNE)
Benedict, right?
I need your help.
What do you do here, again?
Royal mapmaker, sire. Is your
problem cartographical in nature?
Not really.
What I need, Benedict, is
a dagger. A stiletto, really.
Something I can sneak
up and stab someone with.
But regal.
I make maps, Your Majesty.
Well, surely someone
has snuck into your office
and dramatically stabbed a knife
into a map to make a point, no?
The other kings and
queens who died,
we'd always just thought
it was just infighting.
Greed and power.
PENNY: Yeah, well, guess what?
It's just another horrible thing
The Beast is responsible for.
So, how do we reverse this?
(SIGHS) Curses are tricky.
You don't say.
They usually end once
they've run their course.
And not before.
That doesn't help us.
This one seems to wanna run
its course until they're all dead.
Shit. Dead.
I have an idea. Okay.
Do not let them kill each
other, okay? Mmm-hmm.
(WHOOSHING)
I call on you, Our
Lady Underground.
(SIGHS)
As a Child of the Earth,
I seek you, O Mother.
Hey. Hmm?
Do me a favor
and just believe it.
A benevolent mommy
who will solve my problems
with her Gaia power?
Yeah. Or Reynard won't show.
You realize I don't even
own a pair of yoga pants.
So act.
I seek to know
you, Divine Mother.
Giver of life and light.
I ask to gaze upon you.
To hear your voice, to
feel the beating heart of you.
I beseech you. Hear me now!
What happened?
Where are we?
A park. A few blocks away.
Is this a joke?
Take us back, now!
But we can't go back.
Reynard's scented you before.
If he smells you
again, he won't show.
If you want him, you might
just have to risk losing your bait.
I'm sorry. You're
saying this now?
Well, if I'd told you before,
would you have agreed to it?
Fine. I'll walk.
Oh, excellent idea.
By the time we arrive, he'll be so
engrossed in Marina's evisceration,
he won't even realize
we're there. You're good!
(WHISTLING TUNE)
I ask to gaze upon you!
To hear your voice, to
feel the beating heart of you.
I ask to gaze upon you!
To hear your voice, to
feel the beating heart of you!
Oh, you've got to be fucking
kidding. Fuck this noise!
(QUENTIN SIGHS) (CHUCKLING)
What's so funny?
You with a crossbow.
You couldn't hit a fat girl
with a fat-girl-seeking arrow.
Oh, don't give me that
look. It's a figure of speech.
No way in hell I'll miss
you from this range.
Well. If you use that arrow
as good as you use your dick...
You enchanted
yourself, didn't you?
I'm not an idiot.
Margo says go free.
(SIZZLING)
Fuck! (GROWLING)
Jesus Christ!
(WHISPERING) Penny says go free.
(SNARLING)
(ROARING)
(BOTH EXCLAIM)
(COUGHING)
You just had to let him save
you, huh? You're such a girl.
You know, I'd like to see you
dead regardless of your gender.
Just shut up, both of you.
I'm gonna take you
some place safe.
But if I have to shoot you to get
you there, I'll make sure it hurts.
Gee, thanks. But I'm enchanted.
(YELPS IN PAIN)
Your enchantment's weak.
(GASPS)
You shot me, you cock!
Why didn't you shoot her in the
neck? The carotid is right there.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Don't fret.
If Reynard had killed Marina,
don't you think there'd be lots
of little Marina bits lying around?
She ran.
And I don't think she
even finished the spell.
We're gonna have to start this all
over again. And now we've lost Marina.
I don't even know how
we're supposed to do...
Don't be so hasty. Are you
absolutely sure it didn't work?
If I were your fox god, I might
just, say, follow her home,
rather than kill
her on the spot.
You knew this was
going to happen.
(SCOFFS) Why do you
think I took you out of there?
Chin up! If I'm right, our
little summoning worked.
We just need to find foxy
before he's finished with his prey.
N'est-ce pas?
(SIGHS)
You just locked us
both inside, you know.
You must be Marina.
Shit. Her wards are
up. We can't get inside.
Can you break them?
Uh-huh. Here.
There's one.
Settle in. This may take a bit.
(JULIA SIGHS)
Bad news, you're cursed.
Good news, I think
there's a way out.
Does it involve your beheading?
'Cause that's the ending
I'm voting for right now.
I second that.
My ass still hurts.
Enough.
Listen. I can't stop the curse.
So the plan is, we're
gonna let it run its course.
By killing you. All of you.
No likey. What's to likey?
The part where you're
dead sounds perfect.
Shut up!
Now, I took a little
trip to get supplies.
Oh, goody. Heroin.
I always suspected
this was how I'd go.
Potassium chloride
will shut down the heart.
Adrenaline will kickstart it.
You die. Curse
ends. I revive you.
Except, what if any part
of that plan doesn't work?
Look, asshole, you
don't like my idea,
why don't you go
find someone else
to save your
annoying fucking life.
I have about 1,000 better
things to do with my day.
What the hell?
You okay? I'm fine.
(STUTTERS) My fingers are a little
numb due to the anti-curse things.
Well, that's just perfect.
It's fine. It's fine.
So, are we still
hostages, or what?
Yes. Yes, you are.
Um... You point that
thing at their fucking heads.
Everyone, please, please
just stand in your corners
and just quietly... (GRUNTS)
Dang it, Margo.
Yeah, yeah, whatever. You're
dead. (QUENTIN GRUNTS)
(ALL GRUNTING)
I suppose this is one way
to get the killing bit over with?
Yeah, this is what
I was planning.
The wards around this place
were deceptively advanced.
I'm impressed. You have talent.
Hmm. I bet you say
that to all the girls,
right before you
rape them, kill them
and eat their hearts. (CHUCKLES)
You wear that
cynicism so stylishly.
It's too bad I know it's a lie.
Is it?
Oh, no true cynic would
call to the goddess.
That must hurt, to know
she wasn't listening.
On the plus side, I was.
Listen, I love the
foreplay. It's hot.
It really is. But just get
it over with and kill me.
(GRUNTING)
All in good time.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
You know, it doesn't take Freud
to see that a god who
likes to prey on chicks
is compensating for
a lack of something.
(SCOFFS) What even are you?
God of Goat Herding? Grapes?
Oh, wait, is it manure?
I bet you love coming here
and fucking with mortals
'cause back home in
god-land, you barely rank.
Watch your mouth, or
I'll slice out your tongue
and I'll eat it in front of you.
You're really not getting the
message that you don't scare me.
No, I think I do scare you.
(SCOFFS)
(SIGHS)
It's so rare for someone to try to
summon Our Lady on their own.
You're all alone, aren't you?
There's no one
else in your life.
Seriously?
You're trying to
hurt my feelings?
And the best you
can come up with is
"why couldn't you find a man"?
Is anyone really
going to miss you?
I tip the pizza guy pretty well.
(CHUCKLES) (CAT MEOWS)
Ah...
You're not totally alone.
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty,
kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty.
(CHUCKLES)
Cupcake? (CHUCKLES)
What a cutie she is.
You witches and your familiars.
Hmm.
You don't care for people.
But you do love her, don't you?
(CAT MEOWS)
Don't be stupid. She's just
a dumb cat. Put her down.
No.
I'd like to pet her.
(MEOWS)
(BONES CRACKING) (CAT YOWLING)
(REYNARD GRUNTING)
(CAT MEWLING)
REYNARD: (CHUCKLING) Oh!
Look at that. I think she
might still be alive. That's funny.
Uh-uh!
(GRUNTS)
No magic.
(BITING) (SCREAMS)
(GASPING)
See? So much more fun to be had.
What's the rush?
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(MARINA GASPING)
(MARGO AND ELIOT STRUGGLING)
Ha!
I won, bitches.
I'm High motherfucking Queen.
Get the other needles. Hurry!
Hey! Stay back!
PENNY: Margo, we
don't have time for this.
We gotta revive them now!
What's best in life, Penny?
What?
What's best in life?
(STAMMERING) I don't know.
To crush your enemies,
see them driven before you
and hear the lamentations
of their women.
Come at me, farm girl.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTS)
That's one thorough
fucking curse.
Is it wrong to say I find her
death extremely satisfying?
Okay, come on. I need your help.
(GASPING)
Oh, my God!
What the hell?
Welcome back, loser. Yeah.
Um...
Do you want me to get that?
(SCREAMS)
It's time.
Don't know how long I'll
have to cast the Rhinemann.
Ugh. Eliot's right.
It's a stupid name!
And I wish I had a beer.
That really doesn't look right.
Does it require me
playing Rachmaninov?
If not, we're fine.
No, but you still
gotta grab The Beast.
What happens if you
take the bracelets off?
That's a bad idea.
Well, then, how are you...
All I have to do is touch him,
right? So I'll tackle his ass. Okay?
Well, we are down
two cacodemons.
Any ideas how to slow
up The Beast now?
Actually, we only
have one. I let mine go.
Oh, Jesus. Come on!
I could feel it.
Alive under my skin.
I couldn't stand the idea
of it being trapped in there.
Shocking no one.
Just leave her alone. It's not
like you have yours. I do. So...
Because you were too
much of a pussy to use it.
I got this, Q.
Okay, idea.
Do you guys remember
the Sumerian Shield Charm
we learned in PA?
Like, to keep you safe from
shattered glass or something?
Yeah, it's a simple spell, but
that doesn't mean it's not powerful.
Yeah, especially if all
three of us are casting it.
Use a first-year spell to stop The
Beast? That sounds like suicide.
Which I've already tried
today, and no thank you.
Next. No! No! There is no next!
We're running out of time
and options and god jizz.
Look, just imagine dicks, okay?
With one dick, you're
just jerking yourself off.
But with three dicks, suddenly
you've got six people having sex.
Which is more powerful?
I think your metaphor literally
doesn't make any fucking sense.
It doesn't have to.
It just distracted
you long enough
for Alice to power up the spell.
Which is all the
shield charm has to do.
I see what you did there.
REYNARD: Struck
a nerve, didn't I?
Sorry, I wasn't
paying attention.
I fell asleep for a moment.
You ever eat
something still alive?
Can't say that I have.
Civilized species and all.
You're missing out.
I recommend
starting at the far end.
So you can enjoy
the fear. It's chemical.
You can taste it, fear.
Not to mention, the look
on your face is priceless.
So why don't you
and I... (WHOOSHING)
Apologies for the tardiness.
Your wards are rather extensive.
(MARINA BREATHING HEAVILY)
(QUENTIN SIGHS)
Are we ready?
Hey.
(SIGHS)
Yeah.
(EXHALES)
(ENERGY PULSATING)
He's fighting the net.
Not sure how much
longer I can hold this.
Jesus Christ, Julia. Would
you please just gut this guy?
With pleasure.
No! No!
(JULIA GRUNTS)
(ENERGY PULSATING)
Now!
Julia!
Blow that bitch up. Let's go!
No!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(ENERGY PULSATING)
No!
I missed him! I missed him!
I had Reynard. He
was right in front of me.
Yeah! And then you
screwed up our plan, again.
She just grabbed me.
No, you all don't understand.
I had Reynard. I had The Beast.
Man, fuck this. We're out.
Get off me!
Where are we?
Where'd you take me?
Subway's that way. Good
luck with your bullshit.
Hey! Take me back! I need him!
I need The Beast to kill
Reynard! Reynard has the knife.
I can't do it without The Beast.
It's not my problem.
Oh, shit. Duck!
Shit!
What the hell?
The chain was the only thing
keeping my hands from fucking...
Put it back on! I can't!
It's a ritual and I
don't have any of the...
(GRUNTING) Oh, no.
Thank you. Yeah, no problem.
You fucking...
Sorry. Not my problem.
Fuck!
No!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
ALICE: He's injured.
Where else would he be?
He has to be at the Wellspring.
The Royal Carriage can
get there in under an hour.
Okay, but if he
can just blip in...
Well, hopefully his accuracy
isn't at its best right now.
I know mine wouldn't be.
MARGO: Well, if those horses
get us there before The Beast,
I'll gladly fuck them both.
ELIOT: Hey! (SHUSHES)
Careful. Volume. I think
those are talking horses.
Offer stands.
(HORSES WHINNY)
Hey, can you still do this?
I don't know. What
choice do we have?
Okay, we should send
El and Margo for help.
Wait. You don't want us on
the suicide mission with you?
Ember's temple is nearby. So
just go and petition him for a re-up.
Just in case Alice and I...
Fail? Die?
Sorry. Reflex.
Okay, fine. We'll go.
(SIGHS)
Hey. Thought exercise.
Say we kill The
Beast, uh, what then?
Quentin, I don't know.
It's just... It's a distraction.
Come on.
Um... (CLEARS THROAT)
I would, um...
I'd eat an ice cream sundae.
With whipped cream and those
fake, rainbow-colored sprinkles.
And, I don't know,
gummy bears on top.
I'm probably gonna
try and win you back.
Jesus, Quentin!
I'm sorry. It just sort
of flew out of my mouth.
You know, I'm not a prize.
I know that. But you
know what I mean.
No, and you didn't
just lose me like keys.
I know. Which is why I feel like
I need to earn back your trust.
(SIGHS) This isn't fair.
This isn't fair. You
can't trap me in here.
You can't trap me in here
and expect me to deal with
all this heavy emotional shit
when all I can
handle right now...
All I can handle right now is a
goddamn ice cream sundae, okay?
It's not a trap.
Yes, it is. Then why
does it sound like
you're trying to fight with me?
Look. You've changed, okay?
You're not the girl that I met a
million years ago. You're amazing.
And not that you weren't
amazing before, but...
Quentin, where are
you going with this?
You've grown.
And you're still growing.
And my point is that I am, too.
Are you saying you're
not that guy anymore?
No, I'm saying that I'm
not just that guy anymore.
And I think that you should...
I hope that you give
me the opportunity
to be better and
actually deserve you.
And I know that
that sounds stupid,
but I feel like we
could die in like an hour
and that's giving me a
lot of clarity right now.
I don't know what
to say, Quentin.
Also I'm gonna make you the best
ice cream sundae you've ever had.
You're gonna
forget Popper No. 1,
and I'm even gonna put,
um, gummy bears on it.
Even though you don't understand
how absolutely
disgusting that is.
(SNIFFLES)
Quentin...
I'm sorry. I just was in the
moment. Do you still wanna fight?
No.
Ember! Come out!
Hello?
I'm pretty sure Q said the whole
blood, stone thing works right away.
Fine. Give me your hand.
Just...
Oh, come on!
Ow.
That kind of stings! Poor baby.
Great.
(SIGHS) Well, now
we're both bleeding.
Maybe Ember isn't home?
He's a god-in-exile.
Where else could he be?
MARGO: I don't know. (PANTING)
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
Mmm.
Ahh!
Greetings, O powerful
and glorious Martin Chatwin.
My goodness, only
half the man I remember.
You know what happens
if you stay in Fillory?
I know. I know.
I'm leaving, I'm going. I just
had one or two things to do.
Mainly number two.
I have befouled the Wellspring.
(LAUGHS) Pardon me?
I have left my divine
elimination in the font of all magic.
And it's a stinker.
I really hope you weren't
planning to drink from it.
It's hardly potable.
You...
What?
Left my leavings. A godly
floater. (GIGGLES) Behind.
In the Wellspring.
I pooped in it. Am I not
making this very clear?
You wretched bastard.
I know your true game.
I know it exactly. Every
twist, you stinking man-sheep!
Oh, my heavens, look at the
time. I really should be going.
Although technically, I
already went. (LAUGHING)
I never tire of these jokes. Ta!
(WHOOSHING)
(SNIFFS AND GROANS)
(SNEEZES)
(GROANING)
You stinking man-sheep!
You're no god! You're no god!
You're a farm
animal! You're no god!
Ember actually took a
shit in the Wellspring?
MARTIN: You're a farm animal!
Well, that can't
be good for Fillory.
Quentin Coldwater!
Shit.
Why don't you and
Alice come join me?
(PANTING)
Mmm!
You're weaker.
And you're down six fingers.
(LAUGHS) More than
enough to kill you both.
Hard to cast when
you're sliced in two.
(GROANING)
Quentin!
You're a tough piece of
meat, aren't you? No matter.
(GRUNTS) (GASPS)
(PANTING)
(GROANING)
I guess we're gonna die.
To our pretty corpses.
Children of Earth,
I have returned!
Spank my cheeks, you're
both royalty. How delightful.
You have come
here to beseech me?
Well, um, yes.
We have come to, uh,
beseech your, um, aid.
Of course. You shall have it.
Oh. Oh, but then
you're going to miss it!
Miss what? All the action!
Between you and me, I think Alice
should make this a very good show.
No promises, though.
Cheerio! Happy
ruling! Ember, we...
(GASPS)
Great. Kicked us out before
we could even ask for the jizz.
Margo, look.
ALICE: Is that all you've got?
You're not even a real
Magician, are you, Martin?
You're just a scared little boy.
You wouldn't last an hour
at Brakebills. (PANTING)
(GRUNTING, SHRIEKS)
Gah!
(GROANING)
Jesus! Alice is going full Harry
Potter part seven/eight over there.
Oh, God, I hope we're winning.
(PANTING)
Damn it!
(MOANS)
No, no. Alice,
what are you doing?
No! Alice, don't.
Stop! It'll... (GRUNTS)
What's she doing?
She can't, she'll Niffin out.
This is not good, Alice.
(GRUNTS)
Alice, stop!
It's okay. I've
got this, Quentin.
Alice, no!
(GASPING)
(SHRIEKING)
Alice!
(SHRIEKING CONTINUES)
No!
(WHEEZING)
(LAUGHING)
Oops!
Too far.
Too bad.
Let's finally finish this.
(GASPS)
I did it on purpose.
Move.
Let's go. We gotta go.
Go on.
Something you want to say?
Alice, we could make a deal.
Think of the fun we
could have together.
You don't have
to... But I want to.
Disappointing.
ALICE: Your turn.
Alice!
Okay, you've got her
attention. Now what?
MARGO: (WHIMPERING) Uh...
I'm sorry for all the times
I was a total dick to you.
You're talking like you
mean something to me.
Okay, just...
Alice, don't.
Get back.
Quentin says go free.
(GASPS)
(GROWLS)
(ALICE SHRIEKING)
(GASPS)
Fuck!
Fuck.
QUENTIN: Alice? (GROANING)
Alice?
(MOANING)
Alice, hey, hey.
ELIOT: Q! Stop, you're hurt.
Alice. Q.
You have to stop. No,
come on. She might be alive.
Just stop. You have
to stop. She might be...
Q, you have to stop.
(SOBBING)
You have to stop.
(QUENTIN GROANS)