Previously on The Magicians...
The Takers are swarming.
They're swarming because
Seb summoned them with a spell.
Okay, so, what if we locate the tree
from Seb's tattoo and chop it down?
Would that sever this conduit?
In theory, yes. He would be
mortal, and 100% stab-able.
I wouldn't if I were you.
Surprised?
I just have a problem,
and it's getting worse.
Oh.
I traveled us to 1998.
This is where the
signal brought us.
It was just a room.
No windows, no doors.
We can't leave.
That's Miss Persephone.
That's Our Lady Underground.
When the Sister was in
me, I remember everything.
Promise.
Give me the page. If the
finger's still viable, I reattach.
Hey, what happened to your eye?
I lent it to Josh. So I'm
keeping an eye on him, okay?
Hold up. Somebody's near Josh.
It's the Dark King. He's coming.
Your Highness. I
mean, Your Majesty.
I think there's been
a huge... No mistake.
You were part of the plot
to kill me, were you not?
I wouldn't say that,
exactly. It doesn't matter.
There is a way you
can make it up to me.
To Fillory.
Okay, sure. Uh, what?
You are a brave, brave man.
Right, thank you.
Uh... Oh.
Uh... Is this a blood
brothers kind of thing?
I'm guessing this
isn't a medal of valor.
What are you doing?
Your death will not be in vain.
But I will miss your cooking.
What?
No. No! No, please.
Please, no! No!
No!
The walls are solid.
There's no buttons or switches.
Everything I cast is wrong here.
Circumstances are
impossible to read.
Okay, are you sure this is the
room that the signal brought you to?
Yes, but I can't
remember where "here" is.
Okay. I've still got
the Welters plaque.
Let's just try again.
It didn't work last time.
Christ, sit.
The signal pulled us
back. You were right.
That's why you should
listen to your elders, Plum.
Who the hell are you?
That was a Tiffany
lamp, you know.
Crafted from a design I acquired
from Clara Driscoll herself.
Took me ages to make.
Do I need to tell you how
much I don't give a shit?
Why are we here?
What do you want?
I want you to
stop time traveling.
Are you, like, the God
of Time or something?
Hardly. I'm a Time Traveler,
like young Plum here.
I have been monitoring you.
And now you're
keeping us prisoner?
"This one will be
smart," I thought.
"Cautious."
Then you had to risk altering the
future to save some young pervert.
So, is this the part where
you draw us little diagrams
about screwing up the
flow of time or whatever?
Nice thing about the 21st
century, you've all seen Looper.
So, I can get to the point.
We are here because though I
would rather be making lamps,
I am forced to focus on the
most important task there is,
protecting the
integrity of space-time,
which you threaten.
I'd have hoped you'd waste
your time on something useful.
Try to kill Hitler at least.
I was getting to it, I'm not
an asshole. I just found out.
Well, doing any of
those things would be a...
Would be a royal
cluster. We get it.
She gets it.
Yeah. She does, loud and clear.
We promise not to
change the past anymore.
Can we leave?
Well, this isn't a
"pinky swear" situation.
I know how intoxicating the
prospect of altering time can be.
Just this once, I'd like to
relieve you of that burden.
This device
neutralizes your abilities.
It's painless. It's
got fucking teeth!
It's painless once it's on,
works quickly and
permanently to eradicate.
And you can still traverse
space like your peers.
Traveling is in our DNA.
What exactly would
you be eradicating?
Plum, you and I have a mutation
of the plasma factor of the blood.
Luckily, we stop producing
it by the time we can walk.
What's in you now, it's finite.
When we traverse time,
we use up a fraction of it.
So, you want to take away
the thing that makes me me?
That's dramatic.
I'm offering to rid
you of your curse.
I can't force you.
You must consent or the spell
work won't function. It's up to you.
I'm offering to free you.
Yo, this is crazy.
You have no right
to drag us both here...
I didn't.
You, Professor, are a hanger-on.
The signal was meant for her.
I won't do it.
They can never just say yes.
Well, whenever you change your mind,
simply place your arm inside the cuff.
He can't help you, you
have to do it yourself.
Till then, enjoy my
space out of time.
My name is Eliphas, by
the way. Friends call me Eli.
So, Eliphas.
Is he just gonna leave us here?
How do they feel?
Like ghost fingers.
They work, but magically,
they still feel severed.
So, you can't cast?
Not really, no.
One-handed, and that pretty
much rules out most spells.
I'm not going to
forget what you did.
We're gonna get
those pricks for this.
I don't know, Kady. Maybe
we should just walk away.
You can walk away,
but, to be clear,
I'm not done until I cut
that son of a bitch's balls off.
I owe them that for tying me up,
and I owe them triple
for what they did to you.
You can sit it out, okay?
Um, no. We're in this together.
Oh, it's just so
beautiful, you guys.
Female friendship really is
the most underrated
form of love, right?
I'm sorry.
I'm extra emotional.
It's just that,
with the assassination going sideways,
and then Josh and Eliot and Julia
not making it back.
Not to mention all that crazy
stuff Plover told us. It's just...
It's really overwhelming.
So, um, what have
you guys been up to?
No! No, no.
Okay, okay, okay.
Josh... Josh, calm. Calm.
You are in...
Taker Home Base Land, I guess.
Or, never fear.
No reason to fear, because...
Taker Kryptonite,
for some reason.
Focus. Mission, get home.
Also, don't die.
When you were lost at
Burning Man, what did you do?
You called Margo.
Voldemort's clit!
Wait, where's Josh?
Where the Takers come from.
I don't understand.
Is it in Fillory?
Sure as shit
doesn't look like it.
So then, why is Josh there?
No clue, but seems
stuck, wandering around.
And it's... It's...
Stop moving the
damn camera, Josh.
It's like I'm
watching Cloverfield.
I really don't think my eye likes
being in a different world than me.
Is that my blood?
Oh, God. FEN: Margo.
Um, hey, not an expert,
but does that seem...
Real goddamn bad.
Is there a spell or something
to calm Fairy eyes
transmitting from foreign realms?
Even assuming yes, casting's
ultra moon-jacked today.
I can't say I'd risk it.
I have an idea.
Is she trying to do magic?
Mmm-hmm.
Should you tell her
that's a waste of time?
Should I? It seems
like it's helping.
Hmm?
Hey, a gentle reminder,
this is a magic-proof cell.
So...
The hedge witch
explosive arts and crafts are,
at best, wishful thinking.
And you didn't think to tell
me that 45 minutes ago?
It seemed like you
needed an activity.
I'm honestly trying to help.
It's bad enough for me, and I
don't even have a human inside me.
Except you do, technically.
Shit.
Now there's nothing to do.
I really let it go on as
long as I felt morally able.
What are we going to do, Eliot?
We'll think of something?
Is that a question?
I am trying my best
to calm you down.
"Calm me down"? What am
I, a maiden with the vapors?
You're upset. I'm not upset.
I'm locked in a dungeon during
Red fucking Monkey Month
with this baby growing
inside me like a weed on HGH
on a planet without so much
as a fucking prenatal vitamin.
But no, I'm not upset.
I don't get upset.
I figure it out.
There is always something.
Is there? Of course there is.
I agree. Do you?
Do you actually believe that?
Whew. ELIOT: Um...
Can you believe I
thought I could fix this?
I'm the reason we're
here in the first place.
Hey.
No... I wouldn't say that.
Face it. I failed, Eliot.
You didn't fail. You're just
tired, you're... you're cooped up.
I stole a quest, I got it wrong.
I screwed magic on Earth,
I screwed us here.
And the thing about it is, you know,
facing ever-increasing bad odds,
is that you have to be really good
at thinking of the next thing to try.
Hey, let's just, uh, take a
deep breath. Okay? We'll just...
I mean, there is nothing else.
We are done.
No. We're gonna die here.
My baby is going to die
here. We are gonna die.
It all went to shit.
Hey.
You're just... You're
having a moment.
This is not a
moment, it's my life!
You need to calm her. She's
gonna give the baby bad humors.
I just heard a voice
say "bad humors."
You heard that? You heard me?
Can you still hear me?
Uh, this is wonderful.
Yeah. My name is Charlton.
What the fuck's a Charlton?
So, there's a man inside
your head and I heard him.
That's it, more or less.
An excellent summation.
Why all of a sudden could I
hear him, and then why did it stop?
I don't know.
Well, her weird
baby is developing.
My mother, who was a midwife,
once tended a lady pregnant by a nixie.
She often sleepwalked
into the sea,
but no ill befell her because
she developed gestational gills.
Charlton theorizes that
you had a psychic attack,
because of, well, who
and what the baby daddy is.
Wait, so you're
saying that's a thing?
Me being able to take
on what the baby can do?
Maybe.
Well, maybe this
baby's a Traveler,
I mean, that'd be pretty goddamn
handy right about now, no?
Mmm-hmm.
Okay, we need to
quantify this shit.
What's happening,
how can I control it,
keep baby safe, and get
us the hell out of here?
I... I studied this first year.
They make us take sex ed,
inter-Magician relations being
so fraught with STIs and peril.
I think we may have
covered this stuff.
You think, or... I'm not proud,
but I was on a record amount
of greenhouse cannabis,
and so, while technically
I heard every single word,
it was all, you know,
Sondheim lyrics.
I was there, but
in a greater sense,
was I there?
Well, perhaps I can help.
If you were, as
you say, "there,"
perhaps the
remembrance itself is...
Is intact in here still
somehow, that is brilliant.
Can you... Yeah, I
can certainly attempt.
My imaginary friend is on it.
Great.
Do's and don'ts of
magical intercourse.
I avoided real college so I
wouldn't have to see shit like this.
You kidding? This is
spank-bank material.
If it burns when you pee,
infirmary.
Red bumps like a curse,
see a nurse.
Scales, feathers, fur...
Medical attention that rhymes
with fur, read you loud and clear.
Now, let's chat
procreation, shall we?
Let's start with some basics.
Do not assume that
your classmate is human
just because they look it.
Hybrids abound.
DNA magic develops in utero,
which can affect the
mother unpredictably,
which can, of course,
result in maiming or death.
If you think you've been
impregnated by a hybrid or creature,
you may want to take precautions
to prevent any episodes.
Let's go over a few, shall we?
Excuse me, wait,
I have questions.
Who are you? You
are not a student here.
Of course I am. I... I
did a thing to my face.
Hello, it's Todd.
Todd.
Yes, what's your question?
What if a person
wanted the episodes?
Let's say the fetus was
psychic, or even a Traveler?
I cannot speak to that.
Well, but you are
speaking to that.
This is a memory.
I made no mention of
Travelers specifically.
Okay, but say I
wanted my baby...
I can only tell you what's
happening in this memory, Todd,
and how to prevent it.
Yeah, but that won't help
me. You see, I need to know...
Hey, genius,
why don't you just let him tell you
how to stop it and do the opposite?
It's a defense mechanism.
The fetus detects the mother's
distress and reacts protectively.
You freaked the baby out with
your meltdown, so it psyched you up.
Next. And this can be avoided
by cultivating a tranquil mind.
Soothing teas, meditation...
Can we just skip to the part
where Julia travels to safety?
Oh, right. Then she will need
to, aggressively, do the opposite.
The opposite of
tea and meditation?
Wait, is he saying I
need to freak out more?
She needs to feel imminent
life or death danger, yes.
Basically, we need to scare
the living shit out of you.
Great.
This is fine, totally fine.
Just a totally normal walk,
a totally normal forest.
Okay, you can't hear
that, but that is a Taker,
screaming, for some reason.
Whose eye is that? Uh...
Nobody's. It's...
my girlfriend's eye.
That's not better, you know.
She lent it to me.
Where did you come from?
How about that? So did I.
So, how did you
end up down here?
I was taken, with my friends.
Friends. Friends are good.
Uh, where are they?
The Takers put them
in a big, shiny case.
It opens sideways,
and when you poke
its big yellow eye,
its mouth opens and says "Ding."
That sounds like an elevator.
Is that a kind of monster?
No, not a monster.
A machine.
That eats people?
No, it goes up, it goes down.
It's just weird that it's here.
Maybe we should check it
out. Do you know where...
Are you an adult? Of course.
Do I not seem like an adult?
Adults lie and say
everything's okay
when it really isn't.
Then Takers come.
I'm not helping an adult.
Oh. Please. Uh, no.
Just wait.
- No, wait. No, don't touch.
- Let me go.
No, let me go. No!
No! JOSH: Hey!
Huh? Uh...
You like this?
Yeah, shiny. Right?
Yeah, good. Go get it!
Hey, hey, hey.
You okay? Yeah.
How did you do that? Luck.
Let's get the hell out of here.
That'll do it.
My own personal Mar-GoPro.
Trust me, where I'm
from, that was really clever.
Well, here it's stupid, okay?
Now, here's the
cave over there, okay?
Okay. Looks clear.
Let's get a little closer
and see where it goes.
Come on.
Underworld? Do we
not want to go there?
Uh...
Underworld sounds
pretty good right now!
Come on, come on!
Not today, Takers!
But where are we going?
So this is the Underworld?
And it's where we
go when we die?
Does this mean we're dead?
No. No, we're
not... I... I mean,
neither of us died,
technically, so...
Are my friends dead?
Look,
I don't know.
And I'm not gonna
lie, this isn't good.
But I promise you,
I'm going to do whatever I can
to get us both out of here, okay?
You better.
Let's see if we
can find some help.
"Welcome. You are
dead. Please take a card."
Take a card. You
can read, can't you?
Right. Uh, question.
Where do we go
if we aren't dead?
If you're here, you're dead.
And if you're dead,
you take a card.
But I'm not dead.
I can't be dead.
Please, mister. There must
be someone we can talk to.
Great. Now look what you've done.
- Oh.
I'll see if I can find someone.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey. You okay?
Of course. I do
this all the time.
Crying makes
adults uncomfortable.
Not bad.
Hoberman?
Penny? What the fuck...
What are you doing here?
Uh...
Remind me why you dragged
me to the Brakebills lab
instead of staying in our
comfortable penthouse?
We had to bring you
somewhere where we could
control Circumstances.
Besides, I'm going to have to
rely on Kady to do any casting.
I don't even know
where to start.
Trash can.
What? Okay.
That I can handle.
I can see the tether
between you and your eye,
and it's kind of between
worlds. It's all glitchy.
I think we should sever the connection
before it does permanent damage.
My Fairy eye is the only
connection I have to Josh.
You cut that out, I
cut out your uterus.
Uh...
Margo?
Just a gentle observation.
If you scorch your brain pan,
that won't be great for Josh either.
Okay.
That won't work for long. So we're
gonna need a solution yesterday.
Yeah. Okay. You stay with her.
Fen, come with me,
I'm gonna need help.
I'm gonna need to get a
couple other things, stat.
I can only bring
authorized items.
Well, then ask a doctor
about premature labor
and get it authorized.
Now.
Five stalks green nightshade,
one dead quail,
unplucked, rock salt,
and two fingers of bourbon. Now.
Ow. Ow, it really hurts.
Ask the King if he
wants this woman to die.
I need to cast something
to stop her pain,
or alternately, oceans of
blood on your hands, friend.
Chop-chop.
Hey.
Psst.
Okay, so what's
all that really for?
I need you scared, and
you don't scare easy.
So the less you
know, the better.
Gruel?
Hey, you think Ash will be fine
with, uh, what's-her-name, right?
Kathy?
Old friend. She's
great with kids.
Should feel like
recess plus birthday.
It's just, me and the
kid kind of have this
Newt-and-Ripley thing going.
I promised I'd get her home.
Then I should get the
bad news out of the way.
I can't help you.
Why the hell not?
Take a look around.
Librarians have been going
through some shit lately.
No magic. Too much
magic, but unpredictable.
A lot of our folks got
relocated, and we...
kind of, don't
exactly know where.
Okay, perfect world, boss
steps in, oversees shit, but...
Hades has vanished.
Your boss is the god Hades?
That's cool.
Except for the
abandoning you part.
Can't say that's great.
Kind of a skeleton crew.
And here's the bad news for you.
Our connection to the world of
the living, Hades controls that.
And right before he
FO'd, he flipped the switch.
Why?
Man, dead you is
just way more zen.
Uh, so after all that,
why did you stay?
I make a promise, I keep it.
Look, bro, I hear
you, and bad timing,
but me and the
kid, we didn't die.
We just got dragged into a
weird netherworld by the Takers.
Right, you said.
Never heard of 'em.
Well, I promise you,
they're real and they suck,
and we are in the wrong place.
I mean, this can't be
the first time in history
not-dead people
ended up here, right?
Accidents happen. There's
gotta be some protocol.
Or some special
dispensation thing.
Anyone sent to the Underworld by
mistake has 24 hours to file a dispute.
Great! Let's file a dispute.
Disputes have to be sent up top.
And since Hades left, we can't.
So, if we don't find
Hades, we're just stuck?
I'm sorry.
Does he have, like,
a pager or a walkie?
If he doesn't want to
be found, he won't be.
Underworld is big.
He could be anywhere.
Well, could I maybe get a map
and start checking things off?
Shit.
I might know
someone who can help.
God, but it is the suck option.
Penny! You got my invite.
Uh...
Oh.
You need something. Sorry, man.
This is so typical.
You don't come to my
brunches, which I guess is fine,
but you could at least RSVP.
That is the polite thing to do,
so he doesn't
have too much food.
That makes sense.
Anyway, we need an expert.
That is why we're here,
and I gather you are the guy
who knows where everything is.
Well, I do know a thing or two.
And I am very generous with
my time, unlike some people.
We are looking for Hades.
Penny thinks you
might know where he is.
I have no idea.
Penny told you he
disappeared, right? Very odd.
Usually there's at least one
person that can get a hold of him.
This time... But you
know all his spots?
Gods, no.
Quite the opposite. He
is insanely strict on me.
You know, I'm not even allowed
to map the place where he...
Wait a minute.
He forbade me from mapping
an area in the Underworld.
I always suspected he had
some kind of special retreat there.
I'm sorry, if it's not on the map,
what good would that do us?
Well, because I mapped
everything else around it.
So, in an ironic way, it's
like I mapped it perfectly.
Is it time to put another
scratch mark up?
It's been a day, right?
I can't tell anymore.
I think your count is short.
We've been here
longer than a month.
This whole conversation is
predicated on time having meaning,
which it doesn't in here, so...
A Time Traveler walks
into a bar in Vienna, 1908.
Sits next to a young art
student named Adolf Hitler.
Adolf sighs into his beer.
"You know what I hate?" he asks.
Time Traveler says,
"I don't know. Jews?"
And Hitler goes, "Huh.
Now that you mention it..."
I mean, you gotta laugh, right?
You're right.
There are no good
jokes about time-traveling.
At first I thought
it was better,
at least, that we don't get
hungry or tired or need to pee,
but it's just...
Fucking torture.
The sameness, it is intolerable.
Hey. Hey, hey.
We are tolerating fine.
Hey, we are going
to figure this out.
There is nothing to figure out.
It is what it is.
There is just one decision.
I'd still be a regular Traveler.
No, that's not happening.
This is it, Penny.
The... The Chatwin curse.
The tipping of the scale.
No, this is just some self-important
asshole we need to outsmart.
I am not letting you be forced into
a decision that's gonna ruin your life.
It's not my life,
exactly. It's...
You don't know what it is.
You are at the beginning.
That's why, no.
We could be here forever
if we don't do something.
What are you doing?
I'm making my decision.
Wow.
The Underworld is in shambles,
and Hades is out here doing...
Whatever this is.
Pink Himalayan sea salt.
I do a great salt-crusted
cod with a lovely...
You know what, never
mind. Not important.
He uses it as a spa
bath. It extracts toxins.
A great stress releaser.
So I've heard. MAN: Excuse me.
This temple is off-limits.
Yes, hi. We are
looking for Hades.
He's unavailable.
Respectfully, we wouldn't
come here if it wasn't urgent.
Can you please let him
know that we are here?
No. He's gone.
Well, he can't just be gone.
I assume you're here
because he just up and left
and you're worried
it was for good.
Well, I'm sorry to tell you,
when he left, he told me
he might never be back.
Wait, what? Never?
He didn't feel like elaborating.
It's just, some of us are trying
to keep the Underworld running.
Yeah, and some of
us are trying to map it!
And he is a god.
He doesn't answer to any of you.
Well, excuse me,
please... Um, guys.
I think I got something.
Let's just hope
Margo's still watching.
So, here's the plan.
We separate the signal
before it enters Margo's brain,
and then we deflect it.
Like, put it
somewhere else? How?
With this.
Now, I have a mixed
history with prism spells,
so you're gonna need
to check my math.
This feels weird as fuck.
Just don't move.
Did you... Did you
poke her brain parts?
How does that feel?
Like you just stuck a flash
drive into my Jell-O hole.
Oh, my God. I feel something
coming through. What the fuck?
Oh, Channel Josh is live!
How does it feel?
Like I'm getting
acupuncture inside my brain.
But it doesn't hurt.
Oh, thank God he's alive.
Except where the
shit-faced Jesus is he?
Wait, why is Penny
in Taker Land?
That's not... That's
not the Penny...
That's... That's Penny.
That's my Penny.
Wait, but that would mean
that Josh is in the Underworld.
No, no, no. That would mean...
Josh is dead?
Wait. He's trying to
tell us that he's still alive
and needs our help.
But I don't get... Isn't
Hades down there?
I am so confused.
An address! In Queens!
Hades is on Earth?
Well, shit. Go
check. I'd come with,
but I've got a goddamn movie
projector stuck in my eye hole.
Okay.
Now, arrange the feathers
in front of you in a triangle
and then drink this.
What's the bourbon
for? It's for me.
Ugh.
Okay, so, um, this isn't going to do
anything to you or mini-you, physically.
But, um, you will feel a
huge shot of fear and anxiety,
and it's not gonna be nice,
so, hopefully,
that'll do something.
Okay, bottoms up.
Now, listen to, uh, exactly
what I'm going to say
because the next
part can get a little bit...
Um...
Weird.
Okay, on my count. Three, two...
Oh, my God. My water just broke.
What? That's very bad.
Oh, my God. The
baby's coming, Eliot.
Uh, tell her to lay on her back.
I can't lay on my back,
it's coming. It's too soon.
This is way too soon.
Eliot, please do something.
You have to get a guard. Guard!
They won't come. They
never come between meals.
Oh, shit. I'm sorry, there...
Eliot, you have to get
us out of here. I can't.
Tell the baby. What? Okay.
Okay, baby, we gotta go.
We gotta go, okay, baby?
We gotta go. Oh, we gotta go.
Okay, how does Penny travel?
He... He pictures
it in his mind, right?
Right. ELIOT: Right? Okay,
so picture it in your mind,
picture the other side of the bars.
I'm trying, I can't.
Now, Julia. I'm
trying, El, I can't.
Come on, Jules. Now.
Oh, my God.
Eliot, I did it. It worked. Yes.
Okay, now do it for real. What?
I'm sorry.
You motherfucker.
You incepted me.
Your baby's strong, took
three castings to deceive it.
I had to make you believe it, so we had
to tell you the spell was something else.
Honestly, fuck the both of you.
Get mad later. Use
the adrenalin right now.
Do it again.
Now, Julia. Go to hell.
My baby is awesome.
Celebrate later,
escape now. Keys.
Right.
Alice, Kady.
Been expecting you.
Here.
So, did you come here to watch
me play video games, or what?
Our friend is trapped in the
Underworld, but he isn't dead.
Wow.
How'd he manage to do that?
Well, he's, uh,
gifted at screwing up.
Can you please help him?
Sorry, can't.
'Course you can, you
run the Underworld.
I did, but then I quit.
You what? Can you even do that?
I can do what I want. But why?
Our friend, he's not
supposed to be there.
You think death is fair?
You think life is fair?
Skip the sales pitch,
Kady Orloff-Diaz.
I know your life, so I
know you know better.
Give me one reason you deserve to
be treated any better than the rest of us,
and I'll help.
Otherwise, you're
messing up my game.
What is wrong with him?
Why is every god we
meet such a nutsack?
Look around.
What do you see?
A shitty apartment.
Shades drawn,
takeout, he's a mess.
Look familiar?
It's me, after Q died.
Oh, my God.
Our Lady Underground
was his wife.
The Monster's
sister, she killed her.
The God of the
Dead is in mourning.
Let me try to talk to him.
Um... Figured it out, huh?
Can you just put that down
and talk to me for a second?
Look,
there's nothing to say. It's not
the same, your grief and mine.
I disagree.
I think when you lose someone...
When you die, you go somewhere.
You know how I
know? Because I built it.
For you. To help you.
Quentin? Penny?
I eased their passage.
There's no Underworld for gods.
What happens to you?
I don't know.
We're not supposed to die,
but she did,
and that's all I get
to know, forever.
See, you'll die someday,
but I won't.
I'm sorry.
I wish there was something
I could say to help.
But our friend,
Josh, didn't die.
He was in the Taker Realm and...
That's not possible.
That place doesn't
connect to the world above.
Well, someone opened a door.
That's very bad.
The creatures you call Takers,
do you know what they are?
Uh...
They're guard dogs.
Their realm is a
security measure.
A barrier between your world
and the World of the Dead.
If a soul tries to come back,
it takes them and returns
them to the Underworld.
Trust me.
The dead coming back to the
living, that's not a good thing.
So, if they're in Fillory...
Then somebody opened a door
that should not have been opened.
I think I know why.
What if it was a person like us
who just wanted to bring
back someone he loved?
I leave for a couple of months,
and everything goes to shit.
I will help your friend.
But you will clean up this mess.
Stop whoever's trying
to get past the Takers.
If you don't, and let
me say this very clearly,
your world will
be destroyed, too.
Destroyed how?
If this person were
to get past the Takers,
there would be just one door between
them and the person that they lost.
And if they were
to crack that door,
who knows how many of
the dead would spill through.
Not just the one he wants,
but all the dead.
It could mean the
end of everything.
I... I think we're back.
Fillory smells a lot
better than Takerville.
I didn't think you were
a hugger. Shut up.
Mmm.
Look.
Oh, my God. They're all dead.
Is that a good thing?
I don't know.
Okay, we should stop.
It's okay, I can do this.
Okay. All right, come on.
He said this was
eradicating your...
Timey-wimey plasma factor.
Why does it look like
this is collecting it?
What? Let me see that.
Your hand is shaking.
I don't... I don't want
this. Get this thing off.
What the hell is it now?
Step away from her.
This is how you
unburden her curse?
By collecting it?
You don't understand
what you're talking about.
Put that down.
How about I smash it? Wait!
Stop, okay? Your hand,
that tremor.
That's what happens when
you run low? Your finite supply?
Do you ever stop
asking questions?
You're not a guardian
of space-time,
you're a junkie. I wasn't lying.
You used the signal to find us so you
can take what we have to use for yourself.
I wasn't lying about what I do.
Time Travelers are so rare,
but you spend your life chasing
them to unflap every butterfly wing,
it feels like they're
everywhere.
I'm just trying to stop idiots from
destroying the entire universe.
Oh, it's interesting that idiots
include everyone except you.
Tell me most people
can be trusted.
Tell me more power
makes people better. No?
I thought so.
I have been keeping this whole
thing together, by myself, forever.
You didn't think you
could ask me for help?
Oh, I tried a few times with a
few of you when I was your age.
I believed in people.
You mean back before you thought
you were better than everyone else?
You can't understand unless
you've seen what I have,
and I wouldn't wish
that on the devil.
It's why I put you here.
One day maybe you'll
know enough to thank me.
Okay, brass tacks,
we're leaving.
When she finishes, I... I won't.
She's not finishing.
She's walking away with
whatever's in her veins
in exchange for this.
I can't let her go if
she... That's the deal.
Fine.
Learn not to Time Travel.
Because, hear me, if you go
back, if you change a hair on a fly,
you will be seeing me,
and it will be the very
last time you see anyone.
Can't wait.
Hey, help!
Okay, she's breathing.
She's coming to.
Um...
Yeah, uh,
we should probably talk.