QUENTIN: Previously
on The Magicians...
This contract initiates our
services in exchange for...
Unlimited manual
and magical labor?
You signed that insane
contract? Yeah, it's okay.
How the hell is that okay?
Because I get magic back.
Did you do this for me?
I'm Bayler. A proud
soldier of Fillorians United.
And we will not rest until a
Fillorian sits upon the throne.
The Fairies can bring
back the Wellspring?
They can.
And in return?
A royal child of Whitespire.
We're getting married.
Apparently, all monarchs
are entitled to one of
each, a wife and a husband.
Alice, I hope you meant it.
I hope you just go
and do beautiful magic.
Quentin says go free.
KADY: You fed him to Reynard.
JULIA: He knew how to survive.
KADY: Yeah, by
doing what you want!
That's all you see
anymore, is what you want.
You don't feel anymore, Julia,
not the way a human does.
Do you remember the gift
that Jane was given in the book
The Girl Who Told Time?
Ember gave her the
ability to fuck with time,
on a cosmic scale.
And Jane used it
to create a time loop.
In each loop, Jane
alters something
to see if it'll change
the outcome.
What's different this time?
I was at Brakebills? QUENTIN:
You were supposed to be.
Or you were, like, 39 times.
You were the thing they changed.
Very impressive, Ms. Wicker.
Let me do it again.
I was wondering
what would happen
if I connected the sequence
with Atsuko's Spectral Refraction.
All right.
(EXHALES)
(CHUCKLES)
That is a second-year spell.
I read ahead.
More than that, you understood
the theory behind the spell,
and you reshaped it.
Your discipline is meta-composition.
You are a Knowledge student.
Knowledge?
Mmm-hmm. Part
psychic, part physical.
There really is no
branch it doesn't touch on.
The short version, you
are drawn, mind and body,
to the discovery of magic.
Is it true that they, uh...
That we live in the
attic above the Library?
I assure you, it is much
more luxurious than it sounds.
No, I mean, that
sounds like bliss, actually.
I enjoyed it.
You were a Knowledge student?
I am a Knowledge student.
It doesn't end with your degree.
You have a rare gift, Julia.
And I must admit I am envious
of the many rich discoveries
that you have ahead
of you. Welcome.
Thank you.
(DOOR OPENS)
You are free to go.
Why would you let me go?
DEAN: Because, Ms. Wicker,
you are not a student here,
and I am not running a jail.
Kady locked me up
for a good reason.
I should feel terrible
about what I did.
But I don't.
I just think it's terrible,
and I think I would have
never done it if I were me.
One thing I've learned
about you, Ms. Wicker,
is that you are a searcher.
You don't know me.
Thirty-nine times,
I've known you,
which is why I trust that you'll
put aside your fear and self-pity
and look for the answers
that can save you.
ELIOT: Why am I the only
one worried about this wedding?
Mmm...
Congratulations. You failed.
QUENTIN: Oh, hey, um...
King needs more wine.
Of course, sire.
I feel bad. I forgot your name.
It's Smedley, sire.
Smedley. Thanks, Smedley.
Hey, I'll take that.
Oh, no. Wait. I'm not done.
I think you were.
Not cool. Those grapes
died for nothing now.
Those grapes died
so you might live,
because if you keep drinking,
I will seriously cut a bitch.
You never yell at
Eliot for being drunk.
Because Eliot's fun. You're
depressing. It's been three months.
Technically, it's only been a
couple of days on Earth, so...
Three months on
Fillory of Emo Quentin.
Not my favorite Quentin.
I didn't know that you
liked any of the Quentins.
(SIGHS)
You had to let Alice go.
I'm sympathetic, okay?
But meanwhile,
Groomzilla is suddenly
my full time job.
I need your help.
ELIOT: Bambi! This
is an emergency.
These are all wrong. You're
banished forever. Thank you.
He's just so mean when
he needs things. It's...
Eliot needs a friend, asshole.
It's your turn to be button boy
and run his random
Earth errands.
I need a free moment to
rub one out in a hot bath
before I fucking kill someone,
that someone being you.
Message received.
Then get your
feet off my throne.
(SCOFFS)
This is insane. Why the
fuck would Fogg let Julia go?
I mean, haven't you ever
noticed? Fogg isn't that helpful.
Plus, you knew he couldn't
keep her in there forever.
Yeah, well, I thought she'd at
least be in there long enough
for us to figure
out what to do next.
Where are you going?
Look, I still have
Reynard to deal with,
and I really don't
want to run into Julia.
Fine. Let's go.
Okay, no.
Penny, Reynard is my problem.
We've been over this. Rapist
monsters are a universal problem.
Yeah, and the last
time you tried to help,
you signed, like, a billion-year
contract with The Order.
When does that
start, by the way?
Not today.
Takes them four weeks to
process a book request. Let's go.
(KADY SIGHS)
Um...
Where are we?
Penny. We've
processed your application
and would like to formally
welcome you to The Order.
Shit.
Congratulations!
(CLEARS THROAT)
Kady, we've allowed you here
to assist in Penny's transition,
but I'm afraid I'm
not allowed to discuss
the business of The
Order with you present.
Yeah, fine. I'll fuck off.
Ah, no eating or drinking in
the Library, except where posted.
Now, Penny, we need to go
over some of your obligations.
ELIOT: I just don't get it.
I mean, I did head off a famine,
personally staved off a war,
not to mention the
Wellspring is back online.
And yet the people don't like
me any more than they did.
How can you possibly know
what they actually think of you?
There's this Earth
Magician, Nate Silver,
I, uh, adapted one
of his polling spells.
Right now, my
approval rating is at 26%,
which is not good,
Bayler. Not at all.
But still, why ask me?
Mmm, I don't know.
I figured you might know
why they hate me so much,
seeing as you
tried to murder me.
Okay, that was before
I got to know you
and before you introduced
me to this Earth delicacy.
Nachos.
Wait till you try
your first margarita.
Mmm.
Listen, if you're really worried
about what the
people think of you,
let's talk about your
wedding. (GROANS)
Can we not?
Historically, a royal
wedding is the perfect time
for a monarch to make
their appeal to the people.
Idri prefers a private ceremony.
But what if you went public?
Might improve your polling.
One for $20, three for $50.
Which gets you the highest?
Highest?
This is grown locally
from heirloom seed stock,
paired with the ideal pastry
for a curated drug experience.
This will make you levitate.
This is like being
hugged by a rainbow.
This is like being blown by a
rainbow. Do not mix these up.
Yeah, I'll take six.
So the High King needs me?
Yes, he asked
for you specifically.
A command performance.
Righteous. (CHUCKLES)
How are... How are you doing?
The last time I saw you,
you weren't doing so good.
Whatever happened
with the whole, uh...
I let her go. I'm fine.
I've been self-medicating, so...
They don't have
Abilify in Fillory,
but I have been improvising.
Well, this is Doctor
Josh's prescription.
I mean, we don't have to race
off to Fillory right this second.
We have a minute. What's it do?
Dude, lets you see
into other worlds. It's rad.
(MUFFLED VOICES SPEAKING)
This is rad.
(GIRL HUMMING)
Is that you, Quentin?
Um...
You look familiar.
Holy shit, Julia.
Why do you look
like a 12-year-old?
Because I'm her Shade.
Oh, Q, I'm so happy
to see you again.
I really, really missed you.
Her Shade? I thought
that you were gone.
I'm lost. I can't
find my way home.
This is getting less rad.
Please, Quentin,
I've been looking for a way out,
and then suddenly
I could see you.
Yeah, you're in
another world. Um...
Where are you?
I have no idea.
I can't stay here. Time is
running out. Can you help me?
Yeah, I'll try. How
can I find you?
I don't know. I don't
even know how I got here.
Please, Quentin, I
have to get back to Julia.
You have to find me
before it's too late.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Holy shit, are we at war?
I wish we were at war.
These are the place
settings for the wedding.
Much more dangerous.
How's Josh doing in
the royal kitchens? Uh...
He's declared them adequate.
Eliot? I have to
go back to Earth.
Don't be ridiculous. You
have far too much to do here.
No, I had a vision, okay?
A way that I can
maybe help Julia.
I can't ignore it.
Can't you?
It was a motherfucking
vision, El.
Look, I don't know
how else to say it.
I feel like this is something
that I have to do right now.
I can see that.
Yeah.
If you miss my
wedding, I will kill you.
Okay. Okay.
Hey, uh...
Can you help me
find some information?
Of course. What
are you looking for?
Well, say you have a being with
an enormous amount of power.
I'm looking for how someone
might, you know, defeat them?
How much power?
Let's say, god-like?
So classical myths.
No. More like a how-to manual.
Let me check upstairs.
(HISSING)
So do we just wait?
Oh.
I'm afraid we don't
have any books available
on that particular topic.
There's nothing in the entire
Library of the Neitherlands
on killing any kind of god?
Have you considered that it might
not be strictly possible to do so?
Didn't the Norse gods kill
each other, like, all the time?
The Library is full of stories.
It happened. I know it has. In
Fillory, The Beast killed Umber.
That sounds fascinating.
Unfortunately, there is no
written record of the type you seek
regarding the mechanics of
such an event. Terribly sorry.
(SIGHS)
(SIGHS) Struck out looking
for a god-murder spell.
It can't be that no one
in all of history ever...
Well, apparently, no
one ever wrote it down.
(SIGHS) Look, if a
way exists, I'm finding it.
So what's up with your hands?
They told me there
are books to help me,
but I'd have to do the
research on my own time.
Seriously? What are you
supposed to do in the meantime?
My job.
Apparently, I track
down overdue books.
And this one has been
checked out for over 10 years.
You've got to be kidding.
Since I still can't cast,
I thought you could help me
out with a little locator spell?
(EXHALES)
(ELIOT CLEARS THROAT)
My King.
Hi, Fen.
Are you all right?
Yes, fine. How go the
wedding preparations?
Oh...
They're fine.
Is there anything
I can help with?
Is that something that you'd
actually want to help with?
You're acting like you
think I disapprove of it.
Your husband is about to welcome
another husband into his bed.
You're a king. Of
course you will.
I gather a three-person
marriage isn't normal on Earth.
Not outside of Utah,
or some websites.
Those are cities
made of pixels, right?
Close.
My mission, so
you understand it,
is to protect our
growing family.
Your marriage to Idri means a
stronger kingdom to raise our child in.
You're being way more
understanding about this
than I would be in your shoes.
That's my job.
Look, I'm gonna go talk to
my new royal chef. Care to join?
Thanks. I'm not feeling good.
Morning sickness. (CHUCKLES)
Mmm.
(GASPS)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(SIGHS)
Q, leave.
I'm not going anywhere.
Just open the door.
Fuck, I could've... I
could've killed you.
You know, I never
once stopped to ask
if I was doing the right thing.
And now it's all I ask.
"If I did this,
"would Q look at
me like I'm evil?"
Can't really feel
any of it anymore.
I'm doing it from memory.
I'm broken, and that
makes me dangerous,
so you should go.
Jules, I talked to your Shade.
Wait, so you saw her in a...
Yeah, uh, I mean, there were drugs
involved, but I know that it was real.
And she's still alive? Yeah.
Well, I don't really know if that
term applies here, but she's not gone.
So where is she?
I don't know,
but, wherever she is,
she wants us to find her.
ELIOT: What is this?
JOSH: Culinary classic.
Oysters and pearls
from the French Laundry.
I had to get Thomas
Keller so wrecked
before he showed me
the secret to that recipe.
Mmm.
I just don't think
it's Fillory enough.
But half of Fillory
eats boiled mutton.
Let's introduce them
to, like, actual food.
This is their world.
We have to meet them
halfway, don't you think?
Well, if half your
recipe is shit,
it's all going to
taste like shit.
Okay, okay. Fine, fine.
Forget the dish. (CHUCKLES)
Let's start with
what do you want
people to feel when they eat it?
I want everyone to like me.
Then let's just make this easy.
I'll make a potion.
Poof! They'll like you.
Donesies!
I need this.
There's nothing in here, either.
Got to keep looking.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
So scratchy.
Go away, Todd.
Stuff about the
afterlife is super-wonky.
It's too close to religion.
It's hard to figure out what's
not a flat-out lie. Right?
TODD: Hey...
Is this place real?
No.
You're hungover, Todd.
Look, I found a passage here.
Sort of vague, but
it mentions Shades.
One passage in a dozen books.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, Shades.
JULIA: I mean, it's something.
Nobody talks about Shades.
There's got to be a reason.
I know, right? I mean, when Fogg
talked about them the other day,
it was the first I
heard about them.
What?
My work study job,
I type up Fogg's memoirs.
I guess he has, like,
a crazy book deal.
He's led a seriously weird life.
Did you know that
he and Bob Ross
had a dark artistic
rivalry? I mean...
What did he say about Shades?
Something like he knew someone
who was obsessed with them.
DEAN: I do know
or, I suppose, I knew
someone who is
interested in Shades.
Was. Uh, it's rather confusing.
Confusing, why?
Because you know her, too.
It's Alice.
Honestly, I don't think that she
knew anything about Shades.
No, of course not.
That Alice didn't.
This Alice is a different story.
What do you mean, "this Alice"?
Do you recall the time
loop I told you about?
The 39 lifetimes? No one
remembers them except me.
Yeah, of course.
You knew another me.
The Alice from the 23rd timeline
was the sole
survivor of The Beast.
She became obsessed
with the afterlife,
how to commune with
lost souls and Shades.
Okay, well, would she
know where one would go?
I don't know what she knew.
She just talked about them a lot.
She was different
than your Alice.
She was hurt, broken.
We need to talk to her.
Well, you can't. It's
already happened.
Essentially, in
another universe.
It's gone.
What about a Tesla Flexion?
What is it?
It's how we could talk to her.
Can I ask you a woman question?
(SCOFFS) I barely
understand women.
I think my pregnant wife might be
having weird pregnant-wife feelings.
Ew.
Definitely not my rice bowl.
Seems like her head is
elsewhere all the time.
What do you mean?
Every time I run into her,
I feel like I'm interrupting
a conversation,
except there's
no one else there.
What is it?
Nothing. I'll talk to her.
(EXHALES) I need some air.
Yeah.
Fuzz Beat?
It's like a website.
They do serious news and
cat videos at the same time.
That's fucking dumb.
Well, it's where the
tracking spell said to go.
We're looking for Harriet?
And you are?
Just tell her we're
from The Order.
Is that the new Pilates place?
Yes.
Sweet.
Okay.
It's a fucking
unicorn in a tutu.
PENNY: We're here for the book.
Principles of Conjuring
Elementals. It's 10 years overdue.
Whoa! Whoa, whoa!
She's not casting.
She's signing.
Oh.
Yeah, I don't speak that.
She said we don't
look like Librarians.
All right, well, you know, tell
her we're looking for the book.
We need that book back.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Your sign is terrible.
Yeah, my sign is a little rusty.
(KADY LAUGHS) What'd she say?
Oh, don't worry about it.
KADY: So what's your deal?
You write listicles, and you
do magic in your spare time?
No, this is my magic.
What are you talking
about? Your clickbait site?
Yeah, right.
What the fuck is she saying?
See for yourself.
KADY: "Eighteen Pandas With
Things That Look Like Pandas"?
Half of those don't
even look like pandas.
PENNY: That's how
to conjure dark matter.
What did you do to the pandas?
It's an encoded spell.
All these articles are.
Wait. Wait. How about "Drunk
Guys Eating Kids' Vitamins"?
(LAUGHING) No! Really?
Oh, my God, that's...
Yeah, yeah, when you
guys are done bonding,
do you think you could ask
her for the book now, please?
Relax, kid. I'll find it.
(HARRIET EXCLAIMS)
Just give us a sec. (SIGHS)
So I don't get it.
Why do all this?
You're not wrong. (CHUCKLES)
Well, I was looking for
the kind of knowledge
the Library doesn't have.
Oh, the usual. Beauty tips,
recipes, how to kill a trickster god.
Ah.
Here you go. Finally. Let's go.
Have a nice day. Fuck off.
Thank you.
MARGO: Why am I staring at
a plate of half-eaten nachos?
A question I've asked
myself very often at 3:00 a.m.
So I was doing the dishes...
You're supposed to be cooking.
I know. I kind of
roofied the dishwasher.
Um...
That is not okay.
No! Not roofied, roofied.
More like he loves everyone
so much he's catatonic.
It was an accident. I was
testing the potion for you.
Might have made
it a little too strong.
Forget it. Doesn't matter.
The point is, I found this.
"Wedding day. Western gate
unguarded. Bring gifts there."
I'm assuming they're not
talking about actual gifts.
No, they're talking about
chopping our heads off.
(ELIOT GROANS)
That backgammon-playing prick.
(SIGHS) I was so stupid.
After all the hours I spent
down in the dungeon,
I actually thought
I'd won Bayler over.
I thought I had
rehabbed his soul.
Oh, honey, we both know rehab is
about more than nachos and backgammon.
Is it? Is it, Margo?
JOSH: Wait. So you're upset
because the guy
who tried to kill you
is gonna try and kill you again?
I should've executed him. It's
not like anybody likes me anyway.
I mean, I'm down 5%,
and now the FU Fighters
are gonna red my wedding.
No. Okay? We
won't let that happen.
Josh, where's that dishwasher?
Still in the armoire.
Why is he in the armoire?
Because I'm not
good in a crisis, okay?
How were you ever a drug dealer?
Look, that note was
meant for the dishwasher.
He's probably been
passing messages
to the FU Fighters
this whole time,
so here's what we do. We
help him sober up, and then...
We execute him.
No, but it means so much
to me that you want to.
We put the note back
in to the dirty dishes.
We let him find it, and take it
back to the FU Fighters' base.
Josh, how much of that
potion can you make?
I don't know. A buttload?
That'll do.
Bambi, what are you casting?
Tracking spell.
Then we'll know
exactly where to find
those Dave Grohl
wannabe bitches.
Got you. The FU
Fighters' encampment.
Okay, guys, here you go.
(SIGHS) It's a
shame, isn't it, El?
(SIGHS) Utter shame.
I mean, I can't be the one to
sneak into the FU Fighters' base.
Certainly not. You
don't sneak. Mmm-mmm.
And you can't be the
one to dump that potion
into whatever disgusting
stew they're cooking for dinner.
Sadly, no. My eminence is
too easy to spot from afar.
Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.
If only we had someone
they'd never seen before.
Guys, stop the bit. I'll go.
ELIOT: Eternal glory awaits
you, O Joshua of Yonkers.
Eternal glory.
You done?
I'm done.
Great.
Here's your overdue book.
Now, can you find me some
shit to help with my hands, please?
I will look for something to help
you with that in just a moment.
Are you okay?
Uh, hello?
I asked you a question,
man. Are you okay?
No.
I can't control my...
Look out!
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(STRAINING) No.
I can't stop!
(GRUNTING)
(SHATTERS)
(GROANS)
(EXHALES HEAVILY)
The card was cursed.
A Modus Hex.
It forces you to perform
an action against your will.
Yeah, but that dude
killed himself, okay?
The hex didn't make him do that.
His name was Howard.
And if it wasn't
for his bravery,
the hex would have forced him to
do something incredibly dangerous.
Open a door?
That isn't just any door.
Then what is it?
As a novice of The Order,
there are many secrets
that will be imparted to
you when the time is right.
I just watched a man kill
himself. What's behind the door?
The Poison Room.
The what?
It's where we store books
too dangerous for the public.
I suspect Harriet's curse was
an attempt to steal its contents.
Wait. Howard kamikazed himself
'cause someone wanted
some banned books?
That's pretty fucked-up.
What is (WHISPERS) fucked-up
is that there is
knowledge out there
so dangerous we
need a Poison Room,
so it doesn't fall
into the wrong hands.
That is why Howard
sacrificed his life.
It's something all
Librarians would do.
So he had to die to keep someone
from getting their
hands on what?
Some crazy battle magic?
There is knowledge
behind that door, Penny,
that could destroy
more than just people.
It could destroy worlds.
The Tesla Flexion has only been
successfully
employed once before.
Luckily, we're using
the original equipment,
left to Brakebills by
the man who invented it.
Nikola Tesla?
No, Fred Flexion.
Okay, and it's only been
used once before because...
Three people died trying
to shut it down last time.
What's the tent for?
The Flexion is a fold
between two different realities.
The tented area is
where they cross over.
Now, Ms. Wicker and I will
work together to cast the Flexion,
but if we hold it longer than
two minutes, we will all die.
Well, don't sugarcoat it.
Quentin.
Get the answers that
you need, and then get out.
Understood?
And try not to touch
anything in there.
Okay. Why?
Matter from different realities
occupying the same
space can create a paradox.
More like an explosion.
As well as a mess of
problems for the people
who'd find what's
left of our bodies.
Touch nothing. Got it.
Dude, their shit was
seriously jacked up.
Their K-holes
were inside K-holes.
Does that even make sense?
I'm just saying, the FU Fighters
are out-of-comish for
the foreseeable future.
Your wedding may
proceed apace, sire.
And you, good sir, may shave
any nymph in the kingdom.
Like, right now?
Like, right now.
You are my once and future king.
Just floating this.
Would it be weird
if I fucked Josh?
I certainly hope
it would be weird.
(CHUCKLING)
To my quick-thinking Bambi,
who saved the day again.
Speaking of saving the day, did
you ever manage to talk to Fen?
Um, yeah. She's fine.
Good. That's a relief.
MARGO: Fen?
Fen?
I wanna talk to you about
the terms of our deal.
(WHOOSHES)
Oh, shit. Shit.
You saw it? You saw it, too?
Fen. (SIGHS)
I'm not going mad.
Well,
no, you're not.
It was a Fairy, okay?
Look, the day the
Wellspring failed
I made a deal to save
Eliot's life, and you did, too.
I don't understand.
You agreed to do
whatever it took to save him.
But I didn't...
No. You did.
What do they want?
Your baby.
What?
Fen, I can stop this.
You better fix this because I
will not let them take my child.
Fuck!
(POWERING UP)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Quentin? Is that you?
You're in a Tesla Flexion.
I'm from another timeline.
We only have two minutes.
I need you to tell me everything
you know about Shades.
It is you. Another
you. You're alive.
Uh, no. Stop. We can't touch.
I'm sorry. We have to go fast.
I understand. Um...
I'll tell you everything
I know. It's just,
I thought I'd never
see you again.
The Beast, he tore you
apart piece by piece,
but not just your body
but your Shade, everything.
My Shade. Do you
know where it went?
I searched everywhere for it.
You can't rest in
peace without it.
But there are no books
on how to deal with it,
so I traveled the world in search of
anyone, anything that could help me.
What did you learn?
Shades go to the Underworld.
There's an Underworld?
It's only accessible to the
dead, but there's a catch.
Alice, what happened
to your hand?
It doesn't matter. It's the
least I gave up to learn this.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
The living can access the Underworld
with the help of a Gatekeeper.
A Gatekeeper?
An Ancient One, a being
older than the world itself.
Okay, how do you
find one of those?
I don't know. I'm still looking.
No.
(WHIMPERS)
I have to go.
Please. Please. Just
one more thing, okay?
We can't hold it
much longer, Quentin.
I just wanted to say I'm sorry.
Sorry for what?
When you died,
we weren't in a good place.
We were fighting, and I
was just too proud to let it go.
No. I don't know what
that other Quentin thought,
but, in this world, I love you.
Okay.
No matter what, I love you.
(SOBS)
(TESLA FLEXION POWERS DOWN)
Yeah, but Harriet didn't know
the guy was gonna kill himself.
Are you defending her?
No, I'm just saying that
she's not totally wrong.
The Librarians are
hiding some things.
Yeah, things that are
insanely dangerous!
They could have good reasons.
Okay, and who the fuck are
Librarians to decide who gets what?
Do you really want every hedge
witch with a grudge and a bad idea
to get a nuclear bomb?
Fuck you.
I'm not talking about you.
Yeah, you are.
No, I'm not.
I think we might be too late.
Motherfucker.
No.
No. No.
(SIGHS)
PENNY: The Ars Deicidium?
The art of killing gods.
(SOBBING) Eliot. Oh, thank God.
I don't know what to do.
Margo made a
deal with the Fairies,
and they're coming for our baby.
A deal's a deal.
(SOBBING)
You've been staring
at that page for an hour.
Uh...
I just keep seeing her face.
I get that you're hurting.
I don't know what to say
to make you feel better.
It's okay. I don't really
want to feel better anyway.
Maybe I'd better not
show you this, then.
I think I figured out
what an Ancient One is.
No fucking way.