Previously on "The Magicians"...
This contract initiates our
services in exchange for...
Unlimited manual
and magical labor?
You signed that insane contract?
- Yeah, it's okay.
- How the hell is that okay?
Because I get magic back.
Did you do this for me?
I'm Bayler, a proud soldier
of Fillorians United.
We will not rest until
a Fillorian sits
upon the throne.
The fairies can bring back
The Wellspring?
- They can.
- And in return?
A royal child of Whitespire.
We're getting married.
Apparently all monarchs are
entitled to one of each:
a wife and a husband.
Alice, I hope you meant it.
I hope you just go
and do beautiful magic.
Quentin says go free.
You fed him to Reynard.
He knew how to survive.
Yeah, by doing what you want.
That's all you see anymore,
is what you want.
You don't feel
anymore, Julia--
not the way a human does.
Do you remember the gift
that Jane was given in the book
"The Girl Who Told Time"?
Ember gave her the ability
to fuck with time
on a cosmic scale.
Jane used it to create
a time loop.
In each loop,
Jane alters something
to see if it'll
change the outcome.
What's different this time?
I was at Brakebills.
You were supposed to be.
Or you were, like, 39 times.
You were the thing they changed.
Very impressive, Ms. Wicker.
Let me do it again.
I was wondering
what would happen
if I connected the sequence with
Atsuko's Spectral Refraction.
All right.
That is a second year spell.
I--I read ahead.
More than that, you--
you understood the theory
behind the spell, and--
and you reshaped it.
Your discipline is
meta-composition.
You are a Knowledge student.
- Knowledge?
- Part psychic, part physical.
There really is no branch
it doesn't touch on.
The short version:
you are drawn,
mind and body,
to the discovery of magic.
Is it true that they--
um, well that we--
live in the attic
above the Library?
I assure you it is much more
luxurious than it sounds.
No, I mean, it sounds
like bliss, actually.
I enjoyed it.
You were a Knowledge student?
I am a Knowledge student.
It doesn't end with your degree.
You have a rare gift, Julia,
and I must admit I'm envious
of the many rich discoveries
that you have ahead of you.
Welcome.
Thank you.
You are free to go.
Why would you let me go?
Because, Ms. Wicker,
you are not a student here,
and I'm not running a jail.
Kady locked me up
for a good reason.
I should feel terrible
about what I did.
But I don't.
I just think it's terrible,
and I think I would've never
done it if I were me.
One thing I've learned
about you, Ms. Wicker,
is that you are a searcher.
You don't know me.
39 times I've known you.
Which is why I trust that
you'll put aside your fear
and self-pity
and look for the answers
that can save you.
Why am I the only one
worried about this wedding?
Congratulations.
You failed.
Oh, hey, hey, um,
King needs more wine.
Of course, sire.
I feel bad;
I forgot your name.
It's Smedley, sire.
Smedley.
Thanks, Smedley.
Hey. I'll take that.
Oh, no, wait, I'm--
I'm not done.
I think you were.
Not cool.
Those grapes died
for nothing now.
so you might live.
Because if you keep drinking,
I will seriously cut a bitch.
You never yell at Eliot
for being drunk.
Because Eliot's fun.
You're depressing.
It's been three months.
Technically, it's only been
a couple of days on Earth, so...
Three months on Fillory
of emo Quentin.
Not my favorite Quentin.
I didn't know that you liked
any of the Quentins.
I had to let Alice go.
I'm...
sympathetic.
Okay?
But meanwhile,
Groomzilla is suddenly
my full-time job.
I need your help.
Bambi!
This is an emergency.
These are all wrong.
You're banished forever.
Thank you.
He's just so mean
when he needs things.
Eliot needs a friend, asshole.
It's your turn to be button boy
and run his random
Earth errands.
I need a free moment
to rub one out in a hot bath
before I fucking kill someone.
That someone being you.
Message received.
And get your feet off my throne.
This is insane.
Why the fuck would Fogg
let Julia go?
Haven't you ever noticed?
Fogg isn't that helpful.
Plus, you knew he couldn't
keep her in there forever.
Yeah, well, I thought
she'd at least be in there
long enough for us to figure out
what to do next.
Where are you going?
I still have Reynard
to deal with.
And I really don't want
to run into Julia.
Fine, let's go.
Okay, no.
Penny, Reynard is my problem.
We've been over this.
Rapist monsters are
a universal problem.
And the last time
you tried to help,
you signed, like, a billion-year
contract with The Order.
When does that start,
by the way?
Not today.
Takes 'em four weeks to process
a book request.
Let's go.
Uh...
where are we?
Penny, we've processed
your application
and would like to formally
welcome you to The Order.
Shit.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Congratulations!
Kady, we've allowed you here
to assist in Penny's transition.
But I'm afraid I'm not allowed
to discuss the business
of The Order with you present.
Yeah, fine.
I'll fuck off.
Uh, no eating or drinking
in the Library
except where posted.
Now, Penny,
we need to go over some
of your...obligations.
I just don't get it.
I mean, I did head off
a famine--
personally staved off a war.
Not to mention, The Wellspring
is back online.
And yet the people don't like me
any more than they did.
How can you possibly know
what they actually think of you?
There's this Earth magician,
Nate Silver.
I adapted one of his
polling spells.
Right now, my approval rating
is at 26%,
which is not good, Bayler.
Not at all.
But still, why ask me?
Mmm, I don't know.
I figured you might know
why they hate me so much,
seeing as you tried
to murder me.
Okay, that was before
I got to know you.
And before you introduced me
to this Earth delicacy--
na-chos.
Wait till you try
your first margarita.
Mmm.
Listen...
If you're really worried about
what the people think of you,
let's talk about your wedding.
Ugh.
Can we not?
Historically,
a royal wedding is the perfect
time for a monarch
to make their appeal
to the people.
Idri prefers a private ceremony.
But what if you went public?
Might improve your polling.
One for $20, three for $50.
Which gets you the highest?
Highest?
This is grown locally
from heirloom seed stock,
paired with the ideal pastry
for a curated drug experience.
This will make you levitate.
This is like being
hugged by a rainbow.
blown by a rainbow.
Do not mix these up.
Yeah, I'll take six.
So the High King needs me?
Yes, he asked
for you specifically.
A command performance.
Righteous.
How are--
how are you doing?
The last time I saw you,
you weren't...
doing so good.
Whatever happened with
the whole, uh--
I let her go.
I'm fine.
I've been self-medicating, so--
uh, they don't have
Abilify in Fillory,
but I have been improvising.
Well, this is Dr. Josh's
prescription.
I mean, we don't have
to race off to Fillory
right this second.
We have a minute.
What's it do?
Dude, lets you see
into other worlds.
It's rad.
This is rad.
Is that you...
Quentin?
Um...
you look familiar.
Holy shit, Julia?
Why do you look
like a 12-year-old?
Because I'm her Shade.
Oh, Q, I'm so happy
to see you again.
I really, really missed you.
Her Shade?
I thought that you were gone.
I'm lost.
I can't find my way home.
This is getting less rad.
Please, Quentin.
I've been looking for a way out,
and then...
suddenly I could see you.
Yeah, you're in another world.
Um...
where are you?
I have no idea.
I can't stay here.
Time is running out.
- Can you help me?
- Yeah, I'll try.
H-how can I find you?
I don't know.
I don't even know
how I got here.
Please, Quentin.
I have to get back to Julia.
You have to find me
before it's too late.
Holy shit, are we at war?
I wish we were at war.
These are the place settings
for the wedding.
Much more dangerous.
How's Josh doing in
the royal kitchens?
Uh...
he's declared them "adequate."
Eliot, I have to go
back to Earth.
Don't be ridiculous.
You have far too much
to do here.
I had a vision, okay?
A way that I can
maybe help Julia.
I can't ignore it.
Can't you?
It was a motherfucking
vision, El.
Look, I don't know
how else to say it.
I just--I feel like this
is something that I--
I have to do right now.
I can see that.
Yeah.
If you miss my wedding,
I will kill you.
- Okay.
Hey, uh, can you help me
find some information?
Of course.
What are you looking for?
Well, say you have a--
a being with an enormous
amount of power.
I'm looking for how
someone might...
you know, defeat them.
How much power?
Let's say...
god-like?
So classical myths?
No, more like a how-to manual.
Let me check upstairs.
So do we just wait?
Oh.
I'm afraid we don't have
any books available
on that particular topic.
There's nothing in the entire
Library of the Neitherlands
on killing any kind of god?
Have you considered that it
might not be strictly possible
to do so?
Didn't the Norse Gods kill
each other, like, all the time?
The Library is full of stories.
It happened.
I know it has.
In Fillory,
The Beast killed Umber.
Sounds fascinating.
Unfortunately, there is no
written record
of the type you seek regarding
the mechanics of such an event.
Terribly sorry.
Struck out looking
for a god-murder spell.
It can't be that no one
in all of history ever--
Well, apparently,
no one ever wrote it down.
Look, if a way exists,
I'm finding it.
So what's up with your hands?
They told me there are
books to help me,
but I'd have to do the research
on my own time.
Seriously? What are you
supposed to do in the meantime?
My job.
Apparently, I track down
overdue books,
and this one has been checked
out for over ten years.
You got to be kidding.
Since I still can't cast,
I thought you could help me out
with a little locator spell?
My King.
Hi, Fen.
Are you all right?
Yes, fine.
How go the wedding preparations?
Oh... they're fine.
Is there anything
I can help with?
Is that something that you'd
actually want to help with?
You're acting like you think
I'd disapprove of it.
Your husband is about to
welcome another husband
into his bed.
You're a king.
Of course you will.
I gather a three-person marriage
isn't normal on Earth?
Not outside of Utah.
Or some websites.
Those are cities
made of pixels, right?
Close.
My mission,
so you understand it,
is to protect our
growing family.
Your marriage to Idri means
a stronger kingdom
to raise our child in.
You are being way more
understanding about this
than I would be in your shoes.
That's my job.
Look, I'm gonna go talk
to my royal chef.
Care to join?
Thanks.
I'm... not feeling good.
It's morning sickness.
Q, leave.
I'm not going anywhere.
Just open the door.
Fuck, I could've--
I could've killed you.
You know, I never--
I never once stopped to ask
if I was doing the right thing.
And now it's all I ask.
If I did this,
would Q look at me
like I'm evil?
I can't...
really feel any of it anymore.
I'm doing it from memory.
I'm broken.
And that makes me dangerous.
So you should go.
Jules...
I talked to your Shade.
Wait, so you saw her in a--
Yeah, uh, I mean,
there were drugs involved.
But I--I know that it was real.
And she's still alive?
Yeah.
Well, I don't really know
if that term applies here,
but she's not gone.
So where is she?
I don't know.
But wherever she is,
she wants us to find her.
- What is this?
- Culinary classic.
Oysters and pearls
from the French Laundry.
I had to get Thomas Keller
so wrecked
before he'd show me
the secret to that recipe.
Mmm.
I just don't think
it's "Fillory" enough.
But half of Fillory
eats boiled mutton.
Let's introduce them to,
like, actual food.
This is their world.
We have to meet them halfway,
don't you think?
Well, if half your recipe
is shit,
it's all going to taste
like shit.
Okay, okay.
Fine, fine.
Forget the dish.
Let's start with, "What do you
want people to feel
when they eat it?"
I want everyone to like me.
Then let's just make this easy.
I'll make a potion.
Poof!
They'll like you!
- Donesies!
- I need this.
There's nothing in here either.
Got to keep looking.
So scratchy.
Go away, Todd.
Stuff about the afterlife
is super wonky.
It's too close to religion.
It's--it's hard to figure out
what's not a flat-out lie.
Right?
Hey, is this place real?
No.
You're hungover, Todd.
Look, I found a passage here.
Sort of vague,
but it mentions Shades.
One passage in a dozen books?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, Shades.
I mean, something.
Nobody talks about Shades.
There's got to be a reason.
I know, right?
I mean, when Fogg talked
about 'em the other day,
it was the first
I heard about 'em.
What?
My work study job--
I type up Fogg's memoirs.
I guess he has, like,
a crazy book deal.
He's led a seriously weird life.
Did you know that
he and Bob Ross
had a dark artistic rivalry,
and--
What did he say about Shades?
Something like he knew someone
who was obsessed with them?
I do know--
or I suppose I knew
someone who was
interested in Shades--
was.
Ah, it's rather confusing.
Confusing why?
Because you know her too.
It's Alice.
Honestly, I don't think that
she knew anything about Shades.
No, of course not.
That Alice didn't.
This Alice is a different story.
What do you mean "this" Alice?
Do you recall the time loop
I told you about?
The 39 lifetimes?
No one remembers them except me.
Yeah, of course.
You knew another me.
The Alice from the 23rd timeline
was the sole survivor
of The Beast.
She became obsessed
with the afterlife,
how to commune with lost souls,
and Shades.
Would she know
where one would go?
I don't know what she knew.
She just talked
about them a lot.
She was different
than your Alice.
She was hurt--broken.
We need to talk to her.
Well, you can't.
It's already happened.
Essentially in another universe.
It's gone.
Well, what about
a Tesla Flexion?
What is it?
It's how we could talk to her.
Can I ask you a woman question?
Ugh. I barely
understand women.
I think my pregnant wife
might be having weird
pregnant wife feelings.
Ew.
Definitely not my rice bowl.
She just seems like
her head is elsewhere
all the time.
What do you mean?
Every time I run into her,
I feel like I'm interrupting
a conversation.
Except there's
no one else there.
What is it?
Nothing.
I need some air.
Fuzzbeat?
It's, like, a website.
They do serious news
and cat videos at the same time.
That's fucking dumb.
Well, it's where the tracking
spell said to go.
We're looking for Harriet.
And you are?
Just tell we're from The Order.
Is that the new Pilates place?
- Yes.
- Sweet.
That's a fucking unicorn
in a tutu.
We're here for the book.
"Principles of Conjuring
Elementals."
It's ten years overdue.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
She's not casting.
She's signing.
Oh.
Yeah, I--I don't--
I don't speak that.
She said we don't
look like librarians.
All right, well, you know,
tell her we're looking
for the book.
We need that book back.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Your signing is terrible.
Yeah, my signing's
a little rusty.
- What'd she say?
- Uh, don't worry about it.
So what's your deal?
You write listicles, and you do
magic in your spare time?
No.
This is my magic.
What are you talking about?
Your clickbait site?
Yeah, right.
- What the fuck is she saying?
- Shh.
See for yourself.
"18 Pandas With Things
That Look Like Pandas"?
Half of those don't
even look like pandas.
That's how to conjure
dark matter!
What did you do to the pandas?
It's an encoded spell.
All these articles are.
Wait, wait, how about--
how about "Drunk Guys
Eating Kids' Vitamins"?
No! Really?
- Oh, my God, that's--
- Yeah, when you guys
are done bonding, do you think
you could ask her
for the book now, please?
Relax, kid.
I'll find it.
Oh.
Mm!
Just give us a sec.
So I don't get it.
Why do all this?
You're not wrong.
Well, I was looking
for the kind of knowledge
the Library doesn't have.
Oh, the usual--
beauty tips, recipes,
how to kill a trickster god.
Ah.
- Here you go.
- Finally.
Let's go.
- Have a nice day.
- Fuck off.
Thank you.
Why am I staring at a plate
of half-eaten nachos?
A question I've asked myself
very often at 3:00 a.m.
- So I was doing the dishes--
- You're supposed to be cooking.
I know. I...
kind of roofied the dishwasher.
Um, that is not okay.
No, not "roofied" roofied.
Uh, more like he loves
everyone so much,
he's catatonic.
It was an accident.
I was testing
the potion for you.
Might have made it
a little too strong.
Forget it.
Doesn't matter.
The point is, I found this.
"Wedding day.
Western gate unguarded.
Bring gifts there."
I'm assuming they're not talking
about actual gifts.
No.
They're talking about
chopping our heads off.
Ooh.
That backgammon-playing prick.
Ah! I was so stupid.
After all the hours I spent
down in the dungeon,
I actually thought
I'd won Bayler over.
I thought I had
rehabbed his soul.
Oh, honey.
We both know rehab is about more
than nachos and backgammon.
Is it?
Is it, Margo?
Wait, so you're upset because
the guy who tried to kill you
is gonna try and kill you again?
I should've executed him.
It's not like anybody
likes me anyway.
I'm down 5%.
And now the Fu Fighters
are gonna red my wedding!
No.
Okay? We won't let that happen.
Josh, where's that dishwasher?
Still in the armoire.
Why is he in the armoire?
'Cause I'm not good
in a crisis, okay?
How were you ever a drug dealer?
Look, that note was meant
for the dishwasher.
He's probably been passing
messages to the Fu Fighters
this whole time,
so here's what we do.
We help him sober up,
and then--
We execute him.
No.
But it means so much to me
that you want to.
We put the note back
into the dirty dishes.
We let him find it and take it
back to the Fu Fighters' base.
Josh?
How much of that potion
can you make?
I--I don't know.
A buttload?
That'll do.
Bambi, what are you casting?
Tracking spell.
Then we'll know exactly
where to find
those Dave Grohl-wannabe
bitches.
Gotcha.
The Fu Fighters' encampment.
Okay, guys, here you go.
Aw, it's a shame, isn't it, El?
Utter shame.
I mean, I can't be the one
to sneak into
the Fu Fighters' base.
Certainly not.
You don't sneak.
Mm-mm.
And you can't be the one
to dump that potion
into whatever disgusting stew
they're cooking for dinner.
Sadly, no.
My eminence is too easy
to spot from afar.
Hmm.
If only we had someone
they'd never seen--
Guys, stop the bit.
I'll go.
Eternal glory awaits you,
O Joshua of Yonkers.
Eternal glory.
You done?
I'm done.
Great.
Here's your overdue book.
Now can you find me some shit
to help with my hands, please?
I will look for some thing
to help you with that
in just a moment.
Are you okay?
Uh, hello?
Uh, I asked you a question, man.
- Are you okay?
- No!
I can't control my...
look out!
No!
I can't... stop!
The card was cursed.
A Modus Hex.
It forces you to perform
an action against your will.
Yeah, but that dude
killed himself.
Okay? The hex didn't
make him do that.
His name was Howard.
And if it wasn't
for his bravery,
the hex would have forced him
to do something
incredibly dangerous.
Open a door?
It isn't just any door.
Then what is it?
As a novice of The Order,
there are many secrets
that will be imparted to you
when the time is right.
I just watched a man
kill himself!
What's behind the door?
The Poison Room.
The what?
It's where we store books
too dangerous for the public.
I suspect Harriet's curse was an
attempt to steal its contents.
Wait, Howard kamikazed himself
'cause someone wanted
some banned books?
That's pretty fucked up!
What is...
fucked up is that there
is knowledge out there
so dangerous we need
a Poison Room
so it doesn't fall
into the wrong hands.
That is why Howard
sacrificed his life.
It's something all
Librarians would do.
So he had to die to keep
someone from getting
their hands on what?
Some crazy battle magic?
There is knowledge
behind that door, Penny,
that could destroy more
than just people.
It could destroy worlds.
The Tesla Flexion has only
been successfully employed
once before.
Luckily, we're using
the original equipment,
left to Brakebills by
the man who invented it.
Nikola Tesla?
No, Fred Flexion.
Okay.
And it's only been used
once before because--
Three people died trying
to shut it down last time.
What's the tent for?
The Flexion is a fold between
two different realities.
The tented area is where
they cross over.
Now, Ms. Wicker and I
will work together
to cast the Flexion,
but if we hold it longer
than two minutes,
we will all die.
Well, don't sugarcoat it.
Quentin...
Get the answers that you need,
and then get out.
Understood?
And try not to touch
anything in there.
Okay. Why?
Matter from different realities
occupying the same space
can create a paradox.
More like an explosion.
As well a mess of problems
for the people who'd find
what's left of our bodies.
Touch nothing.
Got it.
Dude, their shit was
seriously jacked up.
Their K-holes were
inside K-holes.
Does that even make sense?
I'm just saying, the Fu Fighters
are out of "comish"
for the foreseeable future.
Your wedding may
proceed apace, sire.
And you, good sir, may shave
any nymph in the kingdom.
- Like right now?
- Like right now.
You are my once and future king.
Just floating this:
would it be weird
if I fucked Josh?
I certainly hope
it would be weird.
To my quick-thinking Bambi,
who saved the day again.
Speaking of saving the day,
did you ever manage
to talk to Fen?
Um, yeah.
She's fine.
Good.
That's a relief.
Fen? Fen!
I want to talk to you about
the terms of our deal.
Oh, shit.
- Shit, shit--
- You saw it?
You saw it too.
Fen!
I'm not going mad.
Well...
no.
You're not.
It was a fairy, okay?
Look, the day
The Wellspring failed,
I made a deal to save
Eliot's life.
You did, too.
I don't understand.
You agreed to do whatever
it took to save him.
But I didn't.
Well, you did.
What do they want?
Your baby.
- What?
- Fen...
I can stop this.
You better fix this, because I
will not let them
take my child.
Fuck.
Quentin?
Is that you?
You're in a Tesla Flexion.
I'm from another timeline.
We only have two minutes.
I need you to tell me
everything you know
about Shades.
It is you.
Another you--you're alive.
No, stop.
We can't touch.
I'm sorry.
We have to go fast.
I understand.
Um...
I'll tell you everything I know.
It's just...
I thought I'd never
see you again.
The Beast, he--
he tore you apart
piece by piece,
but not just your body,
but your--your Shade,
everything.
My Shade.
Do you know where it went?
I searched everywhere for it.
You can't rest in peace
without it.
But there are no books
on how to do...
so I traveled the world in
search of anyone, anything,
that could help me.
What did you learn?
Shades go to The Underworld.
There's an Underworld?
It's only accessible
to the dead.
But there's a catch.
Alice, what happened
to your hand?
Doesn't matter.
It's the least I gave up
to learn this.
The living can access
The Underworld
with the help of a Gatekeeper.
- A Gatekeeper?
- An ancient one.
A being older than
the world itself.
Okay, how do you find
one of those?
I don't know.
I'm still looking.
- I have to go.
- Please, please--
just one more thing.
We can't hold it
much longer, Quentin!
I just wanted to say I'm sorry.
Sorry for what?
When you died,
we weren't in a good place.
We were--we were fighting,
and I was too proud to--
to let it go.
I don't know what that
other Quentin felt,
but in this world, I love you.
Okay.
No matter what.
I love you.
Yeah, but Harriet didn't know
the guy was gonna kill himself.
Are you defending her?
No, I'm just saying that
she's not totally wrong.
The Librarians are
hiding something.
Yeah, things that are
insanely dangerous.
They could have good reasons.
Okay, and who the fuck
are librarians to decide
who gets what?
Do you really want every
Hedge Witch with a grudge
and a bad idea to get
a nuclear bomb?
Fuck you.
I'm not talking about you.
Yeah, you are.
No, I'm not.
Think we might be too late.
Motherfucker.
No.
No, no...
"The Ars Deicidium"?
"The Art of Killing Gods."
Eliot?
Oh, thank God.
I don't know what to do.
Margo made a deal with
the fairies and they're
coming for our baby.
A deal is a deal.
You've been staring
at that page for an hour.
Oh.
I just keep seeing her face.
I get that you're hurting.
I don't know what to say
to make you feel better.
It's okay.
I don't really want
to feel better anyway.
Maybe I better not
show you this then.
I think I figured out
what an Ancient One is.
No fucking way.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com