ELIOT: Previously
on The Magicians...
Alice, whose house
is this, exactly?
Alice.
Hi, Dad.
You know how I feel about "Mom."
Fine. Stephanie.
Ugh! I just feel like I'm
being pulled back into this
version of me when I was, like, 12
and furious and invisible and mute.
You cure your
own hands just fine,
but mine you can't do a
fucking thing about, huh?
There are other options.
You can travel to Fillory.
Go there. Get this.
I do what I can.
You may address me
as Reynard the Fox.
JULIA: Reynard is
targeting Hedges.
There was a girl.
Forty years ago, she
banished Reynard from Earth.
I still don't know
what I'm looking for.
JULIA: Any sort of
strange event or aberration.
(COUGHING)
DR. HIGGINS: The
test was positive.
Fuck!
KADY: Yeah, so let's just get
this pesky abortion out of the way.
Kady!
(GASPS) (SCREAMS)
I'm Bayler, a proud
soldier of Fillorians United.
I'm not a FU Fighter anymore.
Help us, or I go to your king and tell
him exactly how well I know his wife.
Then I'll tell him myself.
What's she doing?
She can't, she'll Niffin out.
(SHRIEKING)
ALICE: Your turn.
Quentin says go free.
MARGO: Alice!
(GROWLS)
(ALICE SHRIEKING)
(MOUTHING) Help me.
ELIOT: Um...
Remind me again what summoning
Alice's Niffin has to do with the...
Tai chi?
I mean, ballet.
Ugh. Oh...
God, he should never
do that move again.
MARGO: It's Niffin bait.
You have to call to them at
their point of their transformation
with something personal.
Oh.
It's a sex thing.
No, it's Cirque Du Soleil.
You know Cirque Du Soleil?
You and Alice had
sex to Cirque Du Soleil?
No, it was something I
would do to cheer her up
when she was sad.
It made her laugh.
Oh...
That just made my
heart hurt a little.
Shut up. I was being sincere.
ELIOT: Does he have the box?
I mean, what if
this actually works?
Yes, but be warned, he
wants to try to reason with her.
She was working on
some sort of reversal spell.
He thinks he can
somehow finish it.
He's convinced she
wants him to. Oh, Jesus.
Okay, I'm starting
over. No, Q, stop.
If Alice was still a Niffin,
if she was still here...
You've been at this an hour.
You can't summon
her because she's gone.
It's just that I saw
her. It felt so real.
Why don't we get you
back to the castle, huh?
Some rest, some food.
And hey, there's an entire kingdom's
worth of problems to distract you.
We really are beset
and could use your help.
I hear you. I just...
Good. Vámonos.
QUENTIN: Her
memorial is tomorrow.
I should go and look
her parents in the eye,
tell them how she died.
And then...
I'll come back to Fillory,
and I'll be a king. I promise.
Can I trust you with this? No offense,
Q, you're a little crazy right now.
Maybe. But yeah.
(SIGHS)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(GOAT BLEATING)
Ah, the sacrifice.
The plinth is in the backyard.
Follow me. Just watch the rug.
Daniel reconfigured the
entire house, and still,
everywhere I look, I see
something that Alice touched.
My children loved me.
I was a good mother.
WOMAN: You were,
Stephanie, you were.
So much better than
my mother. Of course...
What have I done
to deserve this?
(WOMAN SOBBING)
Um...
Hi.
Alice?
Alice...
Are you really there?
(SNIFFLING)
Okay.
You're kind of freaking me out.
I mean, I love you, but you're very
ghost-like right now, so... (SNIFFLES)
Okay.
I can't.
Okay, okay...
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
No.
Eliot and Margo
are right. You're...
She's gone, and
you're a little crazy.
(LOCK CHIRPS)
Or not.
Alice.
(KNOCKING)
Yeah, okay.
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
Just don't jump out at me, okay?
DANIEL: Quentin?
Is that you?
Uh, Sorry, Mr. Q...
Uh, Daniel. Sorry.
Give me a hug.
How on earth did you
get into my private study?
Uh...
There's something going on.
KADY: Yeah.
Yeah, I got it.
Tell her I'm Hannah's daughter,
and this is an emergency.
Can you just tell her
to call me, please?
Hey. Hey.
Uh, I mixed up your
dose. It's on the counter.
(KADY SIGHS)
To all the heroin
I am not taking.
Cheers.
Did you get the
pickles? Mmm. Yup.
You found something.
August 19th, 1976, 7:00 a.m.
An unseasonal hailstorm hit the
Northeast. Nothing too crazy, right?
An hour later, a tidal
wave slammed into Miami.
Hour after that, hurricanes struck
both the coasts of Peru, Chile.
I mean, something rippled
down the entire hemisphere,
and if you follow the chain
reaction back to its source...
Hoboken, New Jersey?
Nothing ever starts in
Hoboken, New Jersey.
Well, on August 19th,
sometime before dawn,
this happened.
Industrial park
burned to the ground.
No one could explain
what caused the fire,
or why it left one single
building standing untouched
with a perfect circle
of burn around it.
Thank you. Mmm-hmm.
Mmm-hmm. Next.
Eliot, I need to talk
to you. Oh, thank you.
It's about that FU
Fighter in the dungeon.
What the actual
all-encompassing fuck is this?
Your Majesty, you said you
wanted a unicorn milk latte.
ELIOT: I was joking.
Wait, you milked a unicorn?
So listen, about Bayler...
Holy shit, the walking
plot twist returns.
Hi, I need something. Shocker.
Hey, Fen, look who
it is. Unky Penny.
That's right, I knocked
her up. No big deal.
Congratulations?
Like I needed more
people calling me Daddy,
but yes, thanks. We're thrilled.
Uh...
Fen, um, could you give us
just like one moment, please?
Hmm.
Yeah, so I'm here...
I heard...
You heard...
Alice. I know you
two were close.
Please shut up.
I am trying to ask
if you are okay.
Are you okay?
Okay.
I need to know where your
Dicranium Scoparium Majorus grows.
Are you having a seizure?
Moss? Why?
Fix my hands.
You got a royal
botanist or something?
Oh, well, um, we did,
but apparently he sort
of got eaten on the job.
By what? A plant? (CHUCKLING)
(SIGHS)
I hate this place.
Try the royal map-maker.
Love ya.
So she's only shown
herself to me that I know of.
I don't know.
Maybe I'm tuned into her
ghost channel or something, or...
Maybe it has something
to do with this. I don't know.
I believe you.
You do?
I know my daughter.
She's trying to protect us.
Seeing her like that would be very
upsetting for her mother and me,
but she led you
to this for a reason.
Alice called a
couple of months ago
about some ghost children
trapped in an estate in England.
The Plover Estate.
Yes, yes, that's the one.
I was delighted to
help. Got a hold of this,
planned to give it to her when
she had the time to visit, but then...
Well, anyway, you
see, the ancients had
many ways of dealing with
ghosts out of necessity back then.
Alice's Ka, her soul,
is not at rest, but it can be.
Now, one ancient
civilization that really mastered
the whole getting-one's-
soul-to-rest thing...
The Egyptians.
Wait, are you saying that
Alice wants us to build...
Ecce.
In pyramis.
ELIOT: Oh, my God.
What's going on?
Just another day in the office?
(FANFARE PLAYING)
PICKWICK: Your Majesties,
the much-venerated emissaries
of our neighbors to the north.
I present Prince Ess of Loria.
ELIOT: I'm sorry...
Princess?
Please, call me Ess.
Prince Ess.
(CHUCKLES) Oh, my God.
Fuck your parents, dude.
ESS: We've got a problem.
You guys have been fucking
shit up for over half a century.
Okay.
This is how Lorians
talk? ESS: And look...
(WHISPERING) The
Prince speaks fluent Earth.
Rumor has it his mother
is from, uh... Cincinn-ah-ti.
Oh...
until The Beast
drained the Wellspring.
And then, oh, yeah...
You jokers let Ember take
a dump... Get to your point.
Loria depends on the
Wellspring's tributaries,
but now their magic's
jacked. Not enough.
Crops, rivers, entire
species are affected.
You dicked us over. No.
We're trying to fix it, so...
Great, then this should be easy.
I'm here to propose a treaty
between our two kingdoms.
A 50-50 split of the Wellspring.
(COURTIERS MURMURING)
And to seal the alliance,
I, Crown Prince of Loria,
offer my hand in marriage
to the Virgin Queen Margo.
Um... (SNICKERING) Okay.
Did he just call me a
virgin? Bambi, please, let me.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Ess, thank you.
We will consider
your generous offer.
No, we will not.
Margo, please.
Listen, Prince Ess,
I'm not a sharer,
so why don't you walk
yourself and your un-ironic furs
out of my castle?
All right then.
Plan B. Ilario!
Seriously? A wand?
MARGO: Guards!
(RUMBLING)
Listen, I'm friends with
the High King, okay?
I'll make it worth your
while if you just show me
where the goddamn moss grows.
I told you,
I'll draw your
map for you next...
(RUMBLING)
PENNY: (SOFTLY) Shit.
Oh, this is bad.
This is very bad.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Do you understand that
castle's full of people?
Do you understand there
isn't a single accurate map
of this entire place now?
(ENERGY CRACKLING) What the...
Shit is radioactive.
Your Majesties,
welcome to Loria.
What? Oh, my God!
You kidnapped our castle?
ESS: I'll put it back,
as soon as you come
around to my offer.
So many hostages.
I wouldn't try
anything if I were you.
Guards? Dungeon.
The rest of you, hang here.
MARGO: Shit.
Shit.
ELIOT: Okay, okay, okay, okay.
I'll jump in the doppelbanger,
and I'll find someone
who can... What?
Travel here and help? Yes.
Q took the button to
some godforsaken 'burb.
No, you're not leaving me in a
castle full of barbarian frat bros.
Okay, fine, but while
we're talking about them,
you could've been
a little diplomatic.
By agreeing to marry a
complete stranger on the spot?
I did it.
That was different.
(SCOFFS) You're right, this
would only really be equivalent
if Ess was a girl, and you
found pussy, you know,
interesting in a "sometimes
you like Thai food" kind of way,
and now it's all Thai
food forever till you die.
No, he's a man,
who seems arrogant and entitled
and unclear on the
concept of consent.
I can't imagine what
could possibly go wrong.
Look, I'm not
saying do it. It's just...
You're a queen. I'm a king.
We don't necessarily
marry for love.
It's part of the job.
Fine, I'll talk to him,
but only to negotiate us
out of this epic clusterfuck.
I'm staying a virgin.
JULIA: Forty years ago, everything
burned down except this building.
Wait a minute.
Here.
Okay.
No way is this
sigil 40 years old.
I mean, hardly anything
stays hot that long.
Yeah, except blood. Human blood.
And if that's what it is,
it's the DNA of whoever cast
the banishing, so let's hope, right?
Yeah.
How long does it take?
It should work right away.
It's been decades.
I mean, whoever did the
banishing could be dead by now.
Well, they're probably dead.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
Oh, shit, it's her.
It's my mom's contact.
Hey, head home, wait, okay?
I gotta go.
She can help with
the baby situation.
Hello? Good.
The pyramids of Giza
provide an excellent blueprint,
specifically the one Khufu built
to house the soul of his son,
Kawab, valiantly slain in battle.
Yes, here.
Ow.
Quentin, let's, uh...
Let's not bring
Stephanie into this just yet.
It's too much for her.
Listen, Daniel, I thought
maybe you'd wanna hear about
what happened
to Alice. Uh, no...
A blood relative must coax the
spirit with a bit of mirror magic.
Look into the mirror,
paint a true image of the
deceased with my words.
But first...
Ah...
Quentin,
uh, you go up, hang the mirror.
Oh, and, uh...
First, uh, memorize this.
Recite it when you're up there.
This looks like
Arabic, but not...
Yes, Egyptian Arabic.
Huh? Okay... (STAMMERING)
Well, my Egyptian
Arabic is a little rusty.
No, you'll be fine.
Just whatever you do,
don't let the mirror shatter.
I've already enchanted it.
Now...
We've only got one shot.
Well, then Daniel, I
think that you should do it.
You do it. No. I mean,
if it's that important...
No, Quentin, please. Just you.
Yeah.
Give me a minute with this.
Oh, my God.
There you are.
Who are you? (GASPS)
Why did you follow me?
Hi.
My name is Julia.
I need your help.
It's Reynard. He's back.
How?
Look, it's a long
story. It was a mistake.
He hurt you too, didn't
he? Okay, I'm sorry.
I'm... I cannot help you.
What? Wait, I am pregnant.
He... Don't worry,
the thing will never be born.
I don't care if I have
to jump off a building.
But I cannot let him do
this to another woman.
You banished him once.
All I am asking is for you
to teach me how to do it.
I think you better come inside.
Oh! Shit.
(PANTING)
Well... Alanis Morissette.
Alice loved that cat.
Okay, but why...
I've always had a
terrible fear of heights.
One day, Alanis Morissette
got stuck on the roof.
Alice begged me to get
her down, but I couldn't,
and honestly, I yelled at her,
because sometimes that is what
one does when one is ashamed.
And the cat...
It did not end well.
I don't know if Alice
ever forgave me
for not being brave enough.
Maybe she will now.
No, Daniel, you don't have
to do that. Look, I can do it.
No, I can do it.
For Alice.
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING, SIGHING)
There.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
Oh!
Whoa, whoa! Ow.
Daniel.
(MEN LAUGHING) Yeah, right?
And then they came across.
MARGO: Hey.
Are you kidding me?
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
So...
When's the wedding?
If we forgo the marriage,
I'm willing to grant you periodic
access to the Wellspring...
You think this is a negotiation?
No marriage, no treaty...
No castle back.
Okay, Conan,
let me explain to you how
marriage works where I come from.
Oh, spare me. I know.
My mother shipped me
off to Exeter when I was 16.
You?
Fancy New England
boarding school?
Had a dorm full
of future senators
convinced I was an
exchange student from Iceland.
Point is, I get it.
I'm shockingly progressive
for a Lorian. (SCOFFS)
We get married, I'd still
let you speak in public.
I'd make sure that you...
Jesus, I'm not marrying you.
You think I wanna
marry a virgin?
This is purely
political. Oh, my God.
I'm not a virgin.
Look, I've had
the best in Loria,
and Lorians are the best.
Hmm. So either way,
you're a virgin to
me, sweetheart.
I'm not your sweetheart,
and I'm certain that
I can bang circles
around your boring
little Lorian hoes,
'cause I'm a very smart,
very liberated woman,
and when I set my
mind to something,
I master it.
And you've mastered what?
Never touching a man?
Not touching, touching...
I'm good at both.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Oh... You want me to stop?
Say it, or I'll stop.
Don't stop.
Beg me.
I like you.
ELIOT: So you waited until now
to tell me about you and Bayler?
I've been trying to tell you.
It's been a little insane today.
I'm not trying to keep secrets
from you. That's my point.
Eliot, please understand.
I had a life before you came.
I had no idea if you
even would come.
Fillory is my home,
and I care about it.
So you became a terrorist?
(SIGHS) We're not violent.
I'd call your ex-boyfriend
trying to strangle me
a little bit violent!
He's not my...
We were close, yes,
but hurting people
was never the plan.
I have no idea who
you are. I'm your wife.
Because your father made you.
I could've walked out of here
a long time ago.
Then why didn't you?
If you hate us so much,
if you hate me so much,
why didn't you? Because I don't.
I believe in you.
You think I stayed
because you're just so
deeply attracted to me?
I am a realist who
wants you to succeed.
I want us to.
(SIGHS) So what
am I supposed to do
with your good friend
in the dungeon, huh?
You should keep him there.
I don't think you can trust him.
Do you think I can trust you?
DANA: I was 21.
It didn't seem so
crazy back then to think
I could summon the
goddess, do good.
Yeah, that's what I wanted too.
I couldn't get rid
of the baby either.
What?
I wasn't the only one
he raped that night,
but I was the only
one who got pregnant.
So what did you do?
I tried everything.
I even thought
about killing myself,
but I couldn't go
through with it.
You had it?
I'd rather die.
(SIGHS)
I want to help you, Julia.
I can't banish Reynard again,
but you can.
JULIA: Where's
your cat? DANA: Oh!
He's around here
somewhere. Come on.
Follow me.
You just wait right here, honey.
So sorry about this.
(JULIA GRUNTS)
(DOOR OPENS)
Late, Ms. Hanson.
Sit, you have 10 minutes
to complete your midterm.
Midterm?
But... But I haven't studied.
Even I studied, and I'm dead.
Forgot your clothes too?
Typical. (STUDENTS LAUGHING)
Margo? Hey... Whoa!
I swear I was gonna study. What?
No, no, it's me.
It's actually me.
Oh, God.
Oh, God, I'm asleep.
Uh, yeah, you must not
be in imminent danger
if you're napping,
wherever you are.
Kidnapped, along
with the entire castle.
Yeah, I know, there's a
crater. Where are you?
Loria.
Some canyon with these
purple-ish rock things.
Rock things? What...
Dicks, okay? They look
like dicks. (PENNY LAUGHS)
Uh, full-sail or half?
Honestly, it's a
variety pack out there.
Okay, I got it. I'll find you.
And, Penny, if you ever
tell anyone you saw this...
Ooh, oh, no, no, no.
No, I'd never. I, uh...
I'd much rather have
you owe me huge.
(GASPS)
ESS: Scouring the
room for a weapon?
You have a look in
your eyes, that's all.
It's called resting bitch face.
The Cock Barrens of Loria.
Okay. Show me where.
There. Right there.
Look, I know this isn't gonna
make anything any better.
I want you to know
that Alice died a hero.
It's funny. These
stories we tell.
Hmm? (CHUCKLES)
You'd rather break
both of your legs
than have a conversation
with me about this.
I can't stand to think about it.
Do me a favor,
and get me a tall glass of
whatever looks strongest.
You're on a lot of painkillers.
My daughter is dead.
Let me guess... God!
My husband said
don't bother me, because
I'm too crazy right now.
Come on.
We gonna finish this or what?
Yeah.
(COUGHING)
What... What is... (SHUSHING)
What is that?
Don't be scared.
I don't know what you
want from me, okay?
Okay. I want you to start
by understanding something,
and I don't expect you
to like the idea of this,
but you're going
to have that baby.
What?
What the... That is insane.
Believe me, I know,
but that little demigod
growing inside of you
is like a tiny nuclear reactor.
You have one chance to harness
that power when you give birth.
Then I don't want that power.
Yes, you do,
because that's how
I banished Reynard,
and that's how you'll do it too,
while in labor with his child.
No!
Not your choice anymore.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
Thank you.
Kady, they may be able to
help your friend with her problem,
but listen, I would never
ever do business with them
if I had a choice.
Be careful with people
like this, Maminka.
You don't want to wind
up like your mother.
Thanks.
(BOTH SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(CALL RINGING)
(ON RECORDING) This
is Julia. Leave a message.
Shit.
This place is warded up the ass.
(SCREAMS)
Shit.
Um...
Thank you?
You're trapped
here too, aren't you?
(KNOCKING)
(GRUNTS)
So...
If I had this baby,
would it be like...
(LAUGHS) That's not my baby.
That's my Haxenpaxen.
What?
My Haxenpaxen. I caught it.
Smells unfortunate,
but just imagine
what it's giving off magically.
Not even a
trickster can find us.
We're invisible
while we're near him.
Do have to occasionally stock
up on food and kitty litter, though.
How you found me, I suppose.
So if that's not your child...
My child is safe.
He'll never know
who he really is.
He doesn't even know
who I am. I made sure of it.
It's for the best.
He's a good man, Julia.
An influential man.
(MAGIC CRACKLING)
Kady!
Your magic is no good here.
What?
Oh, God, what's with
Stink-master Flash?
Free him too. He's
coming with us.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Must've been some negotiation.
Say I did marry him...
Say I... Stop,
forget what I said.
This whole marriage
thing is absurd.
You have no idea
who the other person is.
It's dangerous. If it's
that bad, have her killed.
I can't.
We just made a human together.
And the worst is, between
the whole lying back
and thinking of Fillory,
I started to actually like her.
El, what's going on?
One life-altering
crisis at a time.
What do you wanna
do about the princess?
It's your choice.
I just want what's best for you.
Hey!
I went to the exact spot.
No castle, nothing there.
It has to be some other dongs.
There are no more dongs.
That's the only spot
the castle could be.
Yeah, well, it doesn't
make any sense unless...
(CHUCKLES)
God, please don't let
me be wrong about this.
You guys have been
so royally fucked with.
You won't believe where
you've been this whole time.
QUENTIN: Okay.
Now you only get one shot, okay?
So, remember, you
have to tell the truth.
I've got this, Quentin.
Relax. Okay.
(EXHALES)
(INHALES AND EXHALES LOUDLY)
STEPHANIE: Alice...
She needed a strong
female role model.
She was so lucky
to have me for that.
You have to tell the truth.
But that is the truth.
Alice was complicated.
She never figured out
how to be a woman.
That's not the
truth, not for Alice.
Don't be ridiculous. This is
just Alice up to her usual tricks.
She was always so hard on me.
This is not about you.
Will you just for
once in your life
put yourself in your
daughter's shoes?
What do you want me to say?
(SOBS) That I never
understood her?
And that I never really tried?
I didn't know having a
daughter would be this hard.
I resented her sometimes. I...
(STAMMERING)
I just need a minute. No.
No.
Come on, we've gotta
finish it. Stephanie!
(SIGHS)
Ugh.
Idiot.
I cast a Niffin summoning
and you didn't come.
How? Why?
You're wrong.
I was right there.
Oh, Quentin.
We're gonna have so much fun,
just like we did
with my parents.
Hmm.
I killed you. My cacodemon...
Your cacodemon wasn't
powerful enough to kill me.
It tried, but when it
saw that it couldn't win...
Well, let's just say it stuffed
me in a place most convenient.
That stupid tattoo
trap on your back.
We're stuck with each other.
Oh...
Oh, God.
No, no, no.
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
(REYNARD LAUGHS)
(GASPS) Oh, God.
Too slow. Sorry.
(SNIFFS DEEPLY)
Dana. In the flesh.
I'd heard you were dead.
You hid well. I'm impressed.
What happened? You slipped up.
(GASPS)
I think you have
some apologizing to do.
Don't you?
I have reached my decision.
I will marry the Prince
of Loria, on one condition.
I want a tour of his
kingdom right now.
Wedding first, then a tour.
Last tree, and done.
Oh, no.
No, no, no.
This is the worst
day of my life.
I know, right?
Crazy illusion magic.
So, hey, what do you
think about making that...
Map.
You drew it for me.
Yes.
I made an exception.
Thank you.
You're still bat
shit crazy, man.
I heard that.
Margo, please.
You fucked with us.
Mmm-hmm. Yes, you did.
You fucked with our castle.
Amen, sister.
And now we're gonna
put our Jimmy Choos
so far up your ass, you're
gonna taste next season.
Exactly, whatever that means.
Because the High King and I hereby
declare war on the Kingdom of Loria!
Yes!
Wait...
Really?