QUENTIN: Previously
on The Magicians...
KADY: Everett's trying
to squeeze out hedges.
This is just more of the same.
We're here to study
with Mayakovsky.
We hear he's crazy.
MAYAKOVSKY: You heard wrong!
JOSH: So wait.
So you turned
Mayakovsky into a bear?
I can help.
Just let me stay.
You saved my life. You
can save my life 50 times.
It's not gonna change
anything between us.
Goodbye, Alice.
The Poison Room. It's where we
store books too dangerous for the public.
You must seek the Binder.
ALICE: This was
in the Mirror World.
And I heard you were
looking for the Binder, so...
Holy shit.
Foremost saved them
with special weapons
that expel possession.
They call them ice axes,
and I'm assuming
that's poetic license.
MARGO: So we might
have a chance to save Eliot.
MARGO: But Hot and
Dumb just wasn't getting it.
And that's when I
told the Foreskin,
"Welcome to the
New Desert Order.
"It's gonna suck for you."
Wow. You really went
through a lot to get those axes.
Call them by their names.
Sorrow,
and Sorrow. JULIA: Nice.
Where'd you get the axes from?
Fine. I'll tell it
one more time.
So I'm all, "Welcome to the New
Desert Order. (DOOR OPENS)
"Gonna suck for you." (GASPS)
PENNY 23: What's gonna suck?
MARGO: Telling
this story over again.
And so I was like,
"Welcome to the New Desert
Order. Gonna suck for you."
What did I miss? I'm
getting a smoothie.
You fuckers take this.
QUENTIN: You seriously... You
spent that much time in the desert,
and this never occurred to you?
We're dealing with
god-level monsters.
Who possess people.
Those axes pull the spirits out,
and then we bottle them up. Bam!
FTW.
All he's saying is
they're too powerful.
I doubt your bottles
can hold that shit.
Those monsters are
coming for us. Make it work.
Okay, but how?
We could cast an incorporate
bond on the bottles.
Thank you.
I don't know what that
is, but I hate you less now.
It's a way to pin a
being or object in place.
It's like a fourth-dimensional
paperweight.
Mayakovsky was trapped
under one for years.
We just need to pin The
Monster to your bottles
long enough to get rid of them.
Great. Let's do that shit, then.
So who knows how to
cast an incorporate bond?
I did cast an incorporate
bond on Mayakovsky,
but I didn't write
the spell myself.
So who wrote it?
Mayakovsky did.
He didn't know I was
going to use it on him.
He was the only person
capable of writing a spell
which he couldn't break.
He knows more things
about incorporate bonds
than anyone else does.
You wanted a spell
to trap a god, yes?
Well... He's the real expert.
But he's also a
bear. Not exactly.
You see, once magic came back,
he was able to become human. Again.
Much to his wife's dismay.
So where is he now?
He went back to
Brakebills South?
MARGO: I mean, why?
Brakebills isn't using it.
There's not enough magic
for the geese to make it.
I found that out the hard way.
Rest in peace, first years.
So, I guess we have to go down
there and talk to Mayakovsky?
Sounds like a plan.
You two have fun
talking to that old drunk.
No.
Wait. Margo, Margo, hey.
I just... I... There's, um...
Things are still kinda weird
between me and Alice, and I just...
Mmm-hmm, and I'm still rinsing
desert sand out of my twat, all right?
I'm not going to
fucking Antarctica.
Grow a pair of tits, Coldwater.
(WIND HOWLING)
ALICE: Jesus, it's cold.
I forgot my scarf, so...
Good luck with that.
(ZIPPING)
If it makes you feel any better,
I don't wanna be alone with
you, either. I never said that.
Yes, you did. I heard
you say that to Margo.
Let's just not start
by lying to each other.
Okay. Look, I don't
want to be here,
but we're here, so
let's just get it over with.
Quentin.
(SIGHS) Shit.
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
Professor.
Mayakovsky.
(YELPS)
Professor?
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
ALICE: Mayakovsky
did this to himself.
He designed a spell to swap
his present consciousness
with one from a different time.
He called it a timeshare spell.
(SNORING)
QUENTIN: So that's
not our Mayakovsky?
Not mentally, no.
Based on these notes
and his current state,
I think he's from
the future, where...
Mayakovsky has dementia.
Great. (SIGHS) Well,
it was an accident.
He inverted two of the
numbers in the spell.
(SIGHS) So, how do we undo it?
He's the only one who can.
I don't think we can
help him, Quentin.
We may have hit a dead end.
Unless I talk to
him in the past.
You wanna steal Everett's
book from the Poison Room?
It's the only way we can
get ahead of him, but...
I need your help.
Penny died 'cause of
going in there, so... No.
I can get us in
and out unharmed,
but protocol dictates
Librarians enter the
Poison Room in pairs.
For safety.
Fogg can do it.
Unfortunately, I
cannot leave Brakebills.
The Library has been up my ass.
They're even
threatening to put monitors
in all my classrooms.
Henry has a point. It
would draw undue attention.
Oh, to the fact that
he's a fucking coward?
You don't get to be a
Magician my age, dear,
without a very healthy
sense of self-preservation.
ZELDA: Kady.
Please.
JULIA: I mean, if
this is a real language,
it is a dead one that
nobody's ever written about.
Well, maybe it's not a language.
Maybe it's... (INHALES SHARPLY)
Ow! Goddamn paper cut!
(GROANS)
Cocksucking book bit me.
It did!
Why is this book suddenly blank?
Hey, wait a minute.
Is that writing there?
I can barely make it out.
My God. I think it's
written in Margo's blood.
It wants blood, I got blood.
BRB.
Is that... Yep.
It's shark week. You
can thank my uterus later.
JULIA: This is in Latin.
I can't cast. Um, you
better have a look at it.
Oh... (CLEARS THROAT)
Oh, come on!
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING LATIN)
(RUMBLING)
(MAN GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
(PANTING)
And the Binder
stood before them,
and as they stared,
eyes full of wonder,
the Binder thought to himself...
"Took you long enough."
(SIGHS)
KADY: He's in there? ZELDA: Yes.
And he's at an acquisitions
meeting, which should give us
enough time to copy it.
EVERETT: Okay, thanks.
Check back with me later.
Everett. Zelda.
ZELDA: How was the
meeting? Detailed. I snuck out.
What are you doing here?
I was hoping we could talk.
In your office, perhaps.
Of course.
(SIGHS)
The Binder knew Julia
had many questions.
She'd been searching in vain
for how to reacquire her divinity.
He knew the answer.
Hey, what's with
all the third-person,
past-tense bullshit?
The Binder had no idea
what she was talking about.
Hmm.
The Binder explained
he had answers,
but it would require they
learn how he came to be.
To be...
The Binder felt dizzy.
His book was a...
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Oh, it was somehow...
It was somehow...
Missing pages.
PENNY 23: I think he's broken.
The fuck?
When did this happen?
I don't know.
He was talking
normal a second ago.
Normal for him. My God.
What the hell?
(LOCK CLICKS)
JOSH: Fen? Tick?
Guys, the weirdest
thing just happened.
I was eating a
biscuit, not off the floor,
and I had a kind of vision.
Still good.
(WIND HOWLING)
Last looks.
CREW MEMBER: Eating
Out with Josh Hoberman.
Scene one, take one. Marker.
I'm eating what?
But no one in Fillory has a TV
so why am I questioning this?
Action!
(LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING) Any
baker worth their gluten knows a biscuit
is only as good as its flour.
Add a drizzle of
lavender-infused honey,
and trust me, you'd
eat this right off the floor.
(MUSIC STOPS)
The Winds of Fate. They've
come unseasonably early this year.
I think this is a sign
that Fillory's in trouble.
Early Winds of Fate, Lorian
plants silencing the animals,
too many questing creatures.
Seriously, it sounds
like Fillory's ecosystem
is completely jacked
and not in a sexy way.
Interesting you should say that.
Not long ago, we
imprisoned a Naiad
for committing moderate acts of
violence against some farmers.
She deboned one of them.
Really great
knife skills. Jesus.
PICKWICK: Anyway, I
recall her saying something
about Fillory's
failing ecosystem,
but she was covered in guts,
and that's really hard to get past.
Been there. Get
that Let's talk to her.
Okay.
Hello, Ismenie. I brought
you some visitors today.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(HISSING)
Oh, God!
Am I the only one getting The
Ring/Grudge-type vibes here?
She's a Naiad.
Why do you dry-skins torture me?
I came to you with a warning.
Yes, yes. You also
attacked several farmers.
That was my warning.
They were stealing my water,
an assault on my very soul.
She protects a well.
What if your blood
lived outside of your skin
and thoughtless things
drank it, bathed in it, peed in it?
Yes, well, I'm afraid we have
a few questions we need to ask
about Fillory's ecosystem.
I told you all before,
it is The Waters.
They are moving.
It is the fault of
the Thirteenth.
The Thirteenth.
ISMENIE: The thirsty Thirteenth.
He tried to capture
us, dam us in.
Water should flow free.
What he built, there
is no excuse for it.
What did he build?
We're done here, dry-skins.
No, we are not done here!
(ISMENIE HISSING)
ALICE: Once you're there,
you can't do anything or say
anything to anyone that'll...
Risk changing the past.
I get it. I've been
to the movies.
This is serious, Quentin.
The bridge between your past
self and your present self is...
Is delicate. If you break it...
Look, as long as you wipe
past me's memory, we'll be fine.
ALICE: I have a memory
charm ready to go.
(SIGHS)
We'll set the spell
so it takes you back
to where we were
at Brakebills South.
Just go straight to
Mayakovsky's office
and don't talk to
anyone. I won't.
Alice? How did I get up here?
(DOOR OPENS)
Alice, I...
Oh, um...
Oh, God. Alice...
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
(CHUCKLES) (GROANS)
Mmm-mmm.
Alice, wait. No,
I just have to...
What's wrong?
No, no, no. It's fine.
Mmm-mmm.
No, I just... I got to...
What did I do?
You? No, no, it's
me. I'm the problem.
I, um...
Just... I forgot condoms.
So I'm just gonna...
QUENTIN: What am
I doing on the table?
Just stand still.
Whose clothes am I wearing?
Shit, there's no more magic.
Alice, what's going on?
How did we get here?
Uh, I heard that
sometimes Mayakovsky
randomly teleports
students to the lab for testing
to keep us on our toes.
Uh, okay, I hadn't
heard that, but...
No, no, it's a real
thing that he does.
Uh, look, there must
be some sort of test.
Um...
Knots.
Yeah, we need to
tie these into knots
for magic purposes,
like, for sure.
All right, I guess that
could be worse. (SIGHS)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
Yes?
(RINGING CONTINUES)
(SIGHS)
(CLEARS THROAT) Hello?
Oh, thank Christ. I
didn't think I'd get through.
The phones here work off of
GPS coordinates, not numbers.
Well, you were close.
Listen, I don't
have a lot of time.
We need your help.
Surviving first-year students...
(CLEARS THROAT) I'm here
(CLATTERS)
to teach you
what not to do. (CHUCKLES)
Let's begin with a
cloaking spell, shall we?
Which, unfortunately,
you will never do
because the Library,
they don't want you to know it.
(ALL GASPING)
DEAN: Did you see
that? (CHUCKLING)
Now forget it,
because if you learn it,
you'll be in very,
very serious trouble.
(OBJECTS CLATTERING) Damn it!
Good God!
Cock shit!
EVERETT: Surely
you didn't come here
just to gossip about Phyllis.
You don't think her perfumes
are a danger to the books?
I think she smokes and
doesn't want anyone to know.
But we all do.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
It's good to see you smiling.
Been worried about you.
You seem distant lately.
I wondered if something
had happened.
If anything were
wrong, I'd tell you.
You would.
Well, I'm here for you.
You know that, right?
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Yes?
Sorry to interrupt, but
there has been an incident.
It's Fogg.
Perhaps it's time for
someone to talk to him
who isn't a friend. Of course.
Thank you for the tea. Mmm-hmm.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Where the hell did Margo go?
JULIA: I thought
she came in here.
What's with the honeymoon suite?
Huh, that was, uh...
(ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
You didn't do that, did you?
I can't do that.
(OBJECTS RATTLE)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Okay, seriously?
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
PENNY 23: Margo?
Margo?
Some weird-ass ghost
shoved me in a closet.
Yeah.
I can see your non-corporeal
panty-sniffing ass
with my goddamn fairy eye.
Ghost? Or whatevs.
He keeps shaking his head.
I can't hear you.
Keeps pointing at
you for some reason.
HYMAN: Penny 23. (LAUGHS)
Isn't this just berries?
(EXHALES)
I'm here because you
changed my life, Penny.
I mean, not you, Penny
40. But basically you.
When he died/became
my astral best friend...
Yeah, I seriously
doubt that. Oh, my.
You sound just like
P-40 right now. Whoa.
Can we get to the
part where you explain
why you're here, please. Welp.
You guys are my
favorite characters.
Only you disappeared.
So, I left Brakebills to
find out what happened.
And when I did, hoo-boy,
this plot was a mess.
You mean my life?
And I realized,
I'm done watching.
I want to participate.
And you... The other you...
Great twist... Showed
me how to do that.
Turns out I can be stuff
at a level I never
imagined possible.
Is that why Margo
is tied up in a closet
and you're lighting
candles, playing sexy music?
(CHUCKLES)
(MIMICS TONTO)
Patience, Kemosabe.
I'll get there.
Yeah, that's offensive.
(IN NORMAL VOICE) But
I thought you were Indian?
What? Anyhootch,
I had a thought.
I... I mean, in my day, you two
would sip a little giggle water
and get a wiggle on,
but instead we're just...
Waiting. Yawn.
You mean all this insane
shit that is happening
is to get me and
Julia to hook up?
I mean after that little
naked interlude in Fillory...
You watched that? Yeah.
I know a true thing when I
see it, buster, and you're it.
Listen, Hyman, if you stole
the pages from the Binder,
we need them back. Now.
Or I will sic Margo on you.
Maybe I overstepped,
but you just gotta understand I
see what you and Julia keep doing
and I worry about
the both of you.
What are we doing?
You both sacrifice your
own joy to help others.
Julia gave up all
that power, and you...
I mean, other Penny
died because of it.
Yeah, when I think
about it, it's a sad twist.
You can't blame me for wanting
the two of you to be happy,
because you will
never do it for yourself.
Hey, wet 'n' wild, you said
everything's the fault of the Thirteenth
But all mention of him has
been stricken from the archives.
I'm not a conspiracy theorist,
but I'm workin' on a theory
there might be a conspiracy.
Somebody erased
this guy magically.
But you know his
name, don't you?
I will not speak it.
PICKWICK: Oh, yes, you will.
Wait, what are you doing?
I went all the way to your well,
and if you don't tell us
what we need to know
I am going to drink it and
then I'm going to pee it
and then Josh is
going to drink it.
Yeah! Wait, what?
You monster! Tick,
you can't do this.
Dude, yeah, that's
sort of like torture.
I thought we were against that.
We are. She's the only
one who knows the name
of the Thirteenth King
and she is gonna tell us!
Please, please! You can't.
No! (SCREAMING)
Ram's bottom, what was it?
The Thirteenth,
the Thirteenth...
It's Roderick!
"Thirsty Roderick,
"thirteenth of his line, always
liked to have a good time."
Oh, my God, you're right.
About what? FEN:
A nursery rhyme.
I've been trying to
remember it all day.
We used to sing it
while playing Bearskip.
It's a children's game, sort
of like Fillorian hopscotch.
Involving bears?
Ideally skipping them.
"He hides his drink from
his many daughters."
"Builds a cistern to
hoard the waters."
"Underneath the castle fair."
BOTH: "If you jump,
you'll skip the bear!"
Okay.
Your nursery rhyme
used the word "cistern"?
Well, how else are
children supposed to learn
about underground water
containment systems?
You people are sick. Wait.
He built underground
water containment systems?
Ismenie, you said, "The
Waters, they are moving."
But were you really
talking about water?
She's always
talking about water.
Unless she's
talking about magic.
A huge reservoir of magic,
hidden underneath the castle.
That could be what's causing
all the stuff we're seeing.
Wait, wait. (SIGHS)
I think I know how
we can get to it.
Follow me!
Okay.
ISMENIE: God, it hurts!
MAYAKOVSKY: An incorporate bond?
Why do you suddenly
need to know this?
Uh, it's just something that
I've been wondering about.
You're serious?
You could be having fox sex with
your partner, the better Magician.
I realize that.
She could do incorporate bond.
And she's chosen to have
sex with you for some reason.
You should be having as
much sex with her as you can
before she realizes.
Thank you for the
relationship advice,
an area that I'm sure
that you are an expert in.
Oh, little pushback
from B-minus student.
I like this. I'm just saying,
there is something that
you are an actual expert in
that I need to
know about. Right.
You "need" to know how
to cast an incorporate bond.
(SIGHS)
What is your discipline? What?
Your discipline,
B-minus student,
or did you leave that
back in your tiny fox pants?
They tested me.
(SIGHS) Inconclusive.
Well, that is a problem.
Can't cast incorporate
bond without your discipline.
There's got to be some
kind of workaround.
Nope.
Come back when
you're fully formed.
Come on. There's got to be
something that you can do.
I need this.
Fine. Drink that.
This will help
with the test or...
It will kill brain cells. I
have plenty to spare.
You don't, but...
I don't want to drink alone.
KADY: (SIGHS)
So this is it, huh?
Before we go in, there's a
small matter of protection.
Swallow it. Well, what is it?
Insects.
Don't chew. They
have to go down whole
so they can eat any poison
you take into your bloodstream.
(SIGHS)
(COUGHS)
(INSECTS BUZZING)
The bugs only last an
hour, so we need to be quick.
(QUENTIN GROANING)
MAYAKOVSKY: There is
something you're not telling me.
What? No, that's not true.
You're a very bad liar, B-minus.
More like D-plus on this.
(MAYAKOVSKY GRUNTS)
And I don't have
to tell you anything
until you tell me
what you're hiding.
It's complicated.
You're from future, yes?
What?
What is in there is older
than what is in there.
Yeah. Yes, fine. I am.
I... Not me, me, but
my consciousness.
I came here to ask you
about incorporate bonds.
Why didn't you ask
me in your time?
I am dead or something?
No. Look, I can't tell
you anything else.
I can't risk messing
with the past.
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
I've seen Back to the Future.
(GROANS)
You want to fuck
your mother in past?
What? No. Why?
She not attractive?
Look. I just can't tell you any
more about how I did this...
I already know. You
use timeshare spell.
I've been working on it.
Clearly I must have finished it.
And don't worry.
Future is safe.
Everything you
say is in the vault.
This vault.
I will definitely not remember
anything about this conversation
like most conversations
I have with students
like you, D-plus.
(SIGHS)
(WRITING)
This basis for incorporate bond.
We are done here.
You never told me my discipline.
Repair of small objects.
Really?
Hope we did not ruin
your big plans after you get
back to your mysterious future,
Mr. Time Traveler.
Tell my older self...
"Well done."
Um...
(SIGHS) Shit.
(SIGHS) Alice.
What the hell, Q?
What did you cast?
Some sort of spell to
make your future self
take over your past self's body?
What happens that
made you have to do this?
I can't tell you that.
Well, can you talk about
what's happening with us?
Of course you can't.
Paradox rules apply.
I can't risk changing the past.
I could get lost forever.
I could do a
memory charm. Alice.
I know one that will erase
my memory for the last hour.
(SIGHS)
Okay. Yeah, sure.
Why?
So we can talk about
the way you looked at me
when you came back.
There was so much
pain.
A lot of things have happened.
How bad?
Pretty goddamn bad.
What happens?
You, uh, get hurt.
We both do.
So would you rather
I just stop this now
so that we never have
to feel the way you feel?
Look, you're a nice guy,
Q, for trying to warn me.
I'm not trying to...
But I'm not scared
of the future.
I'm scared of losing this.
Maybe it's crazy and
hopeless where you live,
but, you know, maybe
I never told you this,
but you are the best thing
that's ever happened to me.
(SIGHS)
So,
when you go back,
just remember that, okay?
QUENTIN: What do you think
made Mayakovsky so bitter?
Huh? And, like, obsessed
with the vulpine sex
of his two students?
Yeah, it's weird, isn't it?
No, no, it's totally
normal. He's a normal guy.
These are normal school
situations. (CHUCKLES)
Seriously, though, you
think that he would notice
if we stopped tying these knots?
Probably. We shouldn't.
Hey.
Crazy idea.
What if we stopped tying
the knots and instead we...
(MOUTHING)
Hmm?
(CHUCKLES) Um... Hmm?
Ooh, yeah. We could
do it on the table.
(OBJECTS CLATTER) Quentin!
I don't... It was
hotter in my head.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Hmm? Oh.
Sorry, Vix. You okay?
Yeah, no. I'm fine.
Yeah, you are. (CHUCKLES)
That was nice.
Alice. Yeah?
Uh, it's me. I'm... I'm back.
Oh...
(GASPS)
The Binder's story
began in a place
known simply as
the Library.
You were a Librarian?
He did say it
started in the Library.
I mean, it's fucking obvious.
He was studying
the limits of power.
His specialty was the
magic inherent in gods.
PENNY 23: Great. A puppet show.
THE BINDER: The
Binder had a theory.
When a being of great
power, such as a god, is killed,
their energy is lost, but he
believed it could be preserved
by binding it to an object.
That object, in
turn, could be bound
to a Magician of sufficient
training and preparation,
effectively turning the
Magician into a god.
Yeah, but every time a
mortal tries to kill a god,
all magic gets shut off.
The Binder politely
reminded Margo that
not every story was about her.
So the Binder is a catty bitch?
(GROANS)
He continued.
It was a problem that perplexed
the Binder and his
fellow Librarians,
but, as it turned out,
the old gods themselves
provided a solution.
Two siblings. Mistakes.
Born with the
power of many gods.
They were created
with one unique quality
that made them essential
to this experiment.
They could not die.
So no matter what you did
to them, it wouldn't trigger
the old gods to take away magic.
Without fear of the
old gods' retribution,
The Librarians were safe to
move forward with their experiment.
One of the Monsters
was captured,
the older, more
dominant one. The female.
Natch.
The one left behind
would be confused,
afraid, like a child.
Without his sister, he'd have
trouble even remembering them.
What did you do to the sister?
She was split into four parts.
Each part bound in a stone.
Each stone bound in a Librarian.
Bacchus. Iris. Heka. Aengus.
Those ballsacks.
When they were finished,
the Binder came to
regret what he had done.
But the new gods he had
built were afraid of him.
He alone held the secret that
could make them human again.
And so...
They cursed him.
JULIA: They turned
you into a book.
Okay. That does kind of
suck. (THE BINDER SIGHS)
In that form, he became
something they could control.
Hide from the rest of
The Order, from history.
It was only by chance that a
young Librarian read his book
and was convinced
to hide the Binder
in the Mirror World,
where he hoped no
one would find him again.
Until word reached the
Binder of Julia Wicker,
and her quest.
He knew he had the
answers she sought.
So you can help me
become a goddess again?
He could take her
in either direction.
The godhood, or humanity.
The choice was hers.
Either road would be painful.
He wondered aloud
if she was ready.
You and me both.
The Binder knew she needed
time to consider which way to go.
But either way,
he'd need a favor in return.
He needed her to burn his book.
He did not want
to be used again.
Like he was before.
(SIGHS)
I got it.
Do we have time for that?
ZELDA: First thing you learn in
The Order is how to speed read.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Everett's been
lying to all of us.
It's just as we suspected.
He's been hoarding magic.
To do what?
To become a god.
And if this book is correct,
he succeeds.
The floor in this
hallway is laid out
in the exact pattern
of a Bearskip board.
Now, that can't just
be a coincidence.
Can't it though?
Just jump forward three squares.
Okay.
Not the dragon!
Watch the sloth! (GROANS)
Now duck. Duck?
There's a bear on
your right. Seriously?
That one got my leg. Okay!
Oh, no. Don't get me, bear!
Because you successfully
"skipped the bear,"
you get to throw the sweetberry.
And I throw it at
the last whatever?
The hibernation square.
Okay. Jeez.
(SIGHS)
Oh, yes! You did it.
Huh.
That is still good. (BLOWS)
I say what again?
(GROANS) Oh,
right. Right, right.
Honey or die!
(FEN GASPS)
(PICKWICK GASPS)
JOSH: Where does it lead?
Only one way to find out.
Seriously?
ZELDA: Perfect timing.
We should return right
between shift changes.
That's good.
Is it weird I've had this
chocolate taste in my mouth?
As the bugs absorb more
poison, the aftertaste changes.
It's when you taste
mint we're in real trouble.
Okay.
(DOOR RATTLES)
(SIGHS)
It's locked.
Don't you have the key?
The key is for the other side.
Someone locked us in.
I have worse news.
I just tasted mint.
Hmm.
You think Hyman is right?
What he said about us?
God, I don't know if that
man has any fucking clue
what's going on, but maybe.
'Cause I've been thinking
about becoming a goddess a lot.
How to do it without screwing
up like the other gods did.
I don't know.
Maybe I should give some
airtime to the alternative.
Becoming human?
I mean being happy.
Okay.
Pros and cons. You
become a goddess,
you get all powered up.
Maybe help in the fight.
You become human...
I get to feel things.
Yeah, like hunger.
And sadness and... And this...
Was that a pro or a con?
(CHUCKLES)
I have a problem.
She's dying.
Who's dying?
My sister.
I found her a body,
but it's not strong enough.
I need to find one
that is more durable.
Like yours.
(GRUNTS)
So, Mayakovsky told you
what your discipline is?
Repair of small objects.
You did always excel
at minor mendings.
I always thought it'd
be something cooler.
At least it's real.
Now you don't have to fantasize
anymore about who you are
and lie about who
you wish you were.
You just know it now.
And maybe you've
always known it.
Show me.
(SIGHING)
How does it feel?
Like I helped it wake up
and remember what it was before.