In 2166, an immortal
tyrant named Vandal Savage
conquered the world and
murdered my wife and child.
I have assembled an elite team
to hunt him throughout time
and stop his rise to power.
Unfortunately, my plan is opposed
by the body I'd sworn
my allegiance to:
the Time Masters.
In the future, my friends
may not be heroes,
but if we succeed,
they will be remembered as legends.
Previously, on "Legends
of Tomorrow"...
The Time Masters discourage marriage,
but I fell in love and
we had a child, Jonas.
- Maybe we could get a drink?
- Are you asking me out?
Yes. Is that okay?
I think my life's complicated enough
without throwing whatever
this is into the mix.
- This is Star City.
- Yes, Star City, 2046.
It's everything we've ever wanted.
We could live like kings here.
[grunting]
You son of a bitch.
You lay a hand on me
again, you'll burn too.
Go ahead, Jonas.
He's listening.
Hi, Daddy. We miss you.
- And love you.
Anything else you want to say?
Come home soon, Daddy.
[laughing]
Hi, Rip.
Not sure if you got
our last message.
I told Jonas that you
got caught up with work,
but I really thought
you'd be home by now.
London is...
Things have changed.
It's hard to tell what's going on
with so many soldiers and rumors.
I just want to know
you're all right.
Wherever you are,
whenever you are,
I love you, Rip.
Go ahead, Jonas. He's listening.
Hi, Daddy. We miss you.
- And love you.
I'm sorry to interrupt, Captain.
No, uh, not at all. Just,
uh, catching up on work.
What is all this?
Just trying to connect the dots,
find the optimal time to strike at Savage.
And?
And the trail's gone cold.
In order to preserve
the element of surprise,
I wager the best course of action
is to travel further back in time,
but nothing here indicates
where to find him.
Well, perhaps I can help you look.
I've been looking!
I apologize.
It's just the stakes are so high.
I vowed to save my family,
but I'm failing them.
Perhaps I'm not the Time Master they need.
You must be.
You're the only one they have.
- Can't Gideon help us?
- No.
When a timeship returns
to the Vanishing Point
after a mission, its CPU is updated
from the temporal database,
which, given my rogue status,
we are unable to do.
So, what you're saying is
Gideon requires a software update.
Which explains why you've
been holed up in here
for the past week.
- Has it really been a week?
- Mm-hmm.
And some of our teammates
are getting just a tad antsy.
[screaming]
[grunts] I'm done.
Don't mind him.
He's still sore about having to leave 2046.
I'm sore because I was recruited
for my unique ability
to light things on fire.
And now, I'm locked in the one place
where I can't light things on fire:
a spaceship.
Where do you think you're going?
Why?
You gonna clock me in the
head if I don't listen again?
Everything okay with you two?
Yeah, peachy.
Captain, I've just intercepted
a deep space transmission.
It's a distress signal
from the Acheron.
- She's the...
- Flagship of the Time Fleet.
Yes, I know that. Thank you, Gideon.
Systemic malfunction.
I'm stranded, unable to jump.
Controls unresponsive.
This is Captain Eve Baxter
of the timeship Acheron,
requesting critical rescue.
And we care about this chick why?
We don't, but the Acheron's computer
will contain the current
intel on Savage's whereabouts.
Gideon, set a course
for the Acheron's position in deep space.
- Yes, Captain.
- Deep space?
I had no idea we had the ability
to explore the unknown
realms of the galaxy.
- Astonishing.
- No.
What's astonishing is that we're acting
as roadside assistance for
the people who's chasing us.
Doesn't it seem suspicious,
this distress call just
happened to reach us?
How do we know it's not a trap?
We don't, but what we do know
is that Savage's trail has run cold.
And unless Gideon can upload the data
- from the Acheron's computer...
- I'm in.
You are?
The sooner we end Savage, the sooner
- I get back to where I belong.
- Prison?
Any prison on Earth's better
than this one, Professor.
- Gideon.
- Yes, sir.
Engines to full throttle.
Of course, Captain.
[exciting music]
♪
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com
Professor Stein, Mr. Jackson,
would you care to join the boarding party?
A chance for an extra-vehicular
docking maneuver? What
could be more exciting?
Well, I could think of a few things.
Let's get this thing started.
Hey, you think there's something
worth stealing on that ship?
I'm just looking for a change of scenery.
If that's okay with you, boss.
Dr. Palmer.
I leave the ship in your
hands while we're gone.
And I leave him in yours.
♪
I'm having the strangest sensation.
It's like I'm ten years old again.
You do a lot of space
travel as a kid, Professor?
Only in my dreams, after I read
my first issue of "Rick
Starr: Space Ranger."
Space Ranger Stein? Yeah, I don't see it.
I wanted to travel through space,
surviving only by my wits and laser guns.
I even built a rocket
out of cardboard boxes.
What stopped you?
NASA has rather strict guidelines regarding
- nearsightedness.
- And smoking weed.
Gideon, have you been able to link up
to the Acheron's computer?
It appears a self-destruct code
has disabled the ship's
temporal navigation system.
Well, what does that mean?
It's possibly the result of a malfunction.
Just in case, Martin, I'm going to ask you
to remain behind here on the jump ship.
You're telling us if something goes wrong,
egghead's in charge?
Break out the emergency gear.
Space Ranger has a job to do.
Rip? Rip, I need an update.
How about this update?
They've boarded the ship!
- We've been overrun!
- Excellent.
Perhaps you're not taking
this seriously, Miranda.
- Gary?
- Yes, Captain?
Be a dear and open the
portside bulkhead, would you?
Look, I enjoy a suicide mission
- as much as the next person...
- You heard me, Gary.
Yes, ma'am.
What's the plan here?
Rip, you might want to
grab hold of something.
Yes, I am! It's called a gun!
Something else. Do it, please.
Now, Gary.
[screaming]
Gamma-delta hatch opened.
Explosive decompression has
evacuated the time pirates.
Seal hatch, engage time
drive, and punch it.
_
Well done, Lieutenant Coburn.
Well done? She nearly got us killed.
The simulation equivalent, at least.
She demonstrated unconventional thinking
against overwhelming numbers.
You could learn a thing or two from her,
Lieutenant Hunter.
[romantic music]
♪
Declan was right.
- Teach me more.
- [laughs]
[clears throat]
[both gasp]
Sir, I can explain.
Don't bother, Lieutenant.
Save it for your disciplinary hearing.
Hey, hey, hey. We can figure this out.
- We'll get through this together.
- That's just it.
We can't be together.
We knew from the start.
Relationships are strictly forbidden.
There has to be a way to fix this.
I'm sorry.
I need some time to think.
[somber music]
♪
[dramatic music]
Stay close and stay alert.
To quote every "Star Wars" ever made,
"I've got a bad feeling about this."
- [clangs]
- [grunting]
♪
Valiant effort.
Let the man go.
Or else what?
Do as the man says.
[screams]
Who the hell are these guys?
These, Mr. Jackson,
are time pirates.
[dramatic music]
♪
- Captain John Valor.
- Oh.
What happened to Captain Baxter?
She was on her way back
to the Vanishing Point
to imprison us when we made our escape.
But before we could take
control of the Acheron...
She destroyed her time drive
in accordance with protocol.
The same protocol that said
another Time Master
would come to her rescue.
Do I look like a Time Master to you?
You look like the kind of man who'd
throw his grandmother out of an airlock.
Nor am I a Time Master,
so you might as well just let us go.
[laughing]
Correct me if I'm wrong.
You're Rip friggin' Hunter.
I thought you'd be taller.
You never said you were famous.
Infamous.
There was a time when he had men like me
running scared all along the timeline.
Unless you let us return to our ship,
a man named Vandal Savage
will destroy the entire world.
Time Masters and pirates alike.
For once, we're fighting on the same side.
That little slogan should
come with its own shovel.
- Prepare a boarding party!
- Yes, sir.
If I were you, I'd reconsider
your plan, Mr. Valor.
Really?
I gave my crew instructions
to shoot any boarding vessel,
along with the ship launching it.
With the great Rip Hunter on board?
I highly doubt it.
You don't know my crew.
They're iron-willed
and battle-hardened.
The most formidable warriors
to navigate time and space.
Captain's log. Stardate 837.9.
We're awaiting word from the away team
aboard the Acheron.
I hate to break it to you,
but you're no Captain Kirk.
You're Picard.
But Picard was cautious,
pontificating, sort of sexless.
Well, tell that to Vash.
And for the record, Picard
was way hotter than Kirk.
Ooh, Mick had it wrong.
This ship isn't a prison.
It's a torture chamber.
Well, I don't think Mick's
problem is with the ship.
You think it's with me.
You did knock him out
and force him to leave
2046 Star City, which is
like Disneyland for felons.
He'll get over it.
Mick runs hot. He always has.
Once he calms down, everything
will be back to normal.
Yeah, I bet that one sounded
more convincing in your head.
[computer beeping]
I'd like to speak to Acting
Captain Raymond Palmer.
Ooh. Acting Captain. I
like the sound of that.
I'm Captain Palmer. Who are you?
I'm the man holding
your crew hostage.
Captain Palmer, I've
informed Mr. Valor
of the fiery retribution
you'll rain down upon him
if we are not released immediately.
Mm.
[grunts, gasps]
I'm gonna make this real simple.
You surrender your ship, and
I'll drop you off unharmed
at a place and time of your choosing.
- You've got 10 seconds to decide.
- Or else what?
If you want the Waverider for yourself,
there's no way you'll fire on us.
Perhaps, but right now,
I've got my sights set
on your captain's head.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait. Okay.
Just give me a chance to negotiate.
Ten... nine...
- Maybe he's bluffing.
- Eight...
- Doesn't feel like it.
- Seven...
You don't know Palmer,
and how he survived the
"Imperiex" onslaught.
[alarm blares]
Uh, Gideon?
Captain Hunter programmed me
to execute certain protocols
in response to specific keywords.
What does that mean in English?
Strap yourselves in.
We are on the move
and preparing to fire.
♪
Great Scott! We're under attack!
- Gideon, who's firing at us?
- Captain's orders.
- Palmer, you idiot!
- No, Captain Hunter's.
Attacking the pirates
who've taken the rest
of the boarding party hostage.
- Pirates?
- What are you doing, Gideon?
Just a warning shot to let
them know we mean business.
My partner's on that ship.
D... Dr. Palmer?
Captain Hunter? Is anyone there?
It's up to you now, Martin.
- Gilbert!
- Yes, sir.
Set a pursuit course and
prepare to return fire.
♪
If you destroy the Waverider,
none of us are getting back home.
Don't worry. I'm only targeting
your ship's life support systems.
Now, if I were the weapons targeting system
on the Acheron...
where would I be?
There's a hull breach in
the aft portion of the ship,
and the pirates have taken
out the telemetry controls.
Gideon, switch to manual.
What are you doing?
If this is anything like a video game,
flying a space ship.
Where are you guys going?
To deal with the hole in the ship.
Make sure Picard here
doesn't get us all killed.
Actually, I'm more like Sulu right now.
Or Han Solo!
♪
Target their thrusters and fire.
[machinery whining, powers down]
I said fire!
Sir, the weapons systems
have been taken offline.
- Manually.
- Who else is on my ship?
Oh, a good captain keeps
his best weapons hidden
from his enemies, Mr. Valor.
Find the saboteur! Bring
him to me, dead or alive.
I guess we'll just have
to follow your friends
till they're out of air.
Shouldn't take too long, given the size
of the hole in the hull.
[hissing]
- Here.
- [electricity whines]
Hail the crew of the Waverider.
Rip, tell your crew to let us board,
and I will happily save them.
But either way, we are
taking the Waverider.
Take the damn deal, Rip.
A captain never surrenders his ship.
Besides, you'll never catch Captain Palmer.
He once outran Kanjar Ro himself.
Who's Kanjar Ro?
Engaging protocol now, Captain.
- Awesome.
- I wasn't talking to you.
♪
What the hell happened to 'em?
We were following a holographic projection
which allowed the Waverider to slip away.
Giving secret commands to your crew.
- Very clever, Captain.
- Mm-hmm.
Throw them in the brig!
We'll find your friends' bodies.
Eventually.
How long can you keep that up for?
Not long.
I'm gonna run out of charge.
Be advised, the breach is
only partially contained.
Guess we know the
bulkhead doors are working.
Too bad we're on the wrong side of them.
[alarm blaring]
Uh oh.
Thanks for stopping by.
We're gonna get you out of here.
- Just hang tight.
- Is there another option?
Don't mean to rush you, Raymond,
but it's getting cold in here.
Normally I wouldn't complain, but...
Can't you just open the doors, Gideon?
The bulkhead is
designed to remain shut
until the breach is sealed.
Well, that's not happening from in here.
How much time do we have until...
We're dead?
Ah!
Ah...
Captain Baxter. I'm Rip Hunter.
I'm here to rescue you.
I doubt it. You walked
straight into a trap.
I will admit that we've encountered
some... unforeseen obstacles.
Right.
But, we're gonna get you
out of here in a second.
Mr. Jackson, will you
please see what we can do
about disabling this force field?
You don't think I've tried that?
But by all means, if
you think this kid
will have better luck.
- Whoa, who you callin' kid?
- I'm sorry.
- I meant criminal.
- Actually, that's me.
All of you. If we ever do get out of here,
the first thing I'll do is take you
to the Vanishing Point to await trial
before the Time Council.
The great Rip Hunter,
but look at you now.
Yes, look at me now.
Helping you break out of a pirate's
brig aboard your own timeship.
I don't want help from
a man who broke his oath,
stole a timeship, and
decided to change history
for his own selfish reasons.
Doesn't make any sense to me.
No, I don't expect it would.
Rip Hunter.
Miranda Coburn.
Those aren't your real names, are they?
No, sir.
And why is that?
Because if our enemies
knew our true identities,
our ancestors and descendants
across the timeline
could be potential targets.
As well as anyone else you might love.
Which is why...
Personal attachments
are expressly forbidden
by the Council of Time Masters.
And grounds for immediate
discharge from service.
Do either of you deny
that you were conducting
an illicit affair in violation
of this council's rules?
In that case,
I motion that we adjourn
this disciplinary hearing
for one hour to afford you
the opportunity to consider your response.
Though I sincerely doubt there's any answer
you can provide that
will prevent this tribunal
from discharging you both
from the Time Masters.
I suppose this feels like
a day at the beach for you?
If I had to pick a way to die,
freezing wouldn't be the worst.
What's it like?
Dying?
I imagine you've got a unique perspective.
You know, it's funny.
I mean, you'd expect it to be terrifying,
just panic and fear.
What'd you feel?
I guess lonely.
Yeah.
Like everybody I loved
was a million miles away.
I mean, I don't like you, but
at least I'm not dying alone.
Closest I ever came to dying was, uh...
the day I met Mick.
- Why does that not surprise me?
- It wasn't like that.
It was my first day in juvie.
I was 14, and the smallest
kid in there by far.
Some of the older kids
wanted to make sure I knew it.
So they jumped me.
I fought back, but one of them had a shiv
and I figured that was it
until Mick stepped in.
And they didn't mess with me after that.
He's been standing up for me ever since.
Let's just hope he's standing
up for Rip and Jax now.
Who else is gonna take on those pirates?
[dramatic music]
♪
Hey!
- [grunting]
- Ah!
[grunting]
♪
That'll teach you not to
mess with a nuclear physicist.
♪
You ready?
Given I never designed the
Atom suit for outer space,
I'm not exactly sure how
to answer that question.
While I'm gone, you're captain.
Thank you.
But I think we both know
I'm in charge either way.
[chuckles]
Good luck.
Gideon, open the hatch.
- [sighs]
- Sorry, Captain.
I can't jerry-rig the door open.
Don't worry, kid.
It's not your fault. It's his.
In case you've forgotten, Mr. Rory,
you volunteered to be part
of this boarding party.
I volunteered to get away from my partner,
who hasn't been acting like my partner
ever since you fed his
head with fairy tales
about saving the world.
Your partner has a mind of his own,
Mr. Rory, which is more
than I can say of you.
Are you saying that I'm dumb, Captain?
Let's pretend, just for a
moment, that you're the captain,
stuck in the brig while
the rest of your crew
slowly perish on their damaged ship.
Now, what would you do to get
yourself out of that predicament?
Oh, no brilliant ideas? Really?
Why am I not in the least bit surprised?
Shut your mouth, now!
Okay, let's all just take a deep breath.
Or what? You'll punch me in the face,
or burn me alive, or employ
some other barbaric form of violence?
That's why you recruited me, isn't it?
To hit, hurt, and burn?
No, I recruited you
because you and your partner
were a package deal.
- What?
- I'm sorry, Mr. Rory.
But a serial arsonist
was never part of my plan
to stop Savage, much less
one with the IQ of meat.
I didn't mean to be so blunt.
If I could just have a moment of quiet,
then perhaps I can think of a way
of getting us off this pirate ship.
I think I just beat you to it.
Can anyone hear me?
What the hell do you think you're doing?
Me and the pirates are
gonna have a little parlay.
- Do not do this, Rory.
- Too late.
What do you want?
I want to speak to Captain Valor.
- About what?
- About a timeship.
- I am warning you.
- Shut up!
I may have the IQ of meat,
but I know how to cut a deal.
[dramatic music]
♪
[screams]
[eerie music]
♪
[grunts]
I'm listening.
You want the Waverider. I want to go home.
Where is home for a man like you?
2016, Central City.
Of all the places in
time, you want to go there?
That's right.
To the exact moment Hunter
recruited me and my partner
on this suicidal mission of his,
but, this time,
I'm gonna tell him where to shove it.
Let me get this straight.
I let you go,
you'll deliver the Waverider.
Yes.
Do we have an accord?
You think your friends will
believe you were able to escape?
Not unless I do this. [grunting]
How's it going out there?
Good.
By which I mean utterly terrifying.
I'll have the breach
sealed in two more minutes.
Okay. How's your oxygen level?
Uh, I think the technical term is "lousy."
Just two more minutes.
You got this.
Nothing quite like dying to make you think
about all the mistakes,
all the wrong choices.
Is this Leonard Snart coming to God
in his final moments?
- Hardly.
- [shivers]
Just wishing I could
take a few things back.
I should've left Mick in future Star City.
Why didn't you?
Without me to keep him in check,
Mick can be a scary guy.
Agreed.
Hate to break it to you, but
even if we make it out of here alive,
you're still gonna have
a problem on your hands.
And I've seen enough to know
that Mick's in a dark place.
He's not coming back.
Man, I can't believe Rory sold us out.
No, actually I can.
But still, man.
What choice did he have?
The crew left on the Waverider
are most probably dead by now,
and God knows what
happened to Professor Stein.
It's no wonder that Mr. Rory
chose to save his own skin.
And what I can I do about it?
I'm stuck in a pirate's brig and I've lost
both my ship and the loyalty of my crew.
You're one to talk about loyalty.
Oh, but I am, Captain Baxter,
and not because I pledged an oath
to serve as a Time Master,
but a long time ago, I made
a far more important oath.
When you call me a failure,
Captain Baxter, you're right.
'Cause I failed both my wife and my son.
For betraying the Time Council
I have absolutely no regrets.
But failing to save my family?
That is something for which
I will never forgive myself.
[somber music]
♪
Time Master Declan, I...
I thought the tribunal was re-convening.
It's been cancelled.
Lieutenant Coburn assumed full
responsibility for the affair.
The other Time Masters
were moved by her argument.
They've dismissed the charges?
Once Lieutenant Coburn resigned.
- Why would she do that?
- It seems she believes in you.
Now you must prove to
yourself and all of us
that you are indeed the
man she believes you to be.
[electricity powers down]
[dramatic music]
[adventurous music]
I thought we were done for.
Take heart, dear Captain.
This battle is far from over.
Now, who would care to join me
in a daring escape?
- Space Ranger.
- Indeed.
[alarm beeping quickly]
[dramatic music]
Ray, don't go nodding off on me.
No, I wasn't. [exhales sharply]
I was just resting my eyes for a second.
You've got to stay with me, Ray.
Just stay focused on my
voice, and keep talking.
- About what?
- Anything.
Like, um,
what was your first pet's name?
- [chuckles] Slinky.
- Is that a cat?
Burmese python.
Yeah, I'm allergic to cats and dogs.
Pretty much anything without scales.
Okay, then, enough about pets.
Um, what's your favorite color?
Don't have one.
Who doesn't have a favorite color?
It's kind of like having a favorite Beatle.
No, everyone has a favorite Beatle.
Not me.
Wouldn't be fair to the other three.
Okay, fine, enough about
pets, and colors, and Beatles.
It's a good thing we
never went for that drink.
This space date is going terribly.
[alarm beeping rapidly]
♪
Ray?
Are you still with me, Ray?
Ray? Are you there? Ray?
I'm sorry.
It's all I have left.
[triumphant music]
Ray, are you there?
It seems that Mr. Palmer
patched the hole in the hull,
allowing Mr. Snart and Ms.
Lance to escape the engine room.
Okay, as soon as he's on board, I need you
to close the cargo bay and
seal the airlock, Gideon.
Ray.
Ray! Hey, stay with me.
I'm afraid Mr. Palmer has
gone into cardiac arrest.
Please, I can't lose you
too! Ray, I need you! Please!
His chances of survival
are less than 3,720 to 1.
Ray!
Ray, come on. You're strong.
Please, Ray. Come back to me.
Ray! [grunting]
- Ray!
- [gasps]
Could you please stop
punching me in the chest?
Why do they always make it
seem like it's a good thing
- to do in the movies?
- I thought you were dead.
I think I was, there, for a second.
Thank you.
You kids need a moment?
You okay?
Mr. Palmer nearly died.
Welcome to the club.
Gideon, what's happening on the Acheron?
Funny you should ask.
I just received a
message from Mr. Rory.
It seems he escaped capture
and is now returning
to the Waverider.
Told you.
Those pirates picked the
wrong guy to mess with.
Since when does Rory even
know how to fly the jump ship?
How did he even find us?
Actually, I did the flying.
He received quite a beating
at the hands of the pirates.
That's him now.
[suspenseful music]
♪
You okay, Mick?
Boys!
Ship's all yours!
♪
You son of a bitch.
What are you doing, Mick?
I'm getting us home. Are you in?
[electricity whines]
Yeah.
Time to choose a side, I guess.
Chosen.
- Bastard!
- Go!
- Get them!
I'll get the time drive.
Is the Acheron's jump
ship still operational?
- Yes.
- All right, go to it
and get off the Acheron.
I have some unfinished
business with Mr. Valor.
I'm not leaving my ship.
And we're not leaving you behind.
So what's the plan, Captain?
Valor and his men
substantially outnumber us.
We're not going to be able to
defeat them by conventional means.
[dramatic music]
♪
Mr. Rory is making his
way to the engine room
to access the time drive.
I'll handle it.
♪
[grunting]
What's going on?
You're losing.
- Gilbert?
- The time pirates are indeed
ten seconds behind you, and closing.
That doesn't give us much time.
You think Rip's plan will work?
Yeah, that's what I thought.
Step away from it, Mick.
I'll tell you what, Blondie.
Walk away and I won't kill you.
You know I can't do that.
I like you, Sara.
You got a lot of guts.
That's why I'm only gonna
kill you a little bit!
[both grunting]
[exciting music]
♪
[all grunting]
Mick!
Captain Hunter? We're in position.
- Captain Hunter?
- Yes, yes!
I'm a little bit busy right now!
Be that as it may, we've run out of time.
Captain, the plan.
♪
We're waiting for your signal.
- Gilbert?
- Yes, sir?
I need you to listen to me very,
very carefully.
[alarm blares]
[screaming]
Rip! We're good!
- [panting]
- Bulkhead door closed.
Explosive decompression has
evacuated the time pirates.
Thank you, Gilbert.
Please hail the Waverider.
Waverider, this is Captain Hunter.
We've regained control
of the Acheron.
What's your status?
What are you gonna do, Snart?
I suppose it wouldn't be very fair
if I arrested you after
you reclaimed my ship
and apprehended John Valor for me.
Happy to help out a fellow Time Master.
Even though I don't deserve that title.
I was wrong. You've proven that today.
You're still one hell of a Time Master.
Which is why I'm giving you this.
- What's that?
- Gilbert?
Using the Vanishing Point's
most current timeline data,
I calculate a 99.8% probability
that you will find Vandal Savage
in Harmony Falls,
Oregon, in March of 1958.
Thank you, Captain Baxter.
I still don't understand
why you're doing all this.
Before all this started, I
don't think I would've, either.
We protect history, safeguard time itself.
There is no higher calling.
It's called love.
Rip. Rip.
Rip!
Look at me, Rip.
[sighs]
Please don't be mad at me.
Oh, no, I'm not mad at you!
I... I was going to resign.
I know and I couldn't let you.
This has always been your dream.
Yes, but you are so much
better at this than me.
I... I can't understand why you would...
why you'd give all that up.
It's funny, because you're
the one who made me realize
that I could never be a Time Master.
I found something with you,
something wonderful.
I found love.
That thing that the Time Masters
always taught us to hide from,
but they were wrong, Rip.
Love's no threat.
It's beautiful, and powerful,
and once you know it,
love changes everything.
Like it changed me
and that's why I have to resign,
because I could never belong to something
that turns its back on the truth.
Suddenly my chosen profession
seems so terribly unimportant.
No.
The world needs the Time Masters
and the Time Masters, most assuredly,
need Rip Hunter.
- [groans]
- My only wish is that one day,
when you're off traveling space and time,
you'll realize what I have, and understand
why I'm doing what I'm doing.
I hope you think of me when that day comes.
I will...
because I'll be with you.
[soft romantic music]
♪
Hey.
I was just looking for you. I...
How are you feeling?
Good. Yeah.
Turns out I bounce back pretty
quickly from hypothermia.
In fact, I managed to
remember some of the things
you said to me when I was almost dead.
You were
wrong, B-T-W.
You don't need me. You don't need anybody.
I mean, you're pretty amazing
and I'm lucky to be your friend,
be on this mission together with...
♪
That's... surprising.
Okay.
I'll say it.
Why don't we just drop
him off back in 2016?
Because my sister lives in 2016.
And your sister, and your wife.
So what exactly are we talking about here?
Leaving Rory in the brig
until we take down Savage?
No, no, no, no, the brig is unsuitable
for long-term incarceration.
Leaving him free run of
the ship is not an option.
I'll handle it.
By handling it, you mean murder?
I said I'll handle it.
[ominous music]
♪
[grunts]
[groaning]
[sighs]
I told you that'll be
the last time you hit me.
You were right.
That the plan?
Take me out in the middle of nowhere,
where no one can find the body?
I wish there were some other way, Mick,
but you're dangerous.
- A liability to the team.
- Team?
You and I were a team!
What happened to you?
People change.
You think you're some kind of hero,
but deep down you're still the same
punk kid I saved in juvie.
You haven't got the guts.
You want to kill me?
Kill me.
Only one of us is
walking out of here alive.
You're right.
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com