QUENTIN: Previously
on The Magicians...
Quentin... (GRUNTS)
QUENTIN: I killed a god.
Gods like Ember
have parents, you idiot.
When we're harmless,
they ignore us.
But when we become
malignant, they amputate.
Magic is gone.
What is it that you
seek, rude little Earth girl?
FEN: The woman
and child you stole.
Fen wouldn't come because
they have your daughter.
FEN: I had to warn you.
They're coming.
This contract initiates our
services in exchange for...
Unlimited manual
and magical labor?
You signed that insane contract?
Yeah, it's okay.
Did you do this
for me? Just say it.
PENNY: Cancer.
Call it cancer plus.
How long till I die?
Two or three weeks.
I need your help.
If Penny's in the Library,
he can be your mole.
But to do that, he'd
have to be alive.
Deal.
FRIAR JOSEPH: As a
Niffin, you made enemies.
I am here to warn you
that one of them seeks you.
The Lamprey. It
knows you're weak.
It knows you're here.
JULIA: He raped me.
Your son.
He turned me into a monster.
You're a survivor.
ALICE: Why did
you bring me back?
I know what you're trying to do.
(GASPS)
DEAN: There is no actual
evidence of magical surge.
The best we can do is accept that
and continue our theoretical studies.
(SIGHS) We all get flashes,
and we can do it again.
(CRACKLING)
How?
I have no idea.
(SPEAKS LATIN)
Nope. Nothing.
No freeze, no boil.
Shit.
It's okay.
You can still do other stuff.
Q, I can't do anything real.
It's like there's
no pattern to this,
nothing that we do can
make it stronger or better.
I'm starting to feel like
it's all random, you know?
Maybe it was a mistake.
Come on, you don't mean that.
What if this is, like, a smudge?
A fingerprint left by O.L.U. when
she gave me back my Shade,
and she didn't even realize?
You know, it's like,
whoops, speck of magic.
She's a goddess.
Does she seem like
the accident type?
Have you met her son?
Look, I don't wanna
be insensitive...
But you still think I somehow
have this because of Reynard.
I don't know why you have it.
I just... I don't think that we
should discount the possibility.
I mean, you've had...
More contact with
gods than most.
That's a nicer
way of putting it.
For the record, I'm still
leaning towards fluke.
So it's a fluke. There's still something
that could lead us to something.
We have got to keep
chipping away at it, Jules.
Big words coming
from a guy who's mostly
chain-smoking and binge-watching
Six Feet Under when I got here.
You fired me up.
You showed me that
there's a fight to fight.
Now I am the official sidekick to
whatever it turns out you are, okay?
So, get used to it.
MAN: Wake up, asshole.
Ah.
(FOOTSTEPS)
(CHUCKLES)
What, were you a boy scout?
These are great.
Not a good time to
go with smart-ass.
I'm not a killer, but times are strange
and you're the one who broke into my home.
Yeah, well, I'm a Librarian.
You're ignoring our requests.
That book was overdue.
Overdue book? Come on.
It's my job.
What's the Library's real game?
Books?
Why do you care anymore?
'Cause what the hell else
is there to do anymore?
(LAUGHS)
Man, hey, that thing...
Is not your business.
It's Mayakovsky's spell, right?
Little something to brew up current?
It's fake.
It does not make magic.
It does blow up like a meth lab.
MAN: You met Mayakovsky?
I'd know his spellwork anywhere.
Yeah, me too,
and I'm telling you...
All of this is his fault.
It... By his, you mean...
Made a bunch of
apocalypse-proof batteries,
then did something to turn
it all off all over the world.
Breaks his Incorporate Bond,
screws us, he's got magic, he's free.
Tell you what Mayakovsky
didn't think about...
Creatures. They're fine.
Whatever they are, it's DNA.
So I hear.
We're fish bait now.
Thank God I got this
place, 'cause they're coming.
I promise you.
(METAL CLANGS)
(BOOK DROPS)
Well, karma is a righteous
bitch. (CHUCKLES)
Karma's gonna be...
We kill them all, son.
If you can.
I mean, some of
them look just like us.
You'd never know
they're not quite human.
(PANTING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(WIND GUSHES)
I like the little apron.
Penny.
What the hell are you...
Oh, you shouldn't be here.
You don't have that
kind of time to waste.
It's not wasted.
They treating you okay?
Everything's
fine. It's all fine.
Nothing is fine.
I'm looking at
you. There's that.
You look good.
Huh. White-knuckle sobriety
and forced celibacy's my look.
You need to go back.
I was kinda thinking we were
gonna grab a quickie in the car.
Yeah, that sounds great,
except I don't have a car, and...
And you're fucking dying.
Worth it.
Go.
I love you.
We don't have the funds to...
ELIOT: We're just
going to have to borrow.
Begging Pardon,
but Tick is right.
Excuse me, Sire.
Your Majesty?
Look, there is no
unshitty answer
to any of this,
people, so suck it up.
(FEN GIGGLES)
Oh. Oh-oh.
Mmm. Yeah.
Ahem. We need to
discuss the borders.
Great.
After lunch.
Thank you. Dismissed.
We have things to discuss, dear.
Fabulous. Not you.
Your long-suffering high queen.
You may go.
Margo, stay.
FAIRY QUEEN:
Lumbricus Campestris.
Oh, don't tell me.
Feather of a left-handed crow?
Butterfly with PMS this time?
Turtle semen with
a rosemary garnish?
It's a type of earthworm.
It lives abundantly in the
grounds around the castle.
Collect them all.
Okay. (CHUCKLES)
Really enjoying our
ongoing whimsy-fest,
but I am a tad busy trying to
keep the country from starving,
so... Better hurry, then.
(COUGHS)
THE LIBRARIAN:
You were gone too long.
Was I? (LAUGHS)
Thought I was... (RETCHES)
You have to move quickly
out there. (COUGHS)
Every time you leave
this branch, you go where
time moves normally and
where time progresses...
So does my super cancer, I know.
It's a pity the best y'all could do
was a place where time stopped.
You know, time going
backward? (PANTING)
That'd be better.
I've been giving you assignments
that shouldn't take more than an hour.
I don't want you... Me to die?
How sweet of you,
considering you poisoned me.
You know that
wasn't me. (COUGHS)
No one wants you to die.
I know.
You know, Travelers?
Hard to come by.
I wish you wouldn't
be so cynical.
Thank you. You need to rest.
(COUGHING)
How is it?
Out there?
Depressing.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Henry.
(CHUCKLES)
Is that... Is that
Irene McAllistair?
Well, it is good to see you.
(HENRY LAUGHS)
Oh, and how is the...
The board of trustees?
Oh, well, out of their
minds. (LAUGHS)
Well, I don't need to tell you
how many of their companies
went belly up when magic died.
You do not. I have
stock in several.
Join the club. Yeah.
And your family?
Well, you know them.
Stuffy, cautious...
Survive anything.
But the rest of the board...
Look, Henry, I came here
alone because I respect you.
Well, you taught me
everything that I know.
No need to exaggerate. I'm not.
And no one needs to convince
me that this school is important.
I gather that's not
the case for everyone.
They're panicked.
They want magic.
So too do we all.
They believe that there's gotta be
something out there somewhere.
Mayakovsky.
He was working on a battery.
We searched Brakebills South...
Still, they feel that the
resources of this school
would be best spent
continuing to search for...
I cannot stop my
students from searching.
But we are a school.
We still teach here.
It is perhaps more
important than ever.
If they don't learn it,
I fear no one will ever
again, you understand?
I fear that too.
But if you don't find
them something...
The board is gonna
close down Brakebills.
You have to give
them something, Henry.
Quickly.
So, what do you think?
Okay, say you were to do it.
Work your way through
some piddly little Earth gods,
find a way to talk to an actual
old god, and you say what?
Hi, please reconsider,
even though you are
a billion times smarter than
I, and... And... More powerful,
if you could please bring
back magic, that would be great.
I don't know, I just... I
figured it couldn't hurt
to get a little closer and
maybe meet someone
who knew more than we do.
I hear you, Q, I do.
I just... What?
I wouldn't want what happened
to me to happen to anyone else.
Look, you don't have to come.
I just... I just
wanted you to know.
Okay, you're gonna
do a summoning alone?
Yeah. (SIGHS)
I don't... I don't know.
Okay, say I was
willing to risk it.
I mean, it requires
serious, big magic.
Okay, well, cultures all over the
world have believed in these gods.
How did they call them?
JOSH: Suffice to
say, not quite the party
I was expecting when I
came down here, but...
I think I could help you.
KADY: How can I help you?
Yeah.
I was gonna respond, and then
I remembered there's no point.
You can't help Penny anymore.
Says who?
What is that?
Ah-haha.
I have a job for you.
Earthworms.
Get anyone not actively...
Our full team is required
to keep the castle safe.
Okay, okay, so get like
five or six and do this for me.
Quick and dirty.
(SCOFFS)
(SIGHS) There you are.
Come join.
The southern province is
whatever the Fillorian
word for bankrupt is.
I need a drink.
FAIRY QUEEN: So quick,
little Queen. (GASPS)
Where are the worms?
Don't tell me you sent
someone out to do your work.
(CHUCKLES) I'm a delegator.
It's a leadership quality.
You've clearly mastered it.
I thought I was clear.
They are to be plucked
by female hands.
And I desire those
hands to be yours.
But only if you
wish to keep them.
Shit!
Now this is bad.
I waited till I was
sure none of those
creepy little no-eyebrow fuckers
were around before I delegated.
So, how'd she know?
And so fast?
(MUFFLED TRANCE MUSIC PLAYS)
All right, so how do you know
that he'll even be here tonight?
I mean, there's a million
parties happening all over.
Easy.
He's on social media?
How else are followers
supposed to find him?
Met him by total
accident at Art Basel.
He kept that party
going eight full days.
(CHUCKLES)
Best eight days of my life.
Anyway, that's his thing.
Swing in, stoke the party,
soak in the worship, move on.
Inspiring, right?
You guys are gonna love him.
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
Josh "The Animal" Hoberman.
Bacchus. (LAUGHS)
My deity How you living?
So good.
Um, get your fine
ass in this bitch.
Lucy.
Bong hit.
Come back when you're fun.
My mistress wishes
that I tell you...
Uh, and you can see here
cracks from the swordplay
of King Boris The Softspoken.
That is indeed fascinating.
Hmm.
Abigail mentioned you have
many fairy guests these days.
Guests, hostile occupying
force, tomato, tomahto.
I presume you wish to extend
the most elegant level of hospitality.
Do I?
For this reason, I make
you aware of the corridor
built by High Queen Chen Li the Bookish,
of rare stone from the Shivering Sea.
Okay.
Why?
Unfortunately, certain species
are allergic to the substance.
How allergic?
Violently, Your Majesty.
Good to know.
We advise that your guests
cannot tolerate that area
so if you are looking for them,
they will undoubtedly
be somewhere else.
A-plus, Rafe.
Huh. If Rafe says so, guess
maybe we're not the first royals
living a 24/7 fairy
reach-around.
(SIGHS)
So what the hell
are we gonna do?
About Queen Bitch and
all her spooky little bitches?
Poison sounds nice.
Shockingly, all books
on poison disappeared
from the royal library right
around the time they arrived.
They're armed, they're
smart, they're multitudinous,
they are invisible
to the guard...
When you put it that way.
What if they know
about this in Loria?
If I send Idri a message...
Worst case he comes here,
you look at him naked
and cheer up a little.
How dare you make me
sound that shallow, but, yes.
Hi.
Great to see you, as always.
(WHISPERS) I'll
go write that letter.
To who?
Not Idri of Loria?
Actually, yes. (CLEARS THROAT)
Our crops are dying now
that we can't schedule the rain.
I hope he can help.
His library, like yours,
has of course been purged
of any material
pertaining to our species.
And any Lorian aware
of the existence of fairies
has been instructed
to keep their mouth shut
or lose their tongue.
Please don't
underestimate me again.
It hurts my feelings.
We're gonna go take a
walk and have a good think
about our behavior.
(MUFFLED TRANCE MUSIC PLAYS)
(GROANS) Come
on, we not fun yet?
(COUGHS) (CHUCKLES)
Oh.
Yeah, do we not...
Do we not amuse!
Do we not amuse?
Hey.
I think I... I
think I got it, Q.
Okay. (GRUNTS)
Remember that time,
10th grade, right?
And we made up that
dance and it was terrible.
Oh, God. Yes.
So white and bad. Yeah,
that might actually work.
It was very, like, hip
thrusty if I remember.
Oh, yeah. Oh, no.
I remember it, my friend. Uh...
(SINGING) Ayo
I'm tired of using technology
Uh! So why don't
you sit in front of me
Ayo
I'm tired of using technology
Uh! I need you
right in front of me
Uh! She wants it Uh-uh!
She wants it
She wants it, so I
gotta give it to her
Ow! She wants it Uh-uh
She wants it
So you can
fugging give it to her
(DOOR OPENS)
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
Hoberman!
GIRL: Whoo!
(SCREAMS)
So, welcome.
Magicians, right?
Yeah, how can you tell?
Your hands, and your
crazy level of drama.
Cheers to that.
Uh...
Going again.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Part deux.
I just, I w... We would
kind of really love to talk.
Kid, I'm Bacchus.
I am the god of not being
a wiggly, little anxious
wet dish rag that would kind
of really love to talk to you,
so I need you to unclench
your vagina and do that shot
or I'm moving on.
Just a little sexist.
Five, four, three, two...
Attaboy.
Okay, what do you wanna do now?
Twister? You wanna
pierce something?
Oh, I've got Trivial
Pursuit Star Trek edition.
Just... Mr. Bacchus, we...
Magic, and how
it's completely gone.
Magic is gone
for you little guys?
You don't say.
What is... All over the U.S.?
All over everywhere, we think.
Oh, I've been a
little out of touch.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, that sucks for you.
Why?
Well...
I, um...
Sort of killed a god.
A minor... Like, a
very, you know...
JULIA: We had to. A minor god.
JULIA: Not because we wanted
to, but just because we had to.
You understand... Who?
Who the fuck did you kill?
Um, Ember in...
Fillory?
I don't know that guy. (LAUGHS)
Deserved it. I...
Oh!
Tough choices make a
man, man. QUENTIN: Yeah.
Open your mouth.
Sorry?
Like, open your mouth.
Ahh.
Happy birthday.
Okay, so this is gonna be
a little bit more challenging
than we expected.
What did you put in my mouth?
Alice? Where are you going?
I can't do this. I can't
study dead magic.
I can't...
Can we just go sit down
somewhere and talk, please?
Stop. Look, here's the deal.
I thought if we hung
out, maybe had sex,
I don't know, went to
school, it would feel like it did.
I thought I could
forgive you, but I can't.
I just...
Say good-bye and let me go.
Good-bye, Alice.
Alice?
Nope.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, you okay?
Oh. Yeah, sorry.
Hey.
Sorry.
I am so... No, it's...
Very... Me too.
Very high.
I get it. (LAUGHS)
Does your high ever turn on
you and you go from happy to
remembering you live in a
barren world devoid of magic?
Mine more goes from okay to,
"Oh, yeah, you have PTSD
from being sexually assaulted
"by a trickster god."
Long story.
I got time.
Let's talk about something else.
Sure.
Sure, whatever you...
Hey, you ever, uh...
I'm sorry.
I just really loved doing magic.
And I was good at it.
You should have tasted
my tomatoes. (LAUGHS)
And just, the air
smelled different, right?
And I could turn into a
bird, or make a rose bloom.
And I saw actual Fillory.
And I banged a werewolf, yes.
That is weird, but also rad,
because who gets to do that?
And I wasn't just some
extremely average nobody.
I was gifted.
I didn't just belong somewhere.
I belonged anywhere
because I was a Magician.
I just...
I don't even know what
anything is even about anymore.
Maybe there's a
way to get it back.
Look, no offense, I've
been researching, and...
Stick a fork in it.
Please tell me you're not just
really, really good at smoke rings.
Mmm-mmm.
No, I can't even blow one.
How?
I don't know yet.
Julia.
JULIA: Q!
Stop, Q, you're
giving me the spins...
Look, I know that
you're blasted, but...
You're blasted!
Yeah, but even I know that
you cannot show people that.
Why not?
Because if the wrong
people found out...
He is not the wrong people.
I can't go through the rest of
my life just not trusting anyone.
I feel fucked up enough.
I get that.
Just put yourself in my
shoes just for one second, Q.
I have magic.
And what does it do?
More or less jack shit.
And I see someone whose entire
life would change if he could just see it.
I have to be able to
do something with it.
And if that's cheer up Josh
Hoberman, then I'll take it.
Because I can't... You know,
I can't be so precious with
something that is so small.
It's not small, it's the...
It's the biggest magic, Jules.
'Cause as far as we know,
for us little guys, it's
the only magic out there.
Ow! What... Ow!
Dude, you're gonna leave
a mark and I don't like that
in a non-sexual context.
Okay, okay, okay, okay... Um...
You watched Battlestar, right?
Yeah, I love when they
do terrorism allegory
with mostly white people.
Hmm. You remember
Grace Park in season one?
Of course, best storyline.
Why? Duh... Because
she was actually...
You're Grace Park.
Okay?
You're Grace Park, Margo.
(GASPS)
I'm Grace Park. Yeah.
And we have ourselves a bit of a...
Gene Hackman in The Conversation.
I didn't see that one.
Yeah, right... Um...
Someone is "xoxo,
Gossip Girl"-ing our shit.
Remember James
Marsden in X-Men? Hmm?
Your Marsden is xoxo-ing us full
on that great song by The Police.
That Fairuza Balk in The Craft.
Yeah, more Cersei Lannister.
Hey, glad I made you read those.
Well, I read the Wiki.
What? Those books are
like a million pages long.
I have a life. Okay.
Anyway, whatever your Marsden
would xoxo, Cersei xoxo's.
So, we have to keep it
very best episode of Buffy.
Oh, musical?
The other one. Okay.
How do we Lizzie Borden
the shit out of this thing?
'Cause I am about
ready to go full '07 Britney.
Maybe we could've back
when this place was Pottered up.
Still.
Even without a wand, Harry
would figure some shit out.
Honestly, I didn't quite
finish those books either...
Our Harry, I mean.
Oh! Him.
Well, he'd...
Mmm-hmm?
Consult the creepy pedophile.
(DOGS BARK IN DISTANCE)
We're close, I think.
I thought this excursion was
mostly about drinking heavily.
I needed to imply that
so we could get away
without extra eyes on us.
Fairies, Tick.
When magic died, they pounced.
Full occupation.
This explains so much.
What will we do?
The White Lady was
spotted somewhere near here.
We're going to shoot her,
and then we're going to wish
those fairies to the fucking cornfield.
Oh, excellent.
Whatever a cornfield is.
(DOGS BARKING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh! Oh, there he is!
(LAUGHS)
Man... Or, god, I just...
Look, I thank you.
I just... I feel... You know,
whatever you put in my mouth...
I just... I feel like...
You know, like a sugary
cereal in the good way.
You know? It's like, whoa!
All right.
Hey, hey, shots, right?
Shots, shots, shots, shots.
You and me. Shots, shots.
I love you, I love you.
(SINGING) I'm
falling on my knees
In worship of you
Yeah.
Look, so, anyway, I was
thinking, while we're here,
maybe I could ask
you a few questions.
Dude.
You're a vibe-killer.
No. Yes, you are.
And historically, I
do smite vibe-killers.
No, look, I'm a vibe-supporter.
I just also happen to be a
concerned Magician individual
who would like to get a
word in with your parents.
My parents?
Yeah, the old gods.
Are imperious and distant dickwads
who I haven't spoken to in a millennia.
Rambo!
Let's get that foam
gun loaded, baby.
(GROANS)
Look, I know that this
really wasn't on your radar
until you met us, but we've
lost our most precious resource.
Dude, stop, okay?
If fixing magic is, like,
so important to you,
then you should just
talk to this crazy guy
that I met back in
Athens one time.
Rambo! Rambo!
What was the name of
that guy that I met in Athens,
that up-with-humans guy?
Fit bod.
You mean Prometheus?
Prom...
That guy loved Magicians,
and he would want to help you.
RAMBO: He's dead.
What?
Prometheus died, like,
1,500 years ago, man.
Sorry.
Damn it.
Well, he lived a pretty
tortured existence,
so, dying was
probably a relief for him.
Ahem.
But, still, he
would've helped you.
He told me this crazy story
one time about how there's like...
Like, a secret
back door to magic.
Wait, I'm sorry, what?
I don't remember the deets,
okay, my face was melting off.
Secret back door.
Just, something...
Mmm-hmm.
(EXCLAIMS) Wait!
Might've been a brothel.
Shots.
(WHISPERS) Tick?
Tick?
Shit.
(THE GREAT COCK CHUCKLES)
Not the best idea, Eliot.
I was looking for
the White Lady.
Is this she?
Look, if you don't come out of
there, I'm going to have to shoot you.
Gods! Have you never
given a compliment?
For example, my,
my, High King Eliot.
Your long legs look so
well in those breeches.
Thank you.
Your turn.
You sound like a...
Very attractive Creature.
You think so?
I've met many non-humans,
and your voice is by far the...
Sexiest.
Really?
I mean, you sound noble.
I didn't mean...
You're wise, for I am,
indeed, the sexiest in the land.
It is I, the Great Cock
of The Darkling Woods.
The Great...
Cock.
Have you never beheld
one, child of Earth?
No, no.
No, I've beheld one or two.
But you are, by far,
the most majestic.
I'm diligent about hydration.
All right,
petitioner, let's chat.
(SOFT PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
(INSECTS CHIRPING)
I like your style.
What is the point of hearing a
petition if the aesthetics are shit?
I need help with a fairy thing.
Tribal matriarchies
are the absolute worst.
So, I was just hoping in your
great, benevolent handsomeness
that you would see fit to
grant me just one little wish.
That's the sort of thing my sister,
The Winter's Doe, specializes in.
Also, when was the last
time a petitioner didn't get
utterly assfucked
by a wish-granting?
Yeah.
And yet...
I'll do you better.
There's a problem
far greater than fairies.
Solve it, they're nothing.
I'll send you on an epic quest.
That's...
Uh...
Wow, that's great. Thank you.
It's just...
(SIGHS)
My people need help.
They sure do. Today.
The Fairy Queen is sitting
on my throne as we speak.
Do you want your
magic back or not?
Will it not solve
all your problems?
I mean, yes, but, it's just...
How long does a
quest like this take?
A good season.
Right.
My kingdom is in trouble now.
You are a good king.
But it is time to
become a great one.
In order to do that,
you must travel to a land
where you are no king, no
Magician, just a vulnerable man.
Honestly, that sounds like
something I might really fuck up.
Yes, or it wouldn't be a quest.
You have friends, don't you?
I used to.
The one-eyed conqueror,
the traveler, the warrior,
the fool, the god-touched,
the lover of tomatoes,
and the torture artist...
Wait, which one is that?
You lost me there. Nevermind.
You have a brother of the
heart with the foppy hair.
That would be Quentin.
You're parts of one whole.
No one can do this alone.
Okay.
FYI, I can't contact them
or reach them in any way.
You must find the
book with no author.
A tale for children,
but they're hardly that.
There is the key... Or, the
keys... In a place called...
Public Library.
In the shire of Chester
in the land of New Jersey.
Again, that sure
sounds like Earth.
Eliot, the quest I bestow on
you is the task you were born for.
Claim it.
(CLEARS THROAT) Abigail,
talking-animal question.
So, bunnies.
(SQUEAKS)
Her Sluggishness has
noted that you are aware
of their messenger abilities.
So, that is what the Fairy
Queen uses them for?
Bunnies move easily
between worlds.
And do they serve her?
And if so, how loyally?
Every bunny for itself, Majesty.
Thank you.
Need help.
Love, Eliot.
Q.
I think this is it.
The Tale of the Seven Keys.
No author, I mean, I can
feel something coming off of it.
Interesting.
Yeah, if by interesting,
you mean, blank, sure.
Quests never give away the farm.
You've gotta earn everything.
Jules, this is our quest.
And we're already on it.
BUNNIES: Epic quest. We have to.
Map from the
book. Work together.
Also I think... Eliot.
Epic Quest. The Great Cock.
It's called After
Island. A back door to...
The Great Cock. Epic quest.
Keys. Here's the deal.
Epic quest. All seven keys.
Here's the deal. Epic quest.
Just shush for one
second, please.
Uh, that one.
Put him first.
FEN: Your father and
I are so proud of you.
Okay... (CLEARS THROAT)
We are go for epic quest.
You are indeed a brave king.
I am indeed a guy with not much
choice, but thanks for rounding up.
We're looking for keys.
Q and Julia believe
whatever the keys unlock,
will help restore magic.
And they think the first
key is here in Fillory.
Excellent.
Some place called After Island?
Oh.
It lies beyond our
border, Majesty.
You would be venturing to
strange lands not your own.
So, not the friendliest?
It is said that even the Outer
Sea itself wishes ill upon our king.
Some have sailed before you...
And how'd that go?
They drowned.
Oh.
Well, how do we prevent that?
I wish I knew, I only...
I know.
I know exactly
the boat you need.
(MOANING AND GASPING)
Okay! That's enough.
Let's talk.
So transactional.
What do you want
with a Lamprey anyway?
It's more what the
Lamprey wants with me.
(CHUCKLES) Oh, shit.
You poked the wrong
bear, sweetness.
Just tell me what you know.
Please?
Well, if you could do magic...
Yeah, well, I can't.
So...
So, you're down to an
early warning device.
An alarm, if you will.
So, just maybe, you
still got time to run.
Okay, fine, I'll take it.
What, is that a joke?
I gave up jokes 80 years ago.
Tired of being misunderstood.
So get one, and keep it
on your person at all times.
Buena suerte.
Ah.
(DOORBELL DINGS)
Just a side of bacon, please.