Previously on The Magicians...
Christopher Plover. The
children's book author?
You're familiar with my work.
I've read Martin Chatwin's book.
You're the pervert who
turned him into The Beast.
The age-suspension
spells Martin used,
it must still be
keeping me alive.
I don't know what this signal is,
but I know why it's targeting me.
And I'm gonna figure out...
Whoa! Hang on.
Merritt, you don't know
what that's gonna do.
You're right.
What...
Ever since I found this
page, I knew it was important.
It's an instruction
manual. ALICE: For what?
The World Seed. It can
grow into almost anything.
Even an entire world.
The Couple has been looking for
the World Seed page a long time,
and they are not good people.
And they know I
have what they want.
Pregnant.
Shit.
Really appreciate it if we could
keep this between you and I.
Of course.
Let's go find our
books, shall we?
You better be
able to speed read.
No!
Okay, so what if we locate
the tree from Seb's tattoo
and chop it down? Would
that sever this conduit?
In theory, yes.
He would be mortal,
and 100% stab-able.
Jesus, cock and balls.
What's keeping Julia and El?
We just murdered the goddamn
king back there. They should act like it.
Ooh, sorry. Probably
just Julia's toe worms.
Hey, we should stop
so she can catch up.
You've got toe worms, and
you're moving at a normal speed.
Oh, I'm just used to... Hey,
what happened to your eye?
I lent it to Josh.
What happened to his eye?
Nothing. He's an idiot.
He went back to warn Tick and Rafe
to get out before things go shit-shaped.
Okay. Wait, and
so why did you...
I'm worried, so I'm keeping
an eye on him, okay? Christ.
Oh, it's a pun. I get it.
Because you gave him your eye.
Shut the fuck up, Fen.
Okay.
Julia, you have to
hurry. You okay?
Yeah, I'm just, um,
a little out of shape.
Okay, don't mean to push,
but since we don't know
how the Centurions
will react to Seb's body,
and you were intimately
involved in making him dead,
we should probably
move more quickly.
Uh, Eliot? ELIOT: Uh...
I wouldn't if I were you.
Seb.
Surprised?
Take them.
Uh...
Shit.
Sorry about that, Quentin.
Lame-ass Welters nerd.
Merritt?
What? What happened?
You tell me. You said
you were a Chatwin,
you ripped off your patch,
and then you disappeared.
Where's Julia?
And Lipson, and...
You've been gone three weeks.
What?
It was just a room.
No windows. No doors.
No one else there.
That's all I remember.
You remember more than I
did when the signal grabbed me.
But I was there seconds,
at least I thought.
And who knows
how this shit works.
It's a weird one.
What do your rocks say?
That young Merritt isn't under any
memory curses so far as I can see.
My name is actually
Plum, remember?
I just have to own it.
Leave the ranks of Chatwins
who go by middle
names or nicknames
or, you know,
supervillain monikers.
Hi. Plum fucking
Chatwin, cursed freak.
Well, on the plus, you
don't have a brain injury,
you aren't psychotic.
And, uh, except for the disorientation
and a bit of combination skin,
you're perfectly healthy.
Whoa, whoa. So
what, you're done?
Well, first...
I'm gonna grab
a bottle of tequila,
so that I can really enjoy my
post-coma limited work hours.
But, uh, after that,
yeah, I'm done.
Look, this weird room, that's
more than we've had to go on.
It's also nothing
to go on at all.
The way traveling works,
you imagine a place,
you see it in your mind's eye,
and then just go. What?
You do know this is the
most you've actually talked
about traveling since
you took up here?
Look, my point is, you
don't have to point on a map,
just picture it.
You want me to go back.
Not really, because it's dangerous.
But just pointing out that...
That it's the only thing we
have, is what you're pointing out.
When I was a first year,
I had this stupid idea that
teachers knew a ton more than me.
They're above you.
Pretty much no one
knows dick about anything.
Especially Traveler shit.
What the signal is? Why?
No one's waiting
around to solve it.
But I've never traveled by
myself. And I don't know how.
And even, assuming you're
not completely a shit teacher,
I can't go back there.
And not alone. You won't be.
Oh, you stupid twat, that hurts.
Kind of late to ask for the
anesthesia spell. Mmm.
Done.
Now you can take people
with you when you travel.
Which is why it is
important that you...
Yes, I read the chapters you
gave me. I get the principles.
We start with baby steps.
All you gotta do is travel
us both across the lab.
Now, I'm gonna draw
a circle. Just aim for it.
And don't worry.
If you get lost,
I'll be right there.
Professor Adiyodi.
It's Penny.
Bringing you my troubles
has cocked things
up enough already. I...
I don't want to
make things worse.
Yeah, well, messing up my life kind
of runs in your family. I'm used to it.
You're not convincing me.
Which Chatwin
are you related to?
Honestly, I don't know.
My parents are British,
they have the proper sense
not to speak of the family curse.
Well, you are the
third Chatwin I've met.
First one was a beast who
basically tortured me when I was a kid.
But his sister, Jane,
she did everything
she could to stop him.
She changed time.
She was incredible.
So, family curse,
as far as I'm concerned,
the scales are even.
You could tip it either way.
Remember,
aim for the circle.
Here goes nothing.
I did it! I actually did it.
I honestly thought I was
just gonna, like, kill us both.
Like, straight-up
50-50 chance we...
Plum?
Yeah?
Where's the chalk circle? It...
It... Huh? Uh...
Uh...
Hey. Where's everybody going?
Dean Shiring got dial-up
in the computer closet.
We're going to use it
to read the Starr Report.
Or at least the blow job parts.
Dial-up?
The Starr Report?
That came out...
Oh.
I traveled us to 1998.
Yeah, well, I have a strong guess
which Chatwin you're related to.
The Couple? Never heard of them.
I hadn't either until they sent
a shiitake monster after me.
I'd like to know who they are
before they come
looking for me again.
Well, I know a guy.
He owes me, like,
three favors, so, let's see.
Thanks, Kady.
Now you owe me
three favors. Hmm.
He wants to meet.
You are never
gonna believe where.
The hell happened here?
We've been redecorating.
Alice and Kady, I'm so
very glad you've come.
Zelda? What are you doing here?
Rebuilding. Come
to see George, yes?
Didn't know you knew him.
Hmm. He's right over there.
Oh.
Hey.
How did all this happen? Are those
Hedges working with Librarians?
Honestly? It was you.
After you helped me
burn all those books,
I realized the Library needed
to be rebuilt from the ground up.
How did you convince
them to help you?
I'd been helping Kady and
Harriet remove Reed's Marks.
A sort of penance,
if we're being honest.
But suddenly I found myself
surrounded by grateful Magicians
just looking for
something to do.
What was that?
Our new recruits are enthusiastic,
but their education is spotty.
This branch is kept functioning
by very specific spells.
But proper casting,
especially here,
in the Circumstances of the
Neitherlands, sometimes eludes them.
Alice? This is George.
So, you're the one
the Couple's after?
Do you know them?
No. But I know a guy who might.
I need a day to track him down.
Thanks, George.
Two favors to go.
As long as you're waiting, perhaps
you could help us with a problem?
I've pulled some volumes from
the Poison Room. Highly dangerous.
You're some of the few I
trust to look through them.
And what are you looking for?
A way to fix magic.
Unless you have something
more important to do?
Thank God I got
past the Centurion.
How the hell is the Dark King still
alive? We cut down his tree. Stabbed him.
This doesn't seem possible.
El said he's a healer. Maybe he
cast something with his last breath.
I don't know. But our
friends are back there.
I can see Josh hiding out, so he's
safe for now. But Julia and Eliot?
Did they get back
here before us?
Hey. Who the fuck are you?
Cello. Squirrel. Daffodil.
Okay.
Uh, Margo, what are you doing?
Life lesson, Fen.
There's always a point
where you can decide,
"That's not my problem."
Sir Arthur Conan Doyle.
We have friends to
save, a Dark King to re-kill.
Hang with Mad Libs
pedophile all you want,
I'm going back to
double-tap the motherfucker
like he's Osama and
I'm SEAL Team Bitch.
No, no. Excelsior in springtime.
Excelsior in springtime.
Whatever you say.
Wait. I think he's trying
to tell us something.
Exactly. About Fillory?
And the Dark King?
Charcuterie.
Either he had a stroke, or some
whimsical Fillorian shit happened to him.
Secrets and blueberries.
Spongy walrus hat.
On the edge of the Burnt River,
there's an insect called
the Tongue Twister
that supposedly crawls into your
skull and confuses your words.
Is that like a stroke?
Ah. Fingernail clippings.
Hold up. Somebody's near Josh.
Son of a... Shit, it's the
Dark King. He's coming.
Wait, no. God damn it.
What happened?
Josh put my eye in his
pocket, so I can't see shit.
If he's got something to say about
the Dark King, we need to know it.
How? If he's got Tongue
Twisters in his brain hole?
I know a guy.
He's an idiot, but he
might be able to help.
Professor Fogg?
Hi.
Ski masks.
Big trend in the future?
Trying to avoid a time paradox.
Ah. Smart. And stupid. You don't
think I'll recognize your voices?
Kind of counted on
you being a little drunk.
Hmm.
It's the afternoon.
Next time, try Pinter's
facial distortion.
Literally made for
this sort of thing.
Unless you, you
know, prefer this look.
Yeah, look, um, what do you
know about Time Travelers?
They're a myth.
And yet here we are.
Well, it seems like you
have a gift, Miss Ski Mask.
But poor aim.
Can you help?
Maybe.
This time bridge is set
for a fixed moment in time.
But we can remove
the temporal compass,
and adjust it to help you
navigate back to, uh, 2020.
Can you feel the
vibration? Yeah.
Good, it's pointing
towards home.
Thanks, Professor Fogg.
No, gosh, thank you. Thank you.
This might all make an
excellent dissertation.
Might even be worth a promotion.
Oh, God, no. Me, Dean?
No. I'd have to pay off a
lot of colleagues' wives.
Good luck.
Did it work? Are we back?
I don't know.
Excuse me. Be a pal and sweep
up the men's dining room? Thanks.
Nope.
How is Seb still alive?
I have no idea.
I mean, you saw me run
him through with a sword.
Which is not something I expected
to do to anyone, kind of ever.
You okay?
Yeah. Um, I just have a
problem, and it's getting worse.
How did you get so pregnant?
The usual way, except
it's Red Monkey Month
so everything
grows a lot faster.
I guess, congratulations?
Oh. Thanks, I think.
Present deal aside, the
whole "circle of life" of this,
is kind of very moving.
In a far less
dungeon-y time line,
I'd definitely be asking you to throw
me a baby shower right about now.
I know a spell that makes
sparkling cider get you hammered.
Perfect loophole
for this situation.
Glad to see you're
keeping your spirits up.
I wouldn't want it
gloomy down here.
And now I've killed
the conversation.
Are you going to execute us?
I can't.
I need your help.
Basic problem's the same.
We can't fix magic on Earth.
We did some stuff to the moon,
and she's mad, and she's a...
A monumental cunt?
Evidently. So she's
screwing up Circumstances.
My Akkadian's rusty,
but I... I think this says that
we can win the
moon's favor if we...
Virgin sacrifice.
Okay. Well, that's out.
Not to mention the method
of death is pretty gross.
Ew.
That bad, huh?
No it's just the
lights flickered,
and now there's peanut
butter in my turkey sandwich.
I thought wonky casting
was an Earth-specific problem.
I think this issue's more basic.
All the new people
learning Library operations.
Including culinary charms.
At least Zelda can reassign
Hedges that cast for shit.
The moon, however,
has job security.
You're fired, Moon.
Wait, what if we could?
Fire the moon, I mean.
Kind of remember hearing Earth
would end in fiery apocalypse.
No, I'm saying, what if we got
rid of it and made a new one?
That's batshit.
This book is on earthworks
magic in the South Pacific.
You know, how to create
an island out of nothing.
Yeah, that's not
exactly the same.
These books are
from the Poison Room.
Not for amateurs.
If there's a way to make a
new moon, it'll be in here.
Say "ah..."
Fire engine.
Well there's your
problem. He can't talk right.
No shit, Gordy. We
wanna know why.
Check his ears.
Anything in there?
Hmm.
Just your usual ear stuff.
Hold up. What is that?
Give me a minute, it's
deep in there. And blammo!
Yep, it's a Tongue Twister.
How ya feeling now?
Linoleum.
Shit. It wasn't the bug.
Well, maybe not this one.
There's a bunch in there.
Hundreds.
Thousands. All down
his... Mmm... Spinal bones?
I can get 'em out.
If I can keep one.
I'm sure I'll regret
asking. Why?
For the respect.
So I can write a...
A...
Paper?
Right, one of those.
It'd be huge for me.
I'll never get laughed
out of VetCon again.
How long is it gonna take?
Don't know. Looks
like each critter
has an energy-meridian
tether, as well as a physical one.
It's like he's possessed by
a thousand little spirits. So...
This is a possession problem?
No, it's a bug problem. And
those bugs are possessing him.
Don't worry, I deal
with cats all day.
They are possessed
like you wouldn't believe.
Rhubarb.
That should do it.
He's bleeding
out! Call a doctor!
Oh. Yeah.
1920.
Maybe Fogg flipped
a digit, setting it.
If we can figure out what he
got wrong, we can fix his mistake.
I just wish we had
some instructions.
Excuse me?
This area is for
students and faculty only.
I am faculty. I am a student.
And I am the King of Siam. Out.
Look, dude. I don't know what...
Hey, getting in a fight is
only gonna make this harder.
Thank you.
If we can't get in the Library
then we are stuck here
reenacting The Help
with these casually
racist white people.
We don't know anyone
here who can help us.
I swear, Helen, I could
sense something...
Someone watching me in the
bath, like... Like a pervert ghost.
Maybe we do know
someone who can help.
"Of one not easily
jealous, but being wrought.
"Perplexed in the extreme.
"Of one whose hand.
Like the base Indian,
"threw a pearl away,
richer than all his tribe."
You're telling me
this guy whacks off to people
he watches from the astral plane?
Yeah.
The melting mood...
Do we really need his help?
Look, in a hundred years he's
gonna be a really nice guy, so...
Thank you. Thank you.
It just... It...
It won't feel like Othello
until I'm in blackface.
Okay, so, uh, he's
got a ways to go.
Hyman, hey.
Do I know you? Uh,
yeah, I'm Penbrooke...
And this is Prune.
Ah. And you are
visiting mystics?
Right, from India and...
And the... The Dark Continent?
Okay. God give me strength.
Yo, listen, we
needed some help...
I'm sorry, I'm late
to Phrenology.
Okay, buddy.
Listen up, dude,
we know you're the
pervert ghost of Brakebills.
So either you help us,
or everybody knows.
I've looked through
everything Seb gave us,
and seems like some
sort of communication spell.
It's going to take
the three of us.
I have no clue
what it does, though.
El? Help, here?
What's the point?
Once we're done, what reason
does he have to keep us alive?
I don't think
he'll kill us. You.
I saw the way he talked to you.
Nobody is that hurt
if they don't care.
I attract the best
guys, don't I?
You attract basically everyone.
And with that
broad of an appeal,
you're bound to magnetize a
couple of questionable monarchs.
We will figure
something out, I promise.
Okay.
Help. Okay.
This sigil, it looks sort of like
part of a messenger charm
that you would use to send a
letter across a lake or a river...
Oh, shit. Yeah.
Um, I recognize it.
Um, it was in a book I was
reading right after Q died.
I was... I was
doing a lot of, uh...
Grief-googling?
He wants to do a seance.
But I thought
those were bullshit.
Not always.
It's dark magic. And
it can go very wrong.
I never could figure it
out, but maybe he did.
But why cooperative? Three
people means a lot of power.
Well, he must be trying to contact
someone who's been dead a very long time.
Oh, shit.
I think I know who.
Hello, Professor Frank.
Those two can't be in
here during regular hours.
Uh, but they're with me.
I'm doing a report on
magic of the West Indies.
They are translating for me.
Huh.
Nothing... There's nothing
here. It is all theoretical.
There's not even an entry
for a temporal compass.
As far as I can tell, time bridges
haven't even been invented yet.
Uh...
Time bridges? Like
Professor Sato's work?
Is that...
Hey. Yeah?
This looks exactly
like the time bridge
that we pulled the
compass out of.
He's building it.
Today.
That can't be a coincidence.
But still, it doesn't
make any sense.
I mean, why take us here
to today? And why 1998?
Wait, wait, wait. You traveled
to the Year of Our Lord 1998?
Horsefeathers. What, was the
world overrun with metal automatons
taking over all the work of men?
Yes.
Look.
"September, 1998."
I was holding it when
we traveled to 1998.
And then, I was
holding the compass
that was made today
when we landed here today.
Oh.
They're totems.
Remedial Traveler students
sometimes have trouble
picturing their destination,
so holding an object from
that place can sometimes help.
Okay, so that, but
time instead of space?
So I guess in
order to get home...
We need something from our time.
"From our time." I
was gonna say it.
Hey, you know this language?
Um...
The front half looks
like Old Church Slavonic.
The back half, I
don't recognize it.
No, no, no. The
Slavonic part I could read.
It's something about a seed
that could grow into anything.
What if it could
grow into a moon?
I don't believe it.
What?
That this book is missing a page.
Something called the World Seed.
How do you know what it's about
if the page is missing?
Because it's what the Couple's
after. The page. And I have it.
What?
Meanwhile, we're trying
to solve a different problem.
But then...
But there's this book that
happens to be the same book
that the World Seed
page came from?
Coincidence,
synchronicity, or...
I always assume trap.
How much do you
trust the Hedges?
About as much as
you trust the Library.
Hmm.
There's no way this isn't a con.
We're looking for an answer
that requires unusual power.
Something unusually powerful.
Logically, it's gonna be rare,
lot of people wanting it. Right?
So, not weird, right?
Just saying.
True. I mean, it can't
be this easy. Can it?
Maybe everything's been
really hard for a long time,
and we caught a single
fucking break for once.
Oh, hey, a Smoothie
Castle card from 2009.
So we don't have
anything from 2020?
Great, so we're just stuck in
this backwards-ass place here.
Did you do this?
Do what?
Brakebills has
given me the icy mitt.
I've been streeted.
Oh, my God. Expelled.
Someone ratted
me out to the faculty.
Well, it wasn't us.
Someone must've
overheard our conversation.
Well, eavesdropping on a private
moment? Who would do that?
You. Constantly. Which is
why you're getting expelled.
Did you give her permission
to use irony in this way?
Good riddance
to the both of you.
This is bad.
He was supposed to
stay, get caught projecting,
and then be trapped when
someone hides his body.
Okay, so then expulsion
actually saves him
from being trapped in
astral purgatory for a century,
and saves generations of
Brakebills women from being spied on.
You don't get it.
If Hyman doesn't get trapped,
he can't help future me.
And future me can't
save magic, and we lose it.
Forever.
We need to fix this.
But how? By trapping
him ourselves?
Exactly.
Wait!
On the bright side, this is my
chance to finally go to Europe.
I hear Weimar Berlin's got
some swell erotic attractions.
I bet.
God! What am I doing?
I came to Brakebills
to learn, you know,
and the lesson of my
expulsion is clear as a creek.
Maybe, and I know this is crazy,
but maybe it is wrong to
spy on people in the shower.
Well...
I know. "Then why
did God give you
"the ability to spy on
people in the shower?"
Look, I can't tell you
how to live your life.
But, um...
Look, being a Traveler
can feel like a burden, yes.
But not being a Traveler?
Not being able to use
your gift, it's worse.
Believe me.
There's no harm
in looking, right?
You know?
You're a good egg,
Penbrooke. Yeah.
Okay.
Uh... Hey, before I forget,
any idea how I can score some
tickets to the Women's Welters match?
It's in an hour.
Women's Welters has a match
tonight? It's not on the schedule.
Oh, it's a surprise match.
Yeah, uh, they're probably
in the locker room right now.
Uh-huh, uh-huh. Uh-huh. I see.
I am going to need to finish
packing by myself, in private, okay?
Yeah, okay. Um, cool. Great.
Uh...
Yeah, bye.
Okay, it worked. We
only have a few minutes.
Okay. Um...
Hear me out on something.
Yes, it's bad.
Magic's at stake. Do I have
to do the speech again?
I stole this from
Professor Sato's things.
Stasis charm. Freezes
the wearer in time.
Plum, the body isn't supposed to
be preserved, it's supposed to die.
Who says? No one
ever found his body.
Maybe we were the ones
who hid it in the first place.
Not how time works.
How do you know?
What matters is he'd still be
trapped, and still be on the astral plane.
Unless it's a shitty hiding
spot and Hyman finds it.
Unless he doesn't, and 100
years from now we can fix him.
What's the point of
having this stupid ability
if I can't change anything?
Who says there's a point?
You are born with this shit,
and you spend the rest of
your life trying to survive it.
Okay? Let's go.
Or you have it ripped away just
when you figured out you wanted it?
I am sorry your shit is broken.
But the Penny I've heard
about wouldn't give a damn
whether it fucks
the future or not.
He would do the right
thing for his friend.
I guess having your shit
break changes a person.
Okay.
So what kind of person
is new Penny gonna be?
Shit.
I know how to get us back home.
Let's do this and I'll explain.
Oh, okay.
He's gonna be sore
when he wakes up.
If he wakes up.
You ready to go? Yeah.
"Quentin Coldwater,
Welters..." How does that help?
I dropped it the day you
reappeared. When it broke, it...
Became a new thing.
Made the day we
left. So, shall we?
Yeah.
He's stable.
Thank you.
And talking words good.
My work here is done.
Respect, here I come. FEN: Oh.
Shit.
All right. Talk.
It's been centuries since
I've been able to speak.
It's so liberating.
You've been
infected for centuries?
Yeah. From the... Just after
your reign ended until today.
Tell us everything
that happened.
Screw that. What's
up with the Dark King?
Who is he, where does he come
from, and how do we kill him?
Well, I heard the
same story you did.
The Dark King showed up
shortly after the
arrival of the Takers.
That only he could
vanquish them.
So I was curious.
Who was this Magician?
What was his story?
So I sought him out.
And I was shocked to
discover that I knew him.
You are good at telling stories.
Thank you.
Now, in order to talk about who he
is, and where he actually came from,
we need to look further back.
To a time before Martin
Chatwin became The Beast.
Mmm. Shh. Really?
Long before he
discovered the Wellspring,
Martin had another
plan to make sure
that he never got
sent back to Earth.
A conduit spell to
tie himself to Fillory.
Once we begin, we will
only have a few moments.
Seb, we should talk about this.
Look, we know what
you're trying to do.
I strongly doubt that.
We know it. The Dark King used it.
Except we chopped down his tree.
But there's an essential fact
that perhaps you don't
know about the trees of Fillory.
You see, there are many,
but in truth, only one.
What kind of bullshit is that?
Yeah. I mean, I'm Fillorian
and I have never heard that.
You see, the roots of the
trees of Fillory intertwine,
such that they become one,
not just with each
other, but with the land.
And anyone tied
to that can't be killed
by just chopping down a single
tree or, pfft, even an entire forest.
They can only be stopped
by destroying all of Fillory.
Wait. So you're saying Martin
tried, but screwed up or whatever?
He was thwarted,
by someone heroic who
knew what he could become.
Martin's own brother, Rupert.
Rupert Sebastian Chatwin.
Oh, my gods, what a twist.
You're such a natural at this.
He realized that the only way
to stop his brother was sacrifice.
So he tied himself to the
conduit before his brother could.
When Martin discovered what
had happened, oh, he was furious.
He couldn't kill
his own brother.
But he could curse
him with eternal sleep.
The people of Fillory
thought he was dead.
What's happening to him?
Exactly what's meant to.
What happened?
You happened.
You brought surges of magic,
so huge you woke Rupert
up. And he brought the Takers.
And then when he
held them at bay,
the Fillorians, in gratitude,
made him High King.
But why did he do all that?
Yeah. If he was so good,
why did he become so evil?
Because while he slumbered,
he lost the one
thing he cared about.
The man he loved.
Rupert? Is that really you?
Lance?
Lance Morrison?
Rupert!
Yes. Yes, it's me.
Finally. You're here.
My love, my stars, my heart.
I sound like a fool.
You cannot know...
Do you know how
much I missed you?
What took you so long?
Lance, I've... I've been trying.
You left me.
No. You abandoned me.
No, I needed to stop my brother.
And now I'm dead,
and you can never die.
It's cold here. I'm so alone.
Oh, I've almost given
up so many times.
No, for, you see, don't.
I will not break my
promise to you. Okay?
I finally know what to do.
We'll be together soon. So soon.
How? Just wait by the door.
I've tried. I can't
pass through it.
No, I know. But you
will be able to soon.
That's why I reached
out to you, to tell you
to wait by the door.
Okay. Okay.
Rupert.
Listen to me. Wait by the door.
Eliot. What the fuck did you do?
And you actually think this
page might contain the answer?
Tell us what you need. Our
resources are at your disposal.
I just need to go and get it.
We'll send someone.
I'd rather get it myself.
A few Librarians, security.
Seems prudent to send one person.
You almost had me. Just peanut
butter and turkey sandwiches.
I'm afraid I'm not following.
We're in the Library,
where there's glitches
'cause of Hedges, right? Mmm.
So why do these glitches keep
happening during lunar intervals?
Why are the Neitherlands
affected by the Earth's moon?
Makes no sense.
Where am I, really?
Earth. Which you manage to
figure out every motherfucking time.
What is this? Some
sort of illusion?
Psychic spell.
Basically, you're in the Matrix.
Which means we're still
on Earth. Hence, glitches.
How many times have I done this?
Eighteen.
Been sending you back to the
beginning. It's getting tiresome.
Wait, the books, fixing
the moon. It was all just...
Bullshit. Starting with you
getting Kady to text me.
Who are you?
Come on. I'm insulted.
You've been asking about me.
The Couple.
Less impressive the
18th time you figure it out.
Look, you're sick of
this, I'm really sick of this.
Why don't we have this
convo in the real world, huh?
Not doing this 19 times.
Give me the
page, or I kill Kady.
How do I know
that's really Kady?
How do I know this is even real?
Only one way to know,
and that's to feel it.
What are you doing?
Phosphoromancer, right?
Please don't do this. Please.
I know you use
this finger a lot. No!
Promise.
Give me the page. If the
finger's still viable, I reattach.
Middle finger,
also very important.
Love spells need a ring finger.
Pinkies are crucial.
Well, Alice?
Okay.
Well, do you want my thumb, too?
Disappointed this isn't working,
because the next cut
isn't your thumb. It's Kady.
The page, or kill Kady?
What's it gonna be?
Okay. Okay, you win. It's yours.
It's fucking yours.
Oh, good.
Relieved. Now, where do I go?
Oh, hold that thought.
I forgot my pen.
Okay.
Is he all right?
What do you care?
It was never my
intention to hurt him.
You think that matters?
I lost someone, too.
And I loved him so much.
I know the pain.
It's not an excuse to hurt people
just because you want him back.
Maybe you didn't love
him as much as you think.
Because you don't understand.
I have work to do.
You see what you're up against.
Fillory can never be free so
long as the Dark King reigns.
One thing I'm confused about.
Where do you
fit into all of this?
Well, Rupert recognized me.
Oh, he's always disliked me.
He's the one who cursed
me with the Tongue Twisters.
Well, I shall find no happiness
in Fillory so long as he's around.
So after you leave here,
what? Just gonna hit the streets?
Oh, hardly. I shall write.
The things I have seen.
The stories I can tell.
His stories are very good.
Just not exactly
kid-appropriate.
Oh. Oh.
Vexing. Oh, flattery flophouse.
Did you really have to do that?
He seemed like such a nice...
Pedophile? He's
grooming you, Fen,
because you act like you're 12.
Oh, gods.
Remember, make sure to
lock on the right vibration.
Can you feel it?
Mmm.
It feels like home.
Here we go.
Hi.
I think...
I think... I think we did it.
Oh.
Shall I let go of your hand?
This... Did you...
No. Not on purpose.
I'm not sure how I
even did this at all.
Oh, why do I feel like I've...
Been here before?
Because this is it.
This is where the
signal brought us.
Okay, okay. I'll
just travel us out.
Yeah. Mmm-hmm.
Plum? It's not working.
We can't leave.