Previously on The Magicians...
The High King and I hereby
declare war on the Kingdom of Loria!
One cannot simply take
back a declaration of war.
My hands can't
cast spells anymore.
Help me, I do what I can.
I'm a member of The Order,
the keepers of the
libraries of the Neitherlands,
the greatest repository
of knowledge.
You're a Niffin.
Q, I'm not bloodthirsty.
I just want to be free.
Penny! We're getting you out.
Well, I guess I
could help for a price.
I wanna drive. For an hour a
day, I get control of your body.
Fine. It's a deal.
We're gonna make another you.
You sleep here, your
mind goes into the golem.
Eliot!
In the center of your being,
there's a tiny beating heart.
It's called a Shade.
It's what makes you feel
the pain will burn
you till there's nothing.
It's Reynard. He's back.
He hurt you too, didn't he?
My child is safe.
He'll never know
who he really is.
The test was positive.
You'll need to find a Mudang.
But you can abort it, right?
This is exorcism.
That thing is not human.
Did it work? Is it gone?
But, Julia, there
was a complication.
What do you mean,
"lost her Shade"?
When the Mudang cut
the demigod's soul out,
they nicked hers by accident.
Her Shade, it's gone.
Is she gonna be, like...
Honestly,
I don't know.
Good morning.
Jesus, what day is it?
Friday. Are you...
Listen,
I just want to thank you for
everything you did to help me.
You're looking at
me like I'm crazy.
I mean, are you?
How do you feel?
How do I feel?
I feel light.
Like a million-pound
weight's off my chest.
Come. So, what you got?
Anything that skins foxes?
Yeah, well...
So, back in the day,
Zeus and his, well, frat bros,
they ran around kidnapping
and raping with total impunity.
So, the Magicians, they'd write these
spells to protect their communities.
God-killing spells.
The one thing that they all
have in common is they all failed.
Maybe it just can't be done.
You know what?
We need to write our
own. We can use these.
There's some
pretty big holes, but...
I mean, a little ambitious.
We need to be ambitious.
Like Martin Chatwin facing
Ember and Umber ambitious.
It can be done.
But, you know, say
we get the perfect spell.
Think about the energy
it'd take to work it.
Right. See, Dana knew that.
She had her power source. We...
I got rid of mine.
Well, what about Ember in
Fillory? Didn't he help Alice?
He's completely AWOL.
Hmm.
Oh, my God.
Dana's baby.
Reynard's son.
You know, there is a
ton of lore on demigods.
They're powerful
in their own right.
Dana was talking
like he's still out there.
We need to find him.
Hurry up.
I checked your work, it's fine.
Nothing can break
a Word As Bond.
I must've overlooked something.
No hurting anyone.
No casting magic. No sex.
Trust me, you locked
down any possible fun.
I held up my end of the deal, Q.
Now it's your turn.
Or box me now,
because I'll drive you insane.
Midnight. My turn. Got it?
Quentin! Where the hell are you?
I'm just glad we managed
to sneak the golem out.
Is it me or is morgue
security ridiculously lax?
Well, I think stealing
corpses isn't generally a thing.
Should be, kind of fun.
Anyway, according to the healer,
the bridge should take
a few days to enchant.
Then his consciousness
can travel it
from the clay back to his body.
And there's that.
Magic brownout.
Wellspring. Not helping.
How often does
that happen? Lately?
Sometimes twice a week.
Sometimes twice an hour.
Affects anything
that draws current.
Completely jacks all spellwork.
We're still trying to fix it.
Shall we go see the patient?
How's it going?
Every time the magic stutters, they
have to start the enchantment over.
Enchant faster.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Is there anything else
that we can be doing?
Hold off the war till he's back?
I had a pigeon drop a confusion
spell on the Lorian castle,
so they're moving
slow about now.
How can I help?
Honestly?
You can go back to
Brakebills and check on Julia.
You know you want to.
If anything changes...
I'll enchant a two-way
mirror to Brakebills,
like when Rupert yelled at Jane
through the vanity
table in the books.
Hey...
Don't worry.
My takeaway lately is that
anything can happen at any time.
So just be there for
your friend while you can.
Here.
Hey.
Hey. How is she?
Well, she is...
Holy shit!
That info-matrixing spell
worked like a motherfucker.
Oh. Hey, Q. Hey.
So, I found a hospital
outside of Hoboken
that took in a surrendered
newborn August 20th, 1976.
Holy shit.
Jules, what are
you... I have to go.
No, you need to
stay behind the wards.
Reynard is... Reynard
could give a shit about us.
Think. If he was gonna finish
me, he'd have done it by now.
So let's take advantage of that.
Uh, Jules, no. Look, she's
right. You're safer here.
No offense, Q, I didn't
actually ask your opinion.
Thanks, though.
Julia, wait!
Hi, Julia.
Thought I'd forgotten about you?
You seem like the
type to move on quick
when you're
finished with a girl.
Eh, generally.
Unless they're
carrying my child.
I was protecting you.
And what did you go
and do, you little bitch.
Now, Dana wouldn't tell
me what I wanted to know.
And it got very,
very painful for her.
But you have more common
sense than she does.
Tell me where her son is.
Hmm.
I don't know.
Mmm.
You're different.
Someone's had a little,
uh, Shade amputation.
I like it.
I know you're there.
Boy.
Quentin.
All right, run. Go on, run.
I'll give you a head start.
I get it, you wanna
keep me safe.
Thank you. I'm saying, I just
can't sit on my thumbs in Fillory.
Look, you had the thing
before, the Haxenpaxen,
that was making you invisible.
Right? So, we're in Fillory.
There's a lot of crazy shit
here, so find something else.
Then you can go
back. You don't get it.
There isn't time.
Hmm. She's
right, Q, there isn't.
It's my turn soon.
Tick tock.
Uh, okay, look, I
am going to go back.
I'll help Kady. We're
gonna keep working.
Margo. Uh, Julia needs to stay
here for a while. It's an emergency.
Fine. Thank you.
Nice place.
Tick tock.
Dude, you okay?
I'm fine. Nothing to see here.
Using the gold you procured,
we have been able to
amply fund the infantry.
Now, as for Loria...
Some 8,000 troops are
headed to the border.
So we're totally outnumbered.
Perhaps not.
Our spies have spotted
their Master Magician Ilario
at the edge of the woods.
That bald illusionist dick who
disappeared the entire castle?
We suspect he has enhanced
the number of troops with trickery.
We believe the actual
numbers are under 3,000.
I like those odds.
There is also less good news.
Said troops appear
to be amassing
at the edge of the
One-Way-Forest.
A forest of intelligent trees.
Yeah, I've read about it.
Jane Chatwin tried
to pass once and...
Uh, the trees have a
long allegiance with Loria,
and, begging pardon, an
excessive dislike of Fillory.
Can you move the trees?
They are rooted, Your Highness.
Yeah, I mean with an ax.
That would be ill advised.
They are the last of their kind.
Her Languidness suggests
violence against the One-Way-Forest
could cause civil
war here in Fillory.
Well, in the books, the trees
had some sort of ambassador.
A dryad?
You need to negotiate with her.
Your Highness, we
would not advise a...
That worked for Jane?
Sold. Great.
I'll come with you. Uh...
Custom strongly dictates that...
Yeah, I don't care.
Look, I know the books
almost as well as Quentin does.
I'm bored.
Let me be a little
useful, okay? Fine.
But I do the talking.
You just stand there and look
vaguely indignant or whatever.
Let's go.
Oh. Ah.
It wasn't enough.
I need more time.
To do what?
None of your business.
Relax. It's nothing.
What? I like to
read, is that a crime?
You can't be serious.
I have the right to know
what I've been doing.
All right, illuminated
manuscripts.
I remember this
from art history.
Yeah. A-plus for
you. I was just bored.
The monks got tired of writing the
same thing over and over again, so they
embellished in the margins.
Okay, well, a lot of
priests dabbled in magic.
Some exploded.
Yeah,
those monks were drama queens.
Okay. "There must be another
way to bring back our brother."
Are you looking for a
way to reverse it? No.
No, Q, I'm not.
Then why are you reading about all
these holy men trying to fix Niffins?
What does it matter, Q?
They always fail. Alice...
Oh, my God.
Welcome back,
Penny. I need a book.
Future Movements in Magic.
All right, follow me.
Don't they have a
copy at Brakebills?
It got destroyed.
I figure you guys have
every book here, so...
Unfortunately, you won't be
able to take this off the premises,
since you don't
have a library card.
Oh, no, no. I got one. Um...
I'm just the errand boy.
Mayakovsky?
I'm surprised the
two of you get along.
No, we don't. Believe me.
My hands won't cast.
He's the only one
that can help me,
if I finish fetching his
goddamn grocery list
so we can get started, so...
Ah.
I can put a rush on this book.
Thank you. If you're sure
that's what you really want.
Well, I really want
magic, so yeah.
But to pay for it with
servitude to a lying drunkard?
What's the alternative?
Us.
You?
Librarians?
The Order of the Library of the
Neitherlands are Master Magicians.
We can help you, Penny.
Okay.
What's the catch?
This contract initiates our
services in exchange for...
"Unlimited manual
and Magical labor?
"Bound in service to the
Library up to and after my death."
Are you kidding?
All very standard.
"For a period of no less
than one million years."
Okay, lady, are you joking?
No!
Okay.
Okay. Here's what Julia found.
August 20th, 1976,
baby surrendered at hospital,
uh, a nurse, Michelle Walker,
transferred it to a state social worker.
Uh...
And after that...
Nothing. There's no
record of adoption...
Okay, so where's
Michelle Walker now?
Merciful Sisters Cemetery.
Oh, shit.
Shit.
Shit what?
Just dead-ended again.
How's Mayakovsky?
Well, still a
jerk-off, you know.
What's wrong with you?
Hmm?
Your mind is...
- Doing something.
- Uh, no, it's not.
He's talking about me, Q.
Stop that. Stop what?
Stop singing Imagine
Dragons to get me off the track.
Lock it up, Q. Seriously.
Look, why are you always
poking around in me anyway?
Can't you just leave me alone?
Oh, I'd love to.
You leak, asshole.
Okay, I have got to, uh...
The hell was that?
Something's wronger than usual.
And he's a grown man.
Moving on.
Have you eaten lately?
You should eat.
Penny, we still haven't...
You know, talked.
Uh... I thought
we weren't gonna.
Yeah, well, that was when
this was some quick fun,
not hanging out 24/7,
fucking our brains out,
robbing banks thing.
That is fun.
That's funny.
Okay. Here's the deal.
I can't exactly study magic
unless I sign an insane contract,
or Mayakovsky
stops dicking around.
What I can do is
help stop the evil freak
that tried to rip your
heart out of your chest.
I'll sleep better with
him dead. Simple.
You wanna keep things
professional? Fine.
It's no big deal.
Good.
Greetings.
I am Margo, High
Queen of Fillory.
Habla Inglés or what?
Hi.
So, you the nymph?
Dryad.
I thought you were all girls.
- Listen.
I know your tree
buddies don't like us...
The rulers of
Fillory have a long
and tragic history of
arboreal disrespect.
Yeah, okay.
Look, it's a new day.
We're a kinder, gentler Fillory.
So we need to settle some
unrest with our Lorian neighbors.
Settle unrest?
You mean wage war.
No, we mean button
some messy shit up.
Help us here.
We wanna make this work.
Respectfully. That's rich...
Considering your king apparently
wouldn't deign to
come here himself,
sending two females.
Hey.
This is Julia,
Royal Ambassador.
And I am Fillory's one
and only High Queen.
Yes, the insult's been noted.
Passage is denied.
Good day.
Damn it.
Let's go.
Before you ask, no.
No luck with the adoption
records, no luck with the hospital,
and no luck with the nurse.
What's wrong with you?
Your wards are airtight.
You complained. So I fixed them.
Since when are you that
good at fixing anything?
Can we agree that I lose no matter
what I say and just stop talking?
So, Reynard's kid...
Yeah. So, the trail stops
when the nurse dies.
Shit. If only there was a way
to literally see into the past.
You know, I think I just
remembered. There might be a way.
Yeah, a time bridge?
We thought of that, there's
nothing close enough.
No, uh...
Time sight, literally.
We never studied that.
Uh, no, but I think Alice did.
Hmm, uh, can't remember.
Did she or didn't she?
She did, uh.
I think it was,
uh, extra reading
in metageology?
Nope. Nope.
Um, oh, I think, or, it was an elective
in Basics in Vedic Prognostication.
Nope. Nope. Um.
Give me an extra hour
tonight and I'll tell you.
Hmm. Was it, uh, something
we learned in Sunderland's class.
I mean, because we
never studied any...
Are you, like...
Having an ADD
moment right now, or...
No. Um...
Okay, so here's the thing.
Um, there was this one
time, Alice and I, right,
we were studying, we
were sharing lab materials.
And people didn't know this about
Alice, but she was really greedy
with her lab materials.
Um, and so she would offer to
help me for extra time with them...
None of this is
interesting to any of us.
The point is, I would say,
"Twenty extra minutes,
"one time offer,
take it or leave it."
Thirty.
Fine. Deal.
Is how that would
go, in a nutshell.
Phosphoromancy.
My discipline, idiot.
McKellan's got a scope that
can bend light into the past.
Phosphoromancy!
Ugh. I'm an idiot. Correct.
Shut up, I remembered.
Uh, okay, so, the viewing device,
it's in Professor McKellan's office.
Ooh, Penny...
See, even he can't wait
to get away from you.
Is this thing gonna work or not?
Eliot has shit to do.
He has to do the
work of crossing back.
Not everyone chooses to do so.
Okay.
Can you step out for a minute?
Fen, you too, sweetie.
Eliot.
You need to come back.
I know that you have a
constant low-key death wish,
but you can't leave.
They don't want me.
They want the High King.
I'm faking it, El.
So if you could just
please,
please wake up.
I set it to August 20th, 1976.
Holy shit.
What? What do you see?
Uh, just people waiting.
Yeah, here we go.
What?
Uh, nurse with a baby.
Uh...
What?
You gotta be kidding me.
What's wrong?
Ah, shit.
Dana did this.
To protect the baby's identity.
Even from spells 40
years in the future.
She thought of everything.
And back to square nothing.
Hi, I'm Julia.
God, been waiting hours for
you to get close enough to grab.
Think my foot fell asleep.
I will never help Fillory.
I'd sooner be skinned.
All right, boys, let him go.
Give us some air,
but stay close-ish.
Hate Fillory all you want.
I'm here for one thing
and then I'm off this planet.
An invisibility spell.
Strong enough
to hide from a god.
And why should I give it to you?
Because I might not
give a shit about Fillory,
but I do, as its
Royal Ambassador,
have access to its
guards and its dungeons,
and I'll use A to
throw you in B.
But help me, and
I'll let you go free.
I don't believe you.
Your loyalty will always
lie with... With me.
My loyalty will
always lie with me.
Drill a hole in it. Wear it.
No god can sense you.
Thank you.
You're free to go.
Hey, dryad boy!
Come on out. I saw
you in there, sweetheart.
Negotiations are over.
Go home.
I brought you something.
A small token of peace.
It won't change anything.
Just give it to your bosses.
I'm trying to fix this.
Thank you.
I've been looking for you.
You've lived here since
the Bush administration,
but you're thousands
of years old.
You're an Anglerbeast.
That's stupid.
You play too much
Dungeons and Dragons.
You knew a man, a long time ago.
He was special, and
he lived in a monastery,
a Master Magician.
Friar Joseph.
Ring a bell?
I wanna know
everything about him.
Well, in the
parlance of your time,
fuck you, pay me.
Fresh meat.
Newborns are the sweetest.
You know, I thought
about doing that.
But my time is very limited.
So I researched your
weak spots instead.
And you believed what you read?
That was stupid of you.
Oh, my God!
Alice, what did you do?
Relax.
Can't hurt anybody, remember?
But she's... A monster.
Technically I did good here.
I mean, there's a ton of
kid bones in this sandbox.
It wasn't cooperating,
so I had to use
enhanced
interrogation techniques.
To find out what?
We might wanna go before
the rest of it lumbers up here.
It's pretty mad at me.
What the hell were
you thinking, huh?
You burned down
the One-Way-Forest
while I'm trying to wiggle
us out of a full-on war?
Those trees were dicks.
They were endangered!
Now trees all over Fillory are
enraged and calling for action.
Do you have any idea
what you did, Julia?
Yeah.
I helped you.
Now you can cross into Loria
and kick their fucking
asses like you wanted to.
This is not how I
wanted to go about that.
Yeah, I know.
So, the really good news
is you didn't do anything.
Go back and tell the angry
tree lobby it was all crazy Julia.
You're welcome.
Look, I got what I wanted.
The rest was all a favor to you.
So banish me forever.
Send me home.
You know, in a sick way
I sort of admire you.
That being said, here's what
we do to loose cannons in Fillory.
Ready?
Guards!
Take this bitch to the dungeon.
You've got to be kidding me.
Now if you'll excuse me, I
have some damage control to do.
How to break a Word As Bond.
Reversing a Word As Bond.
Amending a Word As Bond.
It's not there.
That's the whole point.
You can't break it.
Why don't you do
something useful
and catch up on all the
classes you missed in Fillory?
This isn't working.
Yeah, tell me about it.
Keeping you a secret and trying to
help you while you do God knows what.
I have to ask for help.
I need to tell someone.
Great idea.
You think you know
locked up for crazy?
They'll put you someplace
you can't even imagine,
and they'll box
me up so quick...
All your efforts for nothing.
Is that what you want?
I want Alice back. I want
the real you. I want, I...
I can't help Fillory,
and I can't help Eliot,
and I can't help Julia.
And I just wanna do...
God, one thing for the person
that deserves it the most.
That's what I want.
God.
I understand.
Do you wanna know the truth?
You are a failure.
So stop using me
to try to fix that.
Uh-oh, look at the time.
Uh, wait, no. Word
As Bond, kid. My turn.
What are we drinking to?
Dead ends.
What?
I'm adjusting.
You used to hold
your liquor better.
Yeah, well, I used
to drink for fun.
Now I drink to get too fucked up
to go out and do anything worse.
Oh, God, I hope
this works as a mixer.
Oh...
Did I forget to mention
that I have to take this now?
Because I'm a junkie.
Ah.
Just trying to stay
straight long enough
to find Reynard without
falling the fuck apart.
Kady, we're gonna find the son.
You think?
I think
you and me,
put our minds together,
shit gets done.
Oh, God.
That is so stupid, it's sad.
And I don't think
you were listening
when I said I'm not
your fucking girlfriend.
Well, good. I don't want one.
Oh, God. Yeah, I get it.
Yeah, you're very tough, right?
Oh, God. Yeah, you're real cool.
You're not hearing me.
I am not your problem.
This isn't your chance to prove
that you're some kind of hero.
You want your dick
sucked, great, I can do that.
Then I'd love it
if you'd fuck off.
I am Liam McFarland
for BBC World News...
I had him stop
for fish and chips.
Best shop in Dublin, he said.
Are you kidding me?
Wait, uh, no, no. Just, uh,
just wait here for a second.
You portaled us to Ireland?
To do what? Where
are we going? Home.
It's done. We already did it.
Did what?
Alice, what did you do?
Uh, oh, uh, sir, where
did we just come from?
About three streets that way.
Great. Can we go back there now?
Right.
Wait, Quentin, no.
I'm serious, don't.
Q, stop. Hold on.
Q, please, wait.
Please. Quentin, don't.
You... Tricked you
with reverse psychology.
It was shockingly easy.
"No, don't go. Please."
Alice, what did you do? Nothing.
I can't do magic, remember?
I'm stuck inside you.
So you did it.
I believe you called to me
with something personal
at the place of
my transformation.
The music you got wrong.
Ponderous.
Ah, but the birds.
I did love those.
All my life I thought them
God's most perfect works of art.
Just look at them.
Bit annoying though,
all that cooing.
Now, why did you summon me?
Or didn't you mean to do that?
Maybe it was you.
You can see me.
Of course I can.
What on Earth are you
doing inside this boy?
Friar Joseph, I've
been searching for you.
I need your help. With him.
This crushable
little field mouse?
Seni baglamak. I bind you.
Seni baglamak. I bind you!
Silly boy.
I can't be boxed.
I read about you.
Priests studying magic
till they've gone too far.
That their brothers
have to box them.
Except sometimes the
boxing doesn't go right.
Yes, the occasional
Niffin did slip through.
That's what I thought.
Until I figured out that
it wasn't a handful who
escaped. It was just you.
You slipped away
over and over again
because you figured
out how to do it.
You can't be boxed.
I need you to teach me.
Al... Will you make him shut up?
I can't do anything
in here. No, I won't...
I'll do anything.
I'm serious.
Shit.
Let him go. If he passes out, I
won't be able to talk to you anymore.
Please show me how you do it.
I've been like this
for six centuries.
The things that I know
now you cannot imagine.
That's what I want.
Please, can I go with you?
You, with me?
You can't even get out of
this shoddy little Magician.
How smart, how
able could you be?
How could you help me
with anything worthwhile?
No, no, listen to me.
It's not that simple.
But it is.
Free yourself.
But I can't! The trap is...
Find a way.
Then find me.
Then I will show
you a secret or two.
Because then you'll have proven
that you deserve to know them.
Please!
Thanks for the birds.
Alice. No. No, no, no, no, no!
Alice, we can talk about
this. Just shut up! Shut up!
Shut up!
The sound of your voice!
Your breath, your
body, your mind,
your weakness, I can't stand it!
Stop it!
Did you do that on purpose?
No.
Then... You know what this is?
This is your body trying
to hold a Niffin inside it.
You can't.
Not for much longer,
or it's gonna kill us both.
Well? Did it work?
No. But...
Well, then get out.
Okay, look.
It's gonna be okay.
I'm pregnant.
We're about to go into
war. We need the King.
I need my husband.
Well, you got me.
I'm gonna take care
of you and the kid.
I will untangle this
war shit somehow.
I know the High
King has the power,
but I will hunt Ember
to the ends of the world
to have that stupid
rule rewritten.
Everything El promised,
I'm gonna deliver. You hear me?
Yeah.
Listen to High King Bambi.
You're alive!
Nice of you to join us, asshole.
Really does sound like
you've got it all handled.
I do.
But it's more fun with you.
From the book of Dana Wallens.
"His adoptive mother christened
him John Spencer Gaines."
Oh, my God.
You found his name.
Stole, technically.
But I think The Librarian might let
it slide, since now I'm an employee.
What?
You signed that insane
contract? Yeah, it's okay.
How the hell is that okay?
Because I get magic back.
At least The Order's
upfront about what shit costs.
Plus, the way I see it, I should
already be dead by now, you know?
So, this is all bonus.
Who gives a shit
about all that future?
Did you do this for me?
Not just. But...
Yeah. You know, yeah, I did.
Were you not listening
to a word I said?
Yeah, I was listening.
But guess what, it's not up to you
to decide if you're worth my time.
I get to do whatever
the fuck I want with it.
Even if it is spend it on a girl that
threatens to bail all the goddamn time.
Because, guess what, Kady?
I didn't think I was ever
gonna fucking see you again.
And that put shit
into perspective.
I love you.
Okay? Deal.
Shit.
Okay. Enough.
What the fuck?
Can we do this some other time?
- No.
First your mind was weird,
then it got locked up,
and now you're bleeding.
Are you high, are you
possessed? What's...
Why do you care?
Because, like it or not,
we're the closest thing
you have to friends.
Yeah, glass jaw. Not a surprise.
Don't look at me. Incept him.
I'll give it to you,
you're practical.
Get out of here right now!
Alice is in there!
What? I don't understand.
Neither do I, but she's in there,
and she just tried to kill me!
Okay. Well, what
the hell should we do?