QUENTIN: Previously
on The Magicians...
You know, it should have worked.
The spell we did to
contact my brother.
I mean, I went over
it, like, a million times.
Wait, you don't want
to try it again, do you?
No! No! No! I bind you!
I bind you!
(CHANTING IN TURKISH)
Why did you think
you had to save me?
He was gonna kill you.
I'm done here, for good.
You should be happy.
When are you gonna
tell me what all this is for?
Bigger, better magic.
MARINA: Let's
go steal their shit.
He's not gonna wake up. Ever.
Marina is a psycho!
You think Brakebills
cut you off from magic?
(SCREAMING)
You don't know "cut off."
You can actually
move between worlds.
If the gift does
not kill you first.
WOMAN: Please, help me. (GASPS)
I have a full schedule
today, Quentin.
What? Uh, I just, um...
The point?
What's gonna happen to Julia?
Ah, yes.
Your hedge witch friend.
I'm going to kill her. I, uh...
(LAUGHING)
I'm...
I'm fucking with you, Quentin.
I'm not going to
do anything to her.
I thought you would erase her
memory, or something again.
Sure, then her buddies tell
her about magic all over again.
Then she bothers me again.
So, she's just gonna
get away with it?
I'm not the magic police,
Quentin. They won't be back here.
They know what'll rain
down on them if they do.
What they do out there,
it's not my business,
it's not yours. Do
you understand?
But don't you worry, hedge
witches tend to crash and burn
quite quickly all on their own.
I want the spells I'm
missing, so I can keep going.
I want the new ones she
stole because I helped her.
You're not coming inside.
Then bring 'em out.
They're locked in
her filing cabinet,
and even if I could, I wouldn't.
I don't want to
see you get hurt,
and Marina will hurt you.
She only helped you get out
of Brakebills jail to save herself.
Next time, you
will not be so lucky.
(LAUGHS) That's bullshit.
I earned that magic just
as much as her. Fuck, more!
It was my friend
that she used...
Your friend!
Look, Marina's the boss.
Life ain't fair. Woe is you.
Now, please, leave
before she sees you here.
(SLAMS)
Think of it as applying
for an internship,
and for outgoing students,
perhaps even a job.
Alumni come and
choose students to mentor.
I can understand why you've
been staying here, Alice.
I know you feel that
you've had to leave,
but I'd really like
you to come back.
This is just one small
corner of the world.
There's a lot more
out there to see,
and I'd like you to
see it. (SCOFFS)
I don't much like the
corners that I've already seen.
Alice, students
leave every year.
And I don't go searching
for every lost lamb.
You didn't invite me.
I had to sneak in just to
take the entrance exam.
I made a mistake.
I felt responsible for what
happened to your brother,
and I didn't want to cause
your family another loss.
Alice, I was wrong.
You are far too gifted
not to be with us.
Just come back for a week,
and if you don't like it, then
please, by all means, be a farmhand.
MARGO: This year, we're going to
win the alumni week Hunger Games.
My mentor last year
was a nun. Never again.
I specialize in feet.
Broken bones, warts.
I have some very interesting
stuff for fungi of the toenail.
99% of these mentors
lead to a lifetime of
soporific bourgeois magic hell.
Alice.
You're, uh...
Hi.
I'm going to get a drink.
Is Genji your aunt?
ELIOT: Oh, hey,
Alice. Is that Genji?
Do you guys know her?
Everyone does.
She runs a retreat.
It's like Camp
David for Magicians.
If Camp David was run
by Caligula. (CHUCKLES)
I mean that in the best way.
Excuse me.
I feel really
terrible about, um...
I just thought, I
wouldn't be standing here
talking to me if I were you.
I don't...
I shouldn't blame you. The truth
is, my brother died five years ago.
Still, I...
I should go help her.
WOMAN: Can anybody hear me?
Anybody?
Ah.
Penny.
I'm Stanley. I'm your mentor.
Yeah, I didn't ask for a mentor.
I don't give a shit.
You are what you
are, so, I'm here.
What, a Pisces?
Travelers are rare.
Hadn't been one at
Brakebills in 35 years, I guess.
There's no discipline that
has more power and possibility.
I get it. It's an amazing gift.
It's a terrible,
life-destroying burden.
I zapped myself onto Mount
Everest. Lost my leg to frostbite.
I'd be dead if not for one
deeply confused Sherpa.
Had the lecture yet on
sticking with astral projection?
I don't watch Star Trek.
Travelers' training wheels.
Your body stays
here, your mind travels.
It's like being a ghost.
Meditating won't stop you
from having a wet dream
and waking up in
the Marianas Trench.
This will.
It works by binding
your body to Earth.
Astral projection only.
Full stop.
Won't make the voices go away,
but it might keep you alive.
How could you know about all
this and become a podiatrist?
This isn't Middle
Earth, Quentin.
There aren't enough
noble quests to go around.
Impress a good mentor,
and you won't have to worry.
How am I supposed
to impress anyone?
Mmm. When you're not
impressive. Glad you asked.
Welters. (GROANS)
What's Welters? The worst.
It's a game designed
a billion years ago
to keep students from
killing each other in duels.
It's like chess.
Kind of. Not really.
You use magic to take
squares. It's terrible.
I don't know. That sounds fun.
It's boring as death.
You're boring. You're boring.
There's gonna be a tournament.
It's supposed to be a
surprise, but I like ruining things.
Each discipline fields a team,
and the mentors
will be watching,
so, don't screw this up for me.
(INHALES)
Quentin.
(EXHALES)
Someone called the admin
office and left a message.
My dad's sick.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Hello, Curly Q.
Hey, Dad.
It's brain cancer,
but it's the good
kind of brain cancer.
Is there anything you can do?
Luckily, there are
some treatment options,
some really interesting
new therapies.
Um, do you...
Uh, do you feel sick?
Nah. I feel decent.
Eh, there was some
dizziness, headaches.
That's why I went in.
Does Mom know?
No, she does not as yet. I...
I could come up with
a reason, I suppose,
but the truth is
I just don't want to talk
to her. (CHUCKLES)
I'm worried about you.
You have brain cancer,
and you're worried about me?
Will you stop
saying "brain cancer"
like it's brain cancer?
(CHUCKLING)
I never see you anymore since
you went to this new school.
Thinking a lot about mistakes,
you know, things I
would do differently.
Quentin, by the time
you were 10 years old,
buddy, I couldn't sit
through one more card trick.
But if that's what makes
the world bearable to you,
then you go off
and do card tricks.
Don't try to be
something you're not.
You're studying
what now? Finance?
(CHUCKLES)
You really a finance guy?
I'm not a kid anymore.
Sure, yeah.
Dump out that bag.
Go on. Dump it out.
I'll give you 20 bucks right now
if there isn't a
Fillory book in there.
Yeah.
You know you're still
on my insurance, right?
You checked yourself into a mental
hospital a couple of months ago.
I didn't say a word. I didn't say
a word. I gave you your space.
But your prescriptions
are still coming here,
which is how I know
you're not taking them.
I don't need them.
(STUTTERS) I'm better.
I'm not trying to pick
a fight with you, son.
I'm just trying to
fix what I broke.
You think I'm broken? No.
I think we are.
(SIGHS)
Need a hand?
We should catch up.
I'm surprised you came back.
I still haven't heard
about your walkabout.
Yeah, well, it wasn't
anything too exciting.
I mostly fed and
killed chickens.
I mean, I wanted
you to come back.
We're friends, right?
Uh, I was wondering if
you could do me a tiny favor.
I helped you find
Emily Greenstreet.
Right.
See, I still haven't been
selected by a mentor yet.
I still haven't been
selected by a mentor.
We're such good
friends, I just...
I figured you could put a
good word in to your aunt.
If you wouldn't mind
putting in a good word for me.
I just feel deeply
that we are connected
and are meant to work together.
I'll see what I can do.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
(DOOR OPENS)
Julia? Hey.
Hey.
Sorry, I'm a little early. I
knocked a couple times.
Um, working on this big paper.
Hmm. I baked.
(CHUCKLES)
(MIMICS DRUM ROLL)
That's actually good.
(LAUGHS) It's,
like, people food.
What can I say?
You have no idea how
relieved I am to see you like this.
Like what? A happy housewife?
Better. Not, uh...
High all the time?
I was gonna put it a bit
more delicately than that.
(CHUCKLES)
Dad?
Dad? (VOMITING)
(GAGS)
We need to go to the hospital.
No, they'll just send
me home. I'm fine.
They need to adjust your meds.
I'm not taking any
meds, Quentin.
How bad is it?
I have a glioblastoma.
(CHUCKLES)
It's the most common
type of brain tumor.
It's also the most severe.
But it's treatable?
There are treatments available.
I chose not to pursue them.
(SIGHS)
You know, I googled
brain tumors just in general.
And one common denominator
that jumps out at you is
impaired cognitive function,
so maybe you deciding not to
pursue treatment
without talking...
My doctors agree with me, Q.
The type of tumor it
is, where it's located,
the person who
comes out of surgery,
might not be me.
I don't want you to die. Yeah...
I'm not too crazy
about it myself.
Then why are you giving up?
You remember this?
My dad and I used to
build model airplanes.
And this, this was
my absolute favorite.
Tenth birthday.
This is a Nieuport 28.
It's the same plane Quentin
Roosevelt flew in World War I.
(SIGHS)
When you were
about two years old,
you got your hands on this and
you broke off one of the wings.
I spent about an hour with
a hot glue gun, trying to fix it.
It ended up in about
20 pieces instead of two.
Quentin, sometimes trying to fix
something only makes it worse.
They match my 401(k) up to 6%.
It's just... It's crazy.
Dr. Meers?
My father's dying, and
I need you to fix him.
If Magicians could cure cancer,
why would anybody have cancer?
Because we like secrets.
There's got to be
some kind of spell.
Amazing things are possible.
But cancer, it's a part of you,
intrinsically, in a way
that magic can't separate.
Some people think it is magic,
an old curse we can't break.
So, then, somebody
must have tried.
Look, even if it's
experimental, I...
Do you know why Dean
Fogg didn't fix his eyes?
I guess I just
assumed he couldn't.
Treating something like that requires
an enormous amount of energy,
and that comes at a cost.
So does everything.
I can give you the names
of some journal articles.
Thank you.
Fair warning.
What you're looking
for might be impossible,
and it will require far more
energy than you can muster.
(WHISPERS) I love you.
Oh...
You baked.
You can have one, if
you think you can afford it.
Please, I have the metabolism
of a Jamaican sprinter.
And I need my strength
so I can properly wrap this
bottle of double-charmed sake
you can only get from a very
particular monk on Okinawa.
But I'm sure Genji is
gonna love your little cakes.
(CHUCKLES WRYLY)
This is war, bitch.
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
(METALLIC CLINK)
(GASPS)
(FIRE SIZZLES) (GRUNTS)
(GASPING)
(WINCES) Ow.
You should know better than
to mess with Google magic.
And starting an invisible
fire in your apartment,
still a fire.
You got lucky.
Pete, there's nothing else
for me to be besides this.
There's a whole world
of things besides this.
I almost burned
down my apartment,
and all I can think
about is trying it again.
Pete, there is nothing else.
Your boyfriend could
have done this for you.
I just got this stuff at Target.
Not that I'm complaining.
You know, a beautiful girl calls
you in the middle of the night,
never mind she's
a little intense...
(SCOFFS)
you answer.
There are other Hedges
and other safe houses.
I want to know where.
(BOTH PANTING)
MARGO: Quentin?
Quentin!
Where have you been?
You're late, and
this is mandatory!
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
MARGO: Welters is a
game of circumstances.
Simply put, we beat that squad
of flower-power ass-clowns
by casting to capture
those squares,
but the squares
won't make that easy.
Each one represents
a different location
and a different set
of circumstances,
so, you can't just cast.
You actually have to know how
to cast for those complications,
then adjust in a dozen ways.
If you get any one of them
wrong, the whole thing goes to hell.
(AUDIENCE GROANS)
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
TED: Will you stop
saying "brain cancer"
like it's brain cancer?
Sometimes trying to fix
something only makes it worse.
MARGO: Quentin. TED: Quentin.
Quentin!
Get your head out of your
twat and throw the damn globe.
(AUDIENCE MURMURING)
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
ALICE QUINN: Are you
sure you want to do that?
(WHISPERING SPELL)
(WIND HOWLING)
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
Q, are you controlling this?
Q, do something!
(WIND WHOOSHING)
(CROWD YELLING)
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
MARGO: One spell so
powerful, it wiped the whole board.
To Quentin!
(ALL CHEERING)
Q, come on, celebrate.
Who knew you had it in you?
Easily worth whatever
it's gonna cost
to replace the roof.
I don't care.
I get your dad is sick.
But like it or not,
you still have to think about your
future, and this matters for that.
One of the mentors came
up to me after the game
and asked me to come to the
Fertile Crescent to stalk a river dragon.
(SCOFFS) I said no, 'cause
grand scheme, none of that matters.
Why do you think you
were able to do that?
Please tell me someone
has pointed out to you
that magic doesn't come from
sunshine and ice cream, for any of us.
(SIGHS)
What you're born with, what
gets slammed on you as a kid,
what happens
now, like your dad...
A great way to get
the things you want
is to be so miserable, you
don't want them anymore.
What kind of system is that?
You know, why
can't it run on love,
or cocaine or something?
(CHUCKLES)
It's the universe
deep-dicking us.
Lie back and try and enjoy it.
(BOTH LAUGH)
Hi there.
Hello.
Pete sent me.
Show us your stars.
I can do you one better.
Um...
Uh, yeah. Um, welcome.
So, what's your name?
This is it?
How do you mean?
This is all you have?
(SCOFFS)
Well, if you know so much,
why don't you show us?
No, I didn't come here to teach.
At least show us that
cool cloud thing again?
Oh, my God. (LAUGHS)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
What day of the
week is it? (GRUNTS)
I don't know. You are
asking the wrong guy.
(BOTH GROAN)
What is this?
You joining the Navy?
Hey. What's wrong?
It's to stop myself from
traveling to an early grave.
Come on, you're
looking at it all wrong.
Look, every idiot on the
planet busts their ass.
For what? To buy the
freedom that you got for free.
It's not freedom
if I can't control it.
Well, then figure out how.
If you do, you could
go anywhere, any time.
I mean, look, not for nothing,
but you could be the
greatest thief who ever lived.
(BOTH LAUGH)
I'm serious.
Come on.
What am I gonna steal?
Hmm. Well, could start
by stealing me a sandwich.
(BOTH LAUGH)
The day-drinking
losers absolutely do not
fulfill the terms
of our agreement.
Our agreement?
I want somewhere better,
some place with real magic.
Please.
It's the number two
safe house in the city.
What? In all of New York?
A city of eight million people?
They got good magic.
It's not their fault that they're
the tortoise and you're the hare.
They're not even in the race.
Look, you want something better,
get out of town, go
to where the talent is.
You think the safe house in
Hoboken's gonna be better?
There's this place
in the Mali desert.
The marabouts
have this object magic
like nothing we have here.
We could go. Together.
Oh.
Can't.
Why?
Because I love my boyfriend.
(SCOFFS) You slept
with me two days ago.
You're welcome.
That's a pretty loose
fucking definition of love.
What, you think
that you and James
are gonna grow old together?
He doesn't know the most
important thing about you.
Then I'll tell him. You can't.
Why? Marina's rules?
Because it's dangerous,
for both of you.
Marina's rules no longer apply.
Julia, you're making a mistake.
Give me spells,
and I won't do it.
(SCOFFS) Right.
(SIGHS)
(VOICES WHISPERING INDISTINCTLY)
WOMAN: (WHIMPERS) Please help.
Okay, I hear you.
WOMAN: Please help me.
(CRYING)
Please come find me.
Please help.
Who the fuck are you?
WOMAN: Let me out of here!
Lady... You can't
keep doing this to me.
Come on, can you hear me?
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
WOMAN: Please help!
Please help me!
Let me out of here!
You can't keep doing this to me!
Whoa.
Okay.
(CHUCKLES) Astral projection.
All right, safety first.
WOMAN: Please.
Help. Hello?
Hello?
(CRYING) No! Please!
Let me out of here!
THE BEAST: You sound
talkative today, Victoria.
(SOBS)
Are you ready to talk?
I can wait all day.
Hello.
(GASPING)
Hey!
You lied to me.
First one in 35 years?
Yes, there was a girl
several years ago...
Yeah, well, I saw her.
While I was astral-ghosting
into some dungeon.
Turns out she's part of that
incredibly famous third-year class,
the missing third-year class.
I didn't know what
happened to her.
I figured she was dead.
You're supposed to
be my fucking mentor.
What the hell do
you want from me?
Christ!
Can you get her back?
Can I?
I don't know where
the hell she is.
You're the one who saw her.
And it's not my problem.
My advice?
Get that tattoo as
soon as possible.
What's your poison?
Um...
I don't know. I just
poured something.
(SNIFFS) Yuck. I have so
much to teach you about drinking.
It's a three-year program.
Graduate level. It begins immediately.
(CHUCKLES) Relax. This isn't
some mentor week full-court press.
Oh. Yeah.
Friends don't let friends drink
Long Island Iced Tea, Alice.
Eliot, I, oh... Sorry.
Sorry.
Um, Alice, do you mind if I
just borrow Eliot for a second?
How may I help you, sir?
What do you know
about Cancer Puppy?
(PUPPY WHIMPERS)
His name is Gerald, but
everyone calls him "Cancer Puppy."
He's sort of our
unofficial mascot.
Why does he have cancer?
Because he's 150, Quentin.
The enchantment just
keeps him a puppy forever.
It doesn't stop him
from being riddled
with every single disease
it's possible to be riddled with.
They've been taking him to a very
confused veterinarian in Ogdensburg.
Yes.
(WHISPERS) Hi.
What if I could fix you?
You're going to
cure Cancer Puppy?
I found a spell that might work,
but it requires a lot of energy,
and I think I might
have that right now.
A little. Just a little.
Okay.
(WHISPERS) Hi.
(SIGHS)
Okay.
(PUPPY YELPS, THUD)
Oh, no.
DEAN: You killed Cancer Puppy?
I was trying to cure him.
The spell you were
attempting to cast
is part of the class of
magic strictly forbidden
for all students.
It is also strictly forbidden
for everyone else.
I was just...
The best Magicians in the
world couldn't work that spell,
and yet you thought a
middling first-year student could.
I had to try.
Why didn't you fix your eyes?
The glasses show me
outlines. I can live with that.
If I had to choose between
my eyes or my hands,
I'd rather be able to cast.
It's on the first page of
your first textbook, Quentin.
"As Magicians, we are the
instrument and the medium.
"We are the chisel
and the marble."
I read it. I just...
But you didn't listen, did you?
Yes, you can save
someone's eyes.
You can even
save someone's life,
but you might alter
their soul in the process.
Then why bother?
What is the point of any of this, of
magic, if we can't fix real problems?
We can fix some things.
So, we fix what we can.
(ROARS)
(ON TV) Get rid of the flare!
Get the kids!
Get rid of the flare!
(DINOSAUR THUNDERING
AND ROARING)
MAN: (ON TV) Hail Mary, full
of grace. The Lord be with you.
(TV STOPS)
Dad?
Dad? Yeah...
It's okay. I'm just,
uh, a little tired.
Curly Q, what's going on?
You were right.
You do know your
kid. At least a little.
I could give a
shit about finance.
You know I just
want you to be happy.
I know. I get that.
I do. Come on.
This is where I've been.
I'm a Magician.
(GASPS)
Hot stuff. Hey.
You usually get me a scone, too.
(BOTH CHUCKLE) Um...
(CLEARS THROAT) I
tried calling, like, a lot.
Uh, anyways, listen, uh,
'cause this is important, so...
Okay, let me stop you one
quick second. Do I know you?
This isn't funny.
I'm sorry.
I think you have me
confused for someone else.
Um...
Sorry.
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
Little problem out here.
Pete. Now, fucker!
What're you thinking? Marina
could be back any second.
You need to leave now.
You're pathetic. I'm really not.
What is this, some
sort of sick revenge
because I wouldn't
screw you again?
I didn't do anything.
No, of course you
didn't. Marina did.
You couldn't get it up for this
kind of magic even if you wanted to.
You sold me out!
It wasn't to hurt you!
It was to save James from you
because you're out of control.
You want everybody's help.
You want to stand
on our shoulders,
and you haven't, not once,
taken any of our advice.
No wonder they didn't
let you into Brakebills.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I gave it a shot. I tried
to get into alumni week.
I just... I'm sorry.
I don't care about
becoming a magical podiatrist
or cataloging cryptids
or throwing huge parties.
Honestly... What
do you care about?
I don't know. I'm
still figuring that out.
Well, then this is the
perfect place to be.
Oh...
Charlie would be
so proud, sweetheart.
And you can always run
away to me whenever you like.
What are these two staring at?
Here she comes.
Get ready for the first
spanking you won't enjoy.
That's actually kind of hot.
Dears, while you are
both quite impressive,
honestly, the thought of
working with you exhausts me,
and I'm too vain to sacrifice
my looks in that way.
No, no. I mean,
we totally get it.
Maybe next year?
Sure.
Well... (SIGHS)
What do we need her for anyway?
We can start our own
bed and breakfast.
Retreat.
Hotel.
Bathhouse? Mmm.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Helps if you hold a pleasant
image in mind, such as a baby,
if you tolerate those.
Circumstances are more
favorable on a waxing moon.
That's not to say
that it can't be done.
It's cooperative,
so, partner up.
(INDISTINCT MURMURING)
Lab partners?
About your dad...
Yeah.
Well, can they fix him?
Can we fix him?
(SIGHS) Quentin?
You can get through this.
I wasn't sure if you
were gonna, um...
I'm glad you came back.
Looks like Game
of Thrones fan art.
Super helpful.
You should ask
Quentin and Alice.
Hell no. It saw you.
Penny, they're involved.
PENNY: All I can say is, it
was some kind of dungeon.
This was on the walls.
That's Ember's seal.
Uh...
Penny, I think
you were in Fillory.