Previously on The Magicians...
When the moment comes, do it.
Mayakovsky told you
what your discipline is?
Repair of small objects.
You did always excel
at minor mending.
I want you in my
life. I want that too.
The Binder knew Julia
had many questions.
And he knew the answer.
So you can help me
become a goddess again?
You're hoarding magic,
trying to become a god?
By becoming one of them, I can
rip their secrets away from them.
I redirected the power
I need into a reservoir.
You're saying Josh
is a fucking fish?
This should fix the whole
fish deal. I'll bring Eliot back.
My sister... I need
to find her a body.
So The Monster took Julia.
We need to find them.
We have the axes and the demon
bottles. You have the incorporate bond.
Casting an incorporate bond
strong enough to hold a god
would take an insane
amount of power.
The question is,
who put us here?
Our parents.
They're more vulnerable than you
think. If we can get to their realm.
We had a key. A scroll.
Julia, if you're in
there, I'm sorry.
Hey, Monster
Lady.
Adorable. So determined.
Maybe I'll keep you as pets.
Then again, I like my pets
strong, and you're weak.
You're already
fading, aren't you?
It worked. Q, the bond.
I don't know how long
that's going to hold.
We need to get to Brakebills.
I have something that can help.
We need to get her
help. Wait, where's Eliot?
We can't. We don't have enough.
We have to go back to the reservoir.
After we get her to a doctor.
No, he's right. We have
to go to the reservoir.
She's right.
Always gotta be a fucking twist.
In my office, under
my desk, trap door,
Popper 22 to unlock.
Don't put your hand in there.
Temperature's at absolute zero.
Should slow her down a bit. Go!
You're okay.
You wanna hurry that up?
Give her something
for the pain at least!
I just did. Twice.
Damn it. Here, my
last one. Use it on her.
You'll be okay. Stay with me.
Thank you, Henry.
Restraints, please!
You're okay.
What's happening to her?
So her body,
which is very weird,
it keeps trying to
close the wound
which is heavily enchanted
because the weapon
was also very weird,
and it just tears itself
right back open again.
Well, make it stop!
I hadn't thought
of that, thank you.
I will use this to keep
her comfortable and...
How long is she
gonna be like this?
We are not in what I would
call charted territory right now.
I think I might know someone.
It was a difficult
choice for Penny 23
to even call upon The Binder.
The Binder was certain, however,
that Penny 23 had made the right choice.
Julia, The Binder explained,
would remain in a cycle of
wounding, agony, for millennia.
Her body required
transformation.
Luckily...
this was The Binder's expertise.
Well, great. Let's
get on with it.
The Binder needed direction.
Initiate her long and arduous
journey to full goddesshood
or revert her body to
that of a mere human?
If it was up to me,
that'd be a no-brainer.
Yeah, but it's not.
It should be her choice.
The Binder paused for
Julia to make that choice.
Then dryly noted, she
wasn't in a talking mood.
The Binder assumed he was
speaking with her
husband or master?
No. No!
And yet the decision
had to be made,
surely not,
The Binder reasoned,
by this spinster nursemaid.
Uh, I run this hospital, Book.
Still, and The Binder replied,
stating the obvious
to the strident female,
someone needed
to choose for Julia.
Reed's Mark.
Best of bad options.
Damage was done.
I'd rather not die, so
it's fine on that level,
but also...
Look, I've no interest
in being Batman,
but there comes a point when
even selfish bros need to mobilize.
Six hedges, in
the last 48 hours,
were pulled into vans
by men wearing gray.
Woke up at home with
Reed's Marks. Jesus.
The Library just
stopped pretending.
They're rounding us up.
We need you.
You know what I
wanted to do with my life?
To be?
Penny's goddamn girlfriend.
I acted tough, but
all I wanted was him.
You're human.
I'm weak.
Kady, die when
less people need you.
Hey. Hey.
Honestly, I feel like
I've been run over
by six or eight
trucks, but I'm fine.
And by fine, you mean...
What does it look like?
We need to talk
about The Monster.
His sister. I saw
her plan, her goal.
And it's way worse than
slaughtering the entire Library.
They want to take it up with
their parents, the Old Gods.
Wait, what does that even mean?
I don't know, and
neither does she.
She just knows it would
feel good to kill them
and eradicate us in some
sort of insane nuclear winter
which she could give
negative three shits about.
Do they know how to
get to the Old Gods?
They found a spell,
uh, in the Library.
It opens a door to their plane.
My guess is The Monster
wants to find his sister,
finish the plan,
kill the Old Gods
or get smashed to a pulp trying.
That means smash Eliot.
Well, the upside to them
inhabiting our bodies
is she left this in my pocket.
Whatever's in this is
sure to unlock the door.
Holy shit, well done.
Well, shit, I was
ready to give up.
Welcome back.
Oh, oh!
Towel? Uh, yeah. Thank you.
So was it weird being a fish?
It felt, uh, very natural.
The weird part was
how you were so
incredibly selfless
and, no offense, sweet.
Which is... Not
on brand? I know.
Anyone who really knows me
knows that I'll do
anything if I love you.
Listen, Hoberman,
don't be stupid.
I'm not actually fun or
easy when I'm in love.
Fun and easy are overrated.
Oh, Christ. Not
my day. Oh! Uh...
Oh, hi! Sorry, I just un-fished.
So, anyone else super hungry?
I'm craving fish sticks.
Is that weird? You know
what? I'm just gonna go with it.
Where's Eliot?
Did you do it?
We got one so far.
You didn't save Eliot, did you?
Of course you didn't.
You cocked it up
trying to save Julia.
That bitch has a bulletproof
body. Not anymore.
We don't even know
if Eliot's still alive.
Yeah, it was a shit-show.
You don't even know
what the hell was going on.
You had one fucking job...
Yeah, fuck off, Margo.
Oh, Jesus Herbert Walker Christ.
You're predictable,
you know that?
Whoa.
What the shit? Oh, my God!
It just came out
of me so strong.
Guys, I think I have
some special fish magicks.
Oh!
Act out, right?
Or you touched the reservoir
and you got dosed up.
Yeah, that makes a
thousand times more sense.
But still pretty act
out worthy, no?
Hello, Kady. How are you, Zelda?
I understand you're angry.
No, see, that'd require
actual human feelings.
Kady...
You piece-of-shit,
pearl-clutching sociopathic...
None of this was
calculated on my part.
Everett...
I have believed in his
goodness for over a century.
Everett is in it for Everett.
If you are right,
then all the death,
all of it,
it's on my hands.
Look,
I know you're not evil.
Just the definition
of obedience.
I used to be.
Prove it.
Hmm. Man, I'm good.
Yeah. Great, thanks.
So you... So you feel okay?
Yeah, thanks.
And by thanks I mean thank
you for deciding that I should age,
grow old, and probably
die from a paper cut.
Oh, yeah, and that I'll
never get to do magic again
because I'm perfect now.
Did Professor Lipson tell you?
I am perfectly normal.
And we all know magic
doesn't come from normal,
so thank you for
deciding that without me.
I, um...
Have to do that thing.
Look, it was a shit decision.
It was my decision. I know.
Do you? 'Cause I don't.
I will never know.
I just know that this is not
how it was supposed to be.
Okay, truth, I was selfish.
You were in pain
and it was never going
to stop, and I couldn't.
And you know what?
I would do it again
to not lose you again.
Wait.
Penny.
You just stay here and
let me be pissed at you.
I can do that.
So Everett wants to be a god.
And now he's so juiced that
he can just rip the god
power right out of Eliot.
So why don't we just let him?
So let that psycho book-fondler
rip The Monster out of Eliot
and probably kill him?
Hey, come on.
Where are you going?
She's pissed at me,
but more pissed at
herself for being so pissed.
She's not great at apologizing,
so she's going to walk around
until she calms down
and hope I forget.
She's right. Anything where
he could die is off the table.
Hello. Shit! I mean, hi.
Where is my sister?
And where is the scroll?
"The scroll"?
Answer me now.
Um, what does
it look like again?
Ahh!
No.
I don't like you, do I?
I have no idea,
but I can assure
you, you will hate me.
Ahh!
Hello!
You did it.
What an achievement,
huh? Two humans!
Task 764 is usually
what trips your kind up.
But, hey, as we say
in Linear Base Binary,
"Infinite time is just
a parabolic lost sock."
Right?
You do speak
Linear Base Binary, don't you?
No? Then how did
you complete Task 764
or the rest of the 1,293?
Okay, so we're not on a quest.
We were. Yeah, last year.
Crushed it. Totally,
except for the part
that we're trying to fix now.
Wait, wait, wait, hold on.
How do you have the
Resonant Singularity Scroll?
Kind of by accident.
My fish magicks went off and...
No, don't.
I was not trained
for this eventuality.
We just want to
talk to an Old God.
Do you now?
Let me explain this in a way
that you might understand.
A chihuahua
just demanded a
blowjob from an archangel.
Hmm? Also I am not explaining
fish magicks to my bosses.
It's a real...
Also
tee time.
No, come on. No,
hang on! Hang on.
Look, we need the Old
Gods, but they need us too!
Need you? Hubris much?
Five minutes? Please.
So the Old Gods wouldn't maybe
be a little bit motivated to help
once we told them about the...
Not really. Those monsters...
Sorry nobody told you,
but they can't be killed.
Then why create them at all?
Why are nickels
bigger than dimes?
Huh. Why are nickels
Stop. Wait, so there's
no way to stop them?
Yes!
You said kill. They
can be stopped.
And can you think
of any good reason
why your bosses
wouldn't want us to do that?
I mean, if they don't have
to actually do anything,
can't hurt.
Okay, boys, here's my advice.
Drop 'em in the Seam.
The Seam?
This is ridiculous!
You're imbeciles!
Not arguing that, but the Seam
between what exactly?
This universe and,
you know, the antiverse.
Where everything's all dead?
Oh.
So we go to the dead-verse?
Duck-on-a-muffin! No!
You go up to the Seam,
you drop the suckers in.
And that would be
where? Use your heads, guys.
The Seam's not quite sealed.
What could that mean? Oh!
Maybe it leaked and created
a weird little pocket world
where everything's all
backwards and lifeless.
Like the Mirror World?
Sure, not a bad name.
So you go there,
you find the Seam,
and whatever you toss in
will never ever
come back out again.
I am insanely late.
Here you go.
To the victors.
Cake.
Okay, but the Mirror
Realm's an entire world.
How are we gonna find the Seam?
God damn it.
I don't think I could ever
eat non-Old God cake again.
Perfection is a curse.
Oh. Right.
Find the Seam. Guy didn't say.
We don't have
to go looking for it.
I think I know where it is.
There's this place, this door,
and what's behind
it felt different.
"Different," like?
Like I knew I shouldn't go
near it even when I was a Niffin.
Well, perfect, we should
definitely all walk right in there.
So according to Fogg, The
Monster's out there right now,
confused for as long
as that spell will last.
23, if you can
travel us out there,
we have an opportunity
to surprise him.
Now this is where we
open up the room for pitches,
because I accidentally
lost all my fish magicks,
and now none of us has
the juice to do the bond.
Well, what about Dean Fogg?
I mean, he's got to have
an extra battery, right?
Uh, nothing powerful
enough. We asked.
There has to be something else.
There is.
Hedge witches.
Can barely tie their shoes.
Fuck you.
And also, you're wrong.
A huge untapped pool.
Look, they're used to crumbs
and, yes, ambient is low,
but you know what amplifies it?
Cooperative magic.
We tell everyone,
and I mean all over the
world, wherever there's a pipe,
Fillory, even,
and we all do the same
thing at the same time.
You can't get that many
people to cooperate.
This isn't Sesame Street.
There are some shitty hedges,
but there are enough good
ones that we could pull this off,
and we need them.
Kady's right, this
is a good idea.
We need a way to get the
message out fast, to time it right.
Yeah. I've got
someone who can help.
They'd have to keep
casting the entire time
so we can keep The
Monsters in the bottles
till we get them
through the Seam.
This is right on the hairy edge
of what I'd even call a plan.
Hey, Q, can we talk for a sec?
Yeah.
I've been thinking...
Me too. I think that, um,
you should tell me where
the Seam is so that I can do it.
Why you?
Because I'm
better equipped to...
Because I want you to be safe.
I want you to be safe.
Are you saying that you...
No, I'm saying that we've...
We've tried the whole
"saving each other" thing
with mixed results.
Yeah. Sure, but I...
I've been thinking
about what works best,
and I think... No, I know we
are best when we're a team.
Okay, when me and you together.
If nothing else, I
like the sound of it.
Because it's true.
So it's decided?
Okay, people, let's do this.
If you need to touch
butts, make it quick,
we got a multiverse to save.
How does she know our thing?
Stop torturing yourself.
I want to help. Julia,
it's gonna be okay.
Or it won't.
You're just zen because
you think this is it.
What other Penny told you,
some big thing you have to do.
No.
I'm zen 'cause there's a
lot scarier shit than dying.
And right now, I'm
looking at you, so I'm good.
Bye, Julia.
Bye.
There's something I
want you to know, sister.
This world, it's not just the bad
things or the ones who wronged us.
There is...
There is such
beauty in everything.
Even the quiet,
especially the quiet.
Hey!
Hey, motherfucker!
Eliot.
Eliot?
Eliot, stay with me.
Now!
Eliot!
Ooh
All this time when we walk
We won't feel
But sometime in a box
It won't steal you
Oh, this time when I walk
I won't feel, I won't feel
Oh, this time when I talk
It's not real, it's not real
Not real
Eliot.
If there's a tunnel
with Grandma,
tell her to piss off
and come back to me,
you selfish fuck! Get back here!
Eliot.
Eliot, please.
Eliot!
Well, when you put it
so sweetly, Bambi, hmm?
Do something, please!
They need all the
ambient for those bottles.
What is the point of being a
magician if you can't use it?
Before I was a magician,
I was a trauma surgeon.
I'm perfectly capable of saving
him the old-fashioned way.
If you need to cry, go outside.
They holding? Yeah, for
now, but we have to hurry.
Okay, home is
right through here.
We do this, we move quick.
Okay, remember, no traveling
and no magic.
It goes bad fast here.
Alice? Just give me a sec.
We'll listen to
your gut next time.
It's the lab. Why?
Who cares?
Careful.
That's it.
It's the Seam.
Okay, let's do this.
Okay, let me...
Everett.
Quentin...
That's mine.
Hand it over, please.
You know you can't cast in here.
I know.
Mutually assured destruction.
Which is why
you'll give it to me.
You tried.
You did. I'm impressed.
But that bond won't hold.
Give it to me before
The Monster gets out
and everything goes
far more shit-shaped.
Quentin, I think you need to...
Your friend Eliot is
safe. I'll let you go.
Just let me handle this.
You'll become a god.
And you've met gods,
but I won't be like them.
I studied them so I
could do better, be better.
Trust me.
Okay.
Okay, I get it.
You always were smarter than
the books gave you credit for.
It'll be okay, Q.
In fact, you'll go
down as a hero.
I'll make sure of it.
Take her, do it now.
No... No!
What did you do? Just
some minor mending.
Quentin! Give it to me!
Hey.
Been awhile.
Welcome to the Underworld.
Oh, shit.
Really?
What's this?
Hot chocolate.
I'm dead, but there's
still hot chocolate.
That's a good sign.
What did I do?
What do you think you did?
I don't know. It
happened so fast.
This is the part
where I can't lie, right?
I mean, my whole life is...
Revealed.
But it only means anything
if you reveal it to yourself.
Okay.
Um...
Most of my life, I've been
in and out of hospitals and...
You know,
just suicidal
thoughts and notes.
A lot of notes.
Attempts and...
Meds and therapy and then...
Then I found Brakebills.
And all that went away.
I thought, but...
But?
Did I do something
brave to save my friends
or did I finally find
a way to kill myself?
Okay.
I can see we're going to need
the deluxe package,
which... It's okay.
No surprise.
Let's go.
I don't know what to say.
I mean, what words
are ever going to...
They won't.
We're talking away
I don't know what I'm to say
I'll say it anyway
Today's another day to find you
Shying away
I'll be coming for
your love, okay?
Take on me
Take me on
I'll be gone
In a day or two
So needless to say
I'm odds and ends
But that's me
I'm stumbling away
Slowly learning
that life is okay
Say after me
It's no better to
be safe than sorry
Take on me
Take me on
I'll be gone
In a day or two
Wow.
Appreciate the level
of sincere grief, dude.
I seem to remember
when I kicked it,
you laughing.
I'm really sorry about that.
It's okay.
I've met you.
I think you know
your answer now.
The story for them,
it's just starting,
but it won't be the same
story because of you.
You didn't just
save their lives,
you changed their lives
as much as they changed yours.
You didn't want to
leave all that, did you?
It's time to say goodbye.
All right, just one last look.
Oh, the things that you say
Is it a life
Or just to play my worries away?
You're all the things
I've got to remember
Shying away
I'll be coming for you anyway
Take on me
Take me on
I'll be gone
In a day or two
Are they gonna be okay?
Oh, yeah.
Once they reach here, just fine.
No, up there.
Oh...
Up there.
You'll notice control is done
with the ring
finger positioning.
If you watch...
And the blood, it feels like
we're never going
to get it all out.
Then we tear down and rebuild,
which is probably long overdue.
I got here as fast as I could.
Thank you.
With so few Librarians,
each is precious.
We're lucky you're still
here to run this place.
Oh, no.
No, I can't do that.
Your humility is charming,
but this isn't the time.
I know what I'm capable of,
what I feel...
It should not be me.
I know exactly who we
need, but I'm not sure they...
We need you to go find someone
and do your very best to
convince them to come and help us.
Alice Quinn.
Eliot and Margo?
Yeah.
Almost kind of funny.
Funny "ha-ha" or funny "uh-oh"?
God, this feels so good.
It sure does.
Okay. Let's see what-the-what
with getting un-banished,
my throne back, and my man
for some white-hot grief banging.
I'm sorry.
That came out way
harsher than I thought.
It's okay.
It's going to be
weird for a little while,
so we're just
going to have to...
Margo.
The fuck did they
do to my castle?
Uh, pardon me, sir.
Crazy question,
but Fillory is still ruled by
Acting High King Fen, right?
If this is some
kind of loyalty test...
Uh, no, no. Uh...
We've just been away for awhile.
The Dark King
reigns, glory to his rule.
High King Fen and
Josh the Fresh Prince
were overthrown 300 years ago.
The gods curse them both.
Have a good day.
The one that I'm the
most worried about is Julia.
I know.
She's fought so hard for magic.
She's been in a weird place.
Then she comes to the
end of this crazy journey
and feels at peace.
And magic?
Comes from pain.
Goodbye, Q.
Q, are you doing this?
Holy shit.
I'm doing this.
Did you... Did
you just see that?
Yeah.
So what are you
going to do with it?
What happens next?
Learn to love the
mysteries, man.
Can I ask you something?
Yes, I'm nicer.
All that stuff that we think
protects us or motivates
us or scares us up there,
here it just all falls away.
You're finally just you.
You'll see.
This is as far as I go, brother.