Previously on The Magicians...
When the moment comes,
do it.
Mayakovsky told you
what your discipline is?
Repair of small objects.
You did always excel
at minor mending.
- I want you in my life.
- I want that too.
The Binder knew Julia
had many questions.
And he knew the answer.
So you can help me
become a goddess again?
You're hoarding magic,
trying to become a god?
By becoming one of them,
I can rip their secrets away from them.
I redirected the power
I need into a reservoir.
You're saying Josh
is a fucking fish?
This should fix the whole fish deal.
I'll bring Eliot back.
My sister...
I need to find her a body.
So The Monster took Julia.
We need to find them.
We have the axes and the demon bottles.
You have the incorporate bond.
Casting an incorporate bond
strong enough to hold a god
would take
an insane amount of power.
The question is,
who put us here?
Our parents.
They're more vulnerable than you think.
If we can get to their realm.
We had a key.
A scroll.
Julia, if you're in there,
I'm sorry.
Hey, Monster
Lady.
Adorable.
So determined.
Maybe I'll keep you as pets.
Then again, I like my pets strong,
and you're weak.
You're already fading,
aren't you?
It worked.
Q, the bond.
I don't know how long
that's going to hold.
We need to
get to Brakebills.
I have something
that can help.
- We need to get her help.
- Wait, where's Eliot?
We can't. We don't have enough.
We have to go back to the reservoir.
After we get her
to a doctor.
No, he's right.
We have to go to the reservoir.
She's right.
Always gotta be
a fucking twist.
In my office,
under my desk, trap door,
Popper 22 to unlock.
Don't put your hand in there.
Temperature's at
absolute zero.
Should slow her down
a bit. Go!
You're okay.
You wanna
hurry that up?
Give her something
for the pain at least!
I just did. Twice.
- Damn it.
- Here, my last one. Use it on her.
You'll be okay.
Stay with me.
Thank you, Henry.
Restraints, please!
You're okay.
What's happening
to her?
So her body,
which is very weird,
it keeps trying
to close the wound
which is heavily enchanted
because the weapon
was also very weird,
and it just tears itself
right back open again.
Well, make it stop!
I hadn't thought of that,
thank you.
I will use this to
keep her comfortable and...
How long is she
gonna be like this?
We are not in what I would call
charted territory right now.
I think I might know someone.
It was
a difficult choice for Penny 23
to even call upon The Binder.
The Binder was certain, however,
that Penny 23 had made the right choice.
Julia, The Binder explained,
would remain in a cycle of wounding,
agony, for millennia.
Her body required
transformation.
Luckily...
...this was The Binder's expertise.
Well, great.
Let's get on with it.
The Binder
needed direction.
Initiate her long and arduous
journey to full goddesshood
or revert her body
to that of a mere human?
If it was up to me,
that'd be a no-brainer.
Yeah, but it's not.
It should be her choice.
The Binder paused for Julia
to make that choice.
Then dryly noted,
she wasn't in a talking mood.
The Binder assumed he was
speaking with
her husband or master?
No. No!
And yet the decision
had to be made,
surely not,
The Binder reasoned,
by this spinster nursemaid.
Uh, I run this hospital, Book.
Still, and
The Binder replied,
stating the obvious
to the strident female,
someone needed
to choose for Julia.
Reed's Mark.
Best of bad options.
Damage was done.
I'd rather not die,
so it's fine on that level,
but also...
Look, I've no interest
in being Batman,
but there comes a point when even
selfish bros need to mobilize.
Six hedges,
in the last 48 hours,
were pulled into vans
by men wearing gray.
- Woke up at home with Reed's Marks.
- Jesus.
The Library
just stopped pretending.
They're rounding us up.
We need you.
You know what
I wanted to do with my life?
To be?
Penny's goddamn girlfriend.
I acted tough,
but all I wanted was him.
You're human.
I'm weak.
Kady, die when
less people need you.
- Hey.
Honestly, I feel like
I've been run over
by six or eight trucks,
but I'm fine.
And by fine,
you mean...
What does it look like?
We need to talk
about The Monster.
His sister. I saw her plan,
her goal.
And it's way worse than slaughtering
the entire Library.
They want to take it up
with their parents, the Old Gods.
Wait, what does that
even mean?
I don't know,
and neither does she.
She just knows it would
feel good to kill them
and eradicate us in some sort
of insane nuclear winter
which she could give
negative three shits about.
Do they know how
to get to the Old Gods?
They found a spell,
uh, in the Library.
It opens a door
to their plane.
My guess is The Monster wants
to find his sister,
finish the plan,
kill the Old Gods
or get smashed
to a pulp trying.
That means smash Eliot.
Well, the upside
to them inhabiting our bodies
is she left this
in my pocket.
Whatever's in this
is sure to unlock the door.
Holy shit,
well done.
Well, shit,
I was ready to give up.
Welcome back.
Oh, oh!
- Towel?
- Uh, yeah. Thank you.
So was it weird
being a fish?
It felt, uh,
very natural.
The weird part was
how you were
so incredibly selfless
and, no offense, sweet.
- Which is...
- Not on brand? I know.
Anyone who
really knows me
knows that I'll do
anything if I love you.
Listen, Hoberman,
don't be stupid.
I'm not actually fun
or easy when I'm in love.
Fun and easy are overrated.
- Oh, Christ. Not my day.
- Oh! Uh...
Oh, hi! Sorry,
I just un-fished.
So, anyone else
super hungry?
I'm craving fish sticks.
Is that weird? You know what?
I'm just gonna go with it.
Where's Eliot?
Did you do it?
We got one so far.
You didn't save Eliot,
did you?
Of course you didn't.
You cocked it up
trying to save Julia.
- That bitch has a bulletproof body.
- Not anymore.
We don't even know
if Eliot's still alive.
Yeah, it was
a shit-show.
You don't even know what
the hell was going on.
You had one fucking job...
Yeah, fuck off, Margo.
Oh, Jesus Herbert
Walker Christ.
You're predictable,
you know that?
Whoa.
- What the shit?
- Oh, my God!
It just came out of me
so strong.
Guys, I think I have
some special fish magicks.
Oh!
Act out, right?
Or you touched the reservoir
and you got dosed up.
Yeah, that makes
a thousand times more sense.
But still pretty
act out worthy, no?
- Hello, Kady.
- How are you, Zelda?
I understand
you're angry.
No, see, that'd require
actual human feelings.
Kady...
You piece-of-shit,
pearl-clutching sociopathic...
None of this was
calculated on my part.
Everett...
I have believed in his goodness
for over a century.
Everett is in it
for Everett.
If you are right,
then all the death,
all of it,
it's on my hands.
Look,
I know you're not evil.
Just the definition
of obedience.
I used to be.
Prove it.
Hmm. Man, I'm good.
Yeah.
Great, thanks.
So you...
So you feel okay?
Yeah, thanks.
And by thanks I mean thank you
for deciding that I should age,
grow old, and probably die
from a paper cut.
Oh, yeah, and that I'll never
get to do magic again
because I'm perfect now.
Did Professor Lipson
tell you?
I am perfectly normal.
And we all know magic
doesn't come from normal,
so thank you for
deciding that without me.
I, um...
Have to do that thing.
Look, it was
a shit decision.
- It was my decision.
- I know.
Do you? 'Cause I don't.
I will never know.
I just know that this is
not how it was supposed to be.
Okay, truth,
I was selfish.
You were in pain
and it was never going to stop,
and I couldn't.
And you know what?
I would do it again
to not lose you again.
Wait.
Penny.
You just stay here
and let me be pissed at you.
I can do that.
So Everett
wants to be a god.
And now he's so juiced that
he can just rip the god power
right out of Eliot.
So why don't we
just let him?
So let that psycho book-fondler rip
The Monster out of Eliot
and probably kill him?
Hey, come on.
Where are you going?
She's pissed at me,
but more pissed at herself
for being so pissed.
She's not great
at apologizing,
so she's going to
walk around
until she calms down
and hope I forget.
She's right. Anything where
he could die is off the table.
- Hello.
- Shit! I mean, hi.
Where is my sister?
And where is the scroll?
"The scroll"?
Answer me now.
Um, what does it
look like again?
Ahh!
No.
I don't like you, do I?
I have no idea,
but I can assure you,
you will hate me.
Ahh!
Hello!
You did it.
What an achievement, huh?
Two humans!
Task 764 is usually what trips your kind up.
But, hey, as we say
in Linear Base Binary,
"Infinite time is just
a parabolic lost sock."
Right?
You do speak
Linear Base Binary,
don't you?
No? Then how did you
complete Task 764
or the rest of the 1,293?
Okay, so we're not
on a quest.
- We were.
- Yeah, last year.
- Crushed it.
- Totally, except for the part
that we're trying
to fix now.
Wait, wait, wait,
hold on.
How do you have the
Resonant Singularity Scroll?
Kind of by accident.
My fish magicks
went off and...
No, don't.
I was not trained
for this eventuality.
We just want to talk
to an Old God.
Do you now?
Let me explain this in a way
that you might understand.
A chihuahua
just demanded a blowjob
from an archangel.
Hmm? Also I am not
explaining fish magicks to my bosses.
It's a real...
Also
tee time.
No, come on.
No, hang on! Hang on.
Look, we need the Old Gods,
but they need us too!
Need you? Hubris much?
Five minutes? Please.
So the Old Gods wouldn't maybe
be a little bit motivated to help
once we told them about the...
Not really.
Those monsters...
Sorry nobody told you,
but they can't be killed.
Then why
create them at all?
Why are nickels bigger
than dimes?
Huh. Why are nickels
bigger than dimes?
Stop. Wait,
so there's no way to stop them?
Yes!
You said kill.
They can be stopped.
And can you think
of any good reason
why your bosses
wouldn't want us to do that?
I mean, if they don't
have to actually do anything,
can't hurt.
Okay, boys,
here's my advice.
Drop 'em in the Seam.
The Seam?
This is ridiculous!
You're imbeciles!
Not arguing that,
but the Seam
between what exactly?
This universe and,
you know, the antiverse.
Where everything's all dead?
Oh.
So we go to
the dead-verse?
Duck-on-a-muffin! No!
You go up to the Seam,
you drop the suckers in.
And that would be
- where?
- Use your heads, guys.
The Seam's not quite sealed.
What could that mean? Oh!
Maybe it leaked and created
a weird little pocket world
where everything's
all backwards and lifeless.
Like the Mirror World?
Sure, not a bad name.
So you go there,
you find the Seam,
and whatever
you toss in
will never ever
come back out again.
I am insanely late.
Here you go.
To the victors.
Cake.
Okay, but the Mirror Realm's
an entire world.
How are we gonna
find the Seam?
God damn it.
I don't think I could ever eat
non-Old God cake again.
Perfection is a curse.
Oh. Right.
Find the Seam.
Guy didn't say.
We don't have to
go looking for it.
I think I know where it is.
There's this place,
this door,
and what's behind it
felt different.
"Different," like?
Like I knew I shouldn't go near
it even when I was a Niffin.
Well, perfect, we should definitely
all walk right in there.
So according to Fogg,
The Monster's out there right now,
confused for as long
as that spell will last.
23, if you can
travel us out there,
we have an opportunity
to surprise him.
Now this is where we open
up the room for pitches,
because I accidentally lost
all my fish magicks,
and now none of us has
the juice to do the bond.
Well, what about
Dean Fogg?
I mean, he's got to have
an extra battery, right?
Uh, nothing powerful enough.
We asked.
There has to be
something else.
There is.
Hedge witches.
Can barely tie
their shoes.
Fuck you.
And also, you're wrong.
A huge untapped pool.
Look, they're
used to crumbs
and, yes, ambient is low,
but you know
what amplifies it?
Cooperative magic.
We tell everyone,
and I mean all over the world,
wherever there's a pipe,
Fillory, even,
and we all do the same thing
at the same time.
You can't get
that many people to cooperate.
This isn't Sesame Street.
There are
some shitty hedges,
but there are enough good ones
that we could pull this off,
and we need them.
Kady's right,
this is a good idea.
We need a way to get the message
out fast, to time it right.
- Yeah.
- I've got someone who can help.
They'd have to keep casting
the entire time
so we can keep
The Monsters in the bottles
till we get them
through the Seam.
This is right on the hairy edge
of what I'd even call a plan.
Hey, Q,
can we talk for a sec?
Yeah.
I've been thinking...
Me too.
I think that, um,
you should tell me where the Seam is
so that I can do it.
Why you?
Because I'm
better equipped to...
Because
I want you to be safe.
- Are you saying that you...
- No, I'm saying that we've...
We've tried the whole
"saving each other" thing
with mixed results.
Yeah. Sure, but I...
I've been thinking
about what works best,
and I think... No, I know
we are best when we're a team.
Okay, when me
and you together.
If nothing else,
I like the sound of it.
Because it's true.
So it's decided?
Okay, people,
let's do this.
If you need to touch butts,
make it quick,
we got a multiverse to save.
How does she
know our thing?
Stop
torturing yourself.
- I want to help.
- Julia, it's gonna be okay.
Or it won't.
You're just zen because
you think this is it.
What other Penny told you,
some big thing you have to do.
No.
I'm zen 'cause there's a lot
scarier shit than dying.
And right now,
I'm looking at you, so I'm good.
Bye, Julia.
Bye.
There's something
I want you to know, sister.
This world, it's not just the bad things
or the ones who wronged us.
There is...
There is such beauty
in everything.
Even the quiet,
especially the quiet.
Hey!
Hey, motherfucker!
Eliot.
Eliot?
Eliot, stay with me.
Now!
Eliot!
Ooh
All this time when we walk
We won't feel
But sometime in a box
It won't steal you
Oh, this time when I walk
I won't feel, I won't feel
Oh, this time when I talk
It's not real, it's not real
Not real
Eliot.
If there's a tunnel
with Grandma,
tell her to piss off
and come back to me,
you selfish fuck!
Get back here!
Eliot.
Eliot, please.
Eliot!
Well, when you put it
so sweetly, Bambi, hmm?
Do something, please!
They need all the ambient
for those bottles.
What is the point of being a magician
if you can't use it?
Before I was a magician,
I was a trauma surgeon.
I'm perfectly capable of saving him
the old-fashioned way.
If you need to cry,
go outside.
- They holding?
- Yeah, for now, but we have to hurry.
Okay, home is
right through here.
We do this,
we move quick.
Okay, remember,
no traveling
and no magic.
It goes bad fast here.
- Alice?
- Just give me a sec.
We'll listen
to your gut next time.
It's the lab. Why?
Who cares?
Careful.
That's it.
It's the Seam.
Okay, let's do this.
Okay, let me...
Everett.
Quentin...
That's mine.
Hand it over, please.
You know
you can't cast in here.
I know.
Mutually assured destruction.
Which is why
you'll give it to me.
You tried.
You did. I'm impressed.
But that bond won't hold.
Give it to me before
The Monster gets out
and everything goes
far more shit-shaped.
Quentin, I think
you need to...
Your friend Eliot is safe.
I'll let you go.
Just let me handle this.
You'll become a god.
And you've met gods,
but I won't be like them.
I studied them so I could
do better, be better.
Trust me.
Okay.
Okay, I get it.
You always were smarter
than the books gave you credit for.
It'll be okay, Q.
In fact, you'll
go down as a hero.
I'll make sure of it.
Take her, do it now.
No... No!
- What did you do?
- Just some minor mending.
- Quentin!
- Give it to me!
Hey.
Been awhile.
Welcome to the Underworld.
Oh, shit.
Really?
What's this?
Hot chocolate.
I'm dead, but there's still hot chocolate.
That's a good sign.
What did I do?
What do you think
you did?
I don't know.
It happened so fast.
This is the part
where I can't lie, right?
I mean, my whole life is...
Revealed.
But it only means anything
if you reveal it to yourself.
Okay.
Um...
Most of my life, I've been
in and out of hospitals and...
You know,
just suicidal thoughts
and notes.
A lot of notes.
Attempts and...
Meds and therapy and then...
Then I found Brakebills.
And all that went away.
I... I...
I thought, but...
But?
Did I do something brave
to save my friends
or did I finally find a way
to kill myself?
Okay.
I can see we're going to need
the deluxe package, which...
It's okay.
No surprise.
Let's go.
I don't know what to say.
I mean, what words
are ever going to...
They won't.
We're talking away
I don't know what I'm to say
I'll say it anyway
Today's another day
to find you
Shying away
I'll be coming
for your love, okay?
Take on me
Take me on
I'll be gone
In a day or two
So needless to say
I'm odds and ends
But that's me
I'm stumbling away
Slowly learning
that life is okay
Say after me
It's no better to be safe
than sorry
Take on me
Take me on
I'll be gone
In a day or two
Wow.
Appreciate the level
of sincere grief, dude.
I seem to remember
when I kicked it,
you laughing.
I'm really sorry about that.
It's okay.
I've met you.
I think you know
your answer now.
The story for them,
it's just starting,
but it won't be the same story
because of you.
You didn't just
save their lives,
you changed their lives
as much as they
changed yours.
You didn't want to
leave all that, did you?
It's time to say goodbye.
All right,
just one last look.
Oh, the things that you say
Is it a life
Orjust to play
my worries away?
You're all the things
I've got to remember
Shying away
I'll be coming for you anyway
Take on me
Take me on
I'll be gone
In a day or two
Are they gonna be okay?
Oh, yeah.
Once they reach here,
just fine.
No, up there.
Oh...
Up there.
You'll notice control is done
with the ring finger
positioning.
If you watch...
And the blood, it feels like
we're never going to
get it all out.
Then we tear down
and rebuild,
which is probably
long overdue.
I got here
as fast as I could.
Thank you.
With so few Librarians,
each is precious.
We're lucky you're still here
to run this place.
Oh, no.
No, I can't do that.
Your humility is charming,
but this isn't the time.
I know what I'm capable of,
what I feel...
It should not be me.
I know exactly who we need,
but I'm not sure they...
We need you
to go find someone
and do your very best to convince them
to come and help us.
Alice Quinn.
Eliot and Margo?
Yeah.
Almost kind of funny.
Funny "ha-ha"
or funny "uh-oh"?
God,
this feels so good.
It sure does.
Okay. Let's see what-the-what
with getting un-banished,
my throne back, and my man
for some white-hot grief banging.
I'm sorry.
That came out
way harsher than I thought.
It's okay.
It's going to be weird
for a little while,
so we're just
going to have to...
Margo.
The fuck did they do
to my castle?
Uh, pardon me, sir.
Crazy question,
but Fillory is still ruled
by Acting High King Fen, right?
If this is some
kind of loyalty test...
Uh, no, no. Uh...
We've just been
away for awhile.
The Dark King reigns,
glory to his rule.
High King Fen
and Josh the Fresh Prince
were overthrown
300 years ago.
The gods curse them both.
Have a good day.
The one that I'm the most
worried about is Julia.
I know.
She's fought so hard
for magic.
She's been
in a weird place.
Then she comes to the end
of this crazy journey
and feels at peace.
And magic?
Comes from pain.
Goodbye, Q.
Q, are you doing this?
Holy shit.
I'm doing this.
Did you...
Did you just see that?
- I...
- Yeah.
So what are you
going to do with it?
What happens next?
Learn to love
the mysteries, man.
Can I ask you something?
Yes, I'm nicer.
All that stuff
that we think
protects us or motivates us or
scares us up there,
here it just all falls away.
You're finally just you.
You'll see.
This is as far as
I go, brother.