Previously on "The Magicians"...
When the moment comes, do it.
Mayakovsky told you
what your discipline is?
Repair of small objects.
You did always excel at Minor Mendings.
- I want you in my life.
- I want that too.
The Binder knew Julia
had many questions,
and he knew the answer.
So you can help me
become a goddess again.
You're hoarding magic,
trying to become a god?
By becoming one of them,
I can rip their secrets away from them.
I redirected the power I
need into a reservoir.
You're saying Josh is a fuckin' fish?
This should fix the whole fish deal.
I'll bring Eliot back.
My sister... I need to find her body.
- So the Monster took Julia.
- We need to find them.
We have the axes and the demon bottles.
- You have the incorporate bond.
- Casting an incorporate bond
strong enough to hold a god
would take an insane amount of power.
The question is who put us here?
Our parents.
They're more vulnerable than you think,
if we can get to their realm.
We had a key, the scroll.
Julia, if you're in there, I'm sorry.
Hey, monster...
lady.
Adorable. So determined.
Maybe I'll keep you as pets.
Then again, I like my pets strong,
and you're weak.
You're already fading, aren't you?
It worked. Cue the bond.
I don't know how long
it's going to hold.
We need to get to Brakebills.
I have something that can help.
- We need to get her help.
- Wait, where's Eliot?
We don't even have enough.
We have to go back
- to the Reservoir.
- After we get her to a doctor.
No, he's right. We have
to go to the reservoir.
She's right.
Always gotta be a fucking twist.
- Synced & corrected by MementMori -
-- www.addic7ed.com --
In my office, under my desk, trap door,
Popper 22 to unlock. Don't
put your hand in there.
Temperature's at absolute zero.
Should slow her down a bit. Go!
You're okay.
You wanna hurry that up?
Give her something for
the pain at least!
Yeah, I just did. Twice.
Damn it.
Here, my last one. Use it on her.
You'll be okay. Stay with me.
Thank you, Henry.
Restraints, please!
You're okay. What's happening to her?
So her body, which is very weird,
it keeps trying to close the wound
which is heavily enchanted
because the weapon was also very weird,
and it just tears itself
right back open again.
- Well, make it stop!
- I hadn't thought of that.
Thank you.
I will use this to keep
her comfortable and...
How long is she gonna be like this?
We are not in what I would call
charted territory right now.
I think I might know someone.
It was a difficult choice for Penny 23
to even call upon The Binder.
The Binder was certain, however,
that Penny 23 had made the right choice.
Julia, The Binder explained,
would remain in a cycle of
wounding, agony for millennia.
Her body required transformation.
Luckily...
this was The Binder's...
expertise.
Well, great. Let's get on with it.
The Binder needed direction:
Initiate her long and arduous journey
to full goddesshood
or revert her body to
that of a mere human?
If it was up to me,
that'd be a no brainer.
Yeah, but it's not.
It should be her choice.
The Binder paused for Julia
to make that choice.
Then dryly noted she
wasn't in a talking mood.
The Binder assumed he was
speaking with her husband
- or master?
- No. No!
And yet the decision had to be made...
surely not, The Binder reasoned,
by this spinster nursemaid.
Uh, I run this hospital, book.
Still, The Binder replied,
stating the obvious to
the strident female,
someone needed to choose for Julia.
Reed's Mark.
Best of bad options. Damage was done.
I'd rather not die, so
it's fine on that level,
but also...
look, I've no interest in being Batman,
but there comes a point
when even selfish bros need to mobilize.
Six hedges in the last 48
hours were pulled into vans
by men wearing gray.
Woke up at home with Reed's Marks.
Jesus.
The Library just stopped pretending.
They're rounding us up.
We need you.
You know what I wanted
to do with my life?
To be?
Penny's goddamn girlfriend.
I acted tough, but all I wanted was him.
You're human.
I'm weak.
Kady, die when less people need you.
- Hey.
Honestly, I feel like I've been run over
by six or eight trucks, but I'm fine.
And by fine, you mean...
What does it look like?
We need to talk about the Monster.
His sister. I saw her plan,
her goal. It's way worse than
slaughtering the entire Library.
They want to take it up with
their parents, the Old Gods.
Wait, what... what does that even mean?
I don't know, and neither does she.
She just knows it would
feel good to kill them
and eradicate us in some sort
of insane nuclear winter
which she could give
negative three shits about.
Do they know how to get to the Old Gods?
They found a spell in the Library.
It opens a door to their plane.
My guess is the Monster
wants to find his sister,
finish the plan, kill the Old Gods
or get smashed to a pulp trying.
That means smash Eliot.
The upside to them
inhabiting our bodies is...
she left this in my pocket.
Whatever's in this is
sure to unlock the door.
Holy shit, well done.
Well, shit, I was ready to give up.
Welcome back.
Oh, oh!
- Towel?
- Uh, yeah. Thank you.
So was it weird being a fish?
It felt, uh,
very... natural.
The weird part was...
How you were so incredibly selfless
and, no offense, sweet.
Which is...
Not on brand? I know.
Anyone who really knows me
knows that I'll do
anything if I love you.
Listen, Hoberman, don't be stupid.
I'm not actually fun or
easy when I'm in love.
Fun and easy are overrated.
Oh, Christ.
- Not my day.
- Oh! Uh...
Oh, hi! Sorry, I just un-fished.
So anyone else super hungry?
I... I... I'm craving fishsticks.
Is that weird? You know what?
I'm just gonna go with it.
Where's Eliot?
Did you do it?
We got one so far.
You didn't save Eliot, did you?
Of course you didn't.
You cocked it up trying to save Julia.
That bitch has a bulletproof body.
- Not anymore.
- We don't even know
- if Eliot's still alive.
- Yeah, it was a shit-show.
You don't even know what
the hell was going on.
You had one fucking job...
- Yeah, fuck off, Margo.
- Oh, Jesus Herbert
Walker Christ... you're
predictable, you know that?
Whoa!
What the shit?
Oh, my God!
It just came out of me so strong.
Guys, I think I have some special
fish magicks.
Oh, act out, right?
Or you touched the Reservoir,
and you got dosed up.
Yeah, that makes a
thousand times more sense.
But still pretty act out worthy, no?
Hello, Kady.
How are you, Zelda?
I understand you're angry.
No, see, that'd require
actual human feelings.
- Kady.
- You piece of shit
pearl-clutching sociopathic...
None of this was calculated on my part.
Everett?
I have believed in his
goodness for over a century.
Everett is in it for Everett.
If you are right, then all the death,
all of it,
it's on my hands.
Look...
I know you're not evil.
Just the definition of obedience.
I used to be.
Prove it.
Hmm, man, I'm good.
Yeah. Great, thanks.
So you... you feel okay?
Yeah, thanks.
And by thanks I mean thank you
for deciding that I should age,
grow old, and probably
die from a paper cut.
Oh, yeah, and that I'll
never get to do magic again
because I'm perfect now.
Did Professor Lipson tell you?
I am perfectly normal.
And we all know that magic
doesn't come from normal,
so thank you for deciding
that without me.
I, um...
have to do that thing.
Look, it was a shit decision.
It was my decision.
- I know.
- Do you?
'Cause I don't.
I will never know.
I just know that this is not
how it was supposed to be.
Okay, truth, I was selfish.
You were in pain and it
was never going to stop,
and I couldn't.
And you know what?
I would do it again to
not lose you again.
Wait.
Penny.
You just stay here and
let me be pissed at you.
I can do that.
So Everett wants to be a god.
And now he's so juiced
that he can just rip the god
power right out of Eliot.
So why don't we just let him?
So let that psycho book-fondler
rip the Monster out of Eliot
and probably kill him?
Hey, come on. Where are you going?
She's pissed at me
but more pissed at herself
for being so pissed.
She's not great at apologizing,
so she's going to walk
around until she calms down
- and hope I forget.
- She right.
Anything where he could
die is off the table.
- Hello.
- Shit! I mean, hi.
Where is my sister?
And where is the scroll?
The scroll?
- Answer me now.
- Um, uh...
what does it look like again?
Ah!
No.
I don't like you. Do I?
I have no idea,
but I can sure you, you will hate me.
- Aah!
_
Hello!
You did it.
What an achievement, huh? Two humans!
Task 764 is usually what
trips your kind up.
But, hey, as we say in
the Linear Base Binary,
"Infinite time is just a
parabolic lost sock."
Right?
You do speak... Linear
Base Binary, don't you?
No? Then how did you complete Task 764
or the rest of the 1,293?
Okay, so we're not on a quest.
- We were.
- Yeah, last year.
- Crushed it.
- Totally, except for the part
that we're trying to fix now.
Wait, wait, wait. Hold on.
How do you have the Resonant
Singularity Scroll?
Kind of by accident.
My fish magicks went off and...
No, don't.
I was not trained for this eventuality.
We just want to talk to an Old God.
Do you now.
Let me explain this in a way
that you might understand.
A Chihuahua...
just demanded a blowjob
from an archangel.
Hmm? Also I am not explaining
fish magicks to my bosses.
It's a real...
Also...
tee time.
No, come on. No, hang on, hang on!
Look, we need the Old Gods
but they need us too!
Need you? Hubris much?
Five minutes? Please.
So the Old Gods wouldn't maybe be
a little bit motivated to help
once we told them about...
Ah, not really. Those monsters...
Sorry nobody told you,
but, uh, can't be killed.
Then why create them at all?
Why are nickels bigger than dimes?
Huh, why are nickels bigger than dimes?
Stop. Wait, so there's
no way to stop them?
You said kill. They can be stopped.
Uh, and can you think of any good reason
why your bosses wouldn't
want us to do that?
I mean, if they don't have
to actually do anything,
can't hurt.
Okay, boys, here's my advice.
Drop 'em in the Seam.
The Seam?
This is ridiculous! You're imbeciles!
Not arguing that,
but the Seam... between what exactly?
This universe and, you
know, the antiverse.
Where everything's all dead?
Oh!
So we go to the... the deadverse.
Duck-on-a-muffin! No!
You go up to the Seam,
you drop the suckers in.
And that would be...
where?
Use your heads, guys.
The Seam's not quite sealed.
What could that mean? Oh!
Maybe it leaked and created
a weird little pocket world
where everything's all
backwards and lifeless.
Like the Mirror World?
Sure, not a bad name.
So you go there, you find the Seam,
and whatever you toss in
will never ever come back out again.
I am insanely late.
Here you go.
To the victors.
Cake.
Okay, but the Mirror
Realm's an entire world.
How are we gonna find the Seam?
God damn it.
I don't think I could ever eat
a non-Old God cake again.
Perfection is a curse.
Oh, right.
Find the Seam. Guy didn't say.
We don't have to go looking for it.
I think I know where it is.
There's this place, this door,
and what's behind it felt different.
Different, like?
Like I knew I shouldn't go near
it even when I was a niffin.
Well, perfect, we should definitely
all walk right in there.
So according to Fogg,
the Monster's out there right now,
confused for as long as
that spell will last.
23, if you can travel us out there,
we have an opportunity to surprise him.
Now this is where we open
up the room for pitches,
because I accidentally
lost all my fish magicks,
and now none of us has the
juice to do the Bond.
Well, what about taking Fogg?
I mean, he's got to have
an extra battery, right?
Uh, nothing powerful enough. We asked.
There has to be something else.
There is.
Hedge witches.
Can barely tie their shoes.
Fuck you.
And also, you're wrong.
A huge untapped pool.
Look, they're used to crumbs
and, yes, ambient is low,
but you know what amplifies it?
Cooperative magic.
We tell everyone,
and I mean all of the world,
wherever there's a pipe.
Fillory, even,
and we all do the same
thing at the same time.
You can't get that many
people to cooperate.
This isn't "Sesame Street."
There are some shitty hedges,
but there are enough good ones
that we could pull this off,
and we need them.
Kady's right, this is a good idea.
We need a way to get
the message out fast,
to time it right.
I've got someone who can help.
They'd have to keep
casting the entire time
so we can keep the
Monsters in the bottles
till we get them through the Seam.
This is right on the hairy edge
of what I'd even call a plan.
Hey, Q, can we talk for a second?
Uh, yeah.
I've been thinking.
Me too. I... I think that, um,
you should tell me where the
Seam is so that I can do it.
Why you?
Because I'm... I'm better equipped to...
Because I just want you to be safe.
I want you to be safe.
Are you saying that you...
No, I'm saying that we've...
we've tried the whole
"saving each other" thing
with mixed results.
Yeah. Sure, but I...
I've... I've been thinking
about what works best,
and I think... no, I know we
are best when we're a team.
Okay, when me and you together.
If nothing else, I like the sound of it.
Because it's true.
So it's decided?
Okay, people, let's do this.
If you need to touch
butts, make it quick,
we got a multiverse to save.
How does she know our thing?
Stop torturing yourself.
- I want to help.
- Julia, it's gonna be okay.
Or it won't.
You're just Zen because
you think this is it.
What other Penny told you,
some big thing you have to do.
No.
I'm Zen 'cause there's a lot
scarier shit than dying.
And right now, I'm looking
at you, so I'm good.
Bye, Julia.
Bye.
There's something I want
you to know, sister.
This world, it's not just the bad things
or the ones who wronged us.
There is...
there is such beauty in everything.
Even the quiet,
especially the quiet.
Hey!
Hey, motherfucker!
Eliot.
Eliot?
Eliot, stay with me.
Now!
Eliot!
Eliot.
If there's a tunnel with Grandma,
tell her to piss off
and come back to me,
you selfish fuck! Get back here!
Eliot.
Eliot, please.
Eliot!
Well, when you put it
so sweetly, Bambi, hmm?
Do something, please!
They need all the ambient
for those bottles.
What is the point of being a
magician if you can't use it?
Before I was a magician,
I was a trauma surgeon.
I'm perfectly capable of saving
him the old-fashioned way.
If you need to cry, go outside.
- They holding?
- Yeah,
for now, but we have to hurry.
Okay, home is right through here.
We do this, we move quick.
Okay, remember, no traveling
and no magic.
It goes bad fast here.
- Alice?
- Just give me a sec.
We'll listen to your gut next time.
It's the lab. Why?
Who cares?
Careful.
That's it.
It's the Seam.
Okay, let's do this.
Okay, let me get it...
Everett.
Quentin... that's mine.
Hand it over, please.
No, you can't cast in here.
I know.
Mutually assured destruction.
Which is why you'll give it to me.
You tried. You did.
I'm impressed.
But that bond won't hold.
Give it to me before
the Monster gets out
and everything goes
far more shit-shaped.
Quentin, I think I need you to... to...
Your friend Eliot is
safe. I'll let you go.
Just let me handle this.
You'll become a god.
And you've met gods, but
I won't be like them.
I studied them so I could
do better, be better.
Trust me.
Okay.
Okay, I get it.
You always were smarter than
the books gave you credit for.
It'll be okay, Q.
In fact, you'll go down as a hero.
I'll make sure of it.
Take her, do it now.
No... no!
- No!
- What did you do?
Just a Minor Mending.
- Quentin!
- Give it to me!
Hey.
Been awhile.
Welcome to the Underworld.
Oh, shit.
Really?
What's this?
Hot chocolate.
I'm dead, but there's
still hot chocolate.
That's a good sign.
What did I do?
What did you think you did?
I don't know. It happened so fast.
This is the part where
I can't lie, right?
I mean, my whole life is...
Revealed.
But it only means anything if
you reveal it to yourself.
Okay.
Um...
Most of my life, I've been
in and out of hospitals
and...
You know, just suicidal thoughts
and notes.
A lot of notes.
Attempts and...
meds and therapy
and then...
Then I found Brakebills...
and all that went away.
I...
I thought, but...
But?
Did I do something brave
to save my friends
or did I finally find
a way to kill myself?
Okay.
I can see we're going to
need the deluxe package,
which... it's okay. No surprise.
Let's go.
I don't know what to say.
I mean, what words are ever going to...
They won't.
♪ We're talking away ♪
♪ I don't know what I'm to say ♪
♪ I'll say it anyway ♪
♪ Today's another day to find you ♪
♪ Shying away ♪
♪ I'll be coming for you love, okay? ♪
♪ Take on me ♪
♪ Take me on ♪
♪ I'll be gone ♪
♪ In a day or two ♪
♪ So needless to say ♪
♪ I'm odds and ends ♪
♪ But that's me ♪
♪ I'm stumbling away ♪
♪ Slowly learning that life is okay ♪
♪ Say after me ♪
♪ It's no better to be safe than sorry ♪
♪ Take on me ♪
♪ Take me on ♪
♪ I'll be gone ♪
♪ In a day or two ♪
Wow.
Appreciate the level of
sincere grief, dude.
I seem to remember when I kicked it...
you laughing.
I'm really sorry about that.
It's okay.
I'm not you.
I think you know your answer now.
The story for them, it's just starting
but it won't be the same
story because of you.
You didn't just save their lives,
you changed their lives
as much as they changed yours.
You didn't want to leave
all that, did you?
It's time to say good-bye.
All right, just one last look.
♪ Oh that things that you say ♪
♪ Is it life ♪
♪ Or just to play my worries away? ♪
♪ You're all the things
I've got to remember ♪
♪ Shying away ♪
♪ I'll be coming for you anyway ♪
♪ Take on me ♪
♪ Take me on ♪
♪ I'll be gone ♪
♪ In a day or two ♪
Are they gonna be okay?
Oh, yeah.
Once they reach here, just fine.
No, up there.
Oh... up there.
You'll notice control is done
with the ring finger positioning.
If you watch...
And the blood,
it feels like we're never
going to get it all out.
Then we tear down and rebuild,
which is probably long overdue.
I got here as fast as I could.
Thank you.
With so few Librarians,
each is precious.
We're lucky you're still
here to run this place.
Oh, no.
No, I can't do that.
Your humility is charming,
but this isn't the time.
I know what I'm capable of,
what I feel...
it should not be me.
I know exactly who I need,
but I'm not sure they...
we need you to go find someone
and do your very best to convince them
to come and help us.
Alice Quinn.
Eliot and Margo?
Yeah.
Almost kind of funny.
Funny "ha-ha" or funny "uh-oh"?
God, this feels so good.
It sure does.
Okay. Let's see what-the-what
on getting unbanished,
my throne back, and my man for
some white-hot grief banging.
I'm sorry.
That came out way
harsher than I thought.
It's okay.
It's going to be weird
for a little while
so we're just going to have to...
Margo.
The fuck did they do to my castle?
Uh, pardon me, sir.
Crazy question,
but, um, Fillory is still ruled
by Acting High King Fen, right?
If this is some kind of loyalty test...
Uh, no, no. Uh, we've just
been away for awhile.
The Dark King reigns, glory to his rule.
High King Fen and Josh the Fresh Prince
were overthrown 300 years ago.
The gods curse them both.
Have a good day.
One that I'm the most
worried about is Julia.
I know.
She fought so hard for magic.
She's been in a weird place.
Then she comes to the end
of this crazy journey
and... feels at peace.
And magic?
Comes from pain.
Good-bye, Q.
Q, are you doing this?
Holy shit.
I'm doing this.
Did you... did you just see that?
- I...
- Yeah.
So what are you going to do with it?
What happens next?
Learn to love the mysteries, man.
Can I ask you something?
Yes, I'm nicer.
All that stuff that we think protects us
or motivates us or scares us up there,
here it just all falls away.
You're finally just you.
You'll see.
_
This is as far as I go, brother.
- Synced & corrected by MementMori -
-- www.addic7ed.com --