QUENTIN: Previously
on The Magicians...
QUENTIN: It is
The Beast, isn't it?
And he's from
Fillory, which is real.
Want to know what
The Beast wants?
He wants control of Fillory
and all the doors that lead there.
ELIZA: I gave you
a book about it.
Stuff they're saying I
did, I don't remember.
Were you blacked
out when we met?
We need something or someone to
lean on that is bigger than ourselves.
JULIA: What was that?
RICHARD: Did it work?
More energy than I've ever felt.
Still the same determined
little Jane Chatwin.
Eliza is dead.
She is the only one who
can actually give me answers.
There are no answers,
because we have no idea
what's going to happen next.
JULIA: Dear Q,
I don't need to tell you how
fucking pissed at you I am.
Probably got the
message around the time
I incepted the shit out of you.
I don't understand why we fell
apart after being friends forever.
Anyway, I'm sorry for my part.
I never meant to really hurt you.
I put it down. I got help.
I know you're not
supposed to say
the other person fucked up, too,
but you fucked up, too.
And it broke us, and I hate you
for that, because I really miss us, Q.
I'm working on forgiving you.
Jules.
QUENTIN: J, got your letter.
I guess we're both still mad.
But I'm glad you're
okay. I really am.
Take care of yourself.
RICHARD: It's not
black and white, Julia.
It's all I thought about all
day when I was in there,
and it's all that I think
about now that I'm out.
Well, there's this sometimes
very handy thing called "penance."
What, like 50 magic
lashes? (CHUCKLES)
That spell you used
to get inside your friend's
mind, do you remember it?
That's a perfect
example of something
that can be used to
help instead of hurt.
If you're not afraid
to do the work...
I'm not.
Okay.
Q?
You can't sleep?
I just, uh...
Eliza gave me the answer,
apparently, and I lost it.
Fillory and Further, book six.
It was important,
and it just vanished.
So did you look for it?
Yeah, of course.
Everywhere. I...
(SIGHS)
Fillory is always deciding
when to let the Chatwins go
and deciding when
to kick them out,
because Ember and Umber...
Right, twin gods of Fillory.
They get mean and take
everything away, I know.
Essentially, yeah.
They have their reasons.
But that's what happened
in the manuscript.
For some reason,
I didn't deserve it.
It's a manuscript, not a
referendum on your character.
No. I...
In the books... So you lost it.
What do you do when
you lose something?
So you had it the whole time.
I don't know what you're
yapping about, as usual.
Book six.
The day we met, you said
you had nothing to do with it.
Like I said, it wasn't me.
(SCOFFS)
Want to get that
thing out of my face?
Fine. I took the stupid thing.
I was bored. It was there.
Now it's gone.
"Gone?" What do
you mean, it's gone?
I mean I read it,
I spilled my beer on it,
I tossed it in the trash,
and then I went
and got another beer.
Unbelievable.
That's unbelievable.
Wait. You said you read
it. Do you remember it?
Ish.
This is important.
Okay, I need you...
I need to punch
you in the throat
if you tell me
what I need to do.
The Beast is trying
to pick us both off.
You've got the
scars to prove it.
I don't understand why we can't
just be basic allies. (CHUCKLES)
You can't possibly
want to be a dick
more than you want to live.
What did Plover say
in the book? Come on.
First of all, what's-his-name
didn't write it.
Plover. Christopher Plover.
(CLEARS THROAT)
The girl did. Jane Chatwin.
Wrote book six? Holy shit.
Yeah, she started off by saying
that the other books were wrong,
and she wanted to go
back and clarify some shit.
Wrong in what way?
Um, this was the
summer that the mom died,
and they were hanging out in
Plover's mansion, eating crumpets.
Right, um...
Jane and Martin opened a
closet, and they went to Fillory.
No. Martin didn't go.
Fillory kept forgetting him.
"Forgetting him"?
Yeah. Martin was
crying like a little bitch
about Fillory not
wanting him anymore,
and Jane said, "Hang tight,"
and she'll find some way
that Martin can go back to
Fillory anytime he wanted.
I dunno, there were, like,
creatures or something.
Questing Creature.
If you catch one,
they're forced to
grant you a wish.
There's seven of them.
There's a, uh, uh, dog, a rabbit...
Stop!
I'm literally becoming less
cool with every word you speak.
So, I assume she, uh,
had her enchanted bow,
uh, so that she
could actually get one.
Uh... (CHUCKLES)
Yes, right. Yes.
Stop, or I'll shoot.
DOG: Hello, human child.
PENNY: It was a dog.
I need a key to unlock
the door to Fillory.
I caught you, dog.
No, wait. Not a dog.
It was a pig.
By decree of Ember and Umber,
you must give me what I ask.
Wrong. No. What was it? Back up.
For fuck's sake.
Hello, human child.
I caught you.
Give me what I ask.
Did it work?
As you wish, so shall it be.
ALICE: Wait.
So, the button is the key?
Well, this all makes sense.
It does?
In the last book, Martin, he's
obsessed with finding the lost button.
He's tearing
Plover's house apart.
The message boards are
insane, um, with different theories,
because the books... They
just say that the button's magic.
They don't... Nothing
specific about it.
This is huge.
Why is this huge?
Because it could still be
there at Plover's house.
Martin never found it.
We could...
You are talking about a direct
ticket to The fucking Beast.
Better than him
having one to us.
Look, this is in a manuscript
that you're probably the
only person to have ever read.
There's a chance
the button's still there.
I'm going, and like it or not,
Penny, you should come.
I'm coming, too.
Okay.
So, what's the quickest
way to England?
Penny, do you...
Dick.
Uh, great. I'll pack.
I'm sure we can
find a direct flight.
ELIOT: To where?
Uh...
Scurry along, Ronald.
Raymond.
Have a great day.
Um...
So, you seem good.
Could use a top-up.
So, where are you
flying off to, exactly?
Uh, England.
Oh?
You don't need a plane.
Margo and I made a door
directly to our favorite pub.
You can get to where
you need to go from there.
I'll show you, if you take me.
Margo's still in Ibiza,
Ronald gives terrible head.
It's not his fault. TMJ.
I'm bored.
You don't even
know... I'll catch up.
RICHARD: How
are you today, Kira?
I brought a friend.
I've been
working on that
thing we talked about.
Julia's here to help.
You want to lock the door?
Yeah.
Kira, I want you to think of
somewhere that you love.
We're going to create that
place together in your mind.
She can hear us, right?
Julia's gonna meet you there.
She's experienced
in mental projection.
I wouldn't call it a specialty.
Look, if anything goes
pear-shaped, I'll pull you right back.
(CHANTING)
(JULIA GASPING)
JULIA: Richard?
Kira?
Hello?
Richard!
I'm stuck! Someone
get me out of here!
We screwed up badly.
(MUMBLING) We screwed up badly.
Someone saw Kill Bill.
(BANGING)
Kira. Kira, if you don't want
me in here, then just let me go.
I know shit Uma didn't know.
Like how to become
impervious to fire,
so I will walk
right out of here.
(GASPS)
KIRA: Are you Richard's friend?
What the hell was that?
Needed to see if you were any
good before I let you near me.
What is it with
Magicians and tests?
Here. You need a pen.
Did Richard tell you who I am?
Just that you're
extremely smart.
I can barely comprehend this.
Can you tell it doesn't work?
There was an answer. I
could feel it. I couldn't get there.
Then my body turned on me.
How long have you... Year.
But I still have this.
So I sat and did the rest of it.
You finished this in your mind?
I talk. You write.
And when you go back out,
remember what you wrote.
Yeah, yeah. Um. (CLEARS THROAT)
Fire at will.
Okay. So we start pretty simply.
The framework from Popper 45.
Okay.
GUIDE: This estate has been in
the Plover family for five generations.
Now, Christopher Plover, already
a prolific and respected author,
was looking for
inspiration for his new book
when Jane, Martin and Rupert
Chatwin moved in next door.
Not exactly. Excuse me?
Question from the back.
No, uh, uh not a question,
more of a correction.
The kids got there
first, Jane and Martin,
and then Rupert got injured.
Oh, so we have ourselves
an expert. (LAUGHS)
And Plover's previous work,
well, he only got
rejections for it.
It just didn't really
show the depth
of the Fillory and
Further series.
Stay close, sir.
I'm not sure I can do
this tour without you.
(CROWD CHUCKLES)
Now we have some
pictures of the Plover family.
Plover's sister, Prudence,
cared for him until his
untimely death in 1952.
GUIDE: Stay with
the group, please.
Not all rooms are
for public viewing.
Prudence said Christopher
so understood children
because of his own
tragic childhood.
He aided many
families in the area.
He paid for the education of
his housekeeper's children,
George and Beatrix.
Not only did he
write for the Chatwins,
but he took them in briefly
when their mother died.
Legend has it, Jane
walked through a closet
in this very house
to get to Fillory.
Follow me to the writing room.
This is where Fillory was born,
where Plover told
tales to Jane and Martin.
As Plover wrote,
"There is no substitute
"for a childhood of
adventure, warmth, and love."
You will never be a man.
PENNY: All right, let's find
this button and get out of here.
(BULB SHATTERING)
Shall we proceed,
criminal element?
This is where he
wrote it. Right here.
This desk saved my life.
So, I liked the books when I was
a kid, and my friend, Julia, and I,
we'd pretend to be
Jane and Martin and...
So, I was 16 the first
time I was hospitalized.
I just couldn't get
out of bed, like, at all.
I didn't know that.
My brain breaks sometimes.
And my dad brought me the
books, and I read them, and I felt...
enough like me to at least try to
get back in the game, you know?
Do you still feel like that?
Broken brain?
I feel like...
I don't feel that
it really fixes.
It just works better now
in its own screwed-up way.
Hey, would you break up with me
if I told you that I've never
been happier in my entire life?
ELIOT: Guys, stop
love-birding and look.
(LOCK TURNING)
(LOCK OPENING)
Boring.
Completely boring.
Wait, this could be something.
It's a letter from Prudence,
his sister, to their lawyer.
Plover died of a
heart attack in 1952,
but this is all about how
he's missing, not dead.
She wants (STAMMERING)
a death certificate issued.
Whoa!
Holy shit. They lied.
Why would she lie if the...
Rumors about Plover.
There are these kids that were
missing, kids that knew Plover.
And in his absence,
people were talking,
and the longer that
they stayed vanished,
the more people started
connecting them in a bad way.
No, I bet it's more
complicated than that, right?
Well, because...
Because Fillory
is actually real.
Exactly, and Plover was crushed
that the Chatwins were missing,
because he knew
exactly where they went.
I love a good cover-up.
And the books were
already getting famous,
so maybe it was easier
just to say he died, I guess.
So what happened to him?
PENNY: I got a theory.
McCabe,
Livingston, Ali, Popper.
Oh, my God.
He was studying magic.
Yeah. I guess that never
made it to the message boards.
But check this out.
Kaminsky, Umar, Aurora.
I've never even heard of those.
PENNY: Of course you
haven't. You're not a Traveler.
It's the entire 101.
Plover was a Traveler?
PENNY: Or he wanted to be.
I mean, you go one inch
wrong, you're torn to shreds.
This is amazing.
What if... PENNY: Try this.
Plover's an idiot, like you, who
wanted to go to Fillory, like you,
so he tries a spell
and gets blown up.
Or it worked.
ELIOT: Fantastic, to idiots.
You want some? It never empties.
(CHILDREN GIGGLING)
CHILDREN: (WHISPERING)
Trapped here. Help us.
GIRL: Trapped here.
QUENTIN: Alice.
Shh... Don't you hear that?
What in God's
name are you doing?
You set off the alarms. You
have to get out of here this instant.
Okay. Look.
Is this something that
can be fixed with money?
But you're not listening.
Are you mad, or are you scared?
You shouldn't be here
at night, so please...
What really happened to Plover?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Yes, you do.
Ugh!
He's so panicked, I can't make
sense of anything he's thinking.
Okay. Enough of this.
(GASPS) I'm a super-villain.
Now talk. GUIDE: Okay.
But then, we need to go.
Plover, what was the real deal?
He was involved
in some dark things.
There's a book. It's
hidden in the writing room.
Yeah. I think we found it.
Prudence, she didn't
want anyone to know
the unnatural things
that her brother...
(LIGHTS BUZZING) Oh, no!
(GASPS) Oh, my God.
Where did they go?
(DOOR CLOSES)
Whoa!
ELIOT: Okay, then.
Let's get the fuck out
of here. All in favor?
Yeah.
Shit. Shit, shit, shit, shit.
Penny!
Alice and Eliot.
Fuck me.
So, where did Richard
find you? Brakebills?
Rehab.
Really?
Yeah. I didn't go
to school for this.
You sound bitter.
You caught that.
You know, I didn't
go to school, either.
Come on.
Well, I went to MIT, but I didn't
study a lick of magic in school.
This is brilliant.
Magic is science.
Hard to crack on your own,
but far from impossible, if
you have the natural bent.
Yeah.
You know, sometimes,
I wonder if I do.
Have it naturally.
What if it's all just
one big party trick
that never adds up to anything?
So? What if it doesn't?
You know what I think
about when I'm in here?
This one day in this
park with my girlfriend.
We sat here in the rain, doing
this dumb little spell over and over,
making a rainbow
that lasted 10 seconds.
Sounds lovely.
It was.
Best day of my life.
What's yours?
Here.
While you and Richard
are juicing me up, show me.
I was 10, with my
friend, Quentin.
No one bothered us under here.
It was like we were invisible.
We'd read Fillory books for hours.
I love those.
One day, we made this.
Like we were gonna go visit.
We were playing,
but it felt real.
KIRA: See this.
JULIA: Chase this.
It's the secret
to how to be you.
(LAUGHS) Okay. Back to the park.
Let's finish this puppy.
Alice?
Eliot?
Alice!
Chill, man. They can
handle themselves.
Shh...
(FOOTSTEPS)
The hell was that?
(CHILDREN GIGGLING)
QUENTIN: This house is
haunted as balls, is what that is.
GIRL: Come in here, please.
PENNY: Okay.
Hello?
Anyone or anything?
(MUSIC PLAYS)
Okay, Jesus, we get it.
There are ghosts in here.
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
I tagged you. You're it.
(SIGHS)
What just happened?
I tag you. You're it.
Do we go with this?
What other option do we have?
Okay, this is a little
kinky, even for me.
Would you care for refreshment?
Oh.
Um, (CLEARS THROAT)
okay, sure. Sounds divine.
Okay.
Thank you.
We must get these things off our
hands. Do you know Popper 29 yet?
No magic in the house.
Be good, or she'll take
you to the quiet place.
We'll be good. Right, Eliot?
I mean, yeah.
You're the boss, kid.
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
She's coming.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Stop doing that.
PRUDENCE: My
brother is too soft.
Caring for you when
he needs peace to work.
He has no idea how
naughty you truly are.
Now drink your tea.
(GRUNTS)
Drink it!
BOY: No. I'm over here.
(GIGGLING)
Holy shit. That's
Christopher Plover.
Is it just me, or does it feel like
we're being shown something,
like how it was?
Yeah, the time slip.
You say that like,
"Yeah, a sunrise."
Sunderland talks about it all the
time. She has a PhD in hauntings.
Her favorite thing
about a haunted house is
you get these ghost movies
of the past running on a loop.
You see shit like it was.
I didn't know any of that.
Of course not. You're an idiot.
Oh, my God, it's her.
It's a tiny chick in a beret.
BOY: Slow down, Jane.
That's Jane and
Martin from the books.
Nerdgasm. This makes sense.
Uh, Plover took them in,
and they spent their days
playing with the
housekeeper's kids.
Martin, he was, like,
really sick that summer...
JANE: Martin, hurry!
MARTIN: Janey, wait for me.
Wait, no. I'm coming with you.
Why won't you take me?
Ember, Umber, why won't
you let me in anymore?
MARTIN: I try to be good.
Martin. Are you all right?
Where's Jane?
Fillory.
What's wrong with me?
(SIGHS) Nothing. Some things just
aren't fair. We can't make sense of them.
Let's have tea, hmm? Come on.
Us left-behinds
ought to stick together.
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
She's coming. We need to hide.
Quentin?
Okay, I'm getting
the fuck out of...
What did I tell you children
about disturbing Mr. Plover?
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
Great.
No talking in the quiet place.
Lady, I don't know
who you think I am, but...
Insolent is what you are.
I've told you I'll sew it shut.
ELIOT: (WHISPERING) Alice.
(CHANTING)
(GRUNTS)
Hey, hey, we need to hustle.
Mrs. Danvers could come back.
Oh, my God.
Do you know what this is?
A vaguely whimsical horror show?
She did this.
She really did this to the
children, Plover's sister.
She tied them up
and drugged them
so that they wouldn't
disturb his work.
Okay, well, maybe ghost girl
can tell us where the button is.
Hey, Beatrix?
Beatrix. Hey.
My tummy feels bad. (GASPING)
Beatrix, it's okay.
(COUGHING)
How can we help her?
I don't think we can.
(COUGHING)
Well, I guess we
know how she died.
ALICE: Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
It's okay. It's over. It's
been over for a long time.
No, no, no. Not for her. She
just keeps reliving it over and over.
We have to... We have
to go. We have to go.
MARTIN: It's not the same.
PLOVER: Yeah, I know. I'm sorry.
Here, have another.
Let's spoil our dinner, hmm?
Oh!
Shall we work a little? I
think that might be nice.
Do you think that might be nice?
Martin, Mr. Plover, I'm
back. I was in Fillory.
JANE: Martin, I brought
you what you asked for.
You must have a look.
We'll be right back, sir.
She's tracking mud
all over the floor.
JANE: Stop that.
You're pinching me.
You've got it?
Yes. Let's go show Mr. Plover.
No, please. Let's not. For me.
JANE: The button's a key.
I know you're here. I
know you're spying on us.
George, come out.
Take this. It's a game, George.
How well can you
hide the button?
All right.
Well, I won't
forget any of it, so...
I know you won't.
Can I give you a
little advice in return?
Yeah. Forget that school.
The world never did help
a smart girl. Why would it?
We scare the shit
out of the world.
If the world goes after
you, take it as a compliment.
You know, I could come
back. We could do more.
This was really the
big one. No, I know.
I just... You know, I'm
sure you have more things...
I do need one other thing.
Yeah, sure. Anything.
Kill me.
That's crazy.
I'm allowed to be done.
No. I can't.
Well, I need you to.
(GASPS)
You knew. You
knew, and you did...
No, I did not sign up for this.
Then what? Pleasantries?
No, how about
not killing anyone?
What do you think
redemption looks like, Julia?
Being nice? Donating
shoes to Africa?
You think that really burns
the tumors off your soul?
What if she's wrong?
You know, what if a Magician
finds a cure tomorrow?
What if there really is a
hell and this takes me there?
You're already
in hell. So is she.
What am I supposed to do?
Whichever's hardest.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(OWL HOOTING)
Oh, thank you.
Drink up, Jane, and eat.
You must be famished.
Jane, don't you want to join us?
Oh, she's tired.
That's all right.
You go ahead,
Martin. Like last time.
I don't know if I want to.
Remember when I took you
and your sister to town for cinema?
Bought her that
dress she wanted.
Yes. We're grateful.
When I was a boy, I didn't have
anyone who thought about me.
I swore it wouldn't happen
to any child I cared about.
I care about you, Martin.
Come on, in front of the camera.
Give me a smile.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
Oh, I have the best news. I
am so close to figuring it all out.
Wild magic. Too strong
to do with human hands.
I'll have to grow another finger.
(LAUGHS) Can you imagine?
Of course, there's spellwork
for that, too, if I can master it.
All right, you can go
ahead and take that off now.
Trousers, too,
darling. All of it.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
I think the solution to all of
our problems lies in Fillory.
I need to go there with you.
But... I know. It's
been for you kids,
but I think we could
find a way to go.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
We could be together.
You're a lovely boy, Martin.
Now turn around.
They play like
that all the time.
A whole pile of naughty
pictures hidden in the dictionary.
Oh, no. The mean lady.
Little spy! I didn't
see anything!
I swear. May God punish you.
My brother is a good man. No.
You all hound
him. It's your fault.
Stop. Leave him alone.
(EXHALES)
To the quiet place.
For the best.
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
ALICE: We should go
back in there. ELIOT: Shh...
I'm trying to think, and I'm
out of cigarettes. This is dire.
Oh, my God. You're okay.
We're great. We're
both great, actually.
Where's Penny?
Knowing him, Disneyland by now.
What if he got to Fillory?
What did he do to Martin?
What are you talking about?
I saw something in there,
who Plover really was,
what he was doing
to Martin Chatwin.
Well, what was he doing?
Oh, God.
QUENTIN: The poor kid, he was
just trying to get a button to Fillory,
you know, so he could escape
this monster, who, by the way,
generations of idiots like me have
been worshiping like a literary god,
who was learning magic...
To get stronger, to travel,
who was wanting to grow
extra fingers for spells.
Grow fingers? Like...
What if The Beast
wasn't from Fillory?
What if he went there
because he had access
via these kids who
he liked to tell stories to
when he wasn't
drugging and raping them?
Jesus.
Well, I still have the
capacity to be surprised.
Thought you ditched us.
What happened to you?
Man, I traveled into a
fucking tree about a mile off,
getting away from that
crazy Prudence's dungeon.
Not so precise with the travel?
Shut up. Wait, what do
you mean, "dungeon"?
I mean some dirt-floor basement
bitch calls "the quiet place,"
'cause that's not
fucking psychotic.
There's a storm
cellar around the back.
QUENTIN: That's where she
took the housekeeper's kid.
He's got the button
in his pocket. Let's go.
Whoa! That's a
great idea if you want
Prudence to grab us immediately.
Dislike.
Okay. I know what
to do about her.
Uh, give me a 10-minute head
start, and then head to the cellar.
What are you doing
out of the playroom?
This is going well.
Where the hell's
Quentin? He's coming.
You're all going
to the quiet place...
QUENTIN: Hey, Prudence!
I heard the nastiest
rumor about your brother.
Okay, fine, but there are
about 48 more of those
that I just hid all
over the house.
I'm gonna make sure everyone knows
exactly what Christopher Plover did.
No.
Okay.
Well, that bought
us about 10 minutes.
Let's go dig up a dead body.
JULIA: It's done.
Richard and I, we...
So this is what that's like.
Do you want me to stay?
So you're found meditating in my
room next to my overdosed corpse?
Yeah, well, when
you put it like that...
(CHUCKLES)
Bye, Julia.
Have a good life.
(GASPING)
(SOBBING)
We'd better go.
(JULIA SOBBING)
Quentin.
ALICE: We have to
go back. Come on.
We have to go back, Quentin.
And do what, exactly?
Help those children.
You can't seriously be
thinking of leaving them there.
They were there
before we were born.
ALICE: Trapped.
This is exactly the kind of thing
that we should be able to fix.
There are ways to
clear a haunted house.
The house, yes. It doesn't
help with the ghosts.
There are rituals in
every civilization...
To prevent this, not reverse it.
We have to help them.
There has to be something.
Those kids, they did
nothing. It is so unfair.
You don't say.
You're not helping.
I'm the only one helping.
(CHUCKLES)
Life ain't fair.
Why in the high, holy fuck
should death be any different?
Thinking that you
can change anything,
it's such an act of
monumental ego.
I mean, who the fuck do
you think you really are?
I mean, you're just
some arrogant, little twat.
So suck it up. Shut the fuck up.
Vix...
If we're gonna go, we got to go.
Thanks, but I'm okay.
No, you're not.
Okay, I'm not.
Are you okay?
No.
Well...
I've been freaked about The
Beast since that day, you know?
And I've been
worried about myself.
And now that we know
who he is, what he is,
what he did to those
kids, Martin, I just...
I want to kill him, you know?
I want to step through the nearest
clock, and I want to wring his neck.
PENNY: Okay.
Let's see this button.
It looks so ordinary.
No, I feel something
coming off of it, hard.
You guys really don't feel that?
I think you should put it away.
Hey, don't talk
to me like I'm you.
Mayakovsky trained me himself.
I stay put until I want to go.
Period.
Told him not to do that.