QUENTIN: Previously
on The Magicians...
QUENTIN: It is The Beast,
isn't it?
And he's from Fillory,
which is real.
Want to know what
The Beast wants?
He wants control of Fillory
and all the doors
that lead there.
ELIZA: I gave you
a book about it.
Stuff they're saying I did,
I don't remember.
Were you blacked
out when we met?
We need something
or someone to lean on
that is bigger than ourselves.
J U LIA: What was that?
RICHARD: Did it work?
More energy than
I've ever felt.
Still the same determined
little Jane Chatwin.
Eliza is dead.
She is the only one
who can actually
give me answers.
There are no answers,
because we have no idea
what's going to happen next.
J U LIA: Dear Q,
I don't need to tell you
how fucking
pissed at you I am.
Probably got
the message around the time
l incepted
the shit out of you.
I don't understand
why we fell apart
after being friends forever.
Anyway, I'm sorry for my part.
I never meant to
really hurt you.
I put it down. I got help.
I know you're
not supposed to say
the other person
fucked up, too,
but you fucked up, too.
And it broke us,
and I hate you for that,
because I really miss us, Q.
I'm working on forgiving you.
Jules.
QUENTIN: J, got your letter.
I guess we're both still mad.
But I'm glad you're okay.
I really am.
Take care of yourself.
RICHARD: It's not black
and white, Julia.
It's all I thought about
all day when I was in there,
and it's all that I
think about now that I'm out.
Well, there's this sometimes
very handy thing
called "penance."
What, like 50 magic lashes?
(CHUCKLES)
That spell you used
to get inside
your friend's mind,
do you remember it?
That's a perfect
example of something
that can be used to
help instead of hurt.
If you're not
afraid to do the work...
I'm not.
Okay-
Q?
You can't sleep?
I just, uh...
Eliza gave me the answer,
apparently, and I lost it.
FiIIory and Further, book six.
It was important,
and it just vanished.
So did you look for it?
Yeah, of course.
Everywhere. I...
(SIGHS)
Fillory is always deciding
when to let the Chatwins go
and deciding when
to kick them out,
because Ember and Umber...
Right, twin gods of Fillory.
They get mean
and take everything away,
I know.
Essentially, yeah.
They have their reasons.
But that's what happened
in the manuscript.
For some reason,
I didn't deserve it.
It's a manuscript,
not a referendum
on your character.
No. I...
In the books...
So you lost it.
What do you do when
you lose something?
So you had it the whole time.
I don't know
what you're yapping about,
as usual.
Book six.
The day we met, you said
you had nothing to do with it.
Like I said, it wasn't me.
(SCOFFS)
Want to get that
thing out of my face?
Fine. I took the stupid thing.
I was bored. It was there.
Now it's gone.
"Gone?"
What do you mean, it's gone?
I mean I read it,
I spilled my beer on it,
I tossed it in the trash,
and then I went
and got another beer.
Unbelievable.
That's unbelievable.
Wait. You said you read it.
Do you remember it?
lsh.
This is important.
Okay, I need you...
I need to punch
you in the throat
if you tell me
what I need to do.
The Beast is trying
to pick us both off.
You've got
the scars to prove it.
I don't understand why
we can't just be basic allies.
(CHUCKLES)
You can't possibly
want to be a dick
more than you want to live.
I...
What did Plover say
in the book? Come on.
First of all, what's-his-name
didn't write it.
Plover. Christopher Plover.
(CLEARS THROAT)
The girl did. Jane Chatwin.
Wrote book six? Holy shit.
Yeah,
she started off by saying
that the other
books were wrong,
and she wanted to go back
and clarify some shit.
Wrong in what way?
Um, this was the summer
that the mom died,
and they were hanging out
in Plover's mansion,
eating crumpets.
Right, um...
Jane and Martin
opened a closet,
and they went to Fillory.
No. Martin didn't go.
Fillory kept forgetting him.
"Forgetting him"?
Yeah. Martin was
crying like a little bitch
about Fillory not
wanting him anymore,
and Jane said, "Hang tight,"
and she'll find some way
that Martin can go back
to Fillory anytime he wanted.
l dunno, there were, like,
creatures or something.
Questing Creature.
If you catch one,
they're forced to
grant you a wish.
There's seven of them.
There's a, uh, uh,
dog, a rabbit...
Stop!
I'm literally
becoming less cool
with every word you speak.
So, I assume she, uh,
had her enchanted bow,
uh, so that she could
actually get one.
Uh... (CHUCKLES)
Yes, right. Yes.
Stop, or I'll shoot.
DOG: Hello, human child.
PENNY: It was a dog-
I need a key to
unlock the door to Fillory.
caughtyou,dog.
No, wait. Not a dog.
It was a pig.
By decree of Ember and Umber,
you must give me what I ask.
Wrong.
No. What was it? Back up.
For fuck's sake.
Hello, human child.
lcaughtyou.
Give me what I ask.
Did it work?
As you wish, so shall it be.
ALICE: Wait.
So, the button is the key?
Well, this all makes sense.
ltdoes?
In the last book, Martin,
he's obsessed with
finding the lost button.
He's tearing
Plover's house apart.
The message boards are insane,
urn, with different theories,
because the books...
They just say that
the button's magic.
They don't...
Nothing specific about it.
This is huge.
Why is this huge?
Because it could still
be there at Plover's house.
Martin never found it.
We could...
You are talking
about a direct ticket
to The fucking Beast.
Better than him
having one to us.
Look, this is in
a manuscript
that you're probably the only
person to have ever read.
There's a chance
the button's still there.
I'm going,
and like it or not,
Penny, you should come.
I'm coming, too.
Okay-
So, what's
the quickest way to England?
Penny, do you...
Dick.
Uh, great. I'll pack.
I'm sure we can
find a direct flight.
ELIOT: To where?
Uh...
Scurry along, Ronald.
Raymond.
Have a great day.
Um...
So, you seem good.
Could use a top-up.
So, where are you
flying off to, exactly?
Uh, England.
Oh?
You don't need a plane.
Margo and I made
a door directly
to our favorite pub.
You can get to where
you need to go from there.
I'll show you,
if you take me.
Margo's still in Ibiza,
Ronald gives terrible head.
It's not his fault. TMJ.
I'm bored.
You don't even know...
I'll catch up.
RICHARD:
How are you today, Kira?
I brought a friend.
I've been
working on that thing
we talked about.
Julia's here to help.
You want to lock the door?
Yeah.
Kira, I want you to think
of somewhere that you love.
We're going to create
that place together
in your mind.
She can hear us, right?
Julia's gonna meet you there.
She's experienced
in mental projection.
I wouldn't call
it a specialty.
Look,
if anything goes pear-shaped,
I'll pull you right back.
(CHANTING)
(JULIA GASPING)
JULIA: Richard?
Kira?
Hello?
Richard!
I'm stuck!
Someone get me out of here!
We screwed up badly.
(MUMBLING)
Someone saw Kill Bill.
(BANGING)
Kira. Kira,
if you don't want me in here,
then just let me go.
I know shit Uma didn't know.
Like how to become
impervious to fire,
so I will walk
right out of here.
(GASPS)
KIRA:
Are you Richard's friend?
What the hell was that?
Needed to see
if you were any good
before I let you near me.
What is it with
Magicians and tests?
Here. You need a pen.
Did Richard tell you who I am?
Just that you're
extremely smart.
I can barely comprehend this.
Can you tell it doesn't work?
There was an answer.
I could feel it.
I couldn't get there.
Then my body turned on me.
How long have you...
Year.
But I still have this.
So I sat and did
the rest of it.
You finished
this in your mind?
I talk. You write.
And when you go back out,
remember what you wrote.
Yeah, yeah.
Um. (CLEARS THROAT)
Fire at will.
Okay.
So we start pretty simply.
The framework from Popper 45.
Okay-
GUIDE: This estate has been
in the Plover family
for five generations.
Now, Christopher Plover,
already a prolific
and respected author,
was looking for
inspiration for his new book
when Jane,
Martin and Rupert Chatwin
moved in next door.
Not exactly.
Excuse me?
Question from the back.
No, uh, uh not a question,
more of a correction.
The kids got there first,
Jane and Martin,
and then Rupert got injured.
Oh, so we have
ourselves an expert. (LAUGHS)
And Plover's previous work,
well, he only got
rejections for it.
It just didn't
really show the depth
of the FiIIory
and Further series.
Stay close, sir.
I'm not sure I can do
this tour without you.
(CROWD CHUCKLES)
Now we have some pictures
of the Plover family.
Plover's sister, Prudence,
cared for him
until his untimely death
in 1952.
GUIDE: Stay with the group,
please.
Not all rooms are
for public viewing.
Prudence said Christopher
so understood children
because of his own
tragic childhood.
He aided many
families in the area.
He paid for the education
of his housekeeper's children,
George and Beatrix.
Not only did he
write for the Chatwins,
but he took them in briefly
when their mother died.
Legend has it,
Jane walked through a closet
in this very house
to get to Fillory.
Follow me to the writing room.
This is where
Fillory was born,
where Plover told
tales to Jane and Martin.
As Plover wrote,
"There is no substitute
"for a childhood of adventure,
warmth, and love."
You will never be a man.
PENNY: All right,
let's find this button
and get out of here.
(BULB SHATTERING)
Shall we proceed,
criminal element?
This is where he wrote it.
Right here.
This desk saved my life.
So, I liked the books
when I was a kid,
and my friend, Julia, and I,
we'd pretend to be
Jane and Martin and...
So, I was 16 the first
time I was hospitalized.
I just couldn't get
out of bed, like, at all.
I didn't know that.
My brain breaks sometimes.
And my dad
brought me the books,
and I read them, and I felt...
...enough like me to at least
try to get back in the game,
you know?
Do you still feel like that?
Broken brain?
lfeelhkeu.
I don't feel that
it really fixes.
It just works better now
in its own screwed-up way.
Hey, would you break
up with me
if I told you
that I've never been happier
in my entire life?
ELIOT: Guys,
stop love-birding and look.
(LOCK TURNING)
(LOCK OPENING)
Boﬂng.
Completely boring.
Wait, this could be something.
It's a letter from Prudence,
his sister, to their lawyer.
Plover died of
a heart attack in 1952,
but this is all about
how he's missing, not dead.
She wants (STAMMERING)
a death certificate issued.
Whoa!
Holy shit. They lied.
Why would she lie if the...
Rumors about Plover.
There are these
kids that were missing,
kids that knew Plover.
And in his absence,
people were talking,
and the longer that
they stayed vanished,
the more people
started connecting them
in a bad way.
No, I bet it's more
complicated than that, right?
VVeH,because“.
Because Fillory
is actually real.
Exactly,
and Plover was crushed
that the Chatwins
were missing,
because he knew
exactly where they went.
I love a good cover-up.
And the books were
already getting famous,
so maybe it was easier
just to say he died, I guess.
So what happened to him?
PENNY: I got a theory.
McCabe,
Livingston, Ali, Popper.
Oh, my God.
He was studying magic.
Yeah.
I guess that never made it
to the message boards.
But check this out.
Kaminsky, Umar, Aurora.
I've never even
heard of those.
PENNY: Of course you haven't.
You're not a Traveler.
It's the entire 101.
Plover was a Traveler?
PENNY: Or he wanted to be.
I mean, you go one inch wrong,
you're torn to shreds.
This is amazing.
What if...
PENNY; Try this.
Plover's an idiot, like you,
who wanted to go to Fillory,
like you,
so he tries a spell
and gets blown up.
Or it worked.
ELIOT: Fantastic, to idiots.
You want some?
It never empties.
(CHILDREN GIGGLING)
CHILDREN: (WHISPERING)
Trapped here. Help us.
GIRL: Trapped here.
QUENTIN: Alice.
Shh... Don't you hear that?
What in God's
name are you doing?
You set off the alarms.
You have to get out
of here this instant.
Okay. Look.
ls this something
that can be fixed with money?
But you're not listening.
Are you mad,
or are you scared?
You shouldn't be here
at night, so please...
What really
happened to Plover?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Yes, you do.
Ugh!
He's so panicked,
I can't make sense of
anything he's thinking.
Okay. Enough of this.
(GASPS)
I'm a super-villain.
Now talk.
GUIDE: Okay.
But then, we need to go.
Plover,
what was the real deal?
He was involved in
some dark things.
There's a book.
It's hidden in
the writing room.
Yeah. I think we found it.
Prudence, she didn't
want anyone to know
the unnatural things
that her brother...
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
Oh, no!
(GASPS) Oh, my God.
Where did they go?
(DOOR CLOSES)
Whoa!
ELIOT: Okay, then.
Let's get the fuck out
of here. All in favor?
Yeah.
Shit. Shit, shit, shit, shit.
Penny!
Alice and Eliot.
Fuck me.
So, where did Richard
find you? Brakebills?
Rehab.
Really?
Yeah. I didn't go
to school for this.
You sound bitter.
You caught that.
You know, I didn't
go to school, either.
Come on.
Well, I went to MIT,
but I didn't study
a lick of magic in school.
This is brilliant.
Magic is science.
Hard to crack on
your own,
but far from impossible,
if you have the natural bent.
Yeah.
You know, sometimes,
I wonder if I do.
Have it naturally.
What if it's all
just one big party trick
that never adds
up to anything?
So? What if it doesn't?
You know what I think about
when I'm in here?
This one day in this
park with my girlfriend.
We sat here in the rain,
doing this dumb little spell
over and over,
making a rainbow
that lasted 10 seconds.
Sounds lovely.
It was.
Best day of my life.
What's yours?
Here.
While you and Richard
are juicing me up, show me.
I was 10,
with my friend, Quentin.
No one bothered us under here.
It was like we were invisible.
We'd read FiIIory
books for hours.
llovethose.
One day, we made this.
Like we were gonna go visit.
We were playing,
but it felt real.
KIRA: See this.
JULIA: Chase this.
It's the secret
to how to be you.
(LAUGHS)
Okay. Back to the park.
Let's finish this puppy.
Alice?
Eliot?
Alice!
Chill, man.
They can handle themselves.
Shh...
(FOOTSTEPS)
The hell was that?
(CHILDREN GIGGLING)
QUENTIN: This house is
haunted as balls,
is what that is.
GIRL: Come in here, please.
PENNY: Okay.
Hello?
Anyone or anything?
(MUSIC PLAYS)
Okay, Jesus, we get it.
There are ghosts in here.
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
I tagged you. You're it.
(SIGHS)
What just happened?
I tag you. You're it.
Do we go with this?
What other option do we have?
Okay,
this is a little kinky,
even for me.
Would you care
for refreshment?
Oh.
Um, (CLEARS THROAT)
okay, sure. Sounds divine.
Okay-
Thank you.
We must get these
things off our hands.
Do you know Popper 29 yet?
No magic in the house.
Be good, or she'll take you
to the quiet place.
We'll be good. Right, Eliot?
I mean, yeah.
You're the boss, kid.
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
She's coming.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Stop doing that.
PRUDENCE:
My brother is too soft.
Caring for you
when he needs peace
to work.
He has no idea how
naughty you truly are.
Now drink your tea.
(GRUNTS)
Drink it!
BOY: No. I'm over here.
(GIGGLING)
Holy shit.
That's Christopher Plover.
Is it just me, or does
it feel like we're being
shown something,
like how it was?
Yeah, the time slip.
You say that like,
"Yeah, a sunrise."
Sunderland talks about it
all the time.
She has a PhD in hauntings.
Her favorite thing
about a haunted house is
you get these ghost movies
of the past running on a loop.
You see shit like it was.
I didn't know any of that.
Of course not.
You're an idiot.
Oh, my God, it's her.
It's a tiny chick in a beret.
BOY: Slow down, Jane.
That's Jane and Martin
from the books.
Nerdgasm.
This makes sense.
Uh, Plover took them in,
and they spent their days
playing with
the housekeeper's kids.
Martin, he was, like,
really sick that summer...
JANE: Martin, hurry!
MARTIN: Janey, wait for me.
Wait, no.
I'm coming with you.
Why won't you take me?
Ember, Umber, why won't you
let me in anymore?
MARTIN: I try to be good.
Martin. Are you all right?
Where's Jane?
Fillory.
What's wrong with me?
(SIGHS) Nothing.
Some things just aren't fair.
We can't make sense of them.
Let's have tea, hmm?
Come on.
Us left-behinds
ought to stick together.
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
She's coming. We need to hide.
Quentin?
Okay, I'm getting
the fuck out of...
What did I tell you children
about disturbing Mr. Plover?
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS)
Great.
No talking in the quiet place.
Lady, I don't know who
you think I am, but...
lnsolent is what you are.
I've told you
I'll sew it shut.
ELIOT; (WHISPERING) Alice.
(CHANTING)
(GRUNTS)
Hey, hey, we need to hustle.
Mrs. Danvers could come back.
Oh, my God.
Do you know what this is?
A vaguely whimsical
horror show?
She did this.
She really did this to
the children, Plover's sister.
She tied them up
and drugged them
so that they
wouldn't disturb his work.
Okay, well, maybe ghost girl
can tell us
where the button is.
Hey, Beatrix?
Beatrix. Hey.
My tummy feels bad.
(GASPING)
Beatrix, it's okay.
(COUGHING)
How can we help her?
I don't think we can.
(COUGHING)
Well,
I guess we know how she died.
ALICE: Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
It's okay. It's over.
It's been over
for a long time.
No, no, no. Not for her.
She just keeps
reliving it over and over.
We have to...
We have to go. We have to go.
MARTIN: It's not the same.
PLOVER: Yeah, I know.
I'm sorry.
Here, have another.
Let's spoil our dinner, hmm?
Oh!
Shall we work a little?
I think that might be nice.
Do you think
that might be nice?
Martin, Mr. Plover,
I'm back. I was in Fillory.
JANE: Martin, I brought
you what you asked for.
You must have a look.
We'll be right back, sir.
She's tracking mud
all over the floor.
JANE: Stop that.
You're pinching me.
You've got it?
Yes. Let's go show Mr. Plover.
No, please.
Let's not. For me.
JANE: The button's a key.
I know you're here.
I know you're spying on us.
George, come out.
Take this.
It's a game, George.
How well can you
hide the button?
All right.
Well, I won't
forget any of it, so...
I know you won't.
Can I give you
a little advice in return?
Yeah.
Forget that school.
The world never did
help a smart girl.
Why would it?
We scare the shit
out of the world.
If the world goes after you,
take it as a compliment.
You know, I could come back.
We could do more.
This was really the big one.
No, I know.
I just... You know,
I'm sure you
have more things...
I do need one other thing.
Yeah, sure. Anything.
Kill me.
That's crazy.
I'm allowed to be done.
No. I can't.
Well, I need you to.
(GASPS)
You knew.
You knew, and you did...
No,
I did not sign up for this.
Then what?
Pleasantries?
No,
how about not killing anyone?
What do you think
redemption looks like, Julia?
Being nice?
Donating shoes to Africa?
You think that really burns
the tumors off your soul?
What if she's wrong?
You know, what if a Magician
finds a cure tomorrow?
What if there really is a hell
and this takes me there?
You're already in hell.
So is she.
What am I supposed to do?
Whichever's hardest.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(OWL HOOTING)
Oh, thank you.
Drink up, Jane, and eat.
You must be famished.
Jane,
don't you want to join us?
Oh, she's tired.
That's all right.
You go ahead, Martin.
Like last time.
I don't know if I want to.
Remember when I took
you and your sister
to town for cinema?
Bought her that dress
she wanted.
Yes. We're grateful.
When I was a boy,
I didn't have anyone
who thought about me.
I swore it wouldn't happen
to any child I cared about.
I care about you, Martin.
Come on,
in front of the camera.
Give me a smile.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
Oh, I have the best news.
I am so close
to figuring it all out.
Wild magic.
Too strong to do
with human hands.
I'll have to grow
another finger. (LAUGHS)
Can you imagine?
Of course, there's spellwork
for that, too,
if I can master it.
All right, you can go ahead
and take that off now.
Trousers, too, darling.
All of it.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
I think the solution
to all of our problems
lies in Fillory.
I need to go there with you.
But...
I know. It's been
for you kids,
but I think we
could find a way to go.
(CAMERA CLICKS)
We could be together.
You're a lovely boy, Martin.
Now turn around.
They play like that
all the time.
A whole pile
of naughty pictures hidden
in the dictionary.
Oh, no. The mean lady.
Little spy!
I didn't see anything!
I swear.
May God punish you.
My brother is a good man.
No.
You all hound him.
It's your fault.
Stop. Leave him alone.
(EXHALES)
To the quiet place.
For the best.
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
ALICE: We should go
back in there.
ELIOT: Shh...
I'm trying to think,
and I'm out of cigarettes.
This is dire.
Oh, my God. You're okay.
We're great.
We're both great, actually.
Where's Penny?
Knowing him,
Disneyland by now.
What if he got to Fillory?
What did he do to Martin?
What are you talking about?
I saw something in there,
who Plover really was,
what he was doing
to Martin Chatwin.
Well, what was he doing?
Oh, God.
QUENTIN: The poor kid,
he was just trying
to get a button to Fillory,
you know, so he could
escape this monster,
who, by the way,
generations of idiots like me
have been worshiping
like a literary god,
who was learning magic...
To get stronger, to travel,
who was wanting to grow
extra fingers for spells.
Grow fingers? Like...
What if The Beast
wasn't from Fillory?
What if he went there
because he had access
via these kids who he
liked to tell stories to
when he wasn't
drugging and raping them?
Jesus.
Well, I still have
the capacity to be surprised.
Thought you ditched us.
What happened to you?
Man, I traveled into
a fucking tree
about a mile off,
getting away from that
crazy Prudence's dungeon.
Not so precise
with the travel?
Shut up.
Wait, what do you mean,
"dungeon"?
I mean some
dirt-floor basement
bitch calls "the quiet place,"
'cause that's not
fucking psychotic.
There's a storm
cellar around the back.
QUENTIN: That's where she took
the housekeeper's kid.
He's got the button in
his pocket. Let's go.
Whoa! That's a great
idea if you want
Prudence to grab
us immediately.
Dislike.
Okay.
I know what to do about her.
Uh, give me
a 10-minute head start,
and then head to the cellar.
What are you doing
out of the playroom?
This is going well.
Where the hell's Quentin?
He's coming.
You're all going to
the quiet place...
QUENTIN: Hey, Prudence!
I heard the nastiest rumor
about your brother.
Okay,
fine, but there are about
48 more of those
that I just hid
all over the house.
I'm gonna make sure
everyone knows exactly what
Christopher Plover did.
No.
Okay-
Well, that bought
us about 10 minutes.
Let's go dig up a dead body.
JULIA: It's done.
Richard and I, we...
So this is what that's like.
Do you want me to stay?
So you're found
meditating in my room
next to my overdosed corpse?
Yeah, well,
when you put it like that...
(CHUCKLES)
Bye,JuHa.
Have a good life.
(GASPING)
(SOBBING)
We'd better go.
(JULIA SOBBING)
Quentin.
ALICE: We have to go back.
Come on.
We have to go back, Quentin.
And do what, exactly?
Help those children.
You can't seriously
be thinking of leaving them
there.
They were there
before we were born.
ALICE: Trapped.
This is exactly
the kind of thing
that we should be able to fix.
There are ways to
clear a haunted house.
The house, yes.
It doesn't help
with the ghosts.
There are rituals in
every civilization...
To prevent this,
not reverse it.
We have to help them.
There has to be something.
Those kids, they did nothing.
It is so unfair.
You don't say.
You're not helping.
I'm the only one helping.
(CHUCKLES)
Life ain't fair.
Why in the high, holy fuck
should death be any different?
Thinking that you
can change anything,
it's such an act
of monumental ego.
I mean, who the fuck
do you think you really are?
I mean, you're just
some arrogant, little twat.
So suck it up.
Shut the fuck up.
Vix...
If we're gonna go,
we got to go.
Thanks, but I'm okay.
No, you're not.
Okay, I'm not.
Are you okay?
No.
Well...
I've been freaked
about The Beast
since that day, you know?
And I've been worried
about myself.
And now that we know
who he is, what he is,
what he did to those kids,
Martin, I just...
I want to kill him, you know?
I want to step
through the nearest clock,
and I want to wring his neck.
PENNY: Okay.
Let's see this button.
It looks so ordinary.
No, I feel something
coming off of it, hard.
You guys really
don't feel that?
I think
you should put it away.
Hey, don't talk
to me like I'm you.
Mayakovsky trained me himself.
I stay put until I want to go.
Peﬂod.
Told him not to do that.