MARGO: Previously
on The Magicians...
There's too much magic.
Everything that I touch just...
It grows like crazy.
I'm gonna let
your bullshit slide
on account of you so recently being
possessed by a homicidal monster.
KADY: There was
a blood worm scare,
so the Library gave a lot
of Hedges the Reed's Mark.
I found a spell to remove
the marks in a depository.
I get you're on a mission.
One of you has gotta jet.
Either one of you
can hang for eternity.
I've earned the
right to step off.
ALICE: We're here to
study with Mayakovsky.
MAYAKOVSKY: I hate all of you.
Professor?
(IN RUSSIAN)
KADY: "Best Bitches."
Wear this and
you'll see what I see.
I'm Clarion, Goddess of Melody.
The way that you're imagining
the Harmonic Convergence
isn't quite enough.
When all the spells cast by
all of the Magicians go haywire,
you're gonna get
earthquakes, starvation, plague.
She didn't have
time to be delicate.
You can't travel anymore.
What exactly are
we looking for, sir?
CAPTAIN: Not what. Who.
You two know each other?
No.
ELIOT: Well, your
subjects are rightly grateful.
For sending that letter?
A.K.A. that thing I
totally didn't do, you did.
I was gonna let
you die for Fillory.
ZELDA: The Convergence
can be stopped.
All you have to do is move that.
The Harmonic Convergence. Mmm.
A.K.A. the end of the world.
Not necessarily.
This constellation forms a cosmic
sigil that increases magical intensity.
It has happened in the past
without causing an apocalypse.
But now there's surges of magic.
So we get the disaster movie
Clarion was talking about.
The Convergence will only
occur during this perfect alignment.
If we move the
moon out of position...
No Convergence, no
circumstance, no apocalypse.
The moon is not just a rock in
space. It has certain properties.
Like? Magic doesn't work on it.
Thanks to Magicians casting
haphazardly on it for millennia,
the moon is now covered by a crust
of spell debris, blocking new spells.
If we move any piece out
of place, no Convergence.
"What if we just moved Mars?"
she said with a straight face.
The other pieces are planets.
We can't move them because
they are, well, very big and far away.
The moon is the only celestial
body we stand a chance of affecting.
Won't that screw with
the circumstances?
What'll magic be
like when we're done?
Impossible to know. It will
be a brand-new circumstance.
But to get to that problem,
we need to solve this one.
Good. Well, I hope you have some
ideas, because we're striking out.
I do. Consult the Lunatics.
The Lunatics? Short
for Lunar Fanatics.
In the Middle Ages,
people thought insanity was caused
by changing phases of the moon.
In fact, it was often a Lunatic
in the throes of worship.
They claim to be able to achieve a
magical connection with the moon,
and even, under some
circumstances, move it.
That sounds useful. Mmm.
Well, if it's just branding, it means
they're not really crazy, right?
My dad always said that
they were batshit insane.
And he married my mom,
so he had a pretty high
bar for mental instability.
Regardless, they know more
about the moon than anyone.
I believe that talking to them
is our only chance at success.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
What people don't understand is
there is a skeleton of the universe,
but we are the bones.
Oh, that's good to know.
I am a humerus. You, patella.
We wanted to ask you about
the moon. Can we talk about it?
It... "It"?
Her Lunacy
identifies as she/her.
That's right. We
knew that. Right?
Of course.
If we wanted to move
her, how could we do that?
You don't move her.
Okay, listen, Reba.
In just a few days, a whole
lot of people are going to die.
That's a whole lot of people that
will never get to worship the moon.
They will never get to
know her like you do.
If she can help us
save all of those lives,
imagine everyone
that will realize
just how much she deserves
their love, their reverence.
So will you help us?
Just to be clear...
You don't move her.
You ask her to move.
And she won't let you speak to
her unless you get moon brain.
So, one of us needs moon brain.
Not one of you. Three of you.
A single Magician cannot
generate enough power to reach her.
So it's a cooperative
spell then?
It is a sign of
respect, Kneecap,
that allows you to
see her as she truly is.
If you have moon brain,
then you will see her aura.
Now, it is red.
But when you perform the
Dianic Ritual, her aura will change.
If it is yellow, she is considering.
If it is green, she is listening.
Only then may you
ask her to move.
JULIA: Red, yellow, green.
Did the guy who invented the
stoplight... Was he a Lunatic, too?
William Potts? Yeah.
Oh. Cool.
All three Magicians
must perform the ritual
until the moon is listening.
A warning. Once
her aura is green,
she may choose to listen to
anyone who calls to her, so be ready.
You must choose one, the
strongest among you, to speak to her.
Like the Old
Lunatics taught us to.
For the second part,
however, there is a price.
A price? Like, blood?
It is like blood to her.
You will need a piece
of her. A sacrifice.
A piece?
What, like a moon rock? Yes.
But be aware,
this will destroy it.
So, don't use your favorite one.
This is the price of
speaking to the moon.
JULIA: Just a few
more questions.
What is moon brain,
and how do we get it?
ORDERLY: Everyone,
line up. Pudding time.
Lovely to speak to you. You,
too, Kneecap. (CLICKS TONGUE)
(SCOFFS)
You ever just spin a globe,
stick your finger down,
see where it lands?
It's almost always water,
because, duh,
Earth is mostly water.
But sometimes it's the
Sahara, sometimes the Urals.
That's what you'd be
doing if you tried to travel.
Only instead of the
globe, the multiverse,
which is bigger and deadlier.
Afraid you'd say that.
I looked at everything I could
think of, magical and medical.
Nada.
You're grounded.
All right, well, since
I ain't traveling,
I should probably step down.
Uh, if you're offering your
resignation, I don't accept.
Not offering. Stating.
With Dean Fogg out indefinitely,
Brakebills has instituted our
Dean Vanishment Protocol.
Of course. That's a thing here.
Yeah. And, uh... (CLEARS THROAT)
that makes me
Acting Dean Lipson.
There's no instruction manual,
so I'm kind of
dean-ing on the fly here.
But one thing I do know is
losing a professor who was disabled
on school grounds ain't happening.
I mean, the optics
would be pure shit flakes.
So, your contract will be
honored. And enforced.
Hmm. Oh, also...
We need a new Welters coach.
I've been on the inside,
and I'm telling you,
it's a goddamn goose-stepping,
Fairy-snatching, ethnic
cleansing Gestapo.
To be fair,
the ethnic cleansing happened
after the Dark King left, so...
He's innocent
because he delegates?
No, that's not what I'm saying.
Someone in this
castle ordered the hunt
on that Fairy.
Could have been the Dark King.
But if it was someone else, killing
Seb might just make things worse,
so we have to find out
who before we coup.
I just want to stab someone.
I haven't heard you
this bloodthirsty in...
Well, not that long. But,
still, it's notable. (SIGHS)
Maybe I'm a bit on edge.
Josh keeps wanting to talk.
You mean about how you wanted
to leave him in the past to die?
Yeah, that.
So far I'm doing a
good job of avoiding him,
but eventually
he's gonna sneak...
Guys. Hey. What's up?
'Sup? First off, kudos
on the hiding spot.
Took me forever to find you.
Pretty busy here, Josh.
You're busy? I just got
promoted to head chef.
ELIOT: Oh,
congratulations. Thank you.
But I'm about to
bail on a state dinner
and leave it to my incompetent
sous chef because...
BUNNY: Apocalypse! Now!
Josh, would you just give it up?
He keeps trying to get
us to join his film club,
which I told him would never work
on a planet with no electricity or taste.
Uh, no. Sorry. This
one's just a little shy.
It's okay, buddy.
Help us stop the...
Apocalypse. Now!
Oh.
We need to get back to Earth.
Margo, our talk will have to
wait till after we save the world.
Oh, but then I have my nephew's
bar mitzvah. So, after that?
Mazel. JOSH: Thanks.
(SIGHS)
What about our thing?
We have a lot of fact-finding to
do before I can get to stabbing.
No problem. I know
just who to handle it.
FEN: You want me to what?
Just find out who in the
castle hates Fairies. Okay?
And what they're doing to them.
And why Fairies
in the first place.
And maybe talk to some
Fairies. Get their side of things.
Okay. And while you're at it...
Yeah? Anything else
that seems important.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
No, um, that seems like a lot of
open-ended questions. Mmm-hmm.
Um, I got this maid job
to be close to you guys,
and now you're deserting me?
(CHUCKLES) I want to
stop an apocalypse, too.
Every apocalypse-stopping
mission
needs a maid on the outside.
It's a key staple
in Earth movies.
Do you mean inside man? 'Cause
that's more of a heist movie thing.
No, that's different. Okay.
Everyone knows the secret,
sexy maid on the outside trope.
Yeah?
Josh has a film club.
You should check it out.
(CHUCKLES)
Maid on the outside, yeah.
So, did your loony friend
say how to get moon brain?
From what we've read, her rituals
are simple first-year Popper tuts.
But moon brain is the insanity you
get from extreme sleep deprivation.
Extreme like a night partying?
Or what are we talking about?
I wish.
Five nights without sleep,
and we can't use magic
to stay awake, either.
Apparently, moon brain
has to come about naturally.
This is completely nuts.
Isn't the Harmonic whatever
happening in five nights?
Yes. So if we all start tonight
we might actually have
a shot at stopping it.
Wait a minute. Wait. (CHUCKLING)
Five nights without sleep
is gonna fuck us up royally.
Can we even cast if
we're that messed up?
Well, three of us have to.
JULIA: Look, guys,
I know it sucks.
But whoever can stay up for 132
hours without sleep and not lose their shit
gets to stop the apocalypse.
I don't know about you
guys, but I am doing great.
Coffee.
Where's our fearless leader?
She's taking a cold shower
to keep herself awake.
Third, fourth time this morning.
Well, I don't know about you
guys, but I am too excited to sleep.
(ELIOT SIGHS) I
mean, we're doing it.
Is this, uh, helping
you find moon rocks?
Mmm.
No, this is helping
us stay awake.
The moment I research,
I'm out like a light.
Know what might help?
If we make this party a
little more '80s themed.
MAN: Eliot.
Oh, I don't think we should.
If we ski the fresh
powder... Know what I mean?
JOSH: Yeah, I get it.
MARGO: I mean
cocaine. Get me cocaine.
JOSH: I am not getting
you cocaine. MAN: Eliot.
JOSH: A five-day bender
would destroy your nose,
and could you imagine what that
would do to your sense of taste?
MARGO: I get a full nine
every night and I'm still a bitch.
This is gonna get real.
Hey, guys, come check this out.
I found something.
NASA brought back
a bunch of moon rocks
from the Apollo missions.
We're stealing from NASA?
Hell yeah. Momma's checking
one more off her bucket list.
Okay, we're not stealing from
NASA. I checked. It's impossible.
I'm sorry. But some of the
rocks that they brought back,
they gave out as gifts
and they went missing.
About 180.
The ones they did find, they found them
in garages, desk drawers, kids' bedrooms.
Just lying around.
People forgot about them.
But they're out there. And I
definitely think we can get one.
Okay, you guys do that. I'm gonna
go get some stay-awake supplies.
I have a muffin recipe
with a special ingredient
that is guaranteed to
keep us alert for five days.
What is it? Meth?
Oh, excuse you.
It is an organic,
locally-sourced,
natural stimulant
that got me through
every finals week,
and it is definitely not meth.
That's exactly what I would say
if I was trying to get us to take meth.
(JOSH CHORTLES) Mmm-hmm.
You're taking retirement well.
I find that organization
helps bring a sense of stability
when one's feeling not stable.
Okay.
I need to find a Book
Depository that got moved.
It's in Hell's Kitchen.
That's all I know.
Library buildings are enchanted
to blend in with their new environs
whenever they're relocated.
You'll have to go door-to-door,
find the building
covered in Library wards.
Great. Let's go.
You're abandoning your friends?
They have enough
people for a rock search.
Plus, whatever's
in Josh's muffins
doesn't sound like something a
person in recovery should be taking.
Hmm.
I need to find the Depository
before we move the
moon and screw up magic.
Right now, we have enough
to remove Reed's Marks.
After? Like you said. Who knows?
I'm not sure I'd be much
use to you, out in the world.
The building is
impenetrable on a good day.
Unless you're a Librarian who
knows the security protocols.
I don't know.
I'm not asking for your help.
I'm giving you a chance to fix
your massive, massive mistake.
Mmm.
Let's go.
High King Fen?
(GASPS) Fairy.
Keep the High King
talk quiet. I'm undercover.
You will come with me. Oh.
That... That is so great. I
have a lot of questions for you.
Some, I don't even
know why I'm asking.
They said you would fear me.
Funny thing, I'm
on a Fairy quest.
See, I'm a maid on the outside.
Super-secret, super-sexy.
Follow me, Maid
On The Outside Fen.
Good. Okay.
MARGO: Guess what I
found. You found a moon rock?
I found a moon rock.
And those muffins smell
amazing. Thank you.
Now all we have
to do is stay awake.
You know what helps me
stay awake? What's that?
An open, naked conversation
about our relationship.
(SHUDDERS)
I wanna tell you about
all my repressed emotions.
One by one. (GASPS)
Oh, baby. (CHUCKLES)
Josh. Josh.
Josh.
Josh!
Oh, no. Josh.
(SIGHS)
Oh, shit. Oh, shit!
We leave you for one afternoon
and you fuck us completely.
I'm sorry, guys.
I sat down for one minute,
because I never fall asleep
when I have
something in the oven.
Well, congratulations.
This is a milestone for you.
Hey, guys. Hope you
had better luck than we did.
Nope. We portal-hopped
to every lead we had.
The closest thing we found
was a chunk of old concrete
with the word "moon" written on it
in Sharpie. Those rocks are gone.
But we did come home to
find Josh sleeping peacefully.
I'm going to assume
your rudeness
is because sleep deprivation
makes you irritable.
Sure. Assume that.
PENNY: Yeah. I get it.
Gonna have to staple my
eyes open. This is rough.
No one else sleeps.
We have four nights. We
need one rock lead to pan out.
But if the spell burns them up,
what if we can't find any rocks
because the Lunatics used them all?
What if there's no more
moon rocks on Earth?
Just saying, we could celebrate
the Harmonic Convergence in Fillory.
It's a little
dystopian at the mo,
but on the plus, their weekend
forecast doesn't call for an apocalypse.
(SIGHS)
Look, guys, if you're looking for
some sort of inspirational speech
on why you should
stay and fight,
I can't help you.
It's gonna suck.
And even if we do
succeed, which we might not,
it's not like we're
gonna get any credit.
The world ends, I end with it,
knowing that I did
everything I could.
Because I won't be able to
live with myself otherwise.
Julia's right. She really does
suck at inspirational speeches.
But also that we should
save the world. I'm with you.
So am I. Me too.
I'm in. And my axe.
Really? No? No.
Should've led with
"You have my bow."
MARGO: Mmm-hmm. Nope.
Josh, put some fresh
meth muffins in the oven.
Again, not meth.
(SCOFFS)
(GASPS)
Hey, no droopy eyes on my watch.
One more.
I'm good now. PENNY: I ain't.
(OVEN BEEPING)
Oh. Well, right on cue.
I tried something
new this round.
A hint of lavender
and goji berry.
How we doing, captain?
Oh, you know, 12 hours
till the end of the world,
and it's like we're still grasping
for needles in hay straw.
Fun. Okay.
Probably not the best
question for morale,
but as the only person
here who's slept this week,
we have 12 hours,
and zero leads.
Is waiting here to die
really the best option?
When are we gonna give
Margo's idea another think?
Guys, I can't trust my brain right now,
but this seems like it could be relevant.
I think this guy
has a moon rock.
Oren Westbrook?
Why do I know him?
MARGO: Because
you're not a cave person.
He invented the
tech for pop-up ads,
and he invented the
tech to block pop-up ads.
Ever since he's just
been a weird rich guy
doing weird rich guy shit.
I heard his blood boy
has his own blood boy.
ELIOT: Ah...
Ew.
What's on his eye?
ALICE: That's the same
tattoo that Reba had.
Julia, I think he's a Lunatic.
All right. So, in order to save
the world, all we have to do
is convince some eccentric
billionaire with armed guards
to give up something he probably
considers to be like his holy grail.
All while we're so tired
we can't see straight.
No sweat.
(YAWNS)
Marvelous. How did
you handle the pain?
Knowing it would bring
me closer to Her Lunacy
helped me get through it.
(EXHALES)
Same as when I got mine.
That, and a handful of opiates.
(ALL LAUGH)
(FORCED LAUGH)
Hey, sorry about the security.
I hope you guys understand.
Ah, please. Can't
let in every Lunatic.
Some people are crazy.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
MAN: Eliot.
OREN: Oh, wow.
You guys really
look awful. What?
MAN: Eliot.
OREN: Your sunken eyes.
MAN: Let me out.
Preparing for moon brain?
The Harmonic Convergence.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Yeah, baby. I'm
celebrating, too.
I'm gonna have a few
friends over for a party.
El? Eliot? Eliot, you good?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Yeah.
Just can't wait to see
this amazing moon rock.
Don't worry. You both
will experience her.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS)
(SIGHS HEAVILY) What
a cozy little nightmare.
I might need you to
punch me to stay awake.
Gotcha. Isn't she wondrous?
Yeah, definitely.
Think we can turn on the lights
and turn off the yoga music?
You got this from the moon how?
I went.
You just went to the moon
like it was Coney Island?
Yeah, actually, it
was pretty tough.
To be honest, I was
trying to impress someone.
But in the end, our
souls did not connect.
Yeah, we need to ask a favor.
For my fellow Lunatics, I
would move heaven and Earth.
(CHUCKLES) About that...
Yeah, like, we know
this rock is special to you.
Super-special. But we need it.
To move her. Hence
the moon brain.
You do know what
that would do, right?
Yes, but it's a matter
of life and death.
We can stop the
Harmonic Convergence
if we can just hold the moon
out of position long enough.
Why?
Because it's going to
cause worldwide destruction.
Magic will become so
powerful, it'll be apocalyptic.
I mean, it's not like it's gonna
wipe out all life on Earth. Just some.
You know exactly how bad
it's going to get, don't you?
What, are you planning to
profit off of this or something?
I'm planning to use my resources
to help the world recover.
Now, I'm an
entrepreneurial spirit.
I can't help but make money.
Now, I do think that the
moon brain is getting to you.
Unless...
Your eye tattoo
is illusion magic.
You're no Lunatic at all. I'll
have my guards escort you out.
Let's go, El. We tried.
OREN: Happens all the time.
(ALICE SIGHS)
PENNY: Get it? All of it.
We have a problem.
So, it's just security cameras until
we get to the Moon Rock Room.
And that's where it gets
tough. One way in, one way out.
(SIGHS) I mean, if we
get caught, we're trapped.
Guys. Guys?
JULIA: Huh.
(LOUD ROCK MUSIC BLARES
OVER SPEAKERS) Thanks.
So, the rock.
Whole lot of wards around
it. Nothing we can't get past.
Except for the one
on the rock itself. It's...
Well, it's a bond that
we've never seen before,
put there by Mayakovsky.
Well, that can't be right.
Oren just got the rock.
And didn't you say the last time you
saw Mayakovsky, he's basically senile?
Yeah, well, I
guess he got better.
I mean, he... He
put his signature
into the lattice
work of the spell.
You can't miss it.
It's the most amazing, most
narcissistic thing I've ever seen.
Mmm.
Hey, Eliot? Mmm?
Can I talk to you
for a sec? Yeah.
ELIOT: I said I'm fine.
I have been awake for
thousands of hours straight.
I saw your moment back there,
and I think I might know what's up.
You think you do, but you don't.
Okay, so, the first
two nights, no sleep.
Things got a
little weird, right?
Like picking up my
phone to call Quentin.
You know? I must have
done that, like, five times.
But then my brain
crossed over into darker...
Here's the deal. When
the Sister was in me,
I remember everything.
Every bloody second of it.
And usually I'm good at
pushing it away, but right now,
it is like a constant
slideshow in the background.
Not fun.
El, The Monster was
in you for months.
Well, it was different.
People have
different experiences.
All that time was just one big
nap to me. Which... (SIGHS)
Which sounds so good
right now. (CHUCKLES)
I don't know why you're
lying to me. Or anyone.
accusing me of lying.
Okay. Neither of us have the
bandwidth for this right now.
And I don't trust you. I don't.
But if you ever do
decide to talk, open door.
(JULIA SIGHS)
Shit.
If I may... Lenses can be sensitive to
changes in your internal circumstances.
You may need to
adjust if you're feeling off.
God damn it.
If something is bothering you,
I know I'm not the ideal
person to talk to, but I am here.
I'm not feeling chatty
at the moment, okay?
(SIGHS)
Look, you're not the only
one that made a mistake.
'Cause clearly it's
still bothering me.
It's Fogg.
He's stuck in the Etheric
Realm, and it's my fault.
Henry's in...
He always was a sensualist.
That place is a trap for people
like him, who enjoy, well...
Getting wasted?
He was trying to quit.
He shouldn't have even been in there.
He was only in there because of me.
And you were only there because
you wanted to help the Hedges.
You know, if we're being honest,
I wanted to get high.
Lucky me, that's the only
way into the Etheric Realm.
Fogg just tagged
along and got unlucky.
(CHUCKLES) That wasn't luck. I
know the emperor of the Realm.
If he kept Henry behind, it was
because he sensed a flaw in him.
And if he kicked you out,
it was because you were
trying to do something good.
Nothing bores him like goodness.
Yeah, how do you know that?
I spent three years there once.
Jesus.
Before I came to the
Library, my life was difficult.
The Etheric Realm was an escape.
How did you get out?
I stopped hating
myself, eventually.
And then the Emperor
grew bored with me.
Whatever kept Henry
there, those are his demons.
And that is something
you couldn't fix.
Well, it doesn't stop me
from feeling like shit about it.
The fact that you feel like
shit, that is why you escaped.
So allow me to be blunt.
Don't waste time on self-pity.
Do what you came to do.
Thanks.
Mmm.
I'll try to be less
of a bitch to you.
Hmm.
If you can.
(EXHALES)
It's working. I can see
the wards. This way.
(ALICE SIGHS)
(MAN SCREAMING)
ALICE: Sounds like he's
home. Look, fair warning...
Who the hell are you?
We're looking for Mayakovsky.
Old, drunk, megalomaniac?
Fondness for knit caps?
Yeah, I'm his daughter.
I didn't realize he...
Fucked my mother?
Neither did he.
Should've seen his face
when I came knocking.
But we're fine now.
What do you want?
Can you let us down? Sure.
Thanks.
Look, we need
to talk to your dad.
He's busy. On our project.
Look, we think he may be the only
person that can help us save the world.
He put a special magical
bond on a moon rock,
and we need his
help to break it.
Wait.
Please tell me you're
trying to rob Oren Westbrook.
How do you know that?
I installed that bond.
Yeah, last nice thing I did
before I dumped his greasy ass.
That was you?
Wait. You dated him?
Don't judge, but yes.
Any fuck, right after
I installed the bond,
I caught the maid pegging him.
And not the maid I
okayed for threesomes.
Mmm-hmm. Okay. So
that means you'll help us?
I could, but I need
something from you.
A Shade.
Either of yours will do.
(CHUCKLES)
What are you gonna do with it?
Are we gonna get it back?
(SCOFFS)
No. You want my help? Mmm-hmm.
One Shade, payment in advance.
Discuss.
(SIGHS)
It's safe. Thanks.
(KADY SIGHS)
Any idea where to find a
Medical Manual in here?
Unfortunately, the
organizational systems are down
so it may... Shh.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(CLATTERING)
May I?
Hmm.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
Sometimes I forget you're
a fucking Master Magician.
I try to keep the
showboating to a minimum.
Well, Harmonic
Convergence is in a few hours.
You know what that means.
I'll take this to Harriet ASAP.
Tell her if,
(SIGHS) God forbid,
we can't stop it,
we might need all the hedges
we can get to un-fuck everything.
(BEEPS)
Desperate times, huh?
Didn't really have much choice.
Hey, um, Julia?
Can you remind me why
I'm dressed like this, please?
He's been like this all night.
Just running on muffin fumes.
Okay, let's just make sure
we're all on the same page, okay?
Okay, so Josh, Margo, Penny, you
guys go inside, loop all the cameras,
open the side door for Natasha.
I'll be outside waiting
with Eliot and Alice.
We won't cast the
spell until your signal.
You won't miss it. Ready? Break.
Eliot, what are you staring at?
Pull the ripcord, get
out. We'll handle this.
I am not cocking out.
You're not right, El,
and we both know why.
My crippling fear
of/attraction to authority?
Are you being honest with me?
Bambi, always.
I don't care if you've
been keeping it from me,
but all our asses
are on the line now.
Margo, do not worry about me.
I know I've been
a little bit off.
Blame it on the moon
brain. I promise I'm fine.
Okay?
(SIGHS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
MAN: Hey, how are you?
Uh, no guests.
Can you fetch me another
plate of those crab puffs? Delish.
Head of security.
Not your waiter.
Oh. Good for you. Have
you tried the crab puffs?
MAN 1: Hey, my drink.
What the... MAN
2: Watch the suit!
MAN 1: That's the third
time you've done that tonight.
WOMAN: Guys... MAN 2:
Watch what you're doing.
MAN 1: I'm going to
take you outside right now.
MAN 3: All right, fellas.
Break it up, break it up.
I looped that one. But I don't
remember if I looped that one.
You don't remember
five seconds ago?
Josh, I haven't had
short-term memory in two days.
Only things I remember
are being worried about Eliot
and feeling like shit for
trying to leave you in the past.
Really?
(CHUCKLING)
Fucking moon brain.
Totally spaced out.
Why are you looking
at me like that?
These are good.
Let's go.
(ALL LAUGHING)
OREN: It's true.
It's true about...
Excuse me, sir. Excuse me.
We have an issue.
OREN: Natasha? What
the hell is she doing here?
Well, my men will find
out, but I have a hunch.
There's one thing you
own that only she can steal.
(LOUD THUD)
Bring back the rock.
Stop! MAN: Wait!
MAN 2: Right there, right there!
Let's go.
Natasha. Where is she going?
For the last time,
we don't know.
And even if we did,
we would never admit it.
HEAD OF SECURITY: No bother.
My men have her now.
Whoa, whoa, whoa... (STUTTERS)
What's going on?
Where's the moon rock?
What? I don't... I don't know.
Look, I was just hitchhiking, and a
woman, she just threw the keys at me, okay?
Look, just take
the van, whatever.
Look, she... She went that way.
She escaped? Where's the rock?
Well, I officially
have moon brain.
I can see her aura. It's red.
Let's do this quick,
before anyone comes in.
How long do we have to
cast the first part again?
Until her aura turns
green and she's listening.
It's working.
Where is Natasha
taking the rock?
Okay, okay. She said
she was going to Philly.
The only thing worse
than a traitor is a snitch.
You make me wanna puke.
Hey, Josh. Do you
have any more muffins?
JULIA: Almost there.
(EXHALES)
Wait. We had it. What happened?
How did it turn red?
Eliot? Wait. Eliot, come back.
We don't have enough
power to finish this without you.
MAN: Eliot.
Eliot.
Let me out.
You're not there.
You're gone forever.
Quentin threw you in the Seam.
(SIGHS)
This isn't happening.
This is moon brain.
(GUN COCKING)
MAN: Stop right there!
My guards are in the
room with your friends.
The rock never left, did it?
I want the snitch to tell me what's
really going on. (WHIMPERING)
What happened?
Asshole fell asleep again.
His fight-or-flight response
is to take a fucking nap.
(MEN GROANING) (THUDDING)
(MEN SNORING)
Or something else is up.
ALICE: Wasn't me.
In here, boss.
JULIA: Marina. (CHUCKLES)
Ladies.
Did you put the guards to sleep?
Yeah, but I'm a little confused
why you aren't snoozing too.
The only thing stronger
than that spell is...
Oh, my God. Are you on meth?
You know, it sure
as hell seems like it.
(SNORING)
What are you doing here?
Keeping you from fucking up my
shit. Harmonic Convergence, I need it.
Like Daddy always said,
even meth can't beat handcuffs.
I don't think you understand
how bad the Convergence is.
No, I do. But what you don't
understand is how good it is for me.
I have a very critical mission,
and I need the power
Convergence boost to do it.
So, just this one time,
could you please go home?
Look, whatever it is you're
doing, it's not worth the world.
Mmm, yes, it is. I put a
shitload of work into this.
I stole a Book Depository,
for Christ's sake.
That was you?
You sent that memory
assassin after me.
Yeah, not a life
assassin. You're welcome.
We're even, since you
tipped us to this party.
Frederick here...
That's not my name.
Okay. Not-Frederick here
overheard you in my Book Depository
making these exciting
plans for the Convergence.
Speaking of, it just started.
I flinch, it fires.
I think we all know
what that was.
It's the surge.
You know what that means,
Chickee-poo? Power is insane.
You're holding a nuke right now.
You let that thing
go, we all go bye-bye.
Kady, she's right. With the
Convergence and the surge,
every spell is, like,
super-powered right now.
Yeah, I bet you could cast something
solo that would normally take three people.
MARINA: Isn't that
what I just said?
JULIA: Marina, please. We're
so close to saving everyone.
You can't just take
that away from us now.
Whatever it is you're after,
what's the point if there's no world?
There'll still be a world.
Just not as many people.
Have you met people?
She's listening. Eliot, go.
The fuck are you
doing? I got it.
You're moving the moon? Yeah.
I'm moving it back.
(BOTH STRAINING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(BOTH GRUNT)
Uh...
Guys.
I think we just broke the moon.
MARINA: Ah, shit.
(SNORING)