Previously on "The Magicians"...
There's too much magic.
Everything that I touch just...
it grows like crazy.
I'm gonna let your bullshit slide
on account of you so
recently being possessed
by a homicidal monster.
There was a blood worm scare,
so the Library gave a lot
of hedges the Reed's Mark.
I found a spell to remove
the Marks in a Depository.
I get you're on a mission.
One of you's got to jet.
Either one of you can hang for eternity.
I've earned the right to step off.
We're here to study with Mayakovsky.
I hate all of you.
Professor?
_
"Best bitches."
Wear this, and you'll see what I see.
I'm Clarion, the goddess of melody.
The way that you're imagining
the Harmonic Convergence
isn't quite enough.
When all the spells cast by
all the Magicians go haywire,
you're gonna get earthquakes,
starvation, plague.
She didn't have time to be delicate.
You can't travel anymore.
What exactly are we looking for, sir?
Not what. Who.
- You two know each other?
- No.
Well, your subjects
are rightly grateful.
For sending that letter?
AKA that thing I totally
didn't do; you did.
I was gonna let you die for Fillory.
The Convergence can be stopped.
All you have to do is move...
that.
The Harmonic Convergence.
- AKA the end of the world.
- Not necessarily.
This constellation forms a cosmic sigil
that increases magical intensity.
It has happened in the past
without causing an apocalypse.
But now there's surges of magic.
So we get the disaster movie
Clarion was talking about.
The Convergence will only occur
during this perfect alignment.
If we move the moon out of position...
No Convergence, no Circumstance,
no apocalypse.
The moon is not just a rock in space.
It has certain properties.
- Like?
- Magic doesn't work on it.
Thanks to Magicians
casting haphazardly on it
for millennia, the moon is
now covered by a crust
of spell debris, blocking new spells.
If we move any piece out
of place, no Convergence.
Well, what if we just moved Mars?
She said with a straight face.
The other pieces are planets.
We can't move them
because they are, well,
very big and far away.
The moon is the only celestial body
we stand a chance of affecting.
But won't that screw
with the Circumstances?
What will magic be like when we're done?
Impossible to know.
It will be a brand-new Circumstance.
But to get to that problem,
we need to solve this one.
Good, well, I hope you have some ideas,
because we're striking out.
I do. Consult the Lunatics.
- The lunatics?
- Short for "Lunar Fanatics."
In the Middle Ages,
people thought insanity
was caused by changing
phases of the moon.
In fact, it was often a Lunatic
in the throes of worship.
They claimed to be able to
achieve a magical connection
with the moon and even under
some circumstances...
move it.
Well, that sounds useful.
- Mm.
- Well, if it's just branding,
it means they're not
really crazy, right?
My dad always said that
they were batshit insane,
and he married my mom,
so he had a pretty high bar
for mental instability.
Regardless, they know more
about the moon than anyone.
I believe that talking to them
is our only chance at success.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[EERIE MUSIC]
♪
- Synced & corrected by MementMori -
-- www.addic7ed.com --
_
What people don't understand
is there is a skeleton of the universe,
but we are the bones.
Oh, that's good to know.
I am a humerus.
You? Patella.
We wanted to ask you about the moon.
Can we talk about it?
It... it?
Her Lunacy...
Identifies as she/her.
That's right. We knew that, right?
- Of course.
- We know.
If we wanted to move Her,
how could we do that?
You don't move Her.
Okay, listen, Reba.
In just a few days, a whole lot
of people are going to die.
That's a whole lot people
that will never get to worship the moon.
They will never get to
know Her like you do.
If She can help us save
all of those lives...
imagine everyone that will realize
just how much She deserves their love,
their reverence.
So will you help us?
Just to be clear.
You don't move Her.
You ask Her to move.
And She won't let you speak to
Her unless you get moon brain.
So one of us needs moon brain.
Not one of you. Three of you.
A single Magician cannot
generate enough power
to reach Her.
So it's a cooperative spell then.
It is a sign of respect, Kneecap,
that allows you to see
Her as She truly is.
If you have moon brain,
then you will see Her aura.
Now it is red, but when you
perform the Dianic Ritual,
Her aura will change.
If it is yellow, She is considering.
If it is green, She is listening.
Only then may you ask Her
to move.
Red, yellow, green.
The guy who invented the stoplight,
was he a Lunatic too?
William Potts? Yeah.
Oh, cool.
All three Magicians
must perform the ritual
until the moon is listening.
A warning: once Her aura is green,
She may choose to listen
to anyone who calls to Her, so be ready.
You must choose one,
the strongest among you,
to speak to Her, like the
old Lunatics taught us to.
For this second part,
however, there is a price.
- A price, like blood?
- It is like blood to Her.
You will need a piece
of Her. A sacrifice.
A piece?
- Or like a moon rock?
- Yes.
But be aware,
this will destroy it,
so don't use your favorite one.
This is the price of
speaking to the moon.
Just a few more questions.
What is moon brain,
and how do we get it?
- Everyone line up.
- Pudding time!
Lovely to speak to you.
You too, Kneecap. [CLICKS TONGUE]
[FUNKY MUSIC]
♪
You ever just spin a globe,
stick your finger down,
see where it lands?
It's almost always water,
because, well, duh.
Earth is mostly water, but
sometimes it's the Sahara,
sometimes the Urals.
That's what you'd be doing
if you tried to travel.
Only instead of the
globe, the multiverse,
which is bigger and deadlier.
Afraid you'd say that.
I looked at everything I could think of,
magical and medical.
Nada. You're grounded.
All right, well, since
I ain't traveling,
I should probably step down.
Uh, if you're offering your resignation,
I don't accept.
Not offering. Stating.
With Dean Fogg out indefinitely,
Brakebills has instituted our
Dean Vanishment Protocol.
Of course, that's a thing here.
Yeah, and uh... [CLEARS THROAT]
That makes me acting Dean Lipson.
There's no instruction manual,
so I'm kinda dean-ing on the fly here,
but one thing I do know
is losing a professor who was disabled
on school grounds ain't happening.
I mean, the optics would
be pure shitflakes.
So your contract will be
honored and enforced.
Oh, also.
We need a new Welters coach.
I've been on the inside,
and I'm telling you
it's a goddamn goose-stepping,
fairy-snatching, ethnic
cleansing Gestapo.
To be fair, the ethnic
cleansing happened
after the Dark King left, so...
He's innocent because he delegates?
No, that's not what I'm saying.
Someone in this castle ordered
the hunt on that Fairy.
It could have been the Dark King,
but if it was someone else,
killing Seb might just
make things worse.
So we have to find out
who before we... coup.
I just wanna stab someone.
I haven't heard you
this bloodthirsty in...
well, not that long,
but still, it's notable.
Maybe I'm a bit on edge.
Josh keeps wanting to talk.
You mean about how you wanted
to leave him in the past to die?
Yeah, that.
So far, I'm doing a good
job of avoiding him,
but eventually he's gonna sneak...
Guys.
- Hey, what's up?
- 'Sup?
First off, kudos on the hiding spot.
It took me forever to find you.
Pretty busy here, Josh.
You're busy?
I just got promoted to head chef.
- Oh, congratulations.
- Thank you.
But I'm about to bail on a state dinner
and leave it to my incompetent
sous-chef because...
Apocalypse! Now!
Josh, would you just give it up?
He keeps trying to get us
to join his film club,
which I told him would
never work on a planet
with no electricity or taste.
Uh, no, uh, sorry.
This one's just a little shy.
It... it's okay, buddy.
- Help us stop the...
- Apocalypse! Now!
- Oh.
- We need to get back to Earth.
Margo, our talk will have to wait
till after we save the world.
Oh, but then I have my
nephew's bar mitzvah.
So after that?
- Mazel.
- Thanks.
[SIGHS]
What about our thing? We have
a lot of fact-finding to do
before I can get to stabbing.
No problem.
I know just who to handle it.
You want me to what?
Just find out who in the
castle hates Fairies.
Okay? And what they're doing to them.
And why Fairies in the first place?
And maybe talk to some Fairies,
get their side of things.
- Okay.
- And while you're at it...
anything else that seems important.
Okay, okay, okay.
No, um... That seems like a
lot of open-ended questions.
- Mm-hmm.
- I got this maid job
to be close to you guys,
and now you're deserting me? [CHUCKLES]
I want to stop an apocalypse too.
Every apocalypse-stopping mission
needs a maid on the outside.
It's a key staple in Earth movies.
Do you mean inside man?
'Cause that's more of
a heist movie thing.
- No, that's different.
- Okay.
Everyone knows
the "secret, sexy maid
on the outside" trope.
- Yeah?
- Josh has a film club.
- You should check it out.
- Huh.
Maid on the outside. Yeah.
So did your loony friend
say how to get moon brain?
From what we read, her rituals
are simple first-year Popper tuts.
But moon brain is...
the insanity you get from
extreme sleep deprivation.
Extreme, like a night partying,
or what are we talking about?
I wish.
Five nights without sleep,
and we can't use magic
to stay awake either.
Apparently, moon brain has
to come about naturally.
This is completely nuts.
Isn't the Harmonic whatever
happening in five nights?
Yes, so if we all start tonight,
we might actually have
a shot at stopping it.
Wait a minute. [LAUGHS]
Five nights without sleep is
gonna fuck us up royally.
Can we even cast if
we're that messed up?
Well, three of us have to.
Look, guys, I know it sucks,
but whoever can stay up for 132 hours
without sleep and not lose their shit...
gets to stop the apocalypse.
I don't know about you guys,
but I am doing great.
- _
- Coffee.
Where's our fearless leader?
- _
- She's taking a cold shower
to keep herself awake.
Third... fourth time this morning.
Well, I don't know about you guys,
but I am too excited to sleep.
I mean, we're doing it!
Is this, uh, helping
you find moon rocks?
Mm.
No, this is helping us stay awake.
The moment I research,
I'm out like a light.
Know what might help?
If we make this party a
little more '80s themed.
Eliot.
Oh, I don't think we should.
If we ski the fresh
powder, know what I mean?
- Yeah, I get it.
- I mean cocaine.
Get me cocaine.
- I am not getting you cocaine.
- Eliot.
A five-day bender would
destroy your nose,
and could you imagine what that would do
to your sense of taste?
I get a full nine every night,
and I'm still a bitch.
This is gonna get real.
Hey, guys, come check this out.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
I found something.
NASA brought back a bunch of moon rocks
from the Apollo missions.
We're stealing from NASA? Hell, yeah.
Mama's checking one more
off her bucket list.
Okay, we're not stealing from NASA.
I checked, it's impossible. I'm sorry.
But some of the rocks
that they brought back,
they gave out as gifts,
and they went missing.
About 180.
The ones they did find,
they found 'em in garages,
desk drawers, kids' bedrooms.
Just lying around.
People forgot about them,
but they're out there,
and I definitely think we can get one.
Okay, you guys do that.
I'm gonna go get some
stay-awake supplies.
I have a muffin recipe
with a special ingredient
that is guaranteed to keep
us alert for five days.
What is it? Meth?
Oh, excuse you.
It is a organic, locally-sourced
natural stimulant that got me
through every finals week,
and it is definitely not meth.
That's exactly what I would say
if I was trying to get us to take meth.
Mm-hmm.
You're taking retirement well.
I find that organization
helps bring a sense of stability
when one's feeling...
not stable.
Okay.
I need to find a Book
Depository that got moved.
It's in Hell's Kitchen,
that's all I know.
Library buildings are
enchanted to blend in
with their new environs
whenever they're relocated.
You'll have to go door-to-door,
find the building covered
in Library wards.
Great. Let's go.
You're abandoning your friends?
They have enough people
for a rock search.
Plus, whatever's in Josh's
muffins doesn't sound like
something a person in
recovery should be taking.
I need to find the Depository
before we move the moon
and screw up magic.
Right now, we have enough
to remove Reed's Marks.
After, like you said, who knows?
I'm not sure I'd be much use to you.
Out in the world.
The building's impenetrable
on a good day.
Unless you're a Librarian who
knows the security protocols.
I don't know...
I'm not asking for your help.
I'm giving you a chance to fix
your massive, massive mistake.
Mm.
Let's go.
♪
High King Fen?
[GASPS] Fairy!
Keep the High King talk quiet.
I'm undercover.
- You will come with me.
- Oh!
That... that is so great.
I have a lot of questions for you.
Some I don't even know why I'm asking.
They said you would fear me.
Funny thing.
I am on a Fairy quest.
See, I'm a maid on the outside.
Super-secret. Super-sexy.
Follow me, Maid on the Outside Fen.
Good.
Okay.
- Guess what I found.
- You found a moon rock?
I found a moon rock.
And those muffins smell amazing.
- Thank you.
- Now all we have to do is stay awake.
You know what helps me stay awake?
- What's that?
- An open, naked conversation
about our relationship.
I wanna tell you about all
my repressed emotions.
One by one.
Oh, baby. [LAUGHS]
Josh.
Josh!
- Oh, no.
- Josh!
[SIGHS]
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
We leave you for one afternoon,
and you fuck us completely.
I'm sorry, guys.
I sat down for one minute
because I never fall asleep
when I have something in the oven.
Well, congratulations.
This is a milestone for you.
Hey, guys.
Hope you had better luck than we did.
Nope, we portal-hopped
every lead we had.
The closest thing we found
was a chunk of old concrete
with the word "moon"
written on it in Sharpie.
Those rocks are gone.
But we did come home
to find Josh sleeping peacefully.
I'm going to assume your rudeness
is because sleep deprivation
makes you irritable.
Sure. Assume that.
Yeah, I get it.
I'm gonna have to staple
my eyes open; this is rough.
No one else sleeps. We have four nights.
We need one rock lead to pan out.
But if the spell burns them up,
what if we can't find any rocks
because the Lunatics used them all?
What if there's no more
moon rocks on Earth?
Just sayin',
we could celebrate the Harmonic
Convergence in Fillory.
It's a little dystopian at the mo',
but on the plus, their weekend forecast
doesn't call for an apocalypse.
[SIGHS]
Look, guys,
if you're looking for some
sort of inspirational speech
on why you should stay and fight,
I can't help you. It's gonna suck,
and even if we do succeed,
which we might not,
it's not like we're
gonna get any credit.
The world ends, I end with it,
knowing that I did everything I could,
because I won't be able to
live with myself otherwise.
Julia's right.
She really does suck at
inspirational speeches.
But also that we should save the world.
I'm with you.
So am I.
Me too.
I'm in.
[AS GIMLI] And my axe!
[CHUCKLES]
Really?
- No?
- No.
Should've led with, "You have my bow."
- Mm-hmm.
- Nope.
Josh, put some fresh meth
muffins in the oven.
Again, not meth.
[SCOFFS]
_
Hey! No droopy eyes on my watch.
One more.
- _
- I'm good now.
I ain't.
Oh, well, right on cue.
I tried something new this round.
A hint of lavender and goji berry.
How we doin', Captain?
Oh, you know, 12 hours
till the end of the world,
and it's like we're still
grasping for needles in a hay straw.
Fun. Okay.
Probably not the best
question for morale,
but as the only person here
who's slept this week,
we have 12 hours and zero leads.
Is waiting here to die
really the best option?
When are we gonna give
Margo's idea another think?
Guys, I can't trust my brain right now,
but this seems like
it could be relevant.
I think this guy has a moon rock.
Oren Westbrook. Why do I know him?
Because you're not a cave person.
He invented the tech for pop-up ads,
and he invented the tech
to block pop-up ads.
Ever since, he's just
been a weird rich guy
doing weird-rich-guy shit.
I heard his blood boy
has his own blood boy.
[SIGHS]
Ew, what's on his eye?
That's the same tattoo that Reba had.
Julia, I think he's a Lunatic.
All right.
So in order to save the
world, all we have to do
is convince some eccentric
billionaire with armed guards
to give up something he
probably considers to be, like,
his Holy Grail.
All while we're so tired
we can't see straight.
Pshh, no sweat.
[YAWNS]
Marvelous.
How did you handle the pain?
Knowing it would bring
me closer to Her Lunacy
- helped me get through it.
- _
- [SIGHS]
Same as when I got mine.
That and a handful of opiates.
[LAUGHTER]
Hey, sorry about the security.
I hope you guys understand.
Ah, please, you can't
let in every Lunatic.
Some people are crazy.
[LAUGHING]
Eliot.
Oh, wow, you guys really look awful.
What?
Eliot...
Your sunken eyes!
- Let me out.
- Preparing for moon brain?
The Harmonic Convergence.
Mm! Yeah, baby.
I'm celebrating too.
I'm gonna have a few
friends over for a party.
Uh, El?
Eliot?
Eliot, you good?
- Yeah, yea... yeah.
- Yeah.
Just can't wait to see
this amazing moon rock.
Don't worry.
You both will experience Her.
[SHAKY BREATH]
[SOFT MUSIC]
♪
[SIGHS] What a cozy little nightmare.
I might need you to
punch me to stay awake.
Gotcha.
- Isn't She wondrous?
- Yeah, definitely.
Think we can turn on the lights
and turn off the yoga music?
You got this from the moon... how?
I went.
You just went to the moon
like it was Coney Island?
Yeah, actually, it was pretty tough.
To be honest, I was trying
to impress someone.
But in the end, our
souls did not connect.
Yeah, we need to ask a favor.
For my fellow Lunatics,
I would move Heaven and Earth.
[CHUCKLES] About that...
Yeah, look, we know this
rock is special to you...
- Super special.
- But we need it.
To move Her. Hence the moon brain.
You do know what that would do, right?
Yes, but it's a matter
of life and death.
We can stop the Harmonic Convergence
if we can hold the moon out
of position long enough.
- Why?
- Because it's going to cause
worldwide destruction.
Magic will become so powerful,
it'll be apocalyptic.
I mean, it's not like it's gonna
wipe out all life on Earth.
Just some.
You know exactly how
bad it's going to get,
don't you?
What, are you planning to
profit off this or something?
I'm planning to use my resources
to help the world recover.
Now, I'm an entrepreneurial spirit.
I can't help but make money.
Now, I do think that the moon
brain is getting to you.
Unless...
Mm, your eye tattoo is illusion magic.
You're no Lunatic at all.
I'll have my guards escort you out.
Let's go, El. We tried.
Happens all the time.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
♪
- Get it?
- All of it.
We have a problem.
So it's just security cameras
until we get to the moon rock room,
and that's where it gets tough.
One way in, one way out.
I mean, if we get caught, we're trapped.
Guys. Guys!
- [LOUD MUSIC]
- Thanks!
So... the rock.
Whole lotta wards around it,
nothing we can't get past,
except for the one on the rock itself.
It's... well, it's a bond that
we've never seen before,
put there by Mayakovsky.
Well, that can't be right.
Oren just got the rock.
And didn't you say the last time
you saw Mayakovsky,
he was basically senile?
Yeah, well, I guess he got better.
I mean, he... he put his signature
into the lattice work of the spell.
You can't miss it.
It's the most amazing,
most narcissistic thing I've ever seen.
Mm.
- Hey, Eliot?
- Hm?
Can I talk to you for a sec?
Yeah.
I said I'm fine.
[SIGHS]
I have been awake for
thousands of hours straight.
Look, I saw your moment back there,
and I think I might know what's up.
You think you do, but you don't.
Okay, so the first two nights, no sleep,
things got a little weird, right?
Like picking up my
phone to call Quentin.
You know, I must've done
that like five times.
But then my brain crossed
over into darker...
Here's the deal.
When the Sister was in me,
I remember everything.
Every bloody second of it.
And usually, I'm good
at pushing it away,
but right now...
it is like a constant
slideshow in the background.
Not fun. El.
The Monster was in you for months.
Well, it was different.
People have different experiences.
All that time was just
one big nap to me,
which... sounds so good right now.
[CHUCKLES]
I don't know why you're lying to me.
Or anyone.
I don't know why you're
accusing me of lying.
Okay.
Neither of us have the
bandwidth for this right now,
and I don't trust you.
I don't.
But if you ever do decide to talk,
open door.
Shit.
If I may, lenses can be sensitive
to changes in your
Internal Circumstances.
You may need to adjust
if you're feeling off.
God damn it.
If something is bothering you,
I know I'm not the ideal
person to talk to,
but I am here.
I'm not feeling chatty
at the moment, okay?
[SIGHS]
Look, you're not the only
one that made a mistake,
'cause clearly it's still bothering me.
It's Fogg.
He's stuck in the Etheric Realm,
and it's my fault.
Henry's in...
He always was a sensualist.
That place is a trap for people
like him, who enjoy, well...
- Getting wasted?
- Mm.
He was trying to quit.
He shouldn't have even been in there.
He was only in there because of me.
And you were only there
because you wanted to help the hedges.
You know, if we're being honest...
I wanted to get high.
Lucky me, that's the only
way into the Etheric Realm.
Fogg just...
tagged along and got unlucky.
That wasn't luck.
I know the Emperor of the Realm.
If he kept Henry behind,
it was because he sensed a flaw in him.
And if he kicked you out,
it was because you were
trying to do something good.
Nothing bores him like goodness.
Yeah, how do you know that?
I spent three years there once.
Jesus.
Before I came to the Library,
my life was... difficult.
The Etheric Realm was an escape.
How did you get out?
I stopped hating myself. Eventually.
And then the Emperor grew bored with me.
Whatever kept Henry there,
those were his demons,
and that is something you couldn't fix.
Well, it doesn't stop me from
feeling like shit about it.
The fact that you feel like shit,
that is why you escaped.
So allow me to be blunt.
Don't waste time on self-pity.
Do what you came to do.
Thanks.
I'll try to be less of a bitch to you.
Mm. If you can.
[BREATHES DEEPLY]
It's working.
I can see the wards.
This way.
[SIGHS]
[MAN SCREAMING]
It sounds like he's home.
Look, fair warning...
Who the hell are you?
We're looking for Mayakovsky.
Old, drunk, megalomaniac?
Fondness for knit caps?
Yeah, I'm his daughter.
I didn't realize he...
Fucked my mother? Neither did he.
Should've seen his face
when I came knockin'.
But we're fine now. What do you want?
Can you let us down?
Sure.
Thanks.
Look.
We need to talk to your dad.
He's busy.
On our project.
Look, we think he may be the only person
that can help us save the world.
He put a special magical
bond on a moon rock,
and we need his help to break it.
Wait, please tell me you're
trying to rob Oren Westbrook.
- How do you know that?
- I installed that bond.
Yeah, last nice thing I did
before I dumped his greasy ass.
- That was you?
- What? You dated him?
Don't judge, but yes.
Anyfuck, right after
I installed the bond,
I caught the maid pegging him,
and not the maid I
okayed for threesomes.
- Mm...
- Okay.
So that means you'll help us?
I could.
But I need something from you.
A shade.
Either of yours will do.
[SCOFFS]
What are you gonna do with it?
- Are we gonna get it back?
- [LAUGHS] No.
- You want my help?
- Mm-hmm.
One shade, payment in advance.
Discuss.
- It's safe.
- Thanks.
- [DOOR CLOSES]
- [SIGHS]
Any idea where to find a
medical manual in here?
Unfortunately,
the organizational systems
- are down, so it may...
- [SCOFFS]
[SPEAKING SWAHILI]
May I?
[SPEAKING URDU]
- [ECHOING WHOOSH]
- Hm.
Sometimes I forget you're
a fucking master Magician.
I try to keep the
showboating to a minimum.
Well, the Harmonic Convergence
is in a few hours.
- You know what that means.
- I'll take this to Harriet ASAP.
Tell her if, God forbid,
we can't stop it...
we might need all the hedges we
can get to unfuck everything.
_
Desperate times, huh?
Didn't really have much choice.
Hey, uh, Julia?
Can you remind me why I'm
dressed like this, please?
He's been like this all night.
Just running on muffin fumes.
Okay, let's just make sure
we're all on the same page.
Okay? Okay, so Josh, Margo, Penny.
You guys go inside,
loop all the cameras,
open the side door for Natasha.
I'll be outside waiting
with Eliot and Alice.
We won't cast the spell
until your signal.
You won't miss it. Ready?
Break.
Eliot. What are you staring at?
Pull the ripcord, get out.
We'll handle this.
I am not cocking out.
You're not right, El,
and we both know why.
My crippling fear of/
attraction to authority?
Are you being honest with me?
Bambi, always.
I don't care if you've
been keeping it from me,
but all of our asses
are on the line now.
Margo.
Do not worry about me.
I know, I've been a little bit off.
Blame it on the moon brain.
I promise I'm fine.
'Kay?
[SIGHS]
_
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Hey! How are you?
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
♪
Oh.
Uh, no guests.
Can you fetch me another
plate of those crab puffs?
- Delish.
- Head of security.
- Not your waiter.
- Oh, good for you.
Have you tried the crab puffs?
Hey, my drink!
- What the...
- Watch the suit!
That's the third time
you've done that tonight!
Watch what you're doing!
I'm gonna take you outside right now.
All right, fellas,
break it up, break it up.
I looped that one,
but I don't remember
if I looped that one.
You don't remember five seconds ago?
Josh, I haven't had short-term
memory in two days.
The only things I remember
are being worried about Eliot
and feeling like shit for trying
to leave you in the past.
Really?
[LAUGHS] Fucking moon brain.
Totally spaced out.
Why are you looking at me like that?
These are good.
Let's go.
[LAUGHTER]
- It's true. It's true.
- [CLEARS THROAT]
Excuse me, sir.
Excuse me.
We have an issue.
Natasha?
What the hell is she doing here?
Well, my men will find out,
but I have a hunch.
There's one thing you own
that only she can steal.
[EXPLOSION]
[CROWD MURMURING]
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪
Bring back the rock.
- Stop!
- Wh...
Right there, right there!
♪
Let's go!
Natasha. Where is she going?
For the last time, we don't know.
And even if we did,
we would never admit it.
No bother.
My men have her now.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
♪
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa. What's going on?
- Where's the moon rock?
- What... I don't...
I don't know!
Look, I was just hitchhiking,
and a woman, she just threw
the keys at me, okay?
Just take the van, whatever.
Look, she went that way.
She escaped?
Where's the rock?
♪
Well, I officially have moon brain.
I can see Her aura. It's red.
Let's do this quick
before anyone comes in.
How long do we have to
cast the first part again?
Until Her aura turns green
and She's listening.
It's working.
♪
Where is Natasha taking the rock?
Okay... okay.
She said she was going to Philly.
The only thing worse than
a traitor is a snitch.
You make me wanna puke.
Hey, hey, Josh.
Do you have any more muffins?
♪
Almost there.
We had it.
What happened?
How did it turn red?
Eliot?
Wait, Eliot, come back!
We don't have enough power
to finish this without you.
Eliot.
Eliot...
Let me out.
[DARK MUSIC]
♪
You're not there.
You're gone forever.
Quentin threw you in the Seam.
[SIGHS]
This isn't happening.
This is moon brain.
♪
Stop right there!
My guards are in the
room with your friends.
The rock never left, did it?
You know, I want the snitch
to tell me what's really going on.
- What happened?
- Asshole fell asleep again.
His fight-or-flight response
is to take a fucking nap.
[MEN GROANING]
Or something else is up.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
It wasn't me.
♪
In here, boss.
- Marina.
- [CHUCKLES]
Ladies.
Did you put the guards to sleep?
Yeah,
but I'm a little confused why
you aren't snoozing too.
The only thing stronger
than that spell is...
Oh, my God. Are you on meth?
You know, it sure as hell seems like it.
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
♪
What are you doing here?
Keeping you from fucking up my shit.
Harmonic Convergence, I need it.
Like Daddy always said,
even meth can't beat handcuffs.
I don't think you understand
how bad the Convergence is.
No, I do.
But what you don't understand
is how good it is for me.
I have a very critical mission,
and I need the power
convergence boost to do it.
So just this one time,
could you please go home?
Look, whatever it is you're doing,
it's not worth the world.
Mm, yes, it is.
I put a shitload of work into this.
I stole a Book Depository,
for Christ sake.
That was you?
You sent that memory assassin after me.
Yeah, and not a life assassin.
You're welcome.
We're even, since you
tipped us to this party.
- Frederick here...
- That's not my name.
Okay, not-Frederick here,
overheard you in my Book Depository
making these exciting plans
for the Convergence.
Speaking of...
just started.
I flinch, it fires.
Oh...
I think we all know what that was.
It's the surge.
You know what that means, Chickee-poo?
Power is insane.
You're holding a nuke right now.
You let that thing go,
we all go bye-bye.
Kady, she's right; with the
Convergence and the surge,
every spell is, like,
super-powered right now.
Yeah, I bet you could
cast something solo
that would normally take three people.
- Isn't that what I just said?
- Marina!
Please, we are so close
to saving everyone.
You can't just take
that away from us now.
Whatever it is you're after,
what's the point if there's no world?
There'll still be a world,
just not as many people.
- Have you met people?
- She's listening!
Eliot, go!
- The fuck are you doing?
- I've got it.
- You're moving the moon?
- Yeah.
I'm moving it back.
[BOTH STRAINING]
[GRUNTING]
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪
[BOTH SCREAMING]
Uh...
guys?
I think we just broke the moon.
Ah, shit.
- Synced & corrected by MementMori -
-- www.addic7ed.com --