Previously,
on "The Magicians"...
There's too much magic.
Everything that I touch just...
It just grows like crazy.
I'm gonna let your bullshit
slide on account of you
so recently being possessed
by a homicidal monster.
There was a blood worm scare,
so the Library gave a lot
of hedges the Reed's Mark.
I found a spell to remove
the Marks in a Depository.
- I get you're on a mission.
- One of you's got to jet.
Either one of you
can hang for eternity.
I've earned the right
to step off.
We're here to study
with Mayakovsky.
I hate all of you.
Professor?
"Best bitches."
Wear this,
and you'll see what I see.
I'm Clarion,
the goddess of melody.
The way that you're imagining
the Harmonic Convergence
isn't quite enough.
When all the spells cast by
all the Magicians go haywire,
you're gonna get earthquakes,
starvation, plague.
She didn't have time
to be delicate.
You can't travel anymore.
What exactly
are we looking for, sir?
Not what. Who.
- You two know each other?
- No.
Well, your subjects
are rightly grateful.
For sending that letter?
AKA that thing I totally
didn't do; You did.
I was gonna let you die
for Fillory.
The Convergence can be stopped.
All you have to do is move...
that.
The Harmonic Convergence.
- AKA the end of the world.
- Not necessarily.
This constellation forms
a cosmic sigil
that increases
magical intensity.
It has happened in the past
without causing an apocalypse.
But now there's surges of magic.
So we get the disaster movie
Clarion was talking about.
The Convergence will only occur
during this perfect alignment.
If we move the moon
out of position...
No Convergence, no Circumstance,
no apocalypse.
The moon is not just
a rock in space.
It has certain properties.
- Like?
- Magic doesn't work on it.
Thanks to Magicians
casting haphazardly on it
for millennia, the moon
is now covered by a crust
of spell debris,
blocking new spells.
If we move any piece
out of place, no Convergence.
Well, what if we just
moved Mars?
She said with a straight face.
The other pieces are planets.
We can't move them
because they are, well,
very big and far away.
The moon is the only
celestial body
we stand a chance of affecting.
But won't that screw
with the Circumstances?
What will magic be like
when we're done?
Impossible to know.
It will be a brand-new
Circumstance.
But to get to that problem,
we need to solve this one.
Good, well,
I hope you have some ideas,
because we're striking out.
I do. Consult the Lunatics.
- The lunatics?
- Short for "Lunar Fanatics."
In the Middle Ages,
people thought insanity
was caused by changing phases
of the moon.
In fact, it was often a Lunatic
in the throes of worship.
They claimed to be able
to achieve a magical connection
with the moon and even under
some circumstances...
move it.
- Well, that sounds useful.
- Mm.
Well, if it's just branding,
it means they're
not really crazy, right?
My dad always said that
they were batshit insane,
and he married my mom,
so he had a pretty high bar
for mental instability.
Regardless, they know more
about the moon than anyone.
I believe that talking to them
is our only chance at success.
What people don't understand
is there is a skeleton
of the universe,
but we are the bones.
Oh, that's good to know.
I am a humerus.
You? Patella.
We wanted to ask you
about the moon.
Can we talk about it?
It... it?
Her Lunacy...
Identifies as she/her.
- That's right.
- We knew that, right?
- Of course.
- We know.
If we wanted to move Her,
how could we do that?
You don't move Her.
Okay, listen, Reba.
In just a few days, a whole lot
of people are going to die.
That's a whole lot people
that will never
get to worship the moon.
They will never get
to know Her like you do.
If She can help us save
all of those lives...
imagine everyone
that will realize
just how much
She deserves their love,
their reverence.
So will you help us?
Just to be clear.
You don't move Her.
You ask Her to move.
And She won't let you speak to
Her unless you get moon brain.
So one of us needs moon brain.
Not one of you. Three of you.
A single Magician cannot
generate enough power
to reach Her.
So it's
a cooperative spell then.
It is a sign of respect,
Kneecap,
that allows you to see Her
as She truly is.
If you have moon brain,
then you will see Her aura.
Now it is red, but when you
perform the Dianic Ritual,
Her aura will change.
If it is yellow,
She is considering.
If it is green,
She is listening.
Only then may you ask Her
to move.
Red, yellow, green.
The guy who invented
the stoplight,
was he a Lunatic too?
William Potts? Yeah.
Oh, cool.
All three Magicians
must perform the ritual
until the moon is listening.
A warning: Once Her aura is
green, She may choose to listen
to anyone who calls to Her,
so be ready.
You must choose one,
the strongest among you,
to speak to Her, like the old
Lunatics taught us to.
For this second part,
however, there is a price.
- A price, like blood?
- It is like blood to Her.
You will need a piece of Her.
A sacrifice.
A piece?
- Or like a moon rock?
- Yes.
But be aware,
this will destroy it,
so don't use your favorite one.
This is the price
of speaking to the moon.
Just a few more questions.
What is moon brain,
and how do we get it?
- Everyone line up.
- Pudding time!
Lovely to speak to you.
You too, Kneecap.
You ever just spin a globe,
stick your finger down,
see where it lands?
It's almost always water,
because, well, duh.
Earth is mostly water,
but sometimes it's the Sahara,
sometimes the Urals.
That's what you'd be doing
if you tried to travel.
Only instead of the globe,
the multiverse,
which is bigger and deadlier.
Afraid you'd say that.
I looked at everything
I could think of,
magical and medical.
Nada. You're grounded.
All right, well,
since I ain't traveling,
I should probably step down.
Uh, if you're offering
your resignation,
I don't accept.
Not offering. Stating.
With Dean Fogg out indefinitely,
Brakebills has instituted
our Dean Vanishment Protocol.
Of course, that's a thing here.
Yeah, and uh...
That makes me
acting Dean Lipson.
There's no instruction manual,
so I'm kinda dean-ing
on the fly here,
but one thing I do know
is losing a professor
who was disabled
on school grounds
ain't happening.
I mean, the optics
would be pure shitflakes.
So your contract
will be honored and enforced.
Oh, also.
We need a new Welters coach.
I've been on the inside,
and I'm telling you
it's a goddamn goose-stepping,
Fairy-snatching,
ethnic cleansing Gestapo.
To be fair,
the ethnic cleansing happened
after the Dark King left, so...
He's innocent
because he delegates?
No, that's not what I'm saying.
Someone in this castle ordered
the hunt on that Fairy.
It could have been
the Dark King,
but if it was someone else,
killing Seb might just make
things worse.
So we have to find out who
before we... coup.
I just wanna stab someone.
I haven't heard you
this bloodthirsty in...
Well, not that long,
but still, it's notable.
Maybe I'm a bit on edge.
Josh keeps wanting to talk.
You mean about how you wanted
to leave him in the past to die?
Yeah, that.
So far, I'm doing a good job
of avoiding him,
but eventually
he's gonna sneak...
Guys.
- Hey, what's up?
- 'Sup?
First off,
kudos on the hiding spot.
- It took me forever to find you.
- Pretty busy here, Josh.
You're busy?
I just got promoted
to head chef.
- Oh, congratulations.
- Thank you.
But I'm about to bail
on a state dinner
and leave it to my incompetent
sous-chef because...
Apocalypse! Now!
Josh, would you just give it up?
He keeps trying to get us
to join his film club,
which I told him would
never work on a planet
with no electricity or taste.
- Uh, no, uh, sorry.
- This one's just a little shy.
It... it's okay, buddy.
- Help us stop the...
- Apocalypse! Now!
- Oh.
- We need to get back to Earth.
Margo, our talk
will have to wait
till after we save the world.
Oh, but then I have
my nephew's bar mitzvah.
So after that?
- Mazel.
- Thanks.
What about our thing?
We have a lot
of fact-finding to do
before I can get to stabbing.
No problem.
I know just who to handle it.
You want me to what?
Just find out who
in the castle hates Fairies.
Okay?
And what they're doing to them.
And why Fairies
in the first place?
And maybe talk to some Fairies,
get their side of things.
- Okay.
- And while you're at it...
anything else
that seems important.
Okay, okay, okay. No, um...
That seems like a lot
of open-ended questions.
Mm-hmm.
I got this maid job
to be close to you guys,
and now you're deserting me?
I want to stop
an apocalypse too.
Every
apocalypse-stopping mission
needs a maid on the outside.
It's a key staple
in Earth movies.
Do you mean inside man?
'Cause that's more
of a heist movie thing.
- No, that's different.
- Okay.
Everyone knows
the "secret, sexy maid
on the outside" trope.
- Yeah?
- Josh has a film club.
- You should check it out.
- Huh.
Maid on the outside. Yeah.
So did your loony friend
say how to get moon brain?
From what we read, her rituals
are simple first-year
Popper tuts.
But moon brain is...
the insanity you get from
extreme sleep deprivation.
Extreme, like a night partying,
or what are we talking about?
I wish.
Five nights without sleep,
and we can't use magic
to stay awake either.
Apparently, moon brain
has to come about naturally.
This is completely nuts.
Isn't the Harmonic whatever
happening in five nights?
Yes, so if we all start tonight,
we might actually have
a shot at stopping it.
Wait a minute.
Five nights without sleep
is gonna fuck us up royally.
Can we even cast
if we're that messed up?
Well, three of us have to.
Look, guys, I know it sucks,
but whoever can stay up
for 132 hours
without sleep
and not lose their shit...
gets to stop the apocalypse.
I don't know about you guys,
but I am doing great.
Coffee.
Where's our fearless leader?
She's taking a cold shower
to keep herself awake.
Third... fourth time this morning.
Well, I don't know
about you guys,
but I am too excited to sleep.
I mean, we're doing it!
Is this, uh,
helping you find moon rocks?
Mm.
No, this is helping us
stay awake.
The moment I research,
I'm out like a light.
Know what might help?
If we make this party
a little more '80s themed.
Eliot.
Oh, I don't think we should.
If we ski the fresh powder,
know what I mean?
- Yeah, I get it.
- I mean cocaine.
- Get me cocaine.
- I am not getting you cocaine.
Eliot.
A five-day bender
would destroy your nose,
and could you imagine
what that would do
to your sense of taste?
I get a full nine every night,
and I'm still a bitch.
This is gonna get real.
Hey, guys, come check this out.
I found something.
NASA brought back
a bunch of moon rocks
from the Apollo missions.
- We're stealing from NASA?
- Hell, yeah.
Mama's checking one more
off her bucket list.
Okay, we're not stealing
from NASA.
I checked, it's impossible.
I'm sorry.
But some of the rocks
that they brought back,
they gave out as gifts,
and they went missing.
About 180.
The ones they did find,
they found 'em in garages,
desk drawers, kids' bedrooms.
Just lying around.
People forgot about them,
but they're out there,
and I definitely think
we can get one.
Okay, you guys do that.
I'm gonna go get some
stay-awake supplies.
I have a muffin recipe
with a special ingredient
that is guaranteed to keep us
alert for five days.
What is it? Meth?
Oh, excuse you.
It is a organic, locally-sourced
natural stimulant that got me
through every finals week,
and it is definitely not meth.
That's exactly what I would say
if I was trying
to get us to take meth.
Mm-hmm.
You're taking retirement well.
I find that organization
helps bring a sense of
stability when one's feeling...
not stable.
Okay.
I need to find a Book
Depository that got moved.
It's in Hell's Kitchen,
that's all I know.
Library buildings
are enchanted to blend in
with their new environs
whenever they're relocated.
You'll have to go door-to-door,
find the building covered in
Library wards.
Great. Let's go.
You're abandoning your friends?
They have enough people
for a rock search.
Plus, whatever's in Josh's
muffins doesn't sound like
something a person
in recovery should be taking.
I need to find the Depository
before we move the moon
and screw up magic.
Right now, we have enough
to remove Reed's Marks.
After, like you said, who knows?
I'm not sure
I'd be much use to you.
Out in the world.
The building's impenetrable
on a good day.
Unless you're a Librarian who
knows the security protocols.
I don't know...
I'm not asking for your help.
I'm giving you a chance to fix
your massive, massive mistake.
Mm.
Let's go.
High King Fen?
Fairy!
Keep the High King talk quiet.
I'm undercover.
- You will come with me.
- Oh!
That... that is so great.
I have a lot
of questions for you.
Some I don't even know
why I'm asking.
They said you would fear me.
Funny thing.
I am on a Fairy quest.
See, I'm a maid on the outside.
Super-secret. Super-sexy.
Follow me,
Maid on the Outside Fen.
Good.
Okay.
- Guess what I found.
- You found a moon rock?
I found a moon rock.
And those muffins smell amazing.
Thank you.
Now all we have to do
is stay awake.
You know what helps me
stay awake?
What's that?
An open, naked conversation
about our relationship.
I wanna tell you about
all my repressed emotions.
One by one.
Oh, baby.
Josh.
Josh!
- Oh, no.
- Josh!
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit!
We leave you for one afternoon,
and you fuck us completely.
I'm sorry, guys.
I sat down for one minute
because I never fall asleep
when I have
something in the oven.
Well, congratulations.
This is a milestone for you.
Hey, guys.
Hope you had better luck
than we did.
Nope, we portal-hopped
every lead we had.
The closest thing we found
was a chunk of old concrete
with the word "moon"
written on it in Sharpie.
Those rocks are gone.
But we did come home
to find Josh
sleeping peacefully.
I'm going
to assume your rudeness
is because sleep deprivation
makes you irritable.
Sure. Assume that.
Yeah, I get it.
I'm gonna have to staple
my eyes open; This is rough.
- No one else sleeps.
- We have four nights.
We need one rock lead
to pan out.
But if the spell burns them up,
what if we can't find any rocks
because the Lunatics
used them all?
What if there's no more
moon rocks on Earth?
Just sayin',
we could celebrate the Harmonic
Convergence in Fillory.
It's a little dystopian
at the mo',
but on the plus,
their weekend forecast
doesn't call for an apocalypse.
Look, guys,
if you're looking for some
sort of inspirational speech
on why you should
stay and fight,
I can't help you.
It's gonna suck,
and even if we do succeed,
which we might not,
it's not like we're gonna
get any credit.
The world ends, I end with it,
knowing that I did
everything I could,
because I won't be able
to live with myself otherwise.
Julia's right.
She really does suck
at inspirational speeches.
But also that we should
save the world.
I'm with you.
So am I.
Me too.
I'm in.
And my axe!
- Really? No?
- No.
Should've led with,
"You have my bow."
- Mm-hmm.
- Nope.
Josh,
put some fresh
meth muffins in the oven.
Again, not meth.
- Hey!
- No droopy eyes on my watch.
One more.
I'm good now.
I ain't.
Oh, well, right on cue.
I tried something new
this round.
A hint of lavender
and goji berry.
How we doin', Captain?
Oh, you know, 12 hours
till the end of the world,
and it's like we're still
grasping for needles
in a hay straw.
Fun. Okay.
Probably not the best question
for morale,
but as the only person here
who's slept this week,
we have 12 hours and zero leads.
Is waiting here to die
really the best option?
When are we gonna give
Margo's idea another think?
Guys, I can't trust
my brain right now,
but this seems like
it could be relevant.
I think this guy
has a moon rock.
- Oren Westbrook.
- Why do I know him?
Because you're not
a cave person.
He invented the tech
for pop-up ads,
and he invented the tech
to block pop-up ads.
Ever since, he's just been
a weird rich guy
doing weird-rich-guy shit.
I heard his blood boy
has his own blood boy.
Ew, what's on his eye?
That's the same tattoo
that Reba had.
Julia, I think he's a Lunatic.
All right.
So in order to save the world,
all we have to do
is convince some eccentric
billionaire with armed guards
to give up something he
probably considers to be, like,
his Holy Grail.
All while we're so tired
we can't see straight.
Pshh, no sweat.
Marvelous.
How did you handle the pain?
Knowing it would bring
me closer to Her Lunacy
helped me get through it.
Same as when I got mine.
That and a handful of opiates.
Hey, sorry about the security.
I hope you guys understand.
Ah, please, you can't
let in every Lunatic.
Some people are crazy.
Eliot.
Oh, wow,
you guys really look awful.
What?
Eliot...
Your sunken eyes!
Let me out.
Preparing for moon brain?
The Harmonic Convergence.
Mm! Yeah, baby.
I'm celebrating too.
I'm gonna have a few friends
over for a party.
Uh, El?
Eliot?
Eliot, you good?
- Yeah, yea... yeah.
- Yeah.
Just can't wait to see
this amazing moon rock.
Don't worry.
You both will experience Her.
What a cozy little nightmare.
I might need you to punch me
to stay awake.
Gotcha.
Isn't She wondrous?
Yeah, definitely.
Think we can turn on the lights
and turn off the yoga music?
You got this
from the moon... how?
I went.
You just went to the moon
like it was Coney Island?
Yeah, actually,
it was pretty tough.
To be honest, I was trying
to impress someone.
But in the end,
our souls did not connect.
Yeah, we need to ask a favor.
For my fellow Lunatics,
I would move Heaven and Earth.
About that...
Yeah, look, we know
this rock is special to you...
- Super special.
- But we need it.
To move Her.
Hence the moon brain.
You do know what that
would do, right?
Yes, but it's a matter
of life and death.
We can stop
the Harmonic Convergence
if we can hold the moon
out of position long enough.
Why?
Because it's going to cause
worldwide destruction.
Magic will become so powerful,
it'll be apocalyptic.
I mean, it's not like
it's gonna wipe out
all life on Earth.
Just some.
You know exactly
how bad it's going to get,
don't you?
What, are you planning to
profit off this or something?
I'm planning to use my resources
to help the world recover.
Now, I'm an entrepreneurial
spirit.
I can't help but make money.
Now, I do think that
the moon brain
is getting to you.
Unless...
Mm, your eye tattoo
is illusion magic.
You're no Lunatic at all.
I'll have my guards
escort you out.
Let's go, El. We tried.
Happens all the time.
- Get it?
- All of it.
We have a problem.
So it's just security cameras
until we get
to the moon rock room,
and that's where it gets tough.
One way in, one way out.
I mean, if we get caught,
we're trapped.
Guys. Guys!
Thanks!
So... the rock.
Whole lotta wards around it,
nothing we can't get past,
except for the one
on the rock itself.
It's... well, it's a bond
that we've never seen before,
put there by Mayakovsky.
Well, that can't be right.
Oren just got the rock.
And didn't you say the last time
you saw Mayakovsky,
he was basically senile?
Yeah, well,
I guess he got better.
I mean, he...
He put his signature
into the lattice work
of the spell.
You can't miss it.
It's the most amazing,
most narcissistic thing
I've ever seen.
Mm.
- Hey, Eliot?
- Hm?
- Can I talk to you for a sec?
- Yeah.
I said I'm fine.
I have been awake for
thousands of hours straight.
Look, I saw your moment
back there,
and I think I might
know what's up.
You think you do, but you don't.
Okay, so the first
two nights, no sleep,
things got
a little weird, right?
Like picking up my phone
to call Quentin.
You know, I must've done that
like five times.
But then my brain
crossed over into darker...
Here's the deal.
When the Sister was in me,
I remember everything.
Every bloody second of it.
And usually,
I'm good at pushing it away,
but right now...
it is like a constant slideshow
in the background.
Not fun. El.
The Monster was
in you for months.
Well, it was different.
People have
different experiences.
All that time was just
one big nap to me,
which... sounds so good
right now.
I don't know
why you're lying to me.
Or anyone.
I don't know why
you're accusing me of lying.
Okay.
Neither of us have the
bandwidth for this right now,
and I don't trust you.
I don't.
But if you ever
do decide to talk,
open door.
Shit.
If I may,
lenses can be sensitive
to changes
in your Internal Circumstances.
You may need to adjust
if you're feeling off.
God damn it.
If something is bothering you,
I know I'm not the ideal
person to talk to,
but I am here.
I'm not feeling chatty
at the moment, okay?
Look, you're not the only one
that made a mistake,
'cause clearly
it's still bothering me.
It's Fogg.
He's stuck in the Etheric Realm,
and it's my fault.
Henry's in...
He always was a sensualist.
That place is a trap for people
like him, who enjoy, well...
- Getting wasted?
- Mm.
He was trying to quit.
He shouldn't have even
been in there.
He was only in there
because of me.
And you were only there
because you wanted
to help the hedges.
You know,
if we're being honest...
I wanted to get high.
Lucky me, that's the only way
into the Etheric Realm.
Fogg just...
tagged along and got unlucky.
That wasn't luck.
I know the Emperor of the Realm.
If he kept Henry behind,
it was because
he sensed a flaw in him.
And if he kicked you out,
it was because you were trying
to do something good.
Nothing bores him like goodness.
Yeah, how do you know that?
I spent three years there once.
Jesus.
Before I came to the Library,
my life was... difficult.
The Etheric Realm was an escape.
How did you get out?
- I stopped hating myself.
- Eventually.
And then the Emperor
grew bored with me.
Whatever kept Henry there,
those were his demons,
and that is something
you couldn't fix.
Well, it doesn't stop me from
feeling like shit about it.
The fact that
you feel like shit,
that is why you escaped.
So allow me to be blunt.
Don't waste time on self-pity.
Do what you came to do.
Thanks.
I'll try to be less
of a bitch to you.
Mm. If you can.
It's working.
I can see the wards.
This way.
It sounds like he's home.
Look, fair warning...
Who the hell are you?
We're looking for Mayakovsky.
Old, drunk, megalomaniac?
Fondness for knit caps?
Yeah, I'm his daughter.
I didn't realize he...
- Fucked my mother?
- Neither did he.
Should've seen his face
when I came knockin'.
But we're fine now.
What do you want?
Can you let us down?
Sure.
Thanks.
Look.
We need to talk to your dad.
He's busy.
On our project.
Look, we think he may
be the only person
that can help us save the world.
He put a special magical bond
on a moon rock,
and we need his help
to break it.
Wait, please tell me you're
trying to rob Oren Westbrook.
- How do you know that?
- I installed that bond.
Yeah, last nice thing I did
before I dumped his greasy ass.
- That was you?
- What? You dated him?
Don't judge, but yes.
Anyfuck, right after
I installed the bond,
I caught the maid pegging him,
and not the maid
I okayed for threesomes.
- Mm...
- Okay.
So that means you'll help us?
I could.
But I need something from you.
A shade.
Either of yours will do.
What are you gonna do with it?
- Are we gonna get it back?
- No.
- You want my help?
- Mm-hmm.
One shade, payment in advance.
Discuss.
- It's safe.
- Thanks.
Any idea where to find
a medical manual in here?
Unfortunately,
the organizational systems
are down, so it may...
May I?
Hm.
Sometimes I forget you're
a fucking master Magician.
I try to keep the showboating
to a minimum.
Well, the Harmonic
Convergence is in a few hours.
You know what that means.
I'll take this to Harriet ASAP.
Tell her if, God forbid,
we can't stop it...
we might need all the hedges we
can get to unfuck everything.
Desperate times, huh?
Didn't really have much choice.
Hey, uh, Julia?
Can you remind me why
I'm dressed like this, please?
He's been like this all night.
Just running on muffin fumes.
Okay, let's just make sure
we're all on the same page.
Okay?
Okay, so Josh, Margo, Penny.
You guys go inside,
loop all the cameras,
open the side door for Natasha.
I'll be outside waiting
with Eliot and Alice.
We won't cast the spell
until your signal.
You won't miss it. Ready?
Break.
- Eliot.
- What are you staring at?
Pull the ripcord, get out.
We'll handle this.
I am not cocking out.
You're not right, El,
and we both know why.
My crippling fear of/
attraction to authority?
Are you being honest with me?
Bambi, always.
I don't care if you've
been keeping it from me,
but all of our asses
are on the line now.
Margo.
Do not worry about me.
I know, I've been
a little bit off.
Blame it on the moon brain.
I promise I'm fine.
'Kay?
Hey! How are you?
Oh.
Uh, no guests.
Can you fetch me another
plate of those crab puffs?
Delish.
- Head of security.
- Not your waiter.
Oh, good for you.
Have you tried the crab puffs?
- Hey, my drink!
- What the...
Watch the suit!
That's the third time
you've done that tonight!
Watch what you're doing!
I'm gonna take you outside
right now.
All right, fellas,
break it up, break it up.
I looped that one,
but I don't remember
if I looped that one.
You don't remember
five seconds ago?
Josh, I haven't had
short-term memory in two days.
The only things I remember
are being worried about Eliot
and feeling like shit
for trying to leave you
in the past.
Really?
Fucking moon brain.
Totally spaced out.
Why are you looking at me
like that?
These are good.
Let's go.
It's true. It's true.
Excuse me, sir.
Excuse me.
We have an issue.
Natasha?
What the hell is she doing here?
Well, my men will find out,
but I have a hunch.
There's one thing you own
that only she can steal.
Bring back the rock.
- Stop!
- Wh...
Right there, right there!
Let's go!
Natasha. Where is she going?
For the last time,
we don't know.
And even if we did,
we would never admit it.
No bother.
My men have her now.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- What's going on?
- Where's the moon rock?
- What... I don't...
I don't know!
Look, I was just hitchhiking,
and a woman, she just
threw the keys at me, okay?
Just take the van, whatever.
Look, she went that way.
She escaped?
Where's the rock?
Well, I officially
have moon brain.
I can see Her aura. It's red.
Let's do this quick
before anyone comes in.
How long do we have to cast
the first part again?
Until Her aura turns green
and She's listening.
It's working.
Where is Natasha
taking the rock?
Okay... okay.
She said she was going
to Philly.
The only thing worse
than a traitor is a snitch.
You make me wanna puke.
Hey, hey, Josh.
Do you have any more muffins?
Almost there.
We had it.
What happened?
How did it turn red?
Eliot?
Wait, Eliot, come back!
We don't have enough power
to finish this without you.
Eliot.
Eliot...
Let me out.
You're not there.
You're gone forever.
Quentin threw you in the Seam.
This isn't happening.
This is moon brain.
Stop right there!
My guards are in the room
with your friends.
The rock never left, did it?
You know, I want the snitch
to tell me what's
really going on.
- What happened?
- Asshole fell asleep again.
His fight-or-flight response
is to take a fucking nap.
Or something else is up.
It wasn't me.
In here, boss.
Marina.
Ladies.
Did you put the guards to sleep?
Yeah, but I'm a little confused
why you aren't snoozing too.
The only thing stronger
than that spell is...
Oh, my God. Are you on meth?
You know,
it sure as hell seems like it.
What are you doing here?
Keeping you from
fucking up my shit.
Harmonic Convergence, I need it.
Like Daddy always said,
even meth can't beat handcuffs.
I don't think you understand
how bad the Convergence is.
No, I do.
But what you don't understand
is how good it is for me.
I have a very critical mission,
and I need the power
convergence boost to do it.
So just this one time,
could you please go home?
Look,
whatever it is you're doing,
it's not worth the world.
Mm, yes, it is.
I put a shitload
of work into this.
I stole a Book Depository,
for Christ sake.
That was you?
You sent that memory assassin
after me.
Yeah, and not a life assassin.
You're welcome.
We're even, since you
tipped us to this party.
Frederick here...
That's not my name.
Okay, not-Frederick here,
overheard you
in my Book Depository
making these exciting plans
for the Convergence.
Speaking of...
just started.
I flinch, it fires.
Oh...
I think we all
know what that was.
It's the surge.
You know what that means,
Chickee-poo?
Power is insane.
You're holding a nuke right now.
You let that thing go,
we all go bye-bye.
Kady, she's right; With
the Convergence and the surge,
every spell is, like,
super-powered right now.
Yeah, I bet you could
cast something solo
that would normally
take three people.
- Isn't that what I just said?
- Marina!
Please, we are so close
to saving everyone.
You can't just
take that away from us now.
Whatever it is you're after,
what's the point
if there's no world?
There'll still be a world,
just not as many people.
- Have you met people?
- She's listening!
Eliot, go!
- The fuck are you doing?
- I've got it.
- You're moving the moon?
- Yeah.
I'm moving it back.
Uh...
guys?
I think we just broke the moon.
Ah, shit.