Previously on The Magicians...
What does that mean?
Jesus, we could
not have screwed up
that spell worse, and
we can't take it back.
You showed up with
that sigil on your hand.
It appeared when I
was dreaming of Fillory.
It came from Jane.
Who are you? I'm a
member of The Order,
the keepers of the
libraries of the Neitherlands.
Any idea who the motherfuckers
in the hoods are that
are trying to kill me?
They've been thoroughly cursed,
so they can't use the fountains,
but that hasn't stopped them
from finding other employment.
The Beast?
We are the best
Magicians we know.
But Menolly is dying.
Bender's trying to stay
off the ledge every day.
And you?
Eight years ago, I
was a drug addict,
and I left my son in a hot car.
We're not learning anything new.
The Beast always kills us.
There was one time we didn't
all die. When we went to Fillory.
Point is, we need some
serious battle magic.
Bottling our emotions.
And when the feelings come
back, it's extremely intense.
Near the bridge,
there's a man who has
served me 1,000 years.
Bring him three gifts.
He'll show you the way.
Huh. Not what I expected.
Yeah.
Die, fucker!
Well, that sucked ass.
Julia, Kady!
Finally.
Are we interrupting?
Ah, no, no, no. Just
passing the time.
So... Uh, yeah, um...
We bring forsythia. Mmm-hmm.
And honeycomb.
Hmm. Hmm-hmm-hmm.
Two down.
Where's the platinum?
We didn't bring that. Too bad.
Exit through the gift shop.
But we did bring something
of great and shining worth.
Just say it.
If you're wrong, you're wrong.
We brought you our faith.
Ooh.
Tricky, tricky, tricky, tricky.
I like it.
But to be honest, I'm sensing
more skepticism than faith here.
Look, I'm trying.
She's the one that
had the dream, okay?
Kady, your mother
used your faith,
but she isn't your true mother.
Our Lady feels you
require a miracle.
Oh, my God.
What...
What did he do?
I don't know. I've
had this tightness
ever since my
mom, but it's gone.
There it is.
Faith.
Okay, so...
Let's get to brass.
You're here, why?
We seek an audience
with Our Lady Underground.
Yeah, no shit.
Why do you think you
deserve to see her?
It's okay.
Why should she waste
her time with you?
I am privileged, and I
have done some stupid shit,
and I have been through nothing
compared to some of my friends.
So you wish to help them?
Heal them? Is that it?
Yes, that is exactly
what I want to do.
No.
No, no, no.
Magicians...
That's all you ever
want, power, every time.
You know what?
For the longest time,
that is all I wanted.
But now, I just want to do
whatever the fuck
it is I'm supposed to.
And if she's around,
if she gives a shit,
I have to believe she
wants her daughters
to show a little ambition.
So, you tell her
that I am trying to
reach something higher.
Nuestra Señora sits and waits,
and no one asks.
She watches.
She weeps.
But today, she's
grinning like a fool.
Here's the invocation.
May her blessings be with you.
Thank you.
And one more piece
of advice for the chosen.
You can't unring a bell,
so, be certain
when you call, Julia.
Okay.
Look.
All of y'all look like you
did a crime last night.
According to all
the probability shit,
we don't have time to wait.
One or another super shitty
ending is coming within days,
if we don't at least
try to go get the knife.
So...
Oh, God.
The Neitherlands is Grand
Central for the multiverse.
The button will bring you in,
and once you're there...
Yes, the fountains are portals.
Can I say this?
For your interest?
As far as I know,
you don't need a button or
anything to ride the fountains,
so don't fall in.
Don't get lost.
The whole place is crawling with
battle magic motherfuckers
with hoods on.
We get separated,
you're dead.
Seriously,
what the fuck is going
on with you people?
Nothing. We're
fine, aren't we, El?
We're phenomenal.
Fine, okay. We're not okay.
Forget it. We just need to...
We're going to...
It's over!
I need a minute.
Alice is just a little
bit sensitive right now.
Would you just shut
the fuck up, Margo?
Are you seriously
mad at me right now?
What the fuck
did I just walk into?
My life. Welcome.
It's not funny,
and it's not a joke.
But it truly is, Quentin.
You people need
to stow your shit!
We get it! Would
you just, please,
give us a goddamn minute?
I just want to dance
all over the room
All I wanted to do
Just celebrate
Party with my
friends or all by myself
How you doing?
Come on.
Stop worrying.
So, the hermit was creepy.
Super creepy.
You didn't feel what I felt.
I don't know. Whatever
he was channeling,
it was the real deal.
She's just nervous.
There's always some creepy guy
when you're about to
blow the patriarchy's
head out of their ass.
Everything is, um...
About to change.
Everything.
Finally.
Yeah. Cheers.
What?
Okay, you are the least crazy.
Tell me what's going on.
It... Nothing. Just forget it.
What the hell are you drinking?
I don't know.
Triple sec?
What did Quentin do?
I don't want to talk about it.
Fair enough.
Can I get some?
It's good.
It's not good.
No, it's not good.
Yeah.
Let you in on a
little secret, though.
I used to drink
Midori in high school.
It's like melon,
crossed with perfume,
crossed with ass.
Yum.
Fuck did I know?
I was trying to get
the voices to go away.
Point is, I'm not judging
anyone for triple sec.
And...
I can tell when someone's
trying to make something go away.
So, Midori, huh?
Does it work?
Nothing works forever.
But, you know,
if you stop worrying
about forever,
there's plenty of shit that can
get you through the next hour.
Is what he said
still bugging you?
He looked at me like
he could see through me.
And Kady doesn't seem
to share your reservation.
She seems better.
Yeah.
I don't know why
I feel this way.
Our Lady came to me in a dream.
Shouldn't that remove all doubt?
Look, something like
this is about intention,
what we bring into it.
Our intentions are pure.
So just stop worrying?
Yeah.
Just like...
For now.
Tomorrow you can
worry all you want
about Our Lady Underground.
Tonight...
Tonight should
be about Dionysus.
Whoo, ooh.
Dionysus, okay.
You, uh...
You bang a lot of
undergrads with that one?
Fewer than I'd hoped.
So...
Hmm? Say it works.
And that means what for you?
You asking if I'm coming back?
Kind of, yeah.
I hadn't much
planned for it, really.
I just want to get there,
and I'll stay, or go
somewhere quiet.
If Our Lady has
other plans, hmm.
I'll do that.
I'll miss you.
I'll miss you, too.
To think you were so crabby in
rehab, we almost never spoke.
Hey.
God, you are really
something, Julia.
I bet you say
that to all the girls
you slept with
three minutes ago.
That's funny. Hmm.
But I mean it. I do.
That bite, that...
That thing in you that wants
to puzzle everything out,
that is gold.
No matter how
crabby it makes me?
I think especially when
it makes you crabby.
I think that us angry,
questioning people
sometimes shut up too fast,
and that is probably part
of why the gods took off.
No one around with the fire
to keep yelling their names.
This is gonna sound
corny, but don't lose that fire.
Well, it sounds like
you're saying goodbye.
I'm saying thank you.
So, this is a little
hitch in our adventure.
Are we just gonna
act like children now?
Now, now, Bambi. He's
got a right to be mad.
No, he doesn't.
People don't get to be mad at me
because I had sex with them.
You're welcome, both of you.
Oh, come on.
We were all messed
up on emotion magic.
We deserve a pass.
I don't need a pass.
You two have ruined my life.
No offense, Quentin, but I
think you did that all yourself.
Can we just cut to the part
where we go to another world,
and skip the whole guilt
and recriminations bit, please?
You would like
that, wouldn't you?
Is it wrong that I'm starting
to side with The Beast?
All right.
Didn't think you
had that in you.
You don't get to shame me.
You slept with two other
people. We broke up.
I was out of my mind.
I made a mistake, and
you aimed a weapon.
I'm glad it hurt.
It should hurt.
Boys and girls,
I hate to cut into what
is clearly a moment,
but the fact is,
according to the best
and only magic we have,
we have to go or
The Beast will kill us.
End of story.
Take out your emotions.
You can fight later.
Sound good?
All right, if you
guys are using those
emotion bottles,
let's go.
How I was feeling about Quentin
would have got us all killed.
I was very angry a moment ago,
but I have to be honest.
You two would
make a cute couple.
Join hands, everyone.
Let's move, fast.
The map says...
Got it.
Quentin?
We've been waiting.
Come on! Hurry!
Run!
Shit.
Okay.
We certainly lost that fight.
How'd you find this place?
I got lucky last time.
Quentin had the map.
Shit. MARGO: No map,
evil mercenary
assholes everywhere,
stuck in a library.
This is not how we
decided this would go.
Penny, you know this place.
There must be
somebody we can talk to.
Yeah, there might be.
Follow me.
Penny, Alice, Eliot, and Janet,
you are all late.
Actually, it's Margo.
This time.
Look, we need your help,
though, you probably
already knew that.
I did.
The answer is yes, you
can stay, with a few caveats.
Here it comes.
One, no harm comes to the books.
Yeah, we get that. Two,
no food, drinks, or
any other intoxicants
are allowed in the
library at any time.
That includes emotion bottles.
Damage always ensues.
You understand, of course.
I planned my whole
outfit around that bottle!
Could you get to
the point, Quentin?
I have a trustees meeting.
You know something about
what's been happening here.
The Beast, Eliza.
I would like to know what
is really going on here.
I know you would,
but we are done.
How did you lose your virginity?
I was 24 years old.
I was too embarrassed
to tell anyone.
She was considerably
older than I,
and much, much more experienced.
But...
Fuck!
You've managed to
dose me, haven't you?
In my tea. You little shit.
Truth serum is toxic,
Quentin, and banned.
And if you were going
to throw magic at me,
you would have done so
already, but you haven't.
Eliza,
who is she?
Eliza's real name
is Jane Chatwin.
Oh.
I was kind of poking around
in the dark with that one.
Uh...
Okay, what does Jane
have to do with The Beast?
Do you remember the gift
that Jane was given in the book,
The Girl Who Told Time?
Uh, yeah, Ember gave
her a watch and a locket.
Ember gave her the
ability to fuck with time,
on a cosmic scale,
and Jane used it to
create a time loop.
When she'd fail
to stop The Beast,
she'd restart the loop.
A time loop.
Okay.
Uh...
So, what do we have
to do with The Beast?
You just keep getting involved.
I don't keep doing anything.
Can you imagine, Quentin,
how many times we've had this
exact conversation?
You've managed
to slip truth serum
to me 27 times,
27 ways, and
I'm quite sick of it.
So, what, this is just some giant,
blood-soaked Groundhog Day?
You always bring
up that fucking movie.
I still haven't seen it.
Now it's a point of pride.
Answer my question.
In each loop,
Jane alters something
to see if it'll change
the outcome.
The sigil that
appeared on your hand,
brought you to Alice.
That was Jane trying
to get the ball rolling,
trying to get you all
together, working fast,
and we all know how
well that particular
great idea worked out, don't we?
So, has anything
actually helped?
So far, all the loops
end in your death.
How many times
have I died? Thirty-nine.
Thirty-nine times.
And if you die a 40th,
at least I won't
have to hear you
ask me this question ever again.
Jane's dead, Quentin.
The loop's done.
There's no one to reset it.
So, this is it?
This isn't my problem.
My problem is that
I'm strong enough
to discern a time loop,
but not strong
enough to change it.
We better hope and pray
that Jane altered the
right thing this time around.
Anything else, Quentin?
What's different this time?
Please, no books on the floor.
I love this one.
Photos from places
I can't imagine.
I know you hate it now,
but Travelers wrote
our most precious books.
The library is what
it is because of them.
You make it sound
so simple and fun.
No.
But it is valuable.
And in my observation,
master Travelers have
a fantastic time doing it.
I was looking for
any technical info
that would get me anywhere
close to mastery, but...
The books you seek
are in another branch.
Of course they are.
Look, could you... Could
you expedite that shit?
I don't have much
time, and I really
need to know how to
take people with me.
I'll put in a request.
Why am I not feeling optimistic?
Probably because Franz
Kafka wrote The Trial
after spending a
week in the library.
But, Penny, if you can
survive long enough,
you will get a handle on it.
I promise.
If?
Say that in my book?
No spoilers.
Hi.
I was at Brakebills?
You were supposed to be.
Or you were, like, 39 times.
You were the thing they changed.
Jane thought, you know,
cast you out in the cold,
and you would
get stronger, and...
So, I was right.
The whole time, I was right.
I don't know what
to say, Jules. I...
I should have
believed you, Jules.
I should have known, and I'm...
Um...
Look, that doesn't make
up for what I did to you,
which was stupid,
and vindictive,
and really dangerous.
I'm so sorry, Q.
Thank you.
So, how do we
fix it? I don't know.
I just know that I'm
gonna get killed soon,
and I don't really want to die
being mad at my oldest friend.
I really fucking missed you.
Yeah, me, too, actually.
You smell the same.
Okay, all right.
Uh...
So...
Big conspiracy.
Wheels within wheels.
Julia doesn't go
to Brakebills, and?
You're taking this a lot
better than I would have.
It's because there is bigger,
better magic in the world.
I mean, you would not believe
some of the shit I've seen.
I can barely believe it.
What?
Some friends and I got
into some pretty eclectic shit.
You and Kady?
Where is she?
On a mission.
They all are.
They got pretty strict
marching orders.
From?
A goddess.
We summoned, and she came.
You mean, um, here?
To your loft?
You don't believe me.
Shit, I wouldn't, either.
That is why she gave me proof.
Is that milk? Yeah.
Cool,
useless, kind of gross.
But look under the hood.
Oh, my God.
Who did this magic?
I told you. She did.
I mean, it was crazy.
It was like being on a
massive dose of ecstasy.
When she touched me,
it was like my psyche
was defragging.
I mean, she... She
touched all of us.
She granted every petition.
She cured Menolly's
breast cancer,
she sent Richard to
where he wanted to go.
I watched this.
I thought magic
couldn't cure cancer.
Not regular magic.
Look, I can't lie, okay?
It was shitty going
for a while there,
not being in Brakebills,
but I can't sit here now,
and think it was
anything but fate.
Right, or just the right
random combination.
Okay, suit yourself, nihilist.
I need your help.
I don't know how to
get back, and, um...
My friends, we got separated,
and I just... I can't let them
fight The Beast on their own,
and I have to find a way...
Let me get this straight.
You want me to come
to Fillory with you?
Yeah.
Come here.
Holy shit. This is our table.
Kind of been planning
this trip since we were nine.
We kind of have, huh?
Our Lady gave me a mission to...
I sound like a nut-job.
Kind of.
What's the mission?
She said it was my destiny
to basically find
a whole new kind of magic.
You know, she said
it was something
that couldn't be given.
It had to be found.
So, we have to find it.
And I bet you it's here.
So, I guess we're
off to see the Wizard.
Have you given any thought
to how we're gonna get there?
Start of the London Blitz, 1940,
and then their mom dies, 1941.
Q, where are you
going with this?
Okay, so we can't just
open a door to Fillory,
but we do know when they open...
Every time the Chatwins go.
So, if we could just
find a way to get there,
then we could follow them in.
Look, all I know is time magic
is apparently a thing,
a thing that's been dicking
with us for the past 39 lifetimes.
So, I say we find a way
to make it work for us.
Wait, but that would put
us in past Fillory, right?
Fillory is magic.
Remember, Jane
falls in that swamp,
and then she comes
out 20 years later.
She strikes a deal with the
Watcher Woman to send her back.
Once you're there,
there's always a way.
I have an idea,
something Richard told me,
but we have to go
somewhere to get it.
Brakebills.
Okay.
Uh, you just have to
be a registered student
in order to get
through the wards.
Alumni key.
Richard gave it to me.
This place is impossible.
How does anyone find anything?
There's a whole
wing on cat paintings.
What have you got? Anything?
The Book of Mike McCormick.
Novella, really.
He was actually a
Republican. Can you believe it?
But the worst part?
His life was happy.
Eliot, he's gone.
Why are you torturing yourself?
Because he's gone
and it's my fault.
And of all the
people in the world
who don't understand,
somehow you top the list.
What are you doing?
Putting the past behind me.
No, stop!
Look, he's had a
really bad week.
We'll pay the fine, whatever.
Nope, no, you are banished
from the library, forever.
It's one book.
No, it's a life.
They're irreplaceable.
No, wait!
What did you do?
Let's go.
"Bridge to ancient Rome."
"Bridge to the
Cretaceous Period."
Oh, hey, here's one. Uh...
"Southampton, England, 1912"?
Voyage of the Titanic?
Oh. Fun.
So, we're pretty sure
these things only go
to one specific
point in time and...
Once you lock a
date in, you're locked.
I mean, they use some tiny piece
of an incredibly rare element.
All got used up by the '70s.
Wait a minute.
Wait. Here's a thesis.
A bunch of students wanted
to go back and kill Hitler.
"Operation Die Fuehrer."
Guess no one
told them Hitler was
a pretty serious
battle Magician.
Yeah.
Yep, and Hitler killed them.
Wait, what's the date
on the time bridge?
Uh, it's April 19th, 1942.
April 19th.
Yeah.
You remember the, uh...
Yeah, "The Flying Forest"?
Yeah, uh, Jane's
going into town.
She's looking for a
present for Martin.
April 21st, 1942.
Two days after this time bridge.
Holy shit, Q, this could work.
I never thought I'd say
it, but thank God for Hitler.
Yeah, no, that still sounds bad.
Yeah.
Earth fountain's blocked off.
I told you it would be.
It was worth a shot.
I mean, what else
are we gonna do?
I don't know. How about
not get us kicked out
of the library in
the first place?
All right, let's keep moving.
Hey. Not one more step.
We're highly trained
Earth Magicians.
Hold up. Hold up. You
guys are from Brakebills?
Dude, Josh
Hoberman, class of '16.
Come with me if
you want to live.
I've always wanted to say that.
But seriously, um, we should go.
Welcome to Chez Hoberman.
You're welcome to whatever.
Just don't eat the carrots.
They're totally psychedelic
for some reason.
Circumstances in the
Neitherlands are super weird.
Holy shit.
This tastes like pizza.
Yeah, I know, right?
How long have you
been down here?
A few weeks.
Just been camped out,
waiting to see if
anyone else will show up.
Anyone else? From my class.
Look, don't freak,
but back at Brakebills, nobody
knows what happened to you guys.
And it's sort of been two years.
Oh, shit. Right, the
whole time thing.
Victoria warned me about that.
- Victoria?
You know her?
She's the only reason I'm alive.
Look, are you gonna
tell us what the fuck
happened to your class, or what?
Where'd you guys go? To Fillory.
For spring break.
V's amazing.
I mean, she literally blips
around the universe, fearless.
Teachers put this
tattoo on her to stop her.
She just cut it off herself.
Joshy. What?
You're not gonna
believe it. What?
I did it. I found Fillory.
What? I found Fillory!
Oh, my God! We're
going to Fillory!
We're going to Fillory?
So, we decided to plan a trip.
You know, party, smoke
out with the centaurs,
be back in time for classes,
but word got out to practically
the whole first-year class,
except for a couple losers.
Luckily, V was so good, she
was able to take them all with.
It was magical.
I mean, more magical
than Brakebills,
like going from black
and white to color.
V and I had a
threesome with a naiad.
This guy Donnie, he had
sex with a talking horse.
I mean, it's not
exactly taboo in Fillory,
since the animals
can give consent,
but we were all still
a bit squicked out.
We get it. You
fucked some animals.
How'd you end up here?
Got roped into this quest.
Ended up being
a trap for Victoria.
This dude, Mothra,
I've been calling him...
Yeah, we know that clown.
It was a bloodbath.
V zapped me here, and
then she went back in.
Told me to stay put, so
I have just been waiting.
V should have been here by now.
He caught her.
But she's still alive.
How do you know
that? I'm like her.
It's why I'm here.
We can all go, rescue Victoria.
You can take us.
Haven't exactly cracked
the whole ride-along, yet.
Okay, forget traveling.
Uh, we'll just take a fountain.
Except we don't know
where the Fillory fountain is.
That's easy.
It's three squares
up, one square left.
The problem is all the
battle magic dick buckets
waiting to vaporize us.
Discuss.
It's in the closet.
El and Margo made a door
to their favorite pub in London.
They look like fun.
Look, you were
supposed to be here.
You were supposed
to be a part of this.
No, you know, I
think Jane was right.
Had I been here living it up,
I would have never felt the need
to figure out what
magic is actually for.
Okay, so what's
magic actually for, then?
For fixing things, dummy.
Trust me.
I, uh, made a lot of mistakes
before I figured that one out.
Yeah, everything I've been
able to fix doesn't matter,
just minor mendings
and bullshit.
Yeah, well, if fixing
big things were easy,
everyone would do it.
Come on.
Alice.
Get some sleep.
I know.
I might as well.
I'll never figure this out.
Trying to think of how to get
us all to the Fillory fountain
without getting us killed.
Need a hand?
Look, Penny,
I'm sorry if I gave you
the wrong idea, but...
Stop.
It was fun, okay?
You're one of the few
people I actually respect.
Uh, yeah, you're right, right.
I'm just making this weird, huh?
Eh, it's weird.
We're weird. So, what?
We're friends, right?
I just keep thinking
about Quentin.
Look, I know.
I just keep thinking
how awful it would be
if, out of all of us,
he was the one who
didn't get to see Fillory.
And then I remember
that I hate him.
Fuck, why am I such an idiot?
Okay.
Quentin is irrelevant.
Just another excuse for
that thing you always do.
What thing? "I
should just give up.
"I'll never figure it out."
Shit got real.
If you're gonna
drop that bullshit,
now's the time.
Phosphoromancy.
I can bend light around us, all
of us, the whole group, I think,
make us invisible.
It'll be difficult with the
two suns but not impossible.
We'll have to move in
a pretty tight formation.
When should we leave?
As soon as possible.
The suns are just
about in position.
It has begun!
Sorry.
Penny, Eliot, you're both tall,
so, you'll have to duck down
and stay close to me, okay?
Or they'll see you. Got it.
We got it, right?
Mmm-hmm.
Eliot, are you coming?
Right behind you, Bambi.
Let's do this.
Okay.
Holy shit.
Is that an air raid siren?
Okay.
1942.
We need to get out of here.
Yeah.
Go to the right.
Is everything all right, Eliot?
Everything's amazing.
Go left. Go left.
Yeah, I brought a gun.
"Thanks, Margo."
You're welcome.
Why didn't you move?
Acid carrots.
Margo, you saved my actual life.
Hooray, you live to
drink another day.
Shit, guys, they see us.
Shit! Go! Go!
Oh, my God.
She looks so young.
Yeah, she's got no
idea what's coming.
Hey.
That's gotta be it, right?
Across the street,
the door to Fillory?
Yeah.
Here she comes.
You ready, Janey?
Why, yes, Martin, I think I am.
Oh, my God.
Q.
Look.