QUENTIN: Previously on
The Magicians...
What does that mean?
QUENTIN: Jesus, we could
not have screwed up
that spell worse,
and we can't take it back.
You showed up with
that sigil on your hand.
QUENTIN: It appeared when
I was dreaming of FiIIory.
It came from Jane.
(SCREAMS)
Who are you?
I'm a member of The Order,
the keepers of
the libraries of
the Neitherlands.
Any idea who
the motherfuckers
in the hoods are that
are trying to kill me?
They've been thoroughly
cursed, so they can't
use the fountains,
but that hasn't
stopped them from
finding other employment.
The Beast?
We are the best
magicians we know.
But Menolly is dying.
Bender's trying to stay off
the ledge every day.
And you?
Eight years ago,
I was a drug addict,
and I left my
son in a hot car.
PENNY: We're not
learning anything new.
The Beast always kills us.
There was one time
we didn't all die.
When we went to Fillory.
Point is, we need some
serious battle magic.
Bottling our emotions.
ALICE: And when
the feelings come back,
it's extremely intense.
(GIGGLING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
WOMAN". Near the bridge,
there's a man who has
served me 1,000 years.
Bring him three gifts.
He'll show you the way.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
(RAP MUSIC PLAYING)
Huh. Not what
I expected.
Yeah.
MAN: Die, fucker!
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
Well, that
sucked ass.
Julia, Kady!
Finally.
(GREETING IN SPANISH)
Are we interrupting?
Ah, no, no, no.
Just passing the time.
Uh, yeah, um...
So...
We bring forsythia.
Mmm-hmm.
And honeycomb.
Hmm. Hmm-hmm-hmm.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Two down.
Where's the platinum?
We didn't bring that.
Too bad.
Exit through
the gift shop.
But we did bring
something
of great and
shining worth.
Just say it.
If you're wrong,
you're wrong.
We brought you
our faith.
Ooh. (CHUCKLES)
Tricky, tricky,
tricky, tricky.
I like it.
But to be honest,
I'm sensing
more skepticism
than faith here.
(SCOFFS)
Look, I'm trying.
She's the one that
had the dream, okay?
Kady, your mother
used your faith,
butsheisn%
your true mother.
Our Lady feels you
require a miracle.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
Oh, my God.
(STAMMERS) What...
What did he do?
I don't know.
I've had this tightness
ever since my mom,
but it's gone.
There it is.
Faith.
Okay, so...
(CLEARS THROAT)
Let's get to brass.
You're here, why?
We seek an audience
with Our Lady Underground.
Yeah, no shit.
Why do you think you
deserve to see her?
It's okay.
Why should she waste
her time with you?
lam privileged,
and I have done
some stupid shit,
and I have been
through nothing
compared to
some of my friends.
So you wish to help them?
Heal them? ls that it?
Yes, that is exactly
what I want to do.
No.
No,no,no.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Magicians...
That's all you ever want,
power, every time.
You know what?
For the longest time,
that is all I wanted.
But now, I just want to do
whatever the fuck it
is I'm supposed to.
And if she's around,
if she gives a shit,
I have to believe
she wants her daughters
to show a little ambition.
So, you tell her
that I am trying to
reach something higher.
Nuestra Seï¬ora
sits and waits,
and no one asks.
She watches.
She weeps.
But today, she's
grinning like a fool.
Here's the invocation.
May her blessings be with you.
Thank you.
And one more piece of
advice for the chosen.
You can't unring a bell,
so, be certain
when you call, Julia.
PENNY: Okay.
Look.
All of y'all
look like you did
a crime last night.
According to all
the probability shit,
we don't have
time to wait.
One or another
super shitty ending
is coming within days,
if we don't at least
try to go get the knife.
So...
Oh, God.
The Neitherlands
is Grand Central
for the multiverse.
The button will bring you in,
and once you're there...
Yes, the fountains
are portals.
PENNY: Can I say this?
For your interest?
As far as I know,
you don't need
a button or anything
to ride the fountains,
so don't fall in.
Don't get lost.
The whole place
is crawling with
battle magic motherfuckers
with hoods on.
We get separated,
you're dead.
Seriously,
what the fuck is going
on with you people?
Nothing. We're fine,
aren't we, El?
We're phenomenal.
Fine, okay.
We're not okay.
Forget it.
We just need to...
We're going to...
It's over!
I need a minute.
Alice is just a little
bit sensitive right now.
Would you just shut
the fuck up, Margo?
Are you seriously
mad at me right now?
What the fuck did
I just walk into?
My life. Welcome.
It's not funny,
and it's not a joke.
But it truly is,
Quentin.
You people need
to stow your shit!
We get it! Would
you just, please,
give us a goddamn minute?
I just want to
dance all over the room
AH I wanted to do
All I wanted to do
Just celebrate
Party with my
friends or all by myself
How you doing?
Come on.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Stop worrying.
So, the hermit
was creepy.
Super creepy.
You didn't feel
what I felt.
I don't know.
Whatever he
was channeling,
it was the real deal.
She's just nervous.
There's always
some creepy guy
when you're about to blow
the patriarchy's
head out of their ass.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Everything is, um...
About to change.
Everything.
Finally.
Yeah.
Cheers.
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
What?
Okay, you are
the least crazy.
Tell me what's going on.
It... Nothing.
Just forget it.
What the hell are
you drinking?
I don't know.
Triple sec?
What did Quentin do?
I don't want to
talk about it.
Fair enough.
Can I get some?
It's good.
It's not good.
No, it's not good.
Yeah.
Let you in on
a little secret, though.
I used to drink
Midori in high school.
It's like melon,
crossed with perfume,
crossed with ass.
Yum.
(CHUCKLES)
Fuck did I know?
I was trying to get
the voices to go away.
Point is, I'm not
judging anyone
for triple sec.
And...
I can tell when someone's
trying to make
something go away.
So, Midori, huh?
Does it work?
Nothing works forever.
But, you know,
if you stop worrying
about forever,
there's plenty of shit
that can get you
through the next hour.
(LAUGHTER AND
INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYING)
ls what he said
still bugging you?
He looked at me like
he could see through me.
And Kady doesn't seem
to share your reservation.
She seems better.
Yeah.
I don't know why
I feel this way.
Our Lady came
to me in a dream.
Shouldn't that
remove all doubt?
Look, something like
this is about intention,
what we bring into it.
Our intentions are pure.
So just stop worrying?
Yeah.
Justhken.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
For now.
Tomorrow you can
worry all you want
about Our Lady Underground.
Tonight...
Tonight should
be about Dionysus.
Whoo, ooh. (CHUCKLES)
Dionysus, okay.
(LAUGHS)
You, uh...
You bang a lot of
undergrads with that one?
Fewer than I'd hoped.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
So...
Hmm? say it works.
And that means
what for you?
You asking if
I'm coming back?
Kind of, yeah.
I hadn't much
planned for it, really.
I just want to get there,
and I'll stay, or go
somewhere quiet.
If Our Lady has other
plans, hmm.
I'll do that.
I'll miss you.
I'll miss you, too.
To think you were
so crabby in rehab,
we almost never spoke.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Hey-
God, you are
really something, Julia.
I bet you say
that to all the girls
you slept with
three minutes ago.
That's funny.
Hmm.
But I mean it. I do.
That bite, that...
That thing in you that wants
to puzzle everything out,
that is gold.
No matter how
crabby it makes me?
I think especially
when it makes you crabby.
I think that us angry,
questioning people
sometimes shut up too fast,
and that is probably part
of why the gods took off.
No one around with the fire
to keep yelling their names.
This is gonna sound corny,
but don't lose that fire.
Well, it sounds like
you're saying goodbye.
I'm saying thank you.
So, this is a little
hitch in our adventure.
Are we just gonna
act like children now?
Now, now, Bambi.
He's got a right to be mad.
No, he doesn't.
People don't get
to be mad at me
because I had
sex with them.
You're welcome,
both of you.
Oh, come on.
We were all messed
up on emotion magic.
We deserve a pass.
I don't need a pass.
You two have
ruined my life.
No offense, Quentin,
but I think you did
that all yourself.
ELIOT: Can we just cut
to the part
where we go
to another world,
and skip the whole guilt
and recriminations
bit, please?
You would like that,
wouldn't you?
ls it wrong that
I'm starting to
side with The Beast?
(MOANS)
(MOANING)
All right.
(EXHALES)
(FOOTSTEPS THUDDING)
Didn't think you
had that in you.
You don't get to
shame me.
You slept with two other
people. We broke up.
I was out of my mind.
I made a mistake,
and you aimed a weapon.
I'm glad it hurt.
It should hurt.
ELIOT: Boys and girls,
I hate to cut into
what is clearly a moment,
but the fact is,
according to the best
and only magic we have,
we have to go or
The Beast will kill us.
End of story.
Take out your emotions.
You can fight later.
Sound good?
PENNY: All right, if you
guys are using those
emotion bottles,
let's go.
(ALL CHANTING TOGETHER
IN JAPANESE)
(ALL GROANING)
(SIGHS)
(SPEAKING JAPAN ESE)
(GASPS)
How I was feeling
about Quentin
would have got
us all killed.
I was very angry
a moment ago,
but I have to be honest.
You two would
make a cute couple.
(SCOFFS)
Join hands, everyone.
(WATER SPLASHING)
Let's move, fast.
The map says...
QUENTIN; Got it.
Quentin?
We've been waiting.
MAN: Come on! Hurry!
Run!
(GRUNTS)
Shit.
Okay-
We certainly
lost that fight.
How'd you find
this place?
I got lucky last time.
Quentin had the map.
Shit.
MARGO: No map,
evil mercenary
assholes everywhere,
stuck in a library.
This is not how we
decided this would go.
Penny, you know
this place.
There must be
somebody we can talk to.
Yeah, there might be.
Follow me.
Penny, Alice, Eliot,
and Janet,
you are all late.
Actually, it's Margo.
This time.
PENNY: Look,
we need your help,
though, you probably
already knew that.
I did.
The answer is yes,
you can stay,
with a few caveats.
Here it comes.
One, no harm comes
to the books.
Yeah, we get that.
Two,
no food, drinks,
or any other intoxicants
are allowed in
the library at any time.
That includes
emotion bottles.
Damage always ensues.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(ALL INHALE AND GROAN)
You understand, of course.
(ALL GROANING AND MOANING)
I planned my whole
outfit around that bottle!
Could you get
to the point, Quentin?
I have a trustees
meeting.
You know something
about what's been
happening here.
The Beast, Eliza.
I would like to
know what is really
going on here.
I know you would,
but we are done.
How did you lose
your virginity?
I was 24 years old.
I was too embarrassed
to tell anyone.
She was considerably
older than I,
and much, much
more experienced.
But...
Fuck!
You've managed to
dose me, haven't you?
In my tea.
You little shit.
Truth serum is toxic,
Quentin, and banned.
And if you were going
to throw magic at me,
you would have
done so already,
but you haven't.
Eliza,
who is she?
Eliza's real name
is Jane Chatwin.
Oh.
I was kind of poking around
in the dark with that one.
Uh...
Okay, what does Jane
have to do with The Beast?
Do you remember
the gift that Jane
was given in the book,
The Girl Who Told Time?
Uh, yeah, Ember gave her
a watch and a locket.
Ember gave her
the ability to
fuck with time,
on a cosmic scale,
and Jane used it to
create a time loop.
When she'd fail
to stop The Beast,
she'd restart the loop.
A time loop.
Okay-
Uh...
So, what do we have
to do with The Beast?
You just keep
getting involved.
I don't keep
doing anything.
Can you imagine,
Quentin,
how many times
we've had this
exact conversation?
You've managed
to slip truth serum
to me 27 times,
27 ways, and I'm
quite sick of it.
So, what, this is
just some giant,
blood-soaked Groundhog Day?
You always bring up
that fucking movie.
I still haven't seen it.
(LAUGHS) Now it's
a point of pride.
Answer my question.
In each loop,
Jane alters something
to see if it'll
change the outcome.
The sigil that
appeared on your hand,
brought you to Alice.
That was Jane trying
to get the ball rolling,
trying to get you all
together, working fast,
and we all know how
well that particular
great idea worked
out, don't we?
So, has anything
actually helped?
So far, all the loops
end in your death.
How many times have I died?
Thirty-nine.
Thirty-nine times.
And if you die a 40th,
at least I won't
have to hear you
ask me this
question ever again.
Jane's dead, Quentin.
The loop's done.
There's no one
to reset it.
So, this is it?
This isn't my problem.
My problem is that
I'm strong enough
to discern a time loop,
but not strong
enough to change it.
We better hope and pray
that Jane altered
the right thing this
time around.
Anything else, Quentin?
What's different this time?
Please, no books
on the floor.
I love this one.
Photos from places
I can't imagine.
I know you hate it now,
but Travelers wrote
our most precious books.
The library is what
it is because of them.
You make it sound
so simple and fun.
No.
But it is valuable.
And in my observation,
master Travelers have
a fantastic time doing it.
I was looking for
any technical info
that would get me anywhere
close to mastery, but...
The books you seek
are in another branch.
Of course they are.
Look, could you...
Could you expedite
that shit?
I don't have much
time, and I really
need to know how to
take people with me.
I'll put in a request.
Why am I not
feeling optimistic?
Probably because
Franz Kafka wrote
The Trial
after spending
a week in the library.
But, Penny, if you
can survive long enough,
you will get
a handle on it.
I promise.
If?
Say that in my book?
No spoilers.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Hi.
I was at Brakebills?
You were supposed to be.
Or you were,
like, 39 times.
You were the thing
they changed.
Jane thought, you know,
cast you out in the cold,
and you would get
stronger, and...
So, I was right.
The whole time,
I was right.
I don't know what
to say, Jules. I...
I should have
believed you, Jules.
I should have known,
and I'm...
Um...
Look, that doesn't
make up for what
I did to you,
which was stupid,
and vindictive,
and really dangerous.
I'm so sorry, Q.
Thank you.
So, how do we fix it?
I don't know.
I just know that I'm
gonna get killed soon,
and I don't really
want to die
being mad at
my oldest friend.
I really fucking
missed you.
Yeah, me, too,
actually.
You smell the same.
(CHUCKLES)
Okay, all right.
Uh...
(CLEARS THROAT)
So...
(SIGHS)
Big conspiracy.
Wheels within wheels.
Julia doesn't go
to Brakebills, and?
You're taking
this a lot better
than I would have.
It's because
there is bigger,
better magic
in the world.
I mean, you would
not believe some of
the shit I've seen.
I can barely believe it.
What?
Some friends and
I got into some pretty
eclectic shit.
You and Kady?
Where is she?
On a mission.
They all are.
They got pretty
strict marching
orders.
From?
A goddess.
We summoned,
and she came.
You mean, um, here?
To your loft?
You don't believe me.
Shit, lwou
dn't, either.
That is why
she gave me proof.
Yeah.
ls that milk?
Cool,
useless, kind of gross.
But look under the hood.
Oh, my God.
Who did this magic?
I told you. She did.
I mean, it was crazy.
It was like being
on a massive dose
of ecstasy.
When she touched me,
it was like my
psyche was defragging.
I mean, she...
She touched all of us.
She granted every petition.
She cured Meno
y's
breast cancer,
she sent Richard to
where he wanted to go.
I watched this.
I thought magic
couldn't cure cancer.
Not regular magic.
Look, I can't lie, okay?
It was shitty going
for a while there,
not being in Brakebills,
but I can't sit
here now,
and think it was
anything but fate.
Right, or just
the right random
combination.
Okay, suit yourself,
nihilist.
I need your help.
I don't know how
to get back, and, um...
My friends, we got separated,
and ljust...
I can't let them fight
The Beast on their own,
and I have to find a way...
Let me get this
straight.
You want me to come
to Fillory with you?
Yeah.
Come here.
QUENTIN: Holy shit.
This is our table.
JULIA: Kind of been
planning this trip
since we were nine.
QUENTIN; We kind Of have, huh?
Our Lady gave me
a mission to...
I sound like a nut-job.
Kind of.
(CHUCKLES)
What's the mission?
She said it was
my destiny
to basically find
a whole new
kind of magic.
You know, she said
it was something
that couldn't be given.
It had to be found.
So, we have to find it.
And I bet you
it's here.
So, I guess we're
off to see the Wizard.
Have you given any thought
to how we're gonna get there?
QUENTIN: Start of
the London Blitz, 1940,
and then their
mom dies, 1941.
Q, where are you
going with this?
Okay, so we can't just
open a door to Fillory,
but we do know
when they open...
Every time the Chatwins go.
So, if we could just
find a way to get there,
then we could
follow them in.
Look, all I know is
time magic
is apparently a thing,
a thing that's been
clicking with us for
the past 39 lifetimes.
So, I say we find a way
to make it work for us.
Wait, but that would
put us in past Fillory,
right?
Fillory is magic.
Remember, Jane falls
in that swamp,
and then she comes
out 20 years later.
She strikes a deal
with the Watcher Woman
to send her back.
Once you're there,
there's always a way.
I have an idea,
something Richard told me,
but we have to go
somewhere to get it.
Brakebills.
Okay-
Uh, you just have to be
a registered student
in order to get
through the wards.
Alumni key.
Richard gave it to me.
MARGO: This place
is impossible.
How does anyone
find anything?
There's a whole
wing on cat paintings.
What have you got?
Anything?
The Book of
Mike McCormick.
Novella, really.
He was actually
a Republican. Can
you believe it?
But the worst part?
His life was happy.
Eliot, he's gone.
Why are you
torturing yourself?
Because he's gone
and it's my fault.
And of all the people
in the world
who don't understand,
somehow you top the list.
What are you doing?
Putting the past
behind me.
(GASPS) No, stop!
Look, he's had
a really bad week.
We'll pay the fine,
whatever.
Nope, no, you are banished
from the library, forever.
It's one book.
No, it's a life.
They're irreplaceable.
No, wait!
What did you do?
PENNY: Let's go.
QUENTIN:
"Bridge to ancient Rome."
"Bridge to
the Cretaceous Period."
Oh, hey, here's one.
Uh...
"Southampton,
England, 1912"?
(CHUCKLES)
Voyage of the Titanic?
Oh. Fun.
So, we're pretty sure
these things only go
to one specific
point in time and...
Once you lock
a date in, you're locked.
I mean, they use
some tiny piece
of an incredibly
rare element.
All got used up
bythe'70s.
Wait a minute.
Wait. Here's a thesis.
A bunch of students
wanted to go back
and kill Hitler.
"Operation Die Fuehrer."
(SCOFFS)
Guess no one
told them Hitler was
a pretty serious
battle magician.
Yeah.
Yep, and Hitler
killed them.
Wait, what's the date
on the time bridge?
Uh, it's April 19th, 1942.
April 19th.
Yeah.
You remember the, uh...
Yeah, "The Flying Forest"?
Yeah, uh, Jane's
going into town.
She's looking for
a present for Martin.
April 21st, 1942.
Two days after
this time bridge.
Holy shit, Q, this could work.
I never thought I'd say it,
but thank God for Hitler.
Yeah, no, that still
sounds bad.
Yeah.
Earth fountain's
blocked off.
I told you it would be.
ELIOT: It was worth a shot.
I mean, what else are
we gonna do?
I don't know.
How about not
get us kicked out
of the library in
the first place?
PENNY: All right,
let's keep moving.
Hey. Not one more step.
We're highly trained
Earth magicians.
Hold up. Hold up.
You guys are from
Brakebills?
Dude, Josh Hoberman,
class of '16.
Come with me if
you want to live.
I've always
wanted to say that.
(CHUCKLES)
But seriously, um,
we should go.
Welcome to Chez Hoberman.
You're welcome to whatever.
Just don't eat
the carrots.
They're totally
psychedelic for
some reason.
Circumstances in
the Neitherlands
are super weird.
Holy shit.
This tastes like pizza.
Yeah, I know, right?
How long have
you been down here?
A few weeks.
Just been camped out,
waiting to see if
anyone else will show up.
Anyone else?
From my class.
Look, don't freak,
but back at Brakebills,
nobody knows what
happened to you guys.
And it's sort of
been two years.
Oh, shit. Right,
the whole time thing.
Victoria warned me about that.
PENNY: Victoria?
You know her?
She's the only
reason I'm alive.
Look, are you gonna
tell us what the fuck
happened to your
class, or what?
Where'd you guys go?
To Fillory.
For spring break.
V's amazing.
I mean, she literally
blips around the universe,
fearless.
Teachers put this
tattoo on her to stop her.
She just cut it
off herself.
Joshy- What?
You're not gonna believe it.
What?
I did it.
I found Fillory.
What?
I found Fillory!
Oh, my God!
We're going to Fillory!
We're going
to Fillory?
So, we decided
to plan a trip.
You know, party,
smoke out with the centaurs,
be back in time for classes,
but word got out to
practically the whole
first-year class,
except for a couple losers.
Luckily, V was so good,
she was able to
take them all with.
It was magical. (CHUCKLES)
I mean, more magical
than Brakebills,
like going from
black and white to color.
V and I had a threesome
with a naiad.
This guy Donnie,
he had sex with
a talking horse.
I mean, it's not
exactly taboo in Fillory,
since the animals
can give consent,
but we were all
still a bit squicked out.
We get it. You fucked
some animals.
How'd you end up here?
Got roped
into this quest.
Ended up being
a trap for Victoria.
This dude, Mothra,
I've been calling him...
Yeah, we know
that clown.
It was a bloodbath.
V zapped me here,
and then she went back in.
Told me to stay put,
so I have just
been waiting.
V should have
been here by now.
He caught her.
But she's still alive.
How do you know that?
I'm like her.
It's why I'm here.
We can all go,
rescue Victoria.
You can take us.
...
Haven't exactly
cracked
the whole
ride-along, yet.
Okay, forget
traveling.
Uh, we'll just
take a fountain.
Except we don't know
where the Fillory
fountain is.
That's easy.
It's three squares up,
one square left.
The problem is
all the battle magic
dick buckets
waiting to
vaporize us.
Discuss.
It's in the closet.
El and Margo made
a door to their
favorite pub in London.
JULIA: They look like fun.
Look, you were
supposed to be here.
You were supposed
to be a part of this.
No, you know,
I think Jane was right.
Had I been here
living it up,
I would have
never felt the need
to figure out what
magic is actually for.
Okay, so what's
magic actually for,
then?
For fixing
things, dummy.
Trust me.
I, uh, made
a lot of mistakes
before I figured
that one out.
Yeah, everything
I've been able to
fix doesn't matter,
just minor mendings
and bullshit.
Yeah, well, if fixing
big things were easy,
everyone would do it.
Come on.
PENNY: Alice.
Get some sleep.
(SIGHS)
I know.
I might as well.
W
never
figure this out.
Trying to think of
how to get us all to
the Fillory fountain
without getting
us killed.
Need a hand?
Look, Penny,
I'm sorry if I gave you
the wrong idea, but...
Stop.
It was fun, okay?
You're one of
the few people
I actually respect.
Uh,yeah,
you're right, right.
I'm just making
this weird, huh?
Eh, it's weird.
We're weird.
So, what?
We're friends, right?
ljust keep
thinking about Quentin.
Look, I know.
I just keep thinking
how awful it would be
if, out of all of us,
he was the one
who didn't get
to see Fillory.
And then I remember
that I hate him.
Fuck, why am I
such an idiot?
Okay-
Quentin is irrelevant.
Just another
excuse for that thing
you always do.
What thing?
"l should just give up.
WW
never
figure it out."
Shit got real.
If you're gonna
drop that bullshit,
now's the time.
ALICE: Phosphoromancy.
I can bend light
around us, all of us,
the whole group, I think,
make us invisible.
It'll be difficult
with the two suns
but not impossible.
We'll have to move
in a pretty tight formation.
When should we leave?
As soon as possible.
The suns are just
about in position.
It has begun!
Sorry.
Penny,EHoL
you're both tall,
so,youWlhaveto
duck down and stay
close to me, okay?
Got it.
Or they'll see you.
We got it, right?
Mmm-hmm.
Eliot, are you coming?
Right behind you,
Bambi.
Let's do this.
Okay-
(DEVICE BUZZING)
(BOTH GRUNT)
Holy shit.
(SIRENS BLARING)
ls that an air raid
sken?
Okay-
1942.
We need to get out of here.
Yeah.
(WHISPERS)
Go to the right.
(ECHOING) ls everything
all right, Eliot?
Everything's amazing.
Go left. Go left.
(GUNSHOT)
Yeah, I brought a gun.
"Thanks, Margo."
You're welcome.
Why didn't you move?
Acid carrots.
Margo, you saved
my actual life.
Hooray, you live to
drink another day.
ALICE: Shit, guys,
they see us.
Shit! Go! Go!
(GASPS)
(THUD5)
Oh, my God.
(GASPS)
She looks so young.
Yeah, she's got no
idea what's coming.
Hey-
That's gotta
be it, right?
Across the street,
the door to Fillory?
Here she comes.
MARTIN: You ready, Janey?
(IN BRITISH ACCENT)
Why, yes, Martin,
I think I am.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, my God.
Q.
Look.
(CHUCKLES)