Previously on "The Magicians"...
What does that mean?
Jesus, we could not have screwed up
that spell worse,
and we can't take it back.
You showed up
with that sigil on your hand.
It appeared when I was
dreaming of Fillory.
- It came from Jane.
- Who are you?
I'm a member of The Order,
the keepers of the libraries
of the Neitherlands.
Any idea who the motherfuckers
in the hoods are, trying to kill me?
They've been thoroughly cursed,
so they can't use the fountains,
but that hasn't stopped them
from finding other employment.
The Beast?
We are the best Magicians we know,
but Menolly is dying.
Bender's trying to stay
off the ledge every day.
- And you?
- Eight years ago,
I was a drug addict,
and I left my son in a hot car.
We're not learning anything new.
Beast always kills us.
There was one time
we didn't all die...
when we went to Fillory.
Point is, we need
some serious battle magic.
Bottling our emotions...
When the feelings come back,
it's extremely intense.
Near the bridge, there's a man
who has served me
a thousand years.
Bring him three gifts.
He'll show you the way.
Huh.
Not what I expected.
Yeah.
Die, fucker!
Well, that sucked ass.
Julia, Kady!
Finally.
Bienvenidas.
Are we interrupting or...
Oh, no, no, no.
Just passing the time.
So...
Uh, yeah, um...
We bring forsythia...
Mm-hmm.
And honeycomb.
Hmm.
Hmm-hmm-hmm.
Muy bien, chicas.
Muy bien.
Two down.
Where's the platinum?
We didn't bring that.
Too bad.
Exit through the gift shop.
But we did bring something
of great and shining worth.
Just say it.
If you're wrong, you're wrong.
We brought you our faith.
Ooh.
Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh.
Tricky, tricky, tricky, tricky.
I like it.
But to be honest,
I'm sensing more skepticism
than faith here.
Look, um, I'm trying.
She's the one
that had the dream, okay?
Hey.
Kady, your mother
used your faith,
but she isn't your true mother.
Our Lady feels
you require a miracle.
Oh, my God.
Wha... what ha...
What did he do?
I don't... I don't know.
I've had this tightness
ever since my mom,
but it's gone.
Ah, there it is.
Faith.
Okay, so...
Let's get to brass.
You're here why?
We seek an audience
with Our Lady Underground.
Yeah, no shit.
Why do you think
you deserve to see her?
- Hmm?
- It's okay.
Why should she waste
her time with you?
I am privileged,
and I have done some stupid shit,
and I have been through nothing
compared to some of my friends.
So you wish to help them?
Heal them? Is that it?
Yes, that is exactly
what I want to do.
No.
No, no, no.
Magicians...
that's all you ever want,
power, every time.
You know what?
For the longest time,
that is all I wanted.
But now I just want to do whatever
the fuck it is I'm supposed to.
And if she's around,
if she gives a shit,
I have to believe
she wants her daughters
to show a little ambition.
So you tell her that I am trying
to reach something higher.
Nuestra Señora sits and waits,
and no one asks.
She watches.
She weeps.
But today, she's
grinning like a fool.
Here's the invocation.
May her blessings be with you.
Thank you.
And one more piece
of advice for the chosen.
You can't unring a bell,
so be certain
when you call, Julia.
Okay.
Look...
All y'all look like
you did a crime last night.
According to all
the probability shit,
we don't have time to wait.
One or another super shitty ending
is coming within days
if we don't at least
try to go get the knife.
So...
Oh, God.
The Neitherlands is
Grand Central for the multiverse.
The button will bring you in,
and once you're there...
Yes, the fountains are portals.
Can I say this?
For your interest?
As far as I know,
you don't need
a button or anything
to ride the fountains,
so don't fall in.
Don't get lost.
The whole place is crawling
with battle magic motherfuckers
with hoods on.
We get separated,
you're dead.
Seriously,
what the fuck is going on
with you people?
Nothing.
We're fine, aren't we, El?
We're phenomenal.
Fine, okay.
We're not okay.
Forget it.
We just need to...
- We're going to...
- It's over!
I need a minute.
Alice is just a little bit
sensitive right now.
Would you just shut
the fuck up, Margo?
Are you seriously
mad at me right now?
What the fuck
did I just walk into?
My life. Welcome.
It's not funny,
and it's not a joke.
But it truly is, Quentin.
You people
need to stow your shit!
We get it!
Would you just, please,
give us a fucking goddamn minute?
How you doing?
Come on.
Stop worrying.
Fine.
- So the hermit was creepy.
- Super creepy.
You didn't feel what I felt.
I don't know.
Whatever he was channeling,
it was the real deal.
She's just nervous.
There's always some creepy guy
when you're about to blow
the patriarchy's head
out of their ass.
Everything is, um,
about to change...
everything, finally.
- Yeah.
- Cheers.
What?
Okay, you are the least crazy.
Tell me what's going on.
It... nothing.
Just forget it.
What the hell are you drinking?
I don't know.
Triple sec?
What did Quentin do?
I don't want to talk about it.
Fair enough.
Can I get some?
It's good.
It's not good.
No, it's not good.
Yeah.
Let you in on
a little secret, though.
I used to drink Midori
in high school.
It's like melon
crossed with perfume
crossed with ass.
Yum.
Fuck did I know?
I was trying to get
the voices to go away.
Point is, I'm not judging
anyone for triple sec.
And...
I can tell when someone's trying
to make something go away.
So Midori, hmm?
Does it work?
Nothing works forever.
But, you know,
if you stop worrying
about forever,
there's plenty of shit that can
get you through the next hour.
Is what he said
still bugging you?
He looked at me like
he could see through me.
And Kady doesn't seem
to share your reservation.
She seems better.
Yeah.
I don't know why
I feel this way.
Our Lady came to me in a dream.
Shouldn't that remove all doubt?
Look, something like this
is about intention,
what we bring into it.
Our intentions are pure.
- So just stop worrying?
- Yeah.
Just like...
For now.
Tomorrow you can worry
all you want
about Our Lady Underground.
Tonight... tonight should be
about Dionysus.
Whoo, ooh.
Dionysus, okay.
You, uh...
you bang a lot of undergrads
with that one?
Fewer than I'd hoped.
- Hmm?
- Say it works.
And that means what for you?
You asking if I'm coming back?
Kind of, yeah.
I hadn't much planned for it really.
I just want to get there,
and I'll stay
or go somewhere quiet.
If Our Lady
has other plans, hmm,
I'll do that.
I'll miss you.
I'll miss you too.
To think you were so crabby in rehab,
we almost never spoke.
God, you are really
something, Julia.
I bet you say that
to all the girls
you slept with
three minutes ago.
- That's funny.
- Hmm.
But I mean it. I do.
That bite, that...
that thing in you that wants
to puzzle everything out,
that is gold.
No matter how crabby
it makes me?
I think especially
when it makes you crabby.
I think that us angry,
questioning people
sometimes shut up too fast,
and that is probably part
of why the gods took off.
No one around with the fire
to keep yelling their names.
This is gonna sound corny,
but don't lose that fire.
Well, it sounds like
you're saying good-bye.
I'm saying thank you.
So this is a little hitch
in our adventure.
Are we just gonna act
like children now?
Now, now, Bambi.
He's got a right to be mad.
No, he doesn't.
People don't get to be mad at me
because I had sex with them.
You're welcome, both of you.
Oh, come on.
We were all messed up
on emotion magic.
- We deserve a pass.
- I don't need a pass.
You two have ruined my life.
No offense, Quentin,
but I think you did that all yourself.
Can we just cut to the part
where we go to another world
and skip the whole guilt
and recriminations bit, please?
You would like that,
wouldn't you?
Is it wrong that I'm starting
to side with The Beast?
Mmm.
Ah! Ah.
Fuck.
All right.
Didn't think
you had that in you.
You don't get to shame me.
You slept with two other people.
We broke up.
I was out of my mind.
I made a mistake,
and you aimed a weapon.
I'm glad it hurt.
It should hurt.
Boys and girls,
I hate to cut into
what is clearly a moment,
but the fact is,
according to the best
and only magic we have,
we have to go
or The Beast will kill us.
End of story.
Take out your emotions.
You can fight later.
Sound good?
All right, if you guys
are using those emotion bottles,
let's go.
How I was feeling about Quentin
would have got us all killed.
I was very angry a moment ago,
but I have to be honest.
You two would make
a cute couple.
Join hands, everyone.
Let's move, fast.
The map says...
Got it.
Quentin?
We've been waiting.
Run!
Shit.
We certainly lost that fight.
- How'd you find this place?
- Got lucky last time.
Quentin had the map.
- Shit.
- No map,
evil mercenary assholes
everywhere, stuck in a library...
this is not how we decided
this would go.
Penny, you know this place.
There must be somebody
we can talk to.
Yeah, there might be.
Follow me.
Penny, Alice, Eliot, and Janet,
you are all late.
Actually, it's Margo.
This time.
Look, we need your help,
though you probably
already knew that.
I did.
The answer is yes, you can stay,
with a few caveats.
Here it comes.
One, no harm comes to the books.
Yeah, we get that.
Two, no food, drinks,
or any other intoxicants
are allowed in the library
at any time.
That includes emotion bottles.
Damage always ensues.
You understand, of course.
I planned my whole outfit
around that bottle!
Could you get
to the point, Quentin?
I have a trustees meeting.
You know something about
what's been happening here...
The Beast, Eliza.
I would like to know
what is really going on here.
I know you would,
but we are done.
- How did you lose your virginity?
- I was 24 years old.
I was too embarrassed
to tell anyone.
She was considerably
older than I
and, oh, much, much
more experienced.
But...
Fuck!
You've managed to dose me,
haven't you?
In my tea.
You little shit.
Truth serum is toxic,
Quentin, and banned.
And if you were going
to throw magic at me,
you would have done so already,
but you haven't.
Eliza...
who is she?
Eliza's real name
is Jane Chatwin.
Oh...
I was kind of poking around
in the dark with that one. Uh...
Okay, what does Jane
have to do with The Beast?
Do you remember the gift
that Jane was given in the book
"The Girl Who Told Time"?
Uh, yeah, Ember gave her
a watch and a locket.
Ember gave her the ability
to fuck with time on a cosmic scale,
and Jane used it
to create a time loop.
When she'd fail to stop The Beast,
she'd restart the loop.
A time loop.
Okay. Uh...
So what do we have to do
with The Beast?
You just keep getting involved.
I don't keep doing anything.
Can you imagine, Quentin,
how many times we've had
this exact conversation?
You've managed to slip
truth serum to me 27 times,
27 ways, and I'm quite sick of it.
So, what, this is just some giant,
blood-soaked "Groundhog Day"?
You always bring up
that fucking movie.
I still haven't seen it.
Now it's a point of pride.
Answer my question.
In each loop,
Jane alters something
to see if it'll
change the outcome.
The sigil that appeared
on your hand,
brought you to Alice...
that was Jane trying
to get the ball rolling,
trying to get you all
together, working fast,
and we all know how well
that particular great idea
worked out, don't we?
So has anything actually helped?
So far, all the loops
end in your death.
How many times have I died?
39.
39 times.
And if you die a 40th,
at least I won't
have to hear you
ask me this question ever again.
Jane's dead, Quentin.
The loop's done.
There's no one to reset it.
So this is it?
This isn't my problem.
My problem is that
I'm strong enough
to discern a time loop
but not strong enough
to change it.
We better hope and pray
that Jane altered the right
thing this time around.
Anything else, Quentin?
What's different this time?
Please, no books on the floor.
I love this one.
Photos from places
I can't imagine.
I know you hate it now,
but travelers wrote
our most precious books.
The library is what it is
because of them.
You make it sound
so simple and fun.
No. But it is valuable.
And in my observation,
master travelers have
a fantastic time doing it.
I was looking
for any technical info
that would get me anywhere
close to mastery, but...
The books you seek
are in another branch.
Of course they are.
Look, could you...
could you expedite that shit?
I don't have much time,
and I really need to know
how to take people with me.
I'll put in a request.
Why am I not feeling optimistic?
Probably because
Franz Kafka wrote "The Trial"
after spending a week
in the library.
But, Penny, if you can
survive long enough,
you will get a handle on it.
I promise.
If?
Say that in my book?
No spoilers.
Hi.
- I was at Brakebills?
- You were supposed to be.
Or you were, like, 39 times.
You were the thing they changed.
Jane thought, you know,
cast you out in the cold,
and you would get stronger,
and...
So I was right.
The whole time, I was right.
I don't know
what to say, Jules. I...
I should have
believed you, Jules.
I should have known,
and I'm... I'm...
Um...
Look, that doesn't make up
for what I did to you,
which was stupid
and vindictive
and really dangerous.
I'm so sorry, Q.
Thank you.
- So how do we fix it?
- I don't know.
I just know that
I'm gonna get killed soon,
and I don't really want to die
being mad at my oldest friend.
- I really fucking missed you.
- Yeah, me, too, actually.
You smell the same.
Okay, all right. Uh...
So...
Big conspiracy.
Wheels within wheels.
Julia doesn't go
to Brakebills, and?
You're taking this a lot
better than I would have.
It's because there is bigger,
better magic in the world.
I mean, you would not believe
some of the shit I've seen.
I can barely believe it.
Wha... what?
Some friends and I got into
some pretty eclectic shit.
You and Kady?
Where is she?
On a mission.
They all are.
They got pretty strict
marching orders.
From?
A goddess.
We summoned, and she came.
You mean, um, here?
To your loft?
You don't believe me.
Shit, I wouldn't either.
That is why she gave me proof.
- Is that milk?
- Yeah.
Cool, useless, kind of gross.
But look under the hood.
Oh, my God.
Who did this magic?
I told you.
She did.
I mean, it was crazy.
It was like being
on a massive dose of ecstasy.
When she touched me,
it was like my psyche
was defragging.
I mean, she...
she touched all of us.
She granted every petition.
She cured Menolly's
breast cancer;
she sent Richard
to where he wanted to go.
I watched this.
I thought magic
couldn't cure cancer.
Not regular magic.
Look, I can't lie, okay?
It was shitty going
for a while there,
not being in Brakebills,
but I can't sit here now
and think it was
anything but fate.
Right, or just the right
random combination.
Okay, suit yourself, nihilist.
I need your help.
I don't know how to get back,
and, um, my friends,
we got separated,
and I just... I can't let them
fight The Beast on their own,
and I have to find a way, um...
Let me get this straight.
You want me to come
to Fillory with you.
Uh, yeah.
Come here.
Holy shit.
This is our table.
Kind of been planning
this trip since we were nine.
We kind of have, huh?
Our Lady gave me a mission to...
I sound like a nutjob.
Kind of.
What's the mission?
She said it was my destiny
to basically find
a whole new kind of magic.
You know, she said
it was something
that couldn't be given.
It had to be found.
So we have to find it.
And I bet you it's here.
So I guess we're off
to see the Wizard.
Have you given any thought
to how we're gonna get there?
Start of the London Blitz, 1940,
and then their mom dies, 1941.
Q, where are you
going with this?
Okay, so we can't just
open a door to Fillory,
but we do know when they open...
every time the Chatwins go.
So if we could just
find a way to get there,
then we could follow 'em in.
Uh...
Look, all I know is time magic
is apparently a thing,
a thing that's been dicking with
us for the past 39 lifetimes.
So I say we find a way
to make it work for us.
Wait, but that would put us
in past Fillory, right?
Fillory is magic.
Remember,
Jane falls in that swamp,
and then she comes out
20 years later.
She strikes a deal with
the Watcherwoman to send her back.
Once you're there,
there's always a way.
I have an idea,
something Richard told me,
but we have to go
somewhere to get it.
Brakebills.
Okay.
Uh, you just have to be
a registered student
in order to get
through the wards.
Alumni key.
Richard gave it to me.
This place is impossible.
How does anyone find anything?
There's a whole wing
on cat paintings.
What have you got?
Anything?
"The Book of Mike McCormick."
Novella, really.
He was actually a Republican.
Can you believe it?
But the worst part?
His life was happy.
Eliot, he's gone.
Why are you torturing yourself?
Because he's gone
and it's my fault.
And of all the people
in the world
who don't understand,
somehow you top the list.
- What are you doing?
- Putting the past behind me.
No, stop!
Look, he's had
a really bad week.
We'll pay the fine, whatever.
Nope, no, you are banished
from the library forever.
It's one book.
No, it's a life.
They're irreplaceable.
No, wait!
What did you do?
Let's go.
"Bridge to ancient Rome."
"Bridge to the Cretaceous period."
Oh, hey, here's one.
"Southampton, England, 1912"?
Voyage of the "Titanic."
Oh, fun.
So we're pretty sure
these things only go
to one specific
point in time and...
Once you log a date in,
you're locked.
I mean, they use some tiny piece
of an incredibly rare element.
All got used up by the '70s.
Wait a minute.
Wait.
Here's a thesis.
A bunch of students wanted
to go back and kill Hitler.
"Operation Die Fuehrer."
Guess no one told 'em Hitler was
a pretty serious
battle Magician?
Yeah.
Uh, yep, and Hitler killed them.
Wait, what's the date
on the time bridge?
Uh, it's April 19, 1942.
April 19th.
Yeah.
You remember the, uh...
yeah, "The Flying Forest."
Yeah, uh,
Jane's going into town.
She's looking for
a present for Martin.
April 21, 1942.
Two days after this time bridge.
Holy shit, Q, this could work.
I never thought I'd say it,
but thank God for Hitler.
Yeah, no, that still sounds bad.
Yeah.
Earth fountain's blocked off.
- I told you it would be.
- It was worth a shot.
I mean, what else
are we gonna do?
I don't know.
How about not get us kicked out
of the library
in the first place?
All right, let's keep moving.
Hey.
Don't walk one more step.
We're highly trained
Earth magicians.
Hold up. Hold up.
You guys are from Brakebills?
Dude, Josh Hoberman,
class of '16.
Come with me
if you want to live.
I've always wanted to say that.
But seriously, um, we should go.
Welcome to Chez Hoberman.
You're welcome to whatever.
Just don't eat the carrots.
They're totally psychedelic
for some reason.
Circumstances in the
Neitherlands are super weird.
Holy shit.
This tastes like pizza.
Yeah, I know, right?
How long have you
been down here?
A few weeks.
Just been camped out,
waiting to see if anyone else
will show up.
Anyone else?
From my class.
Look, don't freak,
but back at Brakebills,
nobody knows what happened
to you guys.
And it's sort of been two years.
Oh, shit.
Right, the whole time thing.
Victoria warned me about that.
Victoria?
You know her?
She's the only reason I'm alive.
Look are you gonna tell us
what the fuck happened
to your class, or what?
Where'd you guys go?
To Fillory for spring break.
V's amazing.
I mean, she literally blips
around the universe, fearless.
Teachers put this tattoo
on her to stop her.
She just cut it off herself.
- Joshy.
- What?
- You're not gonna believe it.
I did it.
I found Fillory.
- What?
- I found Fillory!
- Oh, my God!
- Whoo! We're going to Fillory!
- We're going to Fillory?
- Uh-huh!
So we decided to plan a trip.
You know, party,
smoke out with the centaurs,
be back in time for classes,
but word got out to practically
the whole first year class,
except for a couple losers.
Luckily, V was so good,
she was able
to take them all with.
It was magical.
I mean,
more magical than Brakebills,
like going from black and white
to color.
V and I had a threesome
with a Naiad.
This guy Donnie,
he had sex with a talking horse.
I mean, it's not exactly
taboo in Fillory
since the animals
can give consent,
but we were all still
a bit squicked out.
We get it.
You fucked some animals.
How'd you end up here?
Got roped into this quest.
Ended up being a trap
for Victoria.
This dude... Mothra,
I've been calling him...
Yeah, we know that clown.
It was a bloodbath.
V zapped me here,
and then she went back in.
Told me to stay put,
so I have just been waiting.
V should have been here by now.
He caught her.
But she's still alive.
How do you know that?
I'm like her.
It's why I'm here.
We can all go, rescue Victoria.
You can take us.
I...
haven't exactly cracked
the whole ride-along yet.
Okay, forget traveling.
Uh, we'll just take a fountain.
Except we don't know
where the Fillory fountain is.
That's easy.
It's three squares up,
one square left.
The problem is all the battle magic
dick buckets waiting to vaporize us.
Discuss.
It's in the closet.
El and Margo made a door
to their favorite pub in London.
They look like fun.
Look, you were supposed
to be here.
You were supposed
to be a part of this.
No, you know,
I think Jane was right.
Had I been here living it up,
I would have never
felt the need to figure out
what magic is actually for.
Okay, so what's magic
actually for, then?
For fixing things, dummy.
Trust me.
I, uh, made a lot of mistakes
before I figured that one out.
Yeah, everything I've been
able to fix doesn't matter,
just minor mendings
and bullshit.
Yeah, well, if fixing
big things were easy,
everyone would do it.
Come on.
Alice.
Get some sleep.
I know.
I might as well.
I'll never figure this out.
Trying to think of how to get us
all to the Fillory fountain
without getting us killed.
Need a hand?
Look, Penny,
I'm sorry if I gave you
the wrong idea, but...
Whoa, stop.
It was fun, okay?
You're one of the few people
I actually respect.
Uh, yeah, you're right, right.
I'm just making this weird, huh?
Eh, it's weird.
We're weird.
So what?
We're friends, right?
I just keep thinking
about Quentin.
Look, I know.
I just keep thinking
how awful it would be
if, out of all of us,
he was the one
who didn't get to see Fillory.
And then I remember
that I hate him.
Fuck, why am I such an idiot?
Okay.
Quentin is irrelevant.
Just another excuse
for that thing you always do.
What thing?
"I should just give up.
I'll never figure it out."
Shit got real.
If you're gonna drop
that bullshit, now's the time.
Phosphoromancy.
I can bend light around us,
all of us, the whole group, I think,
make us invisible.
It'll be difficult with the two suns
but not impossible.
We'll have to move
in a pretty tight formation.
- When should we leave?
- As soon as possible.
The suns are just about
in position.
It has begun!
Sorry.
Penny, Eliot, you're both tall,
so you'll have to duck down
and stay close to me, okay?
- Or they'll see you.
- Got it.
We got it, right?
Eliot, are you coming?
Right behind you, Bambi.
Let's do this.
Okay.
Holy shit.
Is that an air raid siren?
Okay. 1942.
- We need to get out of here.
- Yeah.
Go to the right.
Is everything all right, Eliot?
Everything's amazing.
Go left. Go left.
Yeah, I brought a gun.
Thanks, Margo.
You're welcome.
Why didn't you move?
Acid carrots.
Margo, you saved my actual life.
Hooray, you live
to drink another day.
- Oh, shit, guys, they see us.
- Shit! Go! Go!
Oh, my God.
She looks so young.
Yeah, she's got
no idea what's coming.
Hey. That's got to be it, right?
Across the street,
the door to Fillory?
Yeah.
Ooh, here she comes.
You ready, Janey?
Why, yes, Martin, I think I am.
Oh, my God.
Q.
Look.