MARGO: Previously
on The Magicians...
PENNY: The Couple has power
and they are not good people.
Give me the page. If the
finger's still viable, I reattach.
I'm Hyman. Cooper.
I was a student
here in the 1920s.
A Traveler. Someone
moved my body.
I stole this. Stasis charm.
Freezes the wearer in time.
Holy shit. Umber?
You make for an excellent
focus group for my new world.
More of a pocket world, really.
I will get out of here,
and then, I'll turn you
into lobsters and eat you.
Hey, what happened to your eye?
MARGO: I lent it to Josh.
My own personal Mar-GoPro.
Josh didn't die. He
was in the Taker Realm.
(STAMMERS) That's not possible.
Somebody opened a door that
should not have been opened.
It could mean the
end of everything.
I think I can't do
what I need to do
if I'm worried about
how it's gonna affect you.
I think we need to be done.
My pregnancy is
going to be sped up?
It's Red Monkey Month.
Everything goes faster
in Red Monkey Month.
Wait, so you're
saying that's a thing?
Me being able to take
on what the baby can do?
Maybe.
JULIA: Well, maybe
this baby's a Traveler.
Yeah, uh, we
should probably talk.
Seems like I missed a lot here.
MARGO: It's
actually super simple.
The Dark King AKA Rupert Chatwin
is trying to jailbreak his dead
lover out of Hell or whatever,
so he needs to get rid
of the guard dogs first.
Hence using you as a human
smallpox blanket to kill the Takers.
Yeah. Uh, I meant more like...
Uh... (GROANS)
Contraception wards are
supposed to be foolproof.
Don't worry, my
uterus is on lock.
Right, 'cause a werewolf
baby could be... Yikes.
But potentially very cute.
Fucking adorable.
(EYEBALL POPS)
Some day. Not now.
I'm not giving birth to
a goddamn litter, Josh.
Besides,
I thought we were done.
You risked your sanity to
save me from the Taker Realm.
If that doesn't buy us
a clean slate, then...
So, can we skip to
the reunion banging?
(CHUCKLES)
You're wearing three rubbers.
At least.
PENNY: Have you
been to a doctor?
They don't exactly have
ultrasounds in Fillory.
Have you thought about
what this means for us?
What do you want it to mean?
We broke up for good reasons.
None of that has changed.
My dad wasn't around for long.
My mom... Look, I'm
not doing that to our kid.
I want to be there
for him... Her?
No clue yet.
I want you to be there, too.
You guys?
Um, I'm sorry, but,
um, there's a problem.
We were in the elevator and
Eliot and Fen just collapsed.
(SIGHS)
ELIOT: Hello?
Hello?
Anyone?
My...
FEN: Eliot?
Oh.
It's you.
What kind of Fillorian nonsense
is this? Or am I dreaming?
I know I'm not.
In my dreams you're nice to me.
MARGO: What
the shit is going on?
(MARGO CLEARS THROAT) Whoa! Oh!
Look away! Look
away! Still draping here.
We were just settling on safe
words when we woke up here.
Any idea why?
Mmm.
MALE VOICE: (IN
SING-SONG VOICE) Yoo-hoo!
Welcome, High Kings!
Ember, I thought you were dead.
Oh, I am an energetic
emanation, my dear blinking idiot.
A message left by
the great god Ember
to forewarn of
impending apocalypse.
I've met this guy
before. Mmm-hmm.
I have brought you here
because you are the living
former High Kings of Fillory,
and your kingdom rests on
the knife's edge of annihilation.
Ooh! (LAUGHS MISCHIEVOUSLY)
Huh.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(SNORING SOFTLY)
(SIGHS)
You do realize I have
other things to do.
Whatever.
I just had to pull
Josh's pants back on,
so, diagnose.
They're asleep.
I mean, obviously
they're cursed or whatever,
but beyond that? Just wait
and see if they wake up.
Should we just slap them?
Believe me, I tried.
I'm going to see what we
have on narcolepsy spells.
You were not pregnant
the last time I saw you.
Like, at all.
Oh, yeah, well,
things happened fast.
Everything looks fine for now,
but I should do more scans.
It looks like you
have fast-forwarded
through the first
two trimesters.
You're ready to pop.
Accelerated pregnancies
can be dangerous.
And, uh, it's a hybrid.
Have you had any side
effects? Psychic episodes?
Uh, yes. That I kind
of caused myself.
Yeah, she had to,
to get out of, well,
a dungeon, but none since.
Um, actually, that's
not entirely true.
Wait, what?
A couple of aftershocks,
but it's really no big deal.
I've already put up
every mental ward I know.
Okay.
There are treatments,
but they have to
be applied regularly,
and the only place where
it's safe to cast right now is...
The Brakebills lab.
Because the moon
is still pissed at us.
Uh, look, I'll be there
the minute I can.
We're just dealing
with some stuff.
Clearly. Don't wait too long.
EMBER: As you ought to remember,
I am activated by world war,
pandemic, revolt of dwarves...
Or the mass rising of the dead.
Yeah, we know.
We're already on it.
Huzzah! And I have
summoned all of you
because the current ruler is
the nitwit causing the problem.
The thing is, he's
sort of unkillable.
I rescind my huzzah.
In addition to being
just very creepy,
the dead drain life, contaminating
everything they touch,
like a pickle on a sandwich.
I like pickles.
Behold! A dead person
wriggling from their grave!
(GROWLING)
And this is every Fillorian
who has ever lived.
(ALL EXCLAIM)
(ALL GROAN IN DISGUST)
You see? The pickles of
the dead will ruin Fillory.
You must stop this,
whatever the cost.
Well, the cost is blowing
up the entire planet.
Which is... A decent option?
I was going to say
counterproductive.
Only if you care about
peasants. Which I do not.
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
You want to get that, or...
Oh, no, that's just... A
mouse farted or something.
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
EMBER: A very gassy mouse.
ELIOT: (SIGHS) Umber.
It is I, an energetic
emanation of Umber!
Great God of... EMBER: Piss off.
Nobody wants you here.
I have heard your lamentations,
and am here to help.
I was designed to intervene
if my anarchist brother
tries something stupid,
like blowing up the
planet. (HISSES)
Do you have a better suggestion?
I do, sweet Matron of Fillory.
After I faked my own death, I
fled to Earth and built new worlds.
Didn't finish any. Did, too!
Mostly. I intended to rescue
my people from this chaotic place.
So, I also built an ark.
Like, a big-ass boat?
A pocket world.
A temporary vessel that pulls
every living Fillorian off the planet
so that I might deliver them
to a new, more perfect world.
So you're saying
we can use the Ark,
rescue the people, blow up
Fillory and stop the Dark King.
If anyone is going to destroy
this putrid stank-hole, it will be me.
(GRUNTS) (ALL EXCLAIM)
(GRUNTS) (ALL EXCLAIMING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Oh, my gods.
JOSH: Guys.
FEN: And then they just
slapped each other over and over
for hours.
I think they forgot
we were there.
Okay, I'm just having a hard
time with the part where we
save Fillory by destroying it.
Yeah, seems extreme.
What happens to magic?
The Wellspring is on Fillory.
Well, we don't know.
But our only other choice
is to let the dead spill
into our world. Every world.
JOSH: The pocket
world is temporary,
so where do we
put all the Fillorians?
Earth?
Have you seen how we
treat our own refugees?
What about the World Seed?
From Q's page.
If we could find it,
we could use it to build a
new world. A new Fillory.
That's insane.
In a good way.
And a bad way.
I think the Couple have the
Seed and the page they stole
is just an instruction
manual, it's useless on its own.
And they went to some
pretty extreme lengths to get it.
Upside is, we have time and the
moon will keep them from casting on it.
And it's in a dead
language I couldn't decipher.
I took pictures, but...
Okay, well if you work
on finding the Seed,
I can work on the language.
Sticking us with grabbing
the Ark-thingy from Umber's.
Well, Quentin and I went
once. It's in Vancouver.
Is your traveling
still jacked? Yeah.
But there is someone
who could help.
Okay, buddy.
If you can hear me,
be the Hyman.
(GASPING)
(SIGHS) (BONES CRACKING)
I'm alive?
Yeah.
(GASPING)
(SHUDDERING)
Thank you. Thank you.
(KNUCKLES CRACK)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(PLAYING TUNE HARSHLY)
(CHUCKLING)
Ah. (LAUGHS)
Whore!
(GROANS)
(SNIFFS) Ugh.
Just kidding.
Ah.
(SQUEALS SOFTLY)
Oh, my God.
Ah, this is incredible.
I love fingering things!
Right. Okay.
How about a few
being-alive-in-the-21st-century
ground rules? Mmm.
First of all, you can't act like
a fucking pervert anymore.
Even white dudes can't
get away with that shit.
Most of the time.
People can see you,
and hear you, and...
And smell you.
Sorry, pregnancy nose.
No. Ah.
Ground rules, Hyman.
Okay, boys, let's get
back on mission, shall we?
We need you to travel some
people to Umber's house.
You think you can do it?
You guys need me? Whoa. (GASPS)
My traveling's a little rusty, but
I'll do whatever you guys need.
Yeah, about that.
(WHIRRING)
(SCREAMING)
You wouldn't know it from how
stoic I was, but it was the worst pain
anyone has ever felt.
Wow, that's neat. Here's
the address to Umber's.
Are you sure you can do this?
(SCOFFS) Buddy,
I know my onions.
That means yes?
That must mean yes.
Oh.
Hey. Hi.
Remind me, you are...
Fen.
Eliot's wife?
Fillory girl.
Of course, Fillory girl.
You're the one who loves forks.
What's got you grummy?
I'm fine.
As a seasoned viewer of people,
I think you're upset
because their plan is zany,
and you know if you
speak up, they won't listen.
(SCOFFS) What? No,
their plan is... is great.
And they do listen to me.
Didn't Eliot say
you were a hayseed
from a backwards,
prolapsed asshole of a planet?
Or were... You weren't...
Were you not there?
Okay, outsider
to outsider. Yeah?
Doesn't this feel like
the part in the story
where the good
guys are just wrong?
Hearts in the right place,
but they haven't
learned the lesson
of this little morality
play they're in yet,
so they have this crazy plan
that makes them almost
as bad as the villain.
Oh.
Or maybe it's just me.
(GASPS)
(GASPS) I did it.
Ha-ha!
I really did it.
We'll ring you when
we're ready to travel back.
I'm not coming with you inside?
We're all full up
on perverts, here.
Oh.
Oh, that's... That's fine.
I've got other stuff to do.
I'm...
Maybe I'll go google myself.
You know what?
Knock yourself out.
Bye.
(GROANS)
I'm sorry, the master of the
house isn't available right now.
Please return another time.
Wait, why does he look
like Umber but boring?
That's his human form, for
blending in with Canadians.
Must be another emanation.
He's a ghost butler! Who
ya gonna call? That guy!
We spoke to the horny
version of you in Fillory,
he sent us here to
get a thing. Can we?
In the beginning,
there was nothing.
Until a tigress, blind in one
eye, came to a lonely shore.
The tigress looked
upon this raw world and...
And what?
I'm sorry, the master of
the house isn't available.
I think ghost butler is broken.
Or it's a test. Solve the
puzzle, get in the door.
How could it be a test? He's
just spouting random nonsense.
Oh, it's not random.
It's Fillorian scripture.
The birth of Ember and Umber.
You guys haven't heard this story?
What happens next? (CHUCKLES)
Well, the Tigress, she waded
into the ocean and drowned herself.
And as her body disappeared
beneath the waves,
two shells washed ashore.
And from those shells came
Ember, and then his shadow, Umber.
Welcome.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(MURMUR OF CHATTER)
Ow.
God, shut up.
Julia.
I'm fine. I'm just...
Just a little bit of
aftershock. That's all.
PENNY: Hyman.
Penny, did you know they
sell pre-sliced bread now?
That's the greatest invention
since... I don't even know what.
Your parents, were
they magicians?
No. Uh, Dad was a
door-to-door snake salesman.
Snake oil?
No. And my mom worked at a
brothel, you know, just mopping.
Okay, did she, um...
Did she suffer from
any mental problems?
Psychic stuff from
being pregnant with you?
Oh, no, nothing like that.
After the lobotomy,
she mostly just
sat on the porch and
sucked at bits of hay.
Other than that, she
was the perfect mother.
Okay, come on. Uh, I need
your help with something.
Put the sandwich down.
PETE: You want
to find the Couple?
They're a myth. Like the
Boogeyman, or Santa Claus.
Uh... Santa is very real.
And so are the Couple.
We met one of them.
The only other person that I know
who believes they're real is Marina.
The last time we saw her, we
screwed her over, moved the moon,
stopped the Harmonic
Convergence,
which she was going to use for
some heist-of-the-century type of deal.
I didn't say that
she'll help you.
I just said she's the
only one who can.
(SIGHS) (PETE MUNCHING)
Pretty by-the-numbers
defensive wards.
Marina's not a
by-the-numbers kind of girl.
You guys!
Come here. Uh...
Kady, I just wanted to tell you
that I am so sorry for all of
the times that I've hurt you.
Come inside for cookies?
What the fuck was that?
I'm still learning how to bake,
so no judging.
Go ahead. (CHUCKLES)
They're not poisoned.
But they might be?
Marina, why are you...
Nice? Mmm-hmm.
This may surprise
you... (CHUCKLES)
but I made some bad
choices in the past,
and I needed to fix that.
So I went to a
trance healer. Um...
She put a block on all
the parts of my personality
that made aggressive but
ultimately self-destructive choices.
This feels like a scam.
It's a weird scam.
I'm not asking you for anything.
And you came to me.
Seems like you need something?
We're looking for the Couple.
Well, this has been great, but I
actually have to get ready for church.
You know who they are.
I know that going after them
is the very definition of
an old Marina decision.
Look, I want to
help you. I do, really.
If it was anything else.
But they have something we
need to stop the end of everything.
The World Seed.
The most valuable object
in the multiverse, people say.
Which is why I
wanted to steal it,
until you stopped the
Harmonic Convergence.
Wait, that was your
heist of the century?
So you could help us steal it.
No. No, no, no. I... I don't
do things like that anymore.
Stealing from the Couple,
people will get hurt.
Way more people will
get hurt if you don't help us.
Alice... (CHUCKLES)
friends don't make friends
grapple with the trolley problem.
They cut off my fingers.
There's no gray area here.
They're hiding the Seed
inside a hotel called The Nave.
I've been there.
They only let in Magicians.
Everything about it is secret.
Has a vault that's the most
secure place on the planet.
But you had a plan to break in.
I had partners.
We spent months
constructing a map
of every inch of that
hotel and its defenses.
We called it our Heist Book.
The problem is,
things got really crazy
and I don't actually know
where the book ended up.
(SIGHS)
But I know someone who might.
Hey, buddy! Been a minute.
Need some ice chips or
something? Oh, Christ. No. Go away!
Is that Gavin from the
Library? He doesn't...
I don't work for the
sodding Library anymore!
Yeah. What happened to you?
She didn't tell you?
Marina hired me and a few other
poor bastards to rob the Couple.
She didn't tell us that
the plan was suicidal
without the Harmonic
Convergence.
Marina sent us in anyway.
One guy was killed.
Horribly, I might add.
I was lucky. (SCOFFS) But now I'm
stuck here, a bag of shattered bones,
can't travel, with
fucking Daryl over there
talking my fucking ear
off all day and night.
And so help me God, if you wake
him up, I will kill all of your mothers.
Marina beat you to that one.
Then why are you
working with her?
Um, Marina, maybe
you should step outside.
Mmm.
We're not fans of
Marina or the Couple.
But we need the World Seed,
so if you could just
give us the Heist Book,
we can... I would
sooner shit my cast.
Well, it looks like that's gonna
happen either way, so why not help us?
Because that would
mean helping Marina.
And if you think
I'm gonna do that,
then you have a few roos
loose in the top paddock, love.
So either find a way to scratch
my ass or get the hell out.
That's why you did the
spell to make yourself good.
Because you sent them
on a suicide mission.
I thought maybe
they'd get lucky.
Well, they really didn't.
ALICE: We need that Heist Book.
How did you convince Gavin
to help you in the first place?
I had leverage.
Well, then use it, now.
That would be deeply unethical.
(SIGHS)
I think I'm gonna go
get him a smoothie.
(BOTH SCOFF)
If he won't help
us, we're stuck.
We can't be stuck. We need
the book. We need Marina.
Or we need to be Marina.
(DOOR OPENS) Oh, God.
Look, we understand.
You don't want to help us.
We can't make you. But we
can take down your wards.
ALICE: You're a Traveler.
Without mental wards,
you'll hear people's thoughts.
All day, all night. Even
while they're sleeping.
If you do that while the moon
is borked, my head will be, too.
I recently had several fingers
amputated and reattached.
I'd be more concerned
about that if I were you.
(SCOFFS)
I underestimated you, book
tart. You're worse than Marina.
No. Just desperate.
(GRUNTS)
Bugger you all to hell, stop.
(SIGHS) The Heist Book?
I can't give it to you,
because I don't have it.
Who does?
Anna. She took it after
things went pear-shaped.
Who is Anna?
(DOOR OPENS) Ask her.
Well, now we have
a real problem.
(DOOR OPENS)
Is that Chinese and ice cream?
You could smell that?
I have a new superpower.
So, what'd you get?
Well, I... (CHUCKLES) I didn't
know what you were craving,
so, everything. Also...
The Circumstances control panel?
Did you steal that from the lab?
Hyman helped.
We figured if the Couple is
going to use the World Seed,
they need clean magic. So,
without this, they are stuck.
Hence, hiding it here.
If it were going to
be here anyway,
I figured Lipson could
come by, do the treatments,
run some scans, two birds.
Good, but Lipson
said the baby was fine.
She said she needed
to do more tests.
She said it might be dangerous.
And you said you'd have my back,
and instead you're
trapping me here?
She has to reapply the
treatments every couple hours.
I'm just looking out
for you and the baby.
I mean, somebody has to.
HYMAN: Oh, shit. (CHUCKLES)
Sorry, I'll be quiet. Go on.
You can't eavesdrop
on people's shit like that.
But...
Yeah, Hyman, you
have a body now.
You really need to
understand boundaries.
So do you. Julia, wait.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
(HUMS MOCKINGLY)
I stumbled upon this place last time
when I was looking for the bathroom.
This is where he
keeps all of his
pocket worlds.
What the fuck? I swear, this
place was full of them last time.
Well, where the
shit did they go?
Oh.
The Chankly Bore. Aw.
I grew up playing Queen of
the Hump on hills just like this.
If it isn't the Ark,
I don't give a shit.
ELIOT: Okay. (CLAPS HANDS)
Ghost butler?
Uh, I don't think
it works like that.
You can't just summon him.
He's not our butler.
(CHUCKLES) Oh!
Hi.
Greetings. How may I assist you?
We're looking
for a pocket world.
The master of the
house is not available.
ALL: We know.
And so, all pocket worlds have
been removed for security purposes.
It's okay. Umber sent us to
get it. He told us it'd be here.
Which world did he
send you to retrieve?
It's called the Ark.
Very well.
(RUSTLING)
If Umber sent you on this task,
you should be able
to identify the true Ark.
But if you choose poorly...
Ooh. Uh, we age really fast
and then we all turn to dust
just like in The Last Crusade?
NIGEL: Indeed! This
security precaution
is inspired by my master's
love... BOTH: Mmm.
NIGEL: for Indiana Jones
and the Last Crusade.
For copyright purposes, the
consequences of an incorrect choice
has been changed to
something more explosive.
Choose... Wisely, yeah.
We get it.
All right, Fen. You're the
Fillory expert. Have at it.
Any day now.
You know what?
Figure it out yourself.
You need to let me do
the talking. This is sensitive.
How'd you fuck over Anna, huh?
She lose a limb or something?
Well, I definitely fucked her.
Wait, she's your... Anna!
ANNA: Marina.
I want nothing to do with
you. MARINA: Anna, please.
It's an emergency.
(SIGHS)
It wasn't just one lie.
It was how one led to
another and another,
and now I don't know
if any of it was real.
Did you know that she was
from a different timeline?
'Cause I didn't. And then
you tried to rob the Couple.
Our friend died because of you.
I know. I was a terrible person.
I was a greedy,
self-centered sociopath.
And when you left
me, I deserved it.
But I'm making amends now.
I've done a bunch
of things on your list.
I got the trance healing done.
But yet here you are,
asking for the Heist Book.
Uh... Wait, no,
that's just for us.
Or maybe this is
just another lie...
(VOICE QUAVERING) and you
aren't better, you aren't different at all.
Look, trust me,
she is very different.
I mean, she baked us cookies.
Really terrible cookies.
I don't trust you, okay?
You showed up with her.
Just give us the
book, and we'll go.
We'll never pull her into
our life of crime ever again.
Marina doesn't have
to be involved anymore.
But I do.
I'm sorry, I
literally can't lie.
This isn't simple,
like robbing a bank.
You can't do it without me.
And yes, I promised
I would help you.
At least you're honest.
I'm gonna take
the spell off Marina.
What?
The Healer would have
used a synaptic blocker.
Easy to remove, even
under weird circumstances.
You want to bring
back the bad Marina?
To get the book, we need her to tell Anna
that she's not gonna help with the heist.
We need her to lie.
You're the one who said
that we should be like Marina.
This time we need
the real Marina.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
(CLEARS THROAT) Yeah,
I think she needs a minute.
What are you doing?
Word As Bond spell.
It's a magically-binding
contract that guarantees
that you will get
the book for us.
And when you help us with
the heist, you won't fuck us over.
You don't need that.
I mean, with this
spell I'm under,
I couldn't betray you
even if I wanted to.
Better safe than sorry.
Julia? Are you here?
What are you doing?
Just stretching.
You're trying to put yourself
into stasis. The hell, man?
To be honest, I haven't really
enjoyed this episode of my life.
What is so great about
having a body, anyway?
You're hungry all the time.
Everything you
do makes you sore.
You're pooping constantly.
That hasn't been my experience,
but your body's been in a bench
for a century, man. Give it a minute.
And when dramatic things are happening
to your friends, you can't even watch.
This is about me and Julia?
You're pissed because
you can't listen in
on everyone's
personal conversations?
It's none of your business.
But it is! I put
you two together.
I shipped you before you
even shipped yourselves.
Before, I was a
part of everything.
And now, I am a, uh, minor
character in my own story. God.
(SIGHS)
Well, that's...
That's the trade-off.
You don't get to spy on
people's intimate moments.
You get to live your own.
And that's supposed
to be better?
If people wanted to talk to me,
you think I would have
done this in the first place?
So, the spying on
the showers was...
Loneliness.
And horniness.
You're never gonna make a
connection by hiding, Hyman.
You gotta put
yourself out there,
just be honest with people.
It may take a minute,
but you'll find someone
who can stand you.
Ah... Are you doing that thing
where you're giving me advice,
but it's just for you?
No, I'm trying to...
(WHISPERS) Oh, God damn it.
I gotta find Julia.
While I'm gone, promise me
you're not going to stasis yourself.
(SIGHS) Well...
Give me the locket.
Talk to somebody.
Have a conversation.
(DOOR OPENS)
(METAL CLATTERING)
(MUFFLED WHIMPERING)
(WHIMPERING CONTINUES)
Hello? Is someone there?
(MUFFLED SQUEALING)
Ah!
Miss Wicker.
I have been looking for you.
(PANTING)
Yes. It's come to this.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
Sir Effingham. What are
you doing with that trash can?
Some hapless fellow left a
sandwich of roast beef in there,
and as I could not
get to market today...
Oh! Oh, my heavens.
You have embraced
the blessing of your sex.
But surely you have
misplaced your wedding band?
You are widowed then?
No. Oh, you poor dear,
you are carrying a bastard.
Definitely talking to one.
Look, I thought you
chose Todd for this quest?
I fear he is not the intrepid
hero I once thought him to be.
You don't say.
Which is why, in my
gravest hour of need,
I have come to
vouchsafe you a quest.
Look, if this has
to do with Fillory...
For my vision of Fillory's
demise has grown clearer!
I now see those who would
bring the apocalypse to Fillory
have visited many times before.
They enter from a distant
realm through a tree.
Like, a portal tree? Indeed.
These fiends plan to thieve away
every soul in the land
before they destroy it outright.
Huh.
How exactly do they do that?
My vision is hazy.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
But I do know that they will
turn back the clock on Fillory,
resulting in ruin!
Um...
Do these fiends...
Do they succeed in stealing the
people and building a new world for them?
That much I do not know
because...(SNORTS)
Wait, I made no
mention of a new world.
It is you!
It's for Fillory's own good.
The dead will rise. This is the
only way that we can save everyone.
Oh, hogwash. What dark forces
have corrupted your fair mind?
You have.
We wouldn't be on this
quest if you hadn't told me
about it in the first place.
Are you now blaming
me for your own villainy?
Oh, the ways of the sow are
nastier than I thought possible.
But know this, the death of
Fillory cannot come without a cost.
What do you mean?
Those who would destroy
her will lose the ones they love.
Hmm.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
ELIOT: So, we're sorry
for treating you like the friend
who only gets invited to trivia night.
You know I don't
know what that means.
Yeah.
(SIGHS)
Will you please help
us choose a globe?
Margo is chomping at the bit
and Josh is holding her
off for as long as he can.
I thought I could
talk myself into this.
But I just keep thinking,
if this was Earth,
you would try a lot harder
to find some other way.
Yeah, probably.
So maybe it's my job
to represent Fillory.
But not just the
people, the place.
The history.
The things we
can't take with us.
You want my
permission to destroy it.
I can't give that to you.
Well, if you have any
other ideas, we are all ears.
Do you?
No.
Was that supposed to do that?
(CHUCKLES) Fillorians write down
their prayers to Umber and burn them.
This must be where they show up.
So they still pray to him,
even though he's dead?
I know what you're thinking.
It's just like the people of
Fillory to do something so stupid.
No. I was thinking
it's taken me a really
long time to figure out
that you can still love
something, even after it's gone.
Even if you helped kill it?
(SIGHS SOFTLY)
Okay, Fen, it's time for
a come-to-Umber talk.
You don't want to be a
sidekick? You want to have a say?
This is what that feels like.
I'm not asking for
your permission.
Some part of Fillory has to die,
and you're the one
who has to choose.
Is it going to be the
rocks and the dirt,
or is it gonna be the
people and the traditions
and all of the things that
you can take with you?
MARGO: I got it!
(SOFT EXPLOSION) Oh, no.
MARGO: Ah, shit. I don't got it!
JOSH: Aah!
(GASPS) Oh! Oh!
It didn't explode!
I... I did it!
I chose wisely! I'm wise!
All the people of Fillory are
going to fit into a seahorse?
Hmm?
How'd you know that was the one?
Because that's how Ember and
Umber first brought people to Fillory.
They chartered the great
seahorse to carry us in his pouch.
Oh.
FEN: What?
How'd people get to Earth?
Um...
(CHUCKLES AWKWARDLY)
Mmm-hmm. The same. The same.
And I promise I won't have anything
to do with robbing the Couple.
If you give the book to Kady
and Alice, I'll never see it again.
Watching evil Marina
pretend to be good is...
I feel like shit.
KADY: (SIGHS) Yeah,
I feel like shit, too.
Here.
I'm glad to be rid
of it. ALICE: Is that...
The Heist Book? I know
it doesn't look like much.
Thank you.
Are you guys...
We have a lot of
work to do, on us.
But we're going to
try. Now that I'm better.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
ALICE: Great. Okay. So,
I guess we're done here.
And, um, we won't
bother you anymore.
Yeah.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
PENNY: Hey.
I've been looking for you.
Saw the Pig Man again.
Turns out, you know that
apocalypse I've been trying to stop?
We cause it.
If the prophecy says
that Fillory is destroyed,
that means we
succeed, right? And...
Good news? JULIA: Yeah.
Good news.
Look, about earlier,
I need to tell you...
Look, I know. I
was irresponsible.
Look, I should just
accept the fact that
any control I had over
my life is now gone,
and I am a walking
incubator. Julia.
It's just terrifying, you know?
What if Lipson does the
tests and it's bad news?
You know, right now
everything is good.
And the thought of
losing any of that is just...
Julia, it's not the baby
I'm freaking out about.
Look, I told you about how my
dad left. But what I didn't tell you,
what I haven't told anyone is,
around that time, my mom
started having episodes.
Getting disoriented, hearing
shit that wasn't there. Um...
Doctors thought
it was the stress,
from my dad
bailing on us, but...
You think it's because of you.
What's happening to you
looks just like what
happened to my mom.
And the episodes didn't
stop when I was born.
They got worse.
When she burned
down our apartment
was the first time I got
thrown into foster care.
She'd fight to get me back,
and then she'd get sick again.
Eventually the state
took me in for good.
And I was scared,
but I was more scared of my mom.
I fucked her up for life.
I'm so sorry.
I don't want what happened
to her to happen to you.
Okay. I get it.
I'll do it.
The scans, the treatments.
But you have to know, it won't be
like what happened to your mom.
We know about magic.
We have ways to deal with it.
And I won't put you in a cage.
What the hell, man?
I tried to talk to him and
he punched me in the face!
PENNY: Who?
Oh. Mmm-mmm.
I warned you not to cross me.
How the hell'd you get out?
Let this be my last
lesson to you as Dean.
Don't make too many enemies.
They might find each other.
The Couple.
Oh, I can't let you take
that panel out of here.
This is some fate
of the world shit.
Not my world. Not my
problem. (DOOR OPENS)
Then I guess I'm your problem.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Dean Fogg? What's going on?
Huh. This just got
very, very interesting.
Are you stupid enough
to try and stop me?
(CHUCKLES QUIETLY)
What just happened?
The Couple just got
the last thing they need.
They have the Seed,
the page and the panel.
We gotta tell the others. They
need to steal that Seed now.