JULIA: Previously
on The Magicians...
Fuck!
I'm so sorry.
It's Reynard. He's back.
Wait, I am pregnant.
I wasn't the only one
he raped that night,
but I was the only
one who got pregnant.
SUN: This is exorcism.
You understand?
Did it work? Is it gone?
In the center of your being,
there's a tiny beating heart.
It's called a Shade.
It's what makes you feel
the pain will burn
you till there's nothing.
KADY: There was a complication.
Her Shade, it's gone.
I feel light.
Like a million-pound
weight's off my chest.
Say we get the perfect spell.
Think about the energy
it'd take to work it.
Dana's baby. His son.
You know, there is a
ton of lore on demigods.
They're powerful
in their own right.
We need to find him.
As for Loria...
Some 8,000 troops are
headed to the border.
So we're totally outnumbered.
And, of course, our
preparation is affected
by the continued
unsteadiness of the Wellspring.
Looks like... ELIOT:
A major drought's hit.
You can't even get out of
this shoddy little Magician.
Free yourself. Then find me.
Alice, we can talk about this...
ALICE: Just shut up! Shut up!
This is your body trying
to hold a Niffin inside it.
You can't.
Not for much longer,
or it's gonna kill us both.
(PANTING)
(GROANS) Seriously,
guys, I'm in a cage.
Don't you think this
is a tad redundant?
DEAN: Protocol. For werewolves.
Okay, technically, I have
sexually transmitted lycanthropy.
A very mild case.
Would've been cool to actually
fully wolf out, you know? (HOWLS)
Either way, it's
totally curable.
Treatable. There
is no actual cure.
Well, silver bullet.
Hey, don't go through my bag.
Quentin, you're dying.
Yeah, well, aren't we all?
You are dying quickly.
You cannot keep this thing
inside you much longer.
Well, I can't let her go.
Which is why you must box her.
I'm not doing that to Alice.
Quentin, there is no more Alice.
This is uncharted
territory. Nobody knows...
Well, I know that you
will be dead in days
if you don't rid
yourself of her.
May I help you steal from me?
Nope. I got it.
Good luck with all your shit.
(GROANS)
Damn brownouts.
(SIGHS)
We may be the least
trusted monarchs
in the history of Fillory.
Thank God they
don't have polls here.
(DRONING TONE)
That's the third
brownout this week.
(ABIGAIL SQUEAKING) If we don't
fix the Wellspring soon, Your Majesty...
One problem at a time, okay?
Our soldiers are
deserting us in protest,
thanks to Julia
committing tree genocide.
Pardon me, Your Majesty.
For the official records, may I
suggest a slightly less incendiary term.
Perhaps "arbicide"?
Sure, if you can also recommend
how we fight a war
without an army.
(ABIGAIL SQUEAKING)
Your Majesty, there is one
option, a rather obscure law based...
Less words.
One-on-one combat
between monarchs.
A duel? El...
With Ess' dad? He's
got to be at least 50.
And I'm pretty buff
from all the living
without technology
or decent wine.
Slow down.
Is there any rule
about not using magic?
No, Your Majesty.
Highness, if I may,
there is a reason we haven't
brought up this option before,
especially since magic is
not completely dependable.
Simply put, you're
likely to, well, die.
Mmm-hmm.
Tick, if I did this, how
popular would I be?
No king has ever volunteered
for one-on-one combat.
If you were to prevail,
you would easily be the
greatest leader in Fillorian history.
HELOISE: The
greatest. The greatest.
God. He's already
seeing the statues.
I hereby decree,
rulers done gonna rumble!
Eliot's the king of all this?
Yeah, looking for rock solid
proof there's no justice? That.
Even this dungeon's nicer
than any place I lived as a kid.
Well, except for my uncle's BMW.
Would've been even nicer if
he'd actually been my uncle.
Don't be fooled by the
high gloss. This place sucks.
(LOCK CLICKING)
Hey.
What's up?
We found Reynard's son.
So this is a break out.
Why are you in here
anyway? I killed trees.
Seriously? That could talk.
They have talking trees here?
Not anymore.
(SNORTS AND GIGGLES)
So what's Reynard's son like?
I guarantee you won't
believe it. Let's go.
(GROANS) The fuck...
He's marking his territory.
Hey. I refuse to be shamed.
Didn't you hear what Friar Joseph
said? Not all Niffins are the same.
I'm not gonna go on some killing
spree any more than he would.
Q? Don't you believe me?
I believe you believe you.
Sorry?
I'm not talking to you.
I just wanna do
what Joseph does.
Please. Beautiful,
high-level magic.
I am not letting you
loose. It's bad for the world.
And I'm not boxing you 'cause
I don't wanna know a world
without Alice.
Keep this up, and
you won't have to.
We'll both be dead. Good plan.
Eliot... (GIGGLES)
the intel I'm
getting on King Idri
and the protocols
of dueling, not good.
I mean, you ever even
touched a sword before today?
No, but Magician.
Well, sword-fighting spells,
of which there are only two anyone
knows of, take months to master.
Why? It's a giant butter knife.
(SIGHS)
It's all the variables in any
given match. It's almost infinite.
(SIGHS) I mean, sure,
you could slap together
a spell, maybe get
four, five good moves,
which brings us to thing two.
How many things are there?
Look, King Idri
has fought 14 duels,
all opponents dead.
NEWS ANCHOR: Senator Gaines' rise has been
described as nothing less than meteoric.
JULIA: Reynard's
son is John Gaines?
You know him?
I mean, I know who he is.
He's on rails to
the White House.
I hit one of his rallies,
did a psychic scan.
Dude believes
every word he says.
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
I believe that everyone is
born with a flame of goodness.
And if my light or
yours go out, remember,
we're not alone in this world.
(CHEERS AND APPLAUSE)
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
See? Wow.
He's the perfect demigod
spokesmodel of absolute evil.
Who's kind of hot
as shit. (LAUGHS)
What? Sorry.
Look, he's not even my
type, obviously. It's weird.
Dude has more
magic coming off him
than every Magician
on Earth combined
and knows not one
thing about magic.
Well, he's sure gonna.
How's the battle prep?
If someone had told me a year
ago that I'd be venting to my wife
while preparing to do battle on
behalf of my mythical kingdom,
I'd have done a lot more drugs.
I have something
that might help.
Great, depending on what
your definition of "help" is.
I know I haven't always
given you reason to trust me.
My grandpa forged this
sword for a High King
who vanished
without ever claiming it.
Since then, my
family's been saving it
for someone truly worthy.
It's beautiful, but I'm
not sure it actually helps.
I'll never learn
a spell in time.
It was made for a king, as
was the accompanying spell.
Some sword spells
take weeks to master.
Not when it's
written for a king.
My grandpa was the royal
family's favorite swordsmith
because he knew
they were, uh, too...
Too lazy to learn?
Too pre-occupied with
matters of state for busywork.
With this spell and this blade,
you will be a master swordsman.
(CHUCKLES) Insert weak
double entendre I'd have to explain.
Sorry?
(SIGHS)
"Praise Ember's strength
and Umber's wisdom.
"Bring unto me the lifeblood
knowledge of all masters of the blade
"who have come before."
Fen...
Fen, I actually feel
marginally less fucked now.
All my life, I've
put my family first.
Now that's you and our baby.
I'll really try
not to die again.
(LAUGHS)
I'd really appreciate that.
No, no, no. Stop.
Hold on. Hey, Becky?
Security? Security?
It's not working.
All right.
Whatever this is, stop.
Tell me what you want.
Man, you're good. Mmm-hmm.
Let's get to it.
Magic is real.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
(GRUNTS)
(CLATTERING)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
Okay.
Okay, is this some
kind of a gag?
Is this a publicity
stunt for a TV show?
We're Magicians being hunted
by an evil god, and so are you.
Listen, obviously, you guys
believe this, and I respect that.
Bullshit. No, it is not
bullshit. It is... Okay.
This'll take forever. It's
not like we need him alive.
Jesus! What the fuck, Julia?
We don't need him.
We need his energy. No.
You're born, huge energy.
You die, bigger energy.
Especially a demigod.
That is what we are after
here, people, the energy.
Right now, he's just a
skin sack hiding it from us.
Okay, you'd need
something to hold that energy.
Like this? (SCOFFS) Jesus.
Oh, my God. You
planned this all along.
All right, all of you, get the
fuck out of my office now.
I won't die here tonight.
I will not die here!
(PANTING)
(COUGHS) Oh, shit.
He's okay. He just fainted.
Hey! Whoa.
No. We are not... Not
killing a US Senator.
But we will commit a
felony almost as stupid.
MARGO: Okay, sloth,
you're the most honest
one on the damn council,
so I'm counting on you to
not kiss my ass or cover yours.
We've got a sword
spell, so yay us,
but we need the
Wellspring to work.
There can't be one brownout
or blip during the duel.
So straight up, how
do we guarantee that?
(SQUEAKING)
It's too... What?
Um... (SQUEAKING)
There is something, but
we urge you not to do it.
Tell me. Petition the Fairies.
Fairies?
Do I know about the Fairies?
They exist outside our realm.
They can be contacted,
and they have great powers.
Well, can they
fix the Wellspring?
(ABIGAIL SQUEAKING)
Almost certainly.
Guys, the fuck?
Uh, fairies are notoriously
mercurial?
Have you met your King?
They make complex deals
with steep prices and...
Yeah, get me a meeting.
One has to contact their
ambassador, a human,
which can sometimes take days,
even weeks. (ABIGAIL SQUEAKING)
Then chop, chop.
And never keep information
from me again, okay?
Yes, Your Highness.
You, sloth, you read me?
(SQUEAKING)
What? Nothing.
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
Is that that senator dude?
You think we kidnapped a US
senator and stuffed him in a closet?
No, Jesus, of course not. Okay.
How'd you get
him past the wards?
Hey, does one of you
have an alumni key?
So cool. Um, can I
borrow it sometime?
There's this really hot...
Vodka Gibson, four onions.
Yeah, right away.
So what do we do when he wakes
up and starts kicking the door?
Whatever it is has
nothing to do with you.
Stay away from him. Or?
No, you don't wanna go there.
(LAUGHS)
Pretty sure we're already there.
Enough.
I'll keep an eye on the Senator.
She's psychotic.
Look, she's being a
little extreme, yeah,
but she's got her reasons,
okay? Just trust me.
I know Julia.
That's not Julia.
Even she knows that.
The only person who doesn't
seem to know that is you!
(METALLIC CLANGING AND SCRAPING)
(GRUNTS)
Looks good.
What's wrong? Wrong?
Your face. I'm an
obsessive fan, so tell.
Thank you, Soren.
The sword's good. (SIGHS) The spell
makes me great. But great enough?
If I lose, forget me, all of
you are dead or imprisoned.
(SIGHS)
Why didn't I see
how huge this is?
I'm...
I'm scared, for all of us.
You know what
I'm thinking about?
That video you showed me of your
high school production of Les Mis.
You were such a great Valjean.
Ugh.
I was all right at the matinees.
Evenings, I'd agree, I
scaled the heights. Mmm.
But
what's your point?
Well, all this reading
we've been doing on war,
I keep coming across soldiers
who'd sing before going into battle.
To avoid throwing up with fear?
It built confidence, yes.
Projected power, destabilized
the enemy. So give me.
What? The big number.
(SCOFFS)
I can't.
I'll never remember
all the lyrics.
It's practically
the entire cast.
Which is why...
Magic.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
No, I should practice.
So move your ass and sing. Beyoncé
does, which is why she's a boss.
Mmm-mmm.
Don't make me sing.
(SINGING) One day more
Another day, another destiny
This never-ending
road to Calvary
These men who
seem to know my crime
Will surely come a second time
One day more...
I did not live until today
How can I live
when we are parted?
One day more
Tomorrow you'll be worlds away
And yet with you,
my world has started
One more day all on my own
BOTH: Will we ever meet again?
One more day with him not caring
BOTH: I was born to be with you
What a life I might have known
BOTH: And I swear I will be true
But he never saw me there
One more day before the storm
Do I follow where she goes?
At the barricades of freedom
Shall I join my brothers there?
When our ranks begin to form
Do I stay and do I dare?
Will you take your
place with me?
ALL: The time is
now, the day is here
One day more
Sorry, I had to
skip some verses.
They're great, but they don't
really apply to our situation.
Oh.
Okay. Got you.
One day to a new beginning
Raise the flag of freedom high
Every man will be a king
There's a new
world for the winning
There's a new world to be won
Do you hear the people sing?
My place is here
I fight with you
One day more
I did not live until today
How can I live
when we are parted?
One day more
Tomorrow you'll be worlds away
And yet with you
my world has started
Tomorrow we'll be far away
Tomorrow is the judgment day
ALL: Tomorrow we'll discover
What our god in
heaven has in store
One more dawn
One more day
One day more
(MUSIC ENDS)
(PANTING)
I'm confused. Is
the duel not today?
It's a metaphor.
I love that show.
You know it?
Boarding school on
Earth. I played Javert.
Type-casting.
"Praise Ember's strength
and Umber's wisdom.
"Bring unto me the lifeblood
knowledge of all masters of the blade."
(INHALES DEEPLY)
King Idri.
King Eliot.
I'm sorry I have to kill you.
I've died before.
Doesn't seem to take
with me. Shall we?
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(SWORDS CLANGING)
(GRUNTS) Ah!
(GROWLING)
Okay, is he allowed to do that?
Kings do whatever.
Fine, he bitched out. It's over.
It's over when
one ruler is dead.
Another favorite show
of mine, Into the Woods.
I cannot believe how
fucking boring this is.
You know I can see magic?
Not the kind that you can do
with your hands, stone-age bullshit.
I can see pure magic in
1,000 dimensions all at once.
You're not Quentin.
Get me out of here.
Alice. Quentin always
said you were smart.
He said the same about you.
Well, then, between
the two of us,
we should be able to
figure something out.
I'm not sure that's
what Q would want.
What do you want, Julia?
What are you thinking?
(WHISPERS) Oh,
I can almost see it.
Just like I can see that
your Shade is gone,
which is how I know that your
thoughts are pure, unencumbered.
I'm right, aren't I?
We both know life is not cloudy
with regret, need, sadness.
We both know life is
crystalline. Clear, cold, sharp.
You...
He's bleeding.
God, he's so weak.
REYNARD: John, I'm here.
I know you have questions. I have
all the answers you could ever want.
I'm Reynard. Help!
REYNARD: Your
place is with me. Help!
(SHOUTING AND GROANING)
Who the fuck is Reynard,
and why is he in my head?
(SENATOR GAINES PANTING)
(SIGHS)
There's nothing we can do.
It's up to him. (DEAN SIGHS)
Jesus, he's stubborn. SENATOR
GAINES: What's happening?
What is happening? Will
you get him out of my head?
Make it stop! What now?
It's so much worse
than you think.
Put him here. Is
that Senator Gaines?
Probably, I mean, why not?
Can you do something to
ward his mind from the voice?
What voice? Reynard's.
He's after his son.
Where? Outside
the wards, I guess.
Okay, whatever
you're thinking, don't.
I'm not the one you
should worry about.
(GRUNTS) (SWORDS CLANG)
You are out of your
element, Child of Earth.
(BOTH GRUNT) (SWORD WHOOSHES)
Well done. (PANTING) Well done.
(WHISPERS) Yes!
I'd give you an update,
but I hate seeing boys cry.
DEAN: He won't be
able to get in here.
Not after the security protocols
we put in place after The Beast.
As long as they
hold, we're safe.
You're probably right.
I hope you're right, but we are
talking about a not-so-benevolent god
after his only child.
Listen, I'm sorry for getting
so hysterical back there.
I'm having a lot
of trouble with this.
It's okay.
How did you get
his voice to stop?
(GROANS) What the hell
is this thing on my neck?
It's a patch. It blocks
psychic interference. It works.
Trust me. I have to be honest.
I hope I'm in a mental ward.
Majesty, you must
return to Whitespire.
Are you insane?
He will not wait. Who?
The Ambassador to the Fairies.
I'm afraid this has
to end. (GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
Don't prolong it.
Monarch to monarch,
when I kill you, I'll be merciful.
That's kind of you.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
(WHOOSH)
(GROANS)
Oh, shit.
The Wellspring. Shit.
"Praise Ember's strength
and Umber's wisdom.
"Bring unto me the
lifeblood knowledge of all..."
(EXHALES)
All right, come on.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(ALARM BLARING)
Blackout. The wards are down.
Everyone, get to the lab. Now!
(ALARM BLARING)
Let's go. DEAN: Run!
(GROANS)
(REYNARD LAUGHS)
DEAN: Move, people. Quickly!
PENNY: Inside! Let's go.
Come on. This ain't a pop quiz.
Let's go. You don't wanna be out there.
Let's go. Come on.
How long can the emergency
generator in here keep the lab warded?
Hopefully, long enough
until we think of something.
(GRUNTS)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
Of course, those I represent
would always consider
with the utmost respect any
royal request, Your Majesty.
When can we meet face-to-face?
When you conclude
the bargain, with me.
No.
I wanna know who I'm
sealing the deal with.
Not possible, Majesty.
The ways of the Fairies are...
Well, how should I put it?
As implacable as
they are ancient.
In any case, I would imagine
time is of the essence, no?
The Fairies can bring
back the Wellspring?
They can.
And in return?
A royal child of Whitespire.
The Fairies want a baby?
They aren't gonna
eat it, are they?
It'll be raised as a Fairy.
It will know great knowledge
and even greater power.
Well,
I'm not loving this, but I
could get knocked up...
AMBASSADOR: No.
The child that grows in the
womb of the High King's wife.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Highness, a word?
You've offended the Ambassador.
(SCOFFS)
He will no longer
bargain with you. What?
Because you questioned him,
he will only honor the present deal
without further amendment,
or there will be no deal at all.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
SENATOR GAINES: I do not
have powers. That is impossible.
It's impossible you
don't. Look at your career.
Hey. I work hard.
Have you ever failed at
anything, ever? Just be honest.
(SCOFFS)
I've had losses. My parents...
Yeah, died and left
you, what, $20 million?
So what are you saying exactly?
Are you saying I used some kind of
magic spell to kill my parents for money?
No, no.
Look, what you have is bigger
than what any Magician can do.
You used your powers, even
without knowing it, to create you.
And the world was made to
worship and follow you anywhere.
So if my birth father is a
god, and I'm a demigod,
why the hell did
it take me a year
to pass the most boring farm
bill in the history of the Senate?
But it got passed, right?
Well, has any bill you
ever sponsored failed?
Come on. Has it?
Holy shit.
(PANTING)
Hi.
You can't stay up there forever.
(GRUNTS)
Fen, Eliot's going to
lose, if he hasn't already.
Without magic he's
basically unarmed,
and the Wellspring's gone black.
You have to do something.
I think I can,
but I need you to promise me
that if magic is returned,
Eliot lives, and there's no war,
that you will do
exactly what I tell you.
Of course. Whatever it is.
Yes. Please. Don't let him die.
You are most skillful.
I'm a manipulative cunt.
Fix the Wellspring. Now.
(IDRI GRUNTING AND PANTING)
No rush.
I'll win eventually.
I wish your magic
hadn't gone out.
I like my fights fair.
You do realize, if this
is a legit magic blackout,
it fucks both Fillory
and Loria, right?
My people are so
used to scarcity,
I don't even
think it'll register.
Sometimes, I think they
like being dissatisfied.
Ugh. Preach.
If you do kill me, I
guess you'll spare me
decades of trying to fix a kingdom
hell-bent on staying broken,
doomed to sexual frustration...
But you have a wife. Exactly.
Oh. And I'm going
to be a father,
if that changes your mind
about the whole killing-me thing.
Wish I had a choice.
But one of us has to die,
and I'm not the one up a tree.
Worth a shot.
At least you don't have
to worry about getting old.
Excuse me. I would
age like a fine wine.
And you are a total DILF.
Should I be offended?
Let's just say it's
too bad I have a wife.
I get it.
My love for my late wife kept
me from selecting a husband, too.
Um...
Wait. (LAUGHS) What?
It is a shame I
have to kill you.
I actually find
you very attractive.
God damn it.
(SWORD WHOOSHING
AND CLANGING) God damn it!
Where's Quentin? What?
Shit.
Julia's not here, either. What?
I don't understand. You have
a new weapon to kill Reynard?
No, you do. (GROANS) I do, what?
You have a nuclear
bomb inside of you.
Wait. Alice? JULIA:
I talked to her.
She's a killing
machine right now.
Tell her you wanna make a deal.
She kills Reynard, she's free.
No. (GRUNTS)
(GASPS) Do it, or we all
die right here, right now, Q.
(CHUCKLES) (GASPING)
It's not like you to hide behind
wards, Julia. Come face me.
Face him first.
(CHUCKLES) Mmm.
You know, even with
that thing inside of him,
he's nowhere near
as interesting as you.
(REYNARD SNIFFS DEEPLY)
But I'll make do. (GASPS)
Let me out. I'll kill him! No.
Julia.
Get back inside the ward!
Quentin, come on! Come on!
Let me out!
Picked up this little trick your
six-fingered friend pulled on me.
(CHUCKLES) (GASPS)
You waited too long.
You know what's funny, Julia?
You work so hard to
hide from me magically,
yet you get caught
by a simple security
camera, kidnapping a Senator.
It's all over the news. (LAUGHS)
It's grainy, but I'd
recognize you anywhere.
So nice to meet
more of your friends.
I think this is gonna
be a lot of fun.
We have to stop him.
My son.
Whatever you are,
if I am what you say,
don't hurt these people.
Hurt them? No, never.
I froze them so they
wouldn't hurt themselves
or you.
Come. Come closer.
(WHOOSH)
(GASPS)
Damn it!
(SHIMMERING TONE)
(WATER RUSHING)
(IDRI GRUNTING)
"Praise Ember's strength
and Umber's wisdom."
(GRUNTING)
So, magic's back.
The fuck...
(LATCH CLICKS)
(DOOR RATTLING)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(WHISPERS) Shit!
What the fuck?
It's called the Clean
Room. No magic.
Did you put a sleeping
spell on me? Open this door!
I've been trying
to understand you.
At least that's what I thought.
What I've really been doing is
trying to make excuses for you.
But I can't anymore, not after
what you did to Quentin today.
But he's fine, right?
That's just luck,
and you know it.
You fed him to Reynard.
He knew how to survive.
Yeah, by doing what you want!
That's all you see
anymore, is what you want.
You don't feel anymore, Julia,
not the way a human does.
It's not your fault.
I hope we can
figure something out.
But, until then,
this is it for you.
Kady...
Citizens. Your
Warrior King returns.
FEN: Praise Ember!
You scared me, you dick!
Good to see you, too, Bambi.
Eliot, are you
okay? Are you hurt?
All in one piece, thanks
to that sword spell of yours.
I'm just glad you're
safe. We both are.
I can't believe
you actually won!
Is it really that shocking?
Having seen how you
fight without magic, yes.
Hold up. What's King
Daddy Fuckface doing here?
Ah, King Idri is
our honored guest.
What happened to the
whole "one must die" deal?
IDRI: We're kings.
What's the point of having
great power if not to right wrongs?
We made an agreement.
We're getting
married. Wait. What?
Uh, hello?
Pregnant wifey,
your dick no workey?
Before I flay whoever
neglected to inform me sooner,
apparently, all monarchs on
this glorious, magical planet
are entitled to one of
each, a wife and a husband.
So, what, you're all just
gonna shack up together?
We're all just one big
royal polyamorous family.
Isn't it great? No one has to die.
Everyone gets what they want.
El, can we take a second?
(ELIOT SIGHS)
What?
So you fucked his son, it
doesn't have to be weird.
You sure this is a good idea?
I mean, you're
really doubling up
on Fillorian marriage contracts.
Sometimes, you have
to sacrifice for diplomacy.
And just wait until we're
husband and husband.
And what some would
call pillow talk, we call...
Espionage?
"Diplomatic leverage."
Your Highness! Thank
Ember for your safe return.
More good news, the Wellspring
is finally replenishing itself.
(SIGHS) Good old Tick.
Well, everything's
coming up Eliot.
Congrats, future hubby,
your half is now shit-free.
I'm sorry. His what?
IDRI: That was the deal.
Marriage, peace, and
a 50-50 Wellspring split.
So how'd we finally
fix the Wellspring?
Well...
(INSECTS CROAKING)
(BIRD TRILLING)
I am so sorry.
I just can't do this anymore.
Alice,
I hope you meant it.
I hope you just go
and do beautiful magic.
Alice,
Quentin says go free.
(WHOOSHING)
(GASPING)
(GIGGLES)