Previously on "The Magicians"...
- Fuck!
- I'm so sorry.
It's Reynard. He's back.
Wait, I am pregnant.
I wasn't the only one
he raped that night,
but I was the only one who got pregnant.
This is exorcism, you understand?
Did it work? Is it gone?
In the center of your being,
there's a tiny beating heart.
It's called a shade.
It's what makes you feel.
The pain will burn you
till there's nothing.
There was a complication.
Her shade, it's gone.
I feel light,
like a million pound weight's
off my chest.
Say we get the perfect spell,
think about the energy
it'd take to work it.
Dana's baby... his son.
You know, there is
a ton of lore on demigods.
They're powerful in their own right.
We need to find him.
As for Loria...
Some 8,000 troops
are headed to the border.
So we're totally outnumbered.
And of course,
our preparation is affected
by the continued unsteadiness
of the Wellspring.
- Looks like...
- A major drought's hit.
You can't even get out
of this shoddy little magician.
Free yourself, then find me.
- Alice, we can talk about this.
- Just shut up! Shut up!
This is your body trying
to hold a niffin inside it.
You can't... not for much longer,
or it's gonna kill us both.
Seriously, you guys, I'm in a cage.
You think this is, uh, a tad redundant?
- Protocol.
- For werewolves.
Okay, technically, I have
sexually transmitted
lycanthropy... a very mild case.
Would've been cool
to actually fully wolf out.
You know...
Either way, it's totally curable.
Treatable. There is no actual cure.
Well, silver bullet.
Hey, don't go through my bag.
Quentin, you're dying.
Yeah, well, aren't we all?
You are dying quickly.
You cannot keep this thing
inside you much longer.
Well, I can't let her go.
Which is why you must box her.
I'm not doing that to Alice.
Quentin, there is no more Alice.
This is uncharted territory.
Nobody knows.
Well, I know that
you will be dead in days
if you don't rid yourself of her.
May I help you steal from me?
Nope, I got it.
Good luck with all your shit.
These damn brownouts.
We may be the least trusted monarchs
in the history of Fillory.
Thank God they don't have polls here.
That's the third brownout this week.
If we don't fix the Wellspring
soon, Your Majesty...
One problem at a time, okay?
Our soldiers are
deserting us in protest,
thanks to Julia
committing tree genocide.
Pardon me, Your Majesty.
For the official records, may I suggest
a slightly less incendiary term?
Perhaps "arbicide"?
Sure, if you can also recommend
how we fight a war without an army.
Your Majesty, there is one option...
- a rather obscure law, based...
- Less words.
One-on-one combat.
Between monarchs.
- A duel?
- El...
With Ess's dad?
He's gotta be at least 50.
And I'm pretty buff from all the living
without technology or decent wine.
Slow down.
Is there any rule about not using magic?
- No, Your Majesty.
- Highness, if I may,
there is a reason
we haven't brought up this, uh,
option before,
especially since magic
is not completely dependable.
Simply put, you're likely to...
well... die.
Mm-hmm. Tick, if I did this,
how popular would I be?
No king has ever volunteered
for one-on-one combat.
If you were to prevail,
you would easily be
the greatest leader
in Fillorian history.
- The greatest.
God,
he's already seeing the statues.
I hereby decree...
rulers done gonna rumble.
Eliot's the king of all this?
Yeah, looking for rock-solid
proof there's no justice, that.
Even this dungeon's nicer than
any place I lived as a kid...
oh, except for my uncle's BMW.
Would've been even nicer
if he'd actually been my uncle.
Don't be fooled by the high gloss.
This place sucks.
- Hey.
- What's up?
We found Reynard's son.
So this is a breakout.
- Why are you in here anyway?
- I killed trees.
- Seriously.
- That could talk.
They have talking trees here?
Not anymore.
So what's Reynard's son like?
I guarantee you won't believe it.
Let's go.
What the fuck?
He's marking his territory.
Hey, I refuse to be shamed.
Didn't you hear what Friar Joseph said?
Not all niffins are the same.
I'm not gonna go on some killing spree
anymore than he would.
Q... don't you believe me?
I believe you believe you.
Sorry?
I'm not talking to you.
I just want to do what Joseph does.
Please. Beautiful, high-level magic.
I'm not letting you loose.
It's bad for the world.
I'm not boxing you.
I don't want to know
a world without Alice.
Keep this up, and you won't have to.
We'll both be dead.
Good plan.
Eliot...
The intel I'm getting on King Idri
and the protocols of dueling...
not good.
I mean, you ever even touched
a sword before today?
No, but... Magician.
Well, sword fighting spells,
of which there are only two
anyone knows of,
take months to master.
Why? It's a giant butter knife.
It's all the variables
in any given match.
It's almost infinite.
I mean, sure, you could
slap together spell,
maybe get four or five good moves.
- Which brings us to thing two.
- How many things are there?
Look, King Idri has fought 14 duels.
All opponents dead.
Senator Gaines' rise has been described
as nothing less than meteoric.
Reynard's son is John Gaines?
- You know him?
- I mean, I know who he is.
He's on rails to the White House.
I hit one of his rallies,
did a psychic scan.
Dude believes every word he says.
I believe that everyone is
born with a flame of goodness,
and if my light or yours go out,
remember, we're not alone in this world.
- See?
- Wow.
He's the perfect demigod
spokesmodel of absolute evil.
Who's kinda hot as shit.
- What?
- Sorry.
Look, he's not even my type,
obviously; it's... it's weird.
Dude has more magic coming off him
than every Magician on Earth combined
and knows not one thing about magic.
Well, he's sure gonna.
How's the battle prep?
If someone had told me a year ago
that I'd be venting to my wife,
while preparing to do battle on
behalf of my mythical kingdom...
I'd have done a lot more drugs.
I have something that might help.
Great, depending on
what your definition of help is.
I know I haven't always
given you reason to trust me.
My grandpa forged this sword
for a High King
who vanished without ever claiming it.
Since then, my family's been saving it
for someone truly worthy.
It's beautiful, but
I'm not sure it actually helps.
I'll never learn a spell in time.
It was made for a king,
as was the accompanying spell.
And sword spells take weeks to master.
Not when it's written for a king.
My grandpa was the royal
family's favorite sword smith
because he knew they were, uh, too...
- Too lazy to learn?
- Too... preoccupied
with matters of state for busywork.
With this spell and this blade,
you will be a master swordsman.
Insert weak double entendre
I'd have to explain.
Sorry?
"Praise Ember's strength
"and Umber's wisdom.
"Bring unto me the lifeblood knowledge
of all masters of the blade
who have come before."
Fen...
Fen, I actually feel
marginally less fucked now.
All my life, I've put my family first.
Now that's you and our baby.
I'll really try not to die again.
I'd really appreciate that.
No, no, no, stop...
hold on... hey, Becky.
Security?
- Security?
- It's not working.
All right.
Whatever this is, stop.
Tell me what you want.
- Man, you're good.
- Mm-hmm.
Let's get to it.
Magic is real.
Whoa, whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa, hey.
Okay.
Okay, is this some kind of a gag?
Is this a publicity stunt for a TV show?
We're Magicians
being hunted by an evil God,
and so are you.
Listen, obviously you guys believe this,
- and... and I respect that.
- Bullshit.
No, it is not bullshit. It is... okay.
This'll take forever. It's not like
- we need him alive anyway.
- Jesus, what the fuck, Julia?
We don't need him. We need his energy.
- No.
- You're born, huge energy;
you die, bigger energy,
especially a demigod.
That is what we are
after here, people, the energy.
Right now, he's just a skin sack
hiding it from us.
Okay, you need something
to hold that energy.
- Like this?
- Jesus.
- Oh, my God.
- You planned this all along.
All right, all of you,
get the fuck out of my office now!
I won't die here tonight.
I will not die here!
Oh, shit.
He's okay.
He just fainted.
- Hey!
- Whoa! No.
We are not, not, killing a U.S. senator.
But we will commit a felony
almost as stupid.
Ok sloth,
you're the most honest one
on the damn council,
so I'm counting on you to not
kiss my ass or cover yours.
We've got a sword spell, so yay us.
But we need the Wellspring to work.
There can't be one brownout
or blip during the duel.
So straight-up,
how do we guarantee that?
- It's too...
- What?
Um...
There is something,
but we urge you not to do it.
- Tell me.
- Petition the fairies?
Fairies?
Do I know about the fairies?
They exist outside our realm.
They can be contacted,
and they have great powers.
Well, can they fix the Wellspring?
Almost certainly.
Guys? The fuck?
Uh, fairies are notoriously...
- mercurial?
- Have ya met your king?
They make complex deals
with steep prices and...
Yeah, get me a meeting.
One has to contact their ambassador,
a human, which can sometimes
take days, even weeks.
Well, then chop-chop.
And never keep information
from me again, okay?
Yes, Your Highness.
You, Sloth, you read me?
- What?
- Nothing.
Is that that senator dude?
You think we kidnapped a U.S. senator
and stuffed him in a closet?
No. Jesus, of course not.
Okay.
How'd you get him past the wards?
Hey, does one of you have an alumni key?
So cool. Um, can I borrow it sometime?
There's this really hot...
I'd love to sneak her...
Ah, vodka Gibson, four onions.
Yeah, right away.
So what do we do when he wakes
up and starts kicking the door?
Whatever it is has
nothing to do with you.
Stay away from him.
Or?
No, you don't want to go there.
Pretty sure we're already there.
Enough.
I'll keep an eye on the senator.
- She's psychotic.
- Look, she's being
a little... extreme, yeah,
but she's got her reasons, okay?
Just trust me.
- I know Julia.
- That's not Julia.
Even she knows that.
The only person who doesn't seem
to know that is you.
Looks good.
- What's wrong?
- Wrong?
Your face...
I'm an obsessive fan, so tell.
Thank you, Soren.
The sword's good.
The spell makes me great,
but great enough?
If I lose, forget me.
All of you are dead or imprisoned.
Why didn't I see how huge this is?
I'm...
I'm scared...
for all of us.
You know what I'm thinking about?
That video you showed me
of your high school
production of "Les Mis."
You were such a great Valjean.
Ugh.
I was all right at the matinees.
Evenings I'd agree.
- I scaled the heights.
- Mm.
But...
what's your point?
Well, all this reading
we've been doing on war,
I keep coming across soldiers who'd sing
before going into battle.
To avoid throwing up with fear?
It built confidence, yes,
projected power, destabilized the enemy.
So give me.
What?
The big number.
I can't.
I'll never remember all the lyrics.
It's practically the entire cast.
Which is why...
Magic.
No, I should practice.
So move your ass and sing.
Beyoncé does, which is why she's a boss.
Mm-mm. Don't make me sing.
♪ One day more ♪
♪ Another day, another destiny ♪
♪ This never-ending road to Calvary ♪
♪ These men who seem to know my crime ♪
♪ Will surely come a second time ♪
♪ One day more ♪
♪ I did not live until today ♪
♪ How can I live when we are parted? ♪
♪ One day more ♪
♪ Tomorrow you'll be worlds away ♪
♪ And yet with you,
my world has started ♪
♪ One more day all on my own ♪
♪ Will we ever meet again? ♪
♪ One more day with him not caring ♪
♪ I was born to be with you ♪
♪ What a life I might have known ♪
♪ And I swear I will be true ♪
♪ But he never saw me there ♪
♪ One more day before the storm ♪
♪ Do I follow where she goes? ♪
♪ At the barricades of freedom ♪
♪ Shall I join my brothers there?
♪ When our ranks begin to form ♪
♪ Do I stay and do I dare? ♪
♪ Will you take your place with me? ♪
♪ The time is now ♪
♪ The day is here ♪
♪ One day more ♪
Sorry, I had to skip some verses.
They're great,
but they don't really apply
to our situation.
Oh, okay.
Gotcha.
♪ One day to a new beginning ♪
♪ Raise the flag of freedom high ♪
♪ Every man will be a king ♪
♪ There's a new world for the winning ♪
♪ There's a new world to be won ♪
♪ Do you hear the people sing? ♪
♪ My place is here ♪
♪ I fight with you ♪
♪ One day more ♪
♪ I did not live until today ♪
♪ How can I live when we are parted? ♪
♪ One day more ♪
♪ Tomorrow you'll be worlds away ♪
♪ And yet with you,
my world has started ♪
♪ Tomorrow we'll be far away ♪
♪ Tomorrow is the judgment day ♪
♪ Tomorrow we'll discover ♪
♪ What our God in heaven has in store ♪
♪ One more dawn ♪
♪ One more day ♪
♪ One day more... ♪
I'm confused.
- Is the duel not today?
- It's a metaphor.
- I love that show.
- You know it?
Boarding school on Earth.
I played Javert.
Typecasting.
Praise Ember's strength
and Umber's wisdom.
Bring unto me the lifeblood knowledge
of all masters of the blade.
King Idri...
King Eliot...
I'm sorry I have to kill you.
I've died before.
Doesn't seem to take with me.
Shall we?
Ah!
Okay, is he allowed to do that?
Kings do whatever.
Fine, he bitched out. It's over.
It's over when one ruler is dead.
Another favorite show of mine...
"Into the Woods."
I cannot believe how
fucking boring this is.
You know I can see magic?
Not the kind that
you can do with your hands...
that Stone Age bullshit.
I can see pure magic
in a thousand dimensions all at once.
You're not Quentin.
Get me out of here.
Alice.
Quentin always said you were smart.
He said the same about you.
Well, then, between the two of us,
we should be able
to figure something out.
I'm not sure that's what Q would want.
What do you want, Julia?
What are you thinking?
Oh, I can almost see it...
just like I can see
that your shade is gone,
which is how I know that your...
thoughts are pure, unencumbered.
I'm right, aren't I?
We both no life
is not clouded with regret,
need, sadness.
We both know life is
crystalline, clear, cold, sharp.
You...
he's bleeding.
God, he's so weak.
John, I'm here.
I know you have questions.
I have all the answers
you could ever want.
I'm Reynard.
Your place is with me.
Who the fuck is Reynard,
and why is he in my head?
There's nothing we can do.
It's up to him.
- Jesus, he's stubborn.
- What is happening?
What is happening?
Will you get him out of my head?
- Make it stop.
- What now?
This is so much worse than you think.
- Is that Senator Gaines?
- Probably.
I mean, why not?
Can you do something
to ward his mind from the voice?
- What voice?
- Reynard's.
- He's after his son.
- Where?
Outside the wards, I guess.
Okay, whatever you're thinking, don't.
I'm not the one you should worry about.
You are out of your element,
child of Earth.
Well done.
Yes.
I'd give you an update,
but I hate seeing boys cry.
He won't be able to get in here,
not after the security protocols
we put in place after The Beast.
As long as they hold, we're safe.
You're probably right.
I hope you're right,
but we are talking about
a not-so-benevolent god...
- Mm.
- After his only child.
Listen, I'm sorry for getting
so hysterical back there.
I'm having a lot of trouble with this.
It's okay.
How did you get his voice to stop?
What the hell is this thing on my neck?
It's a patch.
It blocks psychic interference.
It works, trust me.
I have to be honest.
I hope I'm in a mental ward.
Majesty, you must return to Whitespire.
- Are you insane?
- He will not wait.
- Who?
- The ambassador to the fairies.
I'm afraid this has to end!
Don't prolong it.
Monarch to monarch,
when I kill you, I'll be merciful.
That's kind of you.
Oh, shit.
- The Wellspring.
- Shit.
Praise Ember's strength
and Umber's wisdom.
Bring unto me the lifeblood knowledge
of all...
All right, come on.
Blackout. The wards are down.
Everyone get to the lab. Now!
- Let's go.
- Run!
What's happening?
- Move, people! Quickly!
- Inside! Lets go!
Come on, this aint a pop quiz, let's go,
you don't want to be out there,
let's go, come on!
How long can the emergency generator
in here keep the lab working?
Hopefully long enough till
we think of something.
Of course those I represent
would always consider
with the utmost respect
any royal request, Your Majesty.
When can we meet face-to-face?
When you conclude the bargain with me.
No.
I wanna know
who I'm sealing the deal with.
Not possible, Majesty.
The ways of the fairies are...
well, how should I put it...
as implacable as they are ancient.
In any case, I would imagine
time is of the essence, no?
The fairies can bring back
the Wellspring?
They can.
And in return?
A royal child of Whitespire.
The fairies want a baby?
They aren't gonna eat it, are they?
It'll be raised as a fairy.
It'll know great knowledge,
and even greater power.
Well... I'm not loving this,
- but I could get knocked up...
- No.
The child that grows in the womb
of the High King's wife.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Highness? A word?
You've offended the ambassador.
He will no longer bargain with you.
- What?
- Because you question him,
he will only honor the present deal
without further amendment,
or there will be no deal at all.
I do not have powers.
That is impossible.
It's impossible you don't.
- Look at your career.
- Hey, I work hard.
Have you ever failed at anything ever?
Just be honest.
I've had losses.
- My parents...
- Yeah, died,
and left you, what, $20 million?
So what are you saying exactly?
Are you saying I used
some kind of magic spell
- to kill my parents for money?
- No. No.
Look, what you have,
it is bigger than...
than... than what any Magician can do.
You know, you used your powers
even without knowing it to create you.
And the world was made to
worship and follow you anywhere.
So if my birth father's a god
and I'm a demigod,
why the hell did it take me
a year to pass
the most boring farm bill
in the history of the Senate?
But it got passed, right?
Come on, has any bill
you ever sponsored failed?
- Come on.
- Has it?
Holy shit.
Hi.
You can't stay up there forever.
Fen, Eliot's going to lose,
if he hasn't already.
Without magic, he's basically unarmed.
And the Wellspring's gone black.
You have to do something.
I think I can,
but I need you to promise me
that if magic is returned,
Eliot lives and there's no war...
that you will do
exactly what I tell you.
- Of course.
- Whatever it is.
Yes. Please. Don't let him die.
You are most skillful.
I'm a manipulative cunt.
Fix the Wellspring, now.
No rush.
I'll win eventually.
I wish your magic hadn't gone out.
I like my fights fair.
You do realize if this
is a legit magic blackout,
it fucks both Fillory and Loria, right?
My people are so used to scarcity,
I don't even think it'll register.
Sometimes, I think they like
being dissatisfied.
Preach.
If you do kill me,
I guess you'll spare me decades
of trying to fix a kingdom
hell-bent on staying broken,
doomed to sexual frustration.
- But you have a wife.
- Exactly.
Oh, and I'm going to be a father,
if that changes your mind about
the whole killing me thing.
Wish I had a choice,
but one of us has to die,
and I'm not the one up a tree.
Worth a shot.
At least you don't have
to worry about getting old.
Excuse me.
I would age like a fine wine.
And you are a total DILF.
Should I be offended?
Let's just say
it's too bad I have a wife.
I get it. My love for my late wife
kept me from selecting a husband too.
Um, wait.
What?
It is a shame I have to kill you.
I actually find you very attractive.
God damn it.
God damn it!
- Where's Quentin?
- What?
Shit. Julia's not here either.
What?
I don't understand.
You have a new weapon
- to kill Reynard?
- No, you do.
I do what?
You have a nuclear bomb inside of you.
- Wait, Alice?
- I talked to her.
She's a killing machine right now.
Tell her you wanna make a deal.
She kills Reynard, she's free.
No.
Do it, or we all die
right here, right now, Q.
It's not like you to
hide behind wards, Julia.
- Come face me.
- Face him first.
Mmm.
Even with that... thing inside of him,
he's nowhere near as interesting as you.
But I'll make due.
- Let me out, I'll kill him.
- No.
Julia.
- Get back inside the ward!
- Come on!
- Let me out!
Picked up this little trick
your six-fingered friend pulled on me.
- You waited too long.
- You know what's funny, Julia?
You work so hard
to hide from me magically,
yet you get caught
by a simple security camera
kidnapping a senator.
It's all over the news.
It's grainy, but I'd
recognize you anywhere.
So nice to meet more of your friends.
I think this is gonna be a lot of fun.
We have to stop him.
My son.
Whatever you are,
if I am what you say,
don't hurt these people.
Hurt them? No. Never.
I froze them so they wouldn't
hurt themselves...
or you.
Come. Come closer.
Damn it!
Praise Ember's strength
and Umber's wisdom.
So...
magic's back.
Shit.
What the fuck?
It's called The Clean Room.
No magic.
Did you put a sleeping spell on me?
Open this door!
I've been trying to understand you.
At least that's what I thought.
What I've really been doing
is trying to make excuses for you.
But I can't anymore,
not after what you did to Quentin today.
But he's fine, right?
That's just luck, and you know it.
You fed him to Reynard.
- He knew how to survive.
- Yeah, by doing what you want.
That's all you see anymore,
is what you want.
You don't feel anymore, Julia,
not the way a human does.
It's not your fault.
I hope we can figure something out,
but until then,
this is it for you.
Kady...
Citizens, your warrior king returns.
- Praise Ember!
- You scared me, you dick.
Good to see you too, Bambi.
Eliot, are... are you okay?
Are you hurt?
All in one piece, thanks
to that sword spell of yours.
I'm just glad you're safe. We both are.
I can't believe you actually won.
Uh, is it really that shocking?
Having seen how you fight
without magic, yes.
Hold up.
What's King Daddy Fuckface doing here?
Ah, King Idri is our honored guest.
What happened to the whole
"one must die" deal?
We're kings.
What's the point of having great power
if not to right wrongs?
We...
made an agreement.
- We're getting married.
- Wait, what?
Uh, hello?
Pregnant wifey? Your dick no work-y?
Before I flay whoever
neglected to inform me sooner,
apparently all monarchs
on this glorious, magical planet
are entitled to one of each.
A wife, and a husband.
So what?
You're all just gonna shack up together?
We're all just one big royal
polyamorous family.
Isn't it great? No one has to die.
Everyone gets what they want.
El, can we take a second?
What? So you fucked his son.
It doesn't have to be weird.
You sure this is a good idea?
I mean, you're really doubling up
on Fillorian marriage contracts.
Sometimes, you have
to sacrifice for diplomacy.
And just wait until
we're husband and husband,
and what some would call
pillow talk, we call...
Espionage?
Diplomatic leverage.
Your Highness!
Thank Ember for your safe return.
More good news, the Wellspring
is finally replenishing itself.
Ah, good old Tick.
Well, everything's coming up Eliot.
Congrats, future hubby.
Your half is now shit-free.
I'm sorry, his what?
That was the deal. Marriage, peace,
and a 50/50 Wellspring split.
So how'd we finally fix the Wellspring?
Well...
I am so sorry.
I just can't do this anymore.
Alice...
I hope you meant it.
I hope you just go and do...
beautiful magic.
Alice...
Quentin says go free.