QUENTIN: Previously on
The Magicians...
Fray isn't yours.
Your real daughter died
during childbirth.
She died?
IRENE: All right,
I can help you.
ls that cocaine?
It's the excretion of
a very rare magical creature.
(SNIFFS)
Penny, Sylvia.
I'm babysitting now?
Sylvia is your supervisor.
If you can't bring me back,
you die too, Penny.
Benedict,
do not do it!
No!
Mmm. Yummy.
Children of Earth have been
making a mess of things here
for some time.
She planned this.
(SCREAMING) I'm your queen,
you motherfuckers!
What're you doing?
Short-circuiting
your panic attack.
Wait a minute'
I know these people.
THE LIBRARIAN:
Well, every book is here,
all the books of all the
people who ever lived.
It's not like I can just
travel to the Underworld.
So we need a gatekeeper.
POPPY: What about
the Library's dragon?
They call it the Bookwyrm.
I hear they use it
to send books
to and from the Underworld.
Well, what if the person
was a book?
Say I get the key
and send it back up,
it's stuck in
the Satellite Library.
We need another Traveler.
Okay, Work
with ms group now.
It's kind of about
freedom of information.
You have to go,
if that's what you wanna do.
I'm sorry we're cursed.
Whoa!
Damn it!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Hey, uh, guy...
Yeah, what is this?
Temp housing,
and before you ask,
yes, the system
is still down.
Rations arrive Tuesday.
Smoking is prohibited.
The outhouses
to your left.
Outhouses here?
No, look, I... I'm...
I'm just looking
for someone.
Did you file a request?
You'll have to hand-deliver it
to the Underworld Hotel.
This is an emergency, okay?
I really, really can't wait.
I might be able to help,
unofficially,
if, uh...
Yeah, uh...
What the hell do you
bribe dead people with?
Uh, is there money here?
And what about
the White Walkers?
Oh, the White Walkers?
Yeah, I mean,
those guys are bad news.
You know, but then
the British-sounding dude
came and, you know,
kicked their asses, so...
Wait, who was that?
You know!
You know, dope outfit.
Speaks in rhymes.
Has eight dragons.
Where did he get
so many dragons?
I mean,
that's the question.
So, you know, he came in
and, uh, won the throne game.
Well, no one does
a twist like they do.
Okay, what's your
friend's name?
Hi, um, I'm looking
for Benedict.
BENEDICT: Go away.
Benedict?
I'm dead!
Go away!
It's... It's Penny.
Oh, Penny, my friend!
Oh. Okay. Um...
Good hug.
Yeah, let's call this, man.
You can't imagine
how terrible this place is.
I'm so happy
to see you.
That isn't to say...
I'm sorry you're dead.
Yeah, about that...
No, I'm...
I'm not technically.
I came to find you.
You did?
Yeah.
Okay, we're...
And we're hugging again.
When you died,
were you holding a key?
Are you here for the key?
Yeah, do you have it?
I thought you, uh...
Because we were
friends, that, um...
Oh. Um...
Yeah, look,
we're not not friends.
It's just, you know,
I'm on a mission,
and if we are friends.“
lam your friend!
Then give me the key,
Phase?
They took it.
Who?
Well, the Library.
Of course. Fuck me.
L just snuck out of there.
Damn it!
Well, the Library's the
only part of the Underworld
that functions now.
It's well-protected.
I'd say just
cut your losses.
There's no way you can
get in there.
Yeah, there is.
I'm a Librarian.
Currently on the lam from
a billion-year contract.
Oh, well, like I said...
Best lei go of it.
Of all of magic?
Would you let that go?
Well, I'll figure it out,
find the key,
avoid indentured servitude...
Even in death,
you lead an exciting life.
I'll help
No, that's okay.
No, I insist!
I can help you sneak.
Loan...
Great. Yeah!
We'll go together.
L just... You know, I just need
to find one more person...
0K3'! -
And then, we'll loop back
and grab you in 10, okay?
Okay, no hugging-
Okay.
All right.
I'll be here.
I'm gonna go this way.
Okay.
Hi, Penny.
Sylvia?
You're about to do
something stupid.
I'm sorry...
For leaving you behind in...
oh, you mean
in the Poison Room?
God, I was a goner.
I'm not mad.
I am.
Well, don't be.
I'm fine, well,
for a dead girl.
You, on the other hand,
are not doing so hot,
between the
stuck-in-the-astral thing
and the
'bout-to-fuck-up-royally thing.
How do you know I'm...
Oh. The same way I knew
that you were here right now.
It is written.
What is that?
Trust me, your best bet
of finding that key
is with the person
who wrote these pages.
Follow me.
Cassandra?
I brought a friend.
Alice?
(SCREAMS)
Cassandra, calm down.
It's okay.
What the hell is going on?
Cassandra doesn't like to see
anybody that she writes about.
I'm sorry, but she just looks
exactly like a friend of mine,
who, last time I checked,
was still alive.
I don’t know
what to tell you.
She's been here, like,
thousands of years.
Make him go away.
I can't. He needs your help.
Here's the deal.
Cassandra has a gift.
A curse.
She kinda got involved
with this guy...
God.
And it didn't end well,
and he was pissed,
so he gave her
magical sight.
She can see the future.
This should sound familiar,
if you've read
any ancient myths.
The one that
no one believed
and it drove her
batshit crazy?
Quiet, squirrels.
I guess some Librarians
found her
and got her to start
writing everything down.
Wait, she's the person
that writes the books
of the people
in the Library?
Well, yes and no.
She can only write
one at a time.
So, at some point,
the Librarians wrote a spell
to, like,
industrialize her thing,
and that's how
all books were written.
That stopped
when magic did,
and now it's just her,
one book at a time.
Trying to concentrate.
Anyway, I take her pages
to the Bookwyrm,
and I read that
you were here,
and then, I read
that I come to help you,
and so I did,
and here we are.
Out of seven billion people
in the world,
she's writing about me?
Well, you and your buds are
on a quest to restore magic,
making you maybe
our only hope.
Nu mesh.
Se, what do we do'!?
Do we just...
Do we just wait for her
to maybe write about
the lost key?
(PAPER RUSTLING)
This one seems to be
about Poppy and Quentin... Oh!
God, it's a sex scene.
QUENTIN: I'm worried that
the plan won't work.
Well, that means my plan
definitely didn't work.
What plan is that?
The one where I bang
the panic right out of you.
I don't know how Harriet
thinks we pull this off.
It's incredibly dangerous,
and I don't think
that we are
fully, you know, equipped.
I assure you, Quentin,
I'm fully equipped.
I can't ask you
to risk your life
for my quest.
(SIGHS)
Real talk, I'm a very
self-interested person,
and I want magic back.
And how do we know
it's not my quest too?
Maybe I'm the second act
add-on that saves the world.
Maybe you have to bring me
or you totally fail. Hmm?
I don't think
that's how this works.
(SIGHS) If it's such a bad
idea, then why are you going?
Because it's the opposite
of what I usually do.
A quest is supposed
to change a quester.
The person who starts it
couldn't, you know,
finish it.
So run a gauntlet
to get the keys,
and the gauntlet is what
makes you the guy
that can get the keys?
Exactly.
I know
what I have to be
to win this quest.
A hero.
I also know what I am,
which is not that, so...
Okay...
I reject your whole premise.
That's all people do:
Try to change.
The real me is an asshole
with no filter.
Believe me, I tried.
Eventually, I realized
the brave thing is to be you
and accept the consequences.
Who's to say that isn't
the key to the quest?
Shit's about
to get awkward, huh.
Oh, because
you slept with Q?
Yeah, I'm not really worried
about his penis right now.
I'm more worried about
how he's about to get killed.
Robbing the Library?
Oh.
How are you even
gonna get there?
We have a Traveler.
Victoria.
But how's she
gonna travel you?
That park's a spell.
Yeah, so,
we're not doing that.
Travelers are magical
creatures...
They' re technically hybrids.
Fine, whatever.
All I know is that
we can use her DNA.
She's gonna build
a Mirror Bridge.
All we need is...
PHD-level skill
and patience
and more Traveler blood than
she has in her entire body.
Exactly.
Look, I know the physics
of Mirror Bridges
from when I was a...
Sociopathic energy monster?
Yeah.
Bridges are usually built
between hedge witch safe houses
a hundred miles apart' max.
Well, we're better
than hedges.
Light years better?
You do know that the distance
changes the metamath, right?
So if you're not perfect,
Victoria dies.
VICTORIA: Forget it. I'm out.
KADY: Okay, hold on.
I was on the fence
when it sounded semi-safe.
Now it sounds a lot like
I could get everyone killed.
Look, we don't do it
until we get the math right,
and I'll make sure that...
None of us understands
how the Bridge works.
Alice does.
Get her to do the math,
we can talk.
She said, "I already
talked to Alice.
"She's not gonna help."
Look, it's simple.
Prove to me the Bridge will be
stable, or I'm out.
Victoria, wait...
Oh, shit.
What do we do now?
(MOUTHING)
What is she after?
Harriet?
What do you mean?
If we're gonna risk
our lives to help her,
we deserve to know why.
0K3'! -
Library's been searching
for this thing
called the Alexandria Cell.
It's a huge battery.
Librarians from
ancient Egypt made it,
and if they followed the
plans, it is fucking massive.
And Harriet thinks
that they found it?
Or her people saw Librarians
doing magic on Earth,
big magic.
But none of it matters
if we can't get to
the Satellite branch.
Niffin notes.
Pages and pages
about Mirror Bridges.
How did... How did you
convince her to help us?
Didn't. I stole them.
I'll make copies
and put them back
before she comes home
from wherever she went
to sulk and be a martyr.
No, this is not a good idea.
Under the circumstances,
it seemed worth it.
See?
Just had to be myself.
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
Okay...
Be careful
when you step through.
(GROANS)
Okay. I have to stay
and feed the sigils,
so, you know,
take your time.
We'll hurry.
Thank you, Victoria.
Okay, she says,
"Go left down the hall."
Said, "You'll find
the book drop chute.
"The Bookwyrm's inside." Okay.
Wait, have you
been here before?
(MOUTHING)
Well, okay... Well, let's go
before Victoria bleeds out.
Come on.
Penny said he'd
hide it in a book.
(SHUSHING)
(FOOTSTEPS IN DISTANCE)
Make sure to check the chute.
Might be stuck.
(DRAGON GROWLS)
Okay, no books.
Just an actual dragon.
God damn it,
we don't have time.
Oh, fuck it.
Hello?
Key's not here.
What?
So, Penny failed?
Shit. Uh, maybe he did. I...
Well, we can't just
stand here and wait.
No, we need the key.
I just realized my part
to play in this quest.
I'm here to tell you it is
time to cut bait and run.
Just live another day.
No, we can't.
Kady and Harriet...
They are on their own trip,
and call me crazy,
but I don't think any of this
is worth Victoria's life.
(SIGHS)
Alice, what the hell?
Come on, we gotta go.
(SIGHS)
Where are they?
I don't know.
Come with me.
No, they'll be stuck.
Do what you need to do.
(GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
This can't be right.
The key's not there.
Quentin's about
to bail without me.
Well, "about to". That means
that there's still a chance.
A lot of this is still
in the future, so...
And what the hell
is Alice is doing
in the Satellite branch?
You'd think she could
at least answer that
Alice, if you're
in there, please...
Where is the key?
Fuck.
Here's a bright idea.
Keep fucking reading.
POPPY:
We're better than hedges.
ALICE: Light years better?
You do know the distance
changes the metamath, right?
If you're not perfect,
Victoria will die.
Then help.
KADY: Look,
bottom line, Alice,
you told Poppy the Mirror
Bridge won't work.
Now Victoria's
not gonna help.
It won't work.
Would you
rather I didn't tell her
and just let you guys
walk off into deep space?
(MOUTHING)
She asked, "Have you
been to the Library?"
Once.
I wasn't there long.
"Brochure makes it
sound great.
"They collect knowledge,
keep it safe...
"But from who?"
Whom.
(OUT LOUD) I said "whom."
(MOUTHING)
"The Library
buries information.
"Only the people they choose
get access.
"The rest of us..."
You just wanna let
all that knowledge loose
for anyone to use?
For good or bad?
"Don't tell me there isn't
a book in the Library
"you wouldn't die to read.
"If you help us,
"we can offer you a piece
of what we find there."
What's that?
The biggest battery
ever created.
You wanna help Penny?
This is how.
If I say yes,
that means risking lives
to give you power
maybe no one should have.
No thank you.
(DOOR RATTLING)
Door was stuck.
Can I have one of those?
FEN: So, I left.
Just needed a little space
from the ol' ball and cock.
It's "ball and chain,"
I think you mean.
No, that doesn't
sound right.
I think I know what you mean.
I lost a lot of
people recently,
including kind of myself.
Mmm. That makes no sense.
I had everything.
I knew everything
there was to know
in every book and more,
and... And I lost it.
I'm sorry...
You think that's the same
kind of problem at all?
My daughter's gone...
Forever.
You forgot some stuff?
What you lost
is still out there.
Go get it back.
Umber's ass, lam drunk.
Oh, Christ.
No. The answer's no.
You don't even know
what I want.
You're a Library groupie.
You got a knowledge boner.
How'd you find out
about this place anyway?
It was Karen.
What?
No, Penny told me.
Bad news, book tart.
The Library's closed,
indefinitely.
I got bored waiting.
Look, I need to speak
to your boss.
I have something
she'll want.
(SCOFFS)
You're so mysterious.
It's important, asshole.
Fine.
Come on then.
Wait, this shouldn't work
without Wellspring magic.
How can you...
Alice Quinn.
Till we meet again,
book tart.
If you're his supervisor,
I wanna file a complaint.
Roguish belligerency is a
common trait among Travelers.
How can he take people
with him when he travels?
You really do
have a battery.
Is that why you're here?
No, I don't care
about the battery.
Well, of course I do.
All I want is a Library Card.
We're no longer accepting
new applications.
What do you know
about Niffins?
I was one for a time,
and this is
all I can remember.
It's half of a puzzle.
The other pieces
fell out of my head,
but they could be
inside your books.
You are suggesting
a trade of information?
More than that.
I wanna finish what I started,
A Grand Unified Theory
of Magic.
But you're just a human
Magician with no magic now.
I'm afraid your experiences
as a Niffin
have already been documented
to our satisfaction.
It's in my book.
You don't want me to finish.
ls... ls that it?
There is something
you could do for us,
and, in exchange,
we would give you
full access to our collection.
You're familiar with
the Quest for the Seven Keys?