Previously on "The Magicians"...
Fray isn't yours. Your real
daughter died during childbirth.
She died?
- All right, I can help you.
- Is that cocaine?
It's the excretion of
a very rare magical creature.
- Penny, Sylvia.
- I'm babysitting now?
Sylvia is your supervisor.
If you can't bring me
back, you die too, Penny.
Benedict... do not do it!
No!
Mmm... yummy.
Children of Earth have been making a
mess of things here for some time.
She planned this.
I'm your queen, you motherfuckers!
- What are you doing?
- Short-circuiting your panic attack.
Wait a minute, I... I... I
know these people.
Well, every book is here,
all the books of all the people
who ever lived.
It's not like I can just
travel to the Underworld.
So we need a gatekeeper.
What about the Library's dragon?
They call it the Bookwyrm.
I hear they use it to send books
to and from the Underworld.
Well, what if the person was a book?
Say I get the Key and send it back up,
it's stuck in the Satellite Library.
We need another traveler.
Okay, I work with this group now.
It's kind of about
freedom of information.
You have to go, if that's
what you wanna do.
I'm sorry we're cursed.
- Synced and corrected by Shazi89 -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Damn it!
Hey, uh, guy...
Yeah, what is this?
Temp housing, and before you ask,
yes, the system is still down.
Rations arrive Tuesday.
Smoking is prohibited.
The outhouses to your left.
Outhouses here? No, look, I... I'm...
- I'm just looking for someone.
- Did you file a request?
You'll have to hand-deliver it
to the Underworld Hotel.
This is an emergency, okay?
I really, really can't wait.
I might be able to help, unofficially,
if, uh...
Yeah, uh...
what the hell do you
bribe dead people with?
Uh... is there money here?
And what about the White Walkers?
Oh, the White Walkers?
Yeah, I mean, those guys are bad news.
You know, but then
the British-sounding dude
came and, uh, you know,
kicked their asses, so...
- W... wait, who was that?
- You know!
You know, dope outfit.
Speaks in rhymes. Has eight dragons.
Where did he get so many dragons?
I mean... that's the question.
So, you know, he came in
and, uh, won the throne game.
Well, no one does a twist like they do.
Okay, what's your friend's name?
Hi, um, I'm looking for Benedict.
- Go away.
- Benedict?
I'm dead! Go away!
It's... it's Penny.
Oh, Penny, my friend!
Oh... okay. Um...
Good hug.
Yeah, let's call this, man.
You can't imagine how
terrible this place is.
I'm so happy to see you.
That isn't to say I'm... I'm...
I'm sorry you're dead.
Oh, yeah, about that:
No, I'm... I'm not technically, uh...
I came to find you.
- You did?
- Yeah.
- Oh!
- Okay, we're...
and we're hugging again.
When you died, were you holding a key?
Are you here for the key?
- Yeah, do you have it?
- I thought you, uh...
because we were friends, that, um...
Oh, um...
Yeah, look, we're not not friends.
It's just, you know,
I'm... I'm on a mission,
and... and if we are friends...
- I am your friend!
- Then give me the key...
uh, please?
- They... they took it.
- Who?
Well, the Library.
Of course. Fuck me.
I just snuck out of there. Damn it!
Well, the Library's the only part of
the Underworld that functions now.
It's well-protected.
I'd say just cut your losses. There's
no way you can get in there.
Yeah, there is.
I'm a Librarian.
Currently on the lam from
a billion-year contract.
Oh, well, like I said...
best let go of it.
Of all of magic?
Would you let that go?
Oh, well, I'll figure it out,
find the Key,
avoid indentured servitude...
Oh, even in death, you lead an
exciting life. I'll... I'll help.
- No... no, that's okay.
- I insist! I can help you sneak.
I can...
Great. Yeah!
We'll go together.
I just... you know, I just
need to find one more person...
And then, uh, we'll loop back
and grab you in ten, okay?
- Okay, no hugging.
- Okay.
- All right.
- I'll be here.
- I'm gonna go this way.
- Okay.
- Hi, Penny.
- Sylvia?
You're about to do something stupid.
I'm sorry...
for leaving you behind in...
Oh, you mean in the Poison Room?
God, I was a goner.
- I'm not mad.
- I am.
Well, don't be.
I'm fine, well, for a dead girl.
You, on the other hand,
are not doing so hot,
between the stuck-in-the-astral thing
and the 'bout-to-fuck-up-royally thing.
How do you know I'm...
Oh, the same way I knew
that you were here right now.
- It is written.
- What is that?
Trust me, your best bet
of finding that key
is with the person
who wrote these pages.
Follow me.
Cassandra? I brought a friend.
Alice?
Cassandra, calm down. It's okay.
- It's okay.
- What the hell is going on?
Cassandra doesn't like to see
anybody that she writes about.
I'm sorry, but she just looks
exactly like a friend of mine,
who, last time I checked,
was still alive.
I don't know what to tell you. She's
been here thousands of years.
- Make him go away.
- I can't. He needs your help.
Here's the deal:
- Cassandra has a gift.
- A curse.
She kinda got involved with this guy...
God.
And it didn't end well,
and he was pissed,
so he gave her magical sight.
She can see the future.
This should sound familiar,
if you've read any ancient myths.
The one that no one believed
and it drove her batshit crazy?
Quiet, squirrels.
I guess some Librarians found her
and got her to start
writing everything down.
Wait, she's the person
that writes the books
of the people in the Library?
Well, yes and no.
She can only write one at a time.
So, at some point,
the Librarians wrote a spell
to, like, industrialize her thing,
and that's how all books were written.
That stopped when magic did,
and now it's just her,
one book at a time.
Trying to concentrate.
Anyway, I take her pages
to the Bookwyrm,
and I read that you were here,
and then, I read
that I come to help you,
and so I did, and here we are.
Out of 7 billion people in the world,
she's writing about me?
Well, you and your buds are
on a quest to restore magic,
making you maybe our only hope.
- No presh.
- So, what do we do?
Do we just... do we just wait for her
to maybe write about the lost key?
This one seems to be
about Poppy and Quentin...
God, it's a sex scene.
I'm worried that the plan won't work.
Well, that means my plan
definitely didn't work.
What plan is that?
The one where I bang
the panic right out of you.
I don't know how Harriet
thinks we pull this off.
It's incredibly dangerous, and
I don't think that we are...
fully... you know, equipped.
I assure you, Quentin,
I'm fully equipped.
I can't ask you
to risk your life for my quest.
Real talk, I'm a very self-interested
person, and I want magic back.
And how do we know
it's not my quest too?
Maybe I'm the second act
add-on that saves the world.
Maybe you have to bring me
or you totally fail, hmm?
I don't think that's how this works.
If it's such a bad idea,
then why are you going?
Because it's the opposite
of what I usually do.
A quest is supposed to change a quester.
The person who starts it
couldn't, you know, finish it.
So run a gauntlet to get the keys,
and the gauntlet is what
makes you the guy
that can get the keys?
Exactly.
I know what I have to be
to win this quest:
a... hero.
I also know what I am,
which is not that, so...
Okay...
I reject your whole premise.
That's all people do: try to change.
The real me is an asshole
with no filter.
Believe me, I tried.
Eventually, I realized
the brave thing is to be you
and accept the consequences.
Who's to say that isn't
the key to the quest?
Shit's about to get awkward, huh?
Oh, because you slept with Q?
Yeah, I'm not really worried
about his penis right now.
I'm more worried about
how he's about to get killed.
- Robbing the Library?
- Oh.
How are you even gonna get there?
We have a traveler: Victoria.
But how's she gonna travel you?
That part's a spell.
Yeah, so, we're not doing that.
- Travelers are magical creatures...
- They're technically hybrids.
Fine, whatever.
All I know is that we can use her DNA.
She's gonna build a Mirror Bridge.
- All we need is, uh...
- PHD-level skill and patience
and more traveler blood than
she has in her entire body.
Exactly.
Look, I know the physics
of Mirror Bridges
- from when I was a...
- Sociopathic energy monster?
Yeah.
Bridges are usually built
between hedge witch safe houses
a hundred miles apart, max.
Well, we're better than hedges.
Light years better?
You do know that the distance
changes the metamath, right?
So if you're not perfect, Victoria dies.
- Forget it. I'm out.
- Okay, hold on.
I was on the fence
when it sounded semi-safe.
Now it sounds a lot like
I could get everyone killed.
We don't do it until we get the
math right, and I'll make sure that...
None of us understands
how the Bridge works.
Alice does.
Get her to do the math, we can talk.
She said, "I already talked to Alice.
She's not gonna help."
Look, it's simple.
Prove to me the Bridge
will be stable, or I'm out.
Victoria, wait...
Oh, shit. Fuck.
What do we do now?
What is she after?
- Harriet?
- What do you mean?
If we're gonna risk
our lives to help her,
we deserve to know why.
Okay.
Library's been searching for this thing
called the Alexandria Cell.
It's a huge battery.
Librarians from ancient Egypt made it,
and if they followed the plans,
it is fucking massive.
And Harriet thinks that they found it?
Or her people saw Librarians
doing magic on Earth,
big magic.
But none of it matters
if we can't get to the Satellite branch.
Niffin notes.
Pages and pages about Mirror Bridges.
How did... how did you
convince her to help us?
Didn't. I stole them.
I'll make copies and put them
back before she comes home
from wherever she went
to sulk and be a martyr.
No, this is... this is not a good idea.
Under the circumstances,
it seemed worth it.
See?
Just had to be myself.
Okay...
Be careful when you step through.
Okay. I have to stay
and feed the sigils,
so, you know, take your time.
We'll hurry.
Thank you, Victoria.
Okay, she says, "Go left down the hall."
Said, "You'll find the book drop chute."
"The Bookwyrm's inside." Okay.
Wait, have you been here before?
Well, okay... well, let's go before
Victoria bleeds out. Come on.
Penny said he'd hide it in a book.
Make sure to check the chute.
Might be stuck.
Okay, no books. Just an actual dragon.
Ooh.
Uh... God damn it, we don't have time.
Oh, fuck it.
- Hello?
- Key's not here.
What?
So, Penny failed?
Shit. Uh, maybe he did. I...
Well, we can't just stand here and wait.
No, we need the key.
I just realized
my part to play in this quest.
I'm here to tell you
it is time to cut bait and run.
- Just live another day.
- No, we can't.
- Kady and Harriet...
- They are on their own trip,
and call me crazy,
but I don't think any of this
is worth Victoria's life.
Alice, what the hell?
Come on, we gotta go.
- Where are they?
- I don't know.
Come with me.
No, they'll be stuck.
Do what you need to do.
This can't be right.
The key's not there.
Quentin's about to
bail without me.
Well, "about to": That means
that there's still a chance.
A lot of this is still
in the future, so...
And what the hell is Alice is
doing in the Satellite branch?
You'd think she could
at least answer that.
Alice, if you're in there, please...
Where is the key?
Fuck.
Here's a bright idea:
Keep fucking reading.
- We're better than hedges.
- Light years better?
You do know the distance
changes the metamath, right?
If you're not perfect,
Victoria will die.
Then help.
Look, bottom line, Alice,
you told Poppy
the Mirror Bridge won't work.
Now Victoria's not gonna help.
It won't work.
Would you rather I didn't tell her
and just let you guys
walk off into deep space?
She asked, "Have you
been to the Library?"
Once.
I wasn't there long.
"Brochure makes it sound great.
"They collect knowledge, keep it safe...
but from who?"
Whom.
I said "whom."
"The Library buries information.
"Only the people they choose get access.
The rest of us"...
You just wanna let all that
knowledge loose for anyone to use?
For good or bad?
"Don't tell me there isn't
a book in the Library
"you wouldn't die to read.
"If you help us,
we can offer you a piece
of what we find there."
What's that?
The biggest battery ever created.
You wanna help Penny? This is how.
If I say yes, that means risking lives
to give you power
maybe no one should have.
No thank you.
Door was stuck.
Can I have one of those?
So, I left.
Just needed a little space
from the ol' ball and cock.
It's "ball and chain," I think you mean.
No, that doesn't sound right.
I think I know what you mean.
I lost a lot of people recently,
including kind of myself.
Mm. That makes no sense.
I had everything. I knew
everything there was to know
in every book and more,
and... and I lost it.
I'm sorry...
You think that's the same
kind of problem at all?
My daughter's gone...
forever.
You forgot some stuff?
What you lost is still out there.
Go get it back.
Umber's ass, I am drunk.
Oh, Christ.
No. The answer's no.
You don't even know what I want.
You're a Library groupie.
You got a knowledge boner.
How'd you find out
about this place anyway?
- It was Karen.
- What?
N... no, Penny told me.
Bad news, book tart.
The Library's closed, indefinitely.
I got bored waiting.
Look, I need to speak to your boss.
I have something she'll want.
Oh. You're so mysterious.
It's important, asshole.
Fine.
Come on then.
Wait, this shouldn't work
without Wellspring magic.
How can you...
Alice Quinn.
Till we meet again, book tart.
If you're his supervisor,
I wanna file a complaint.
Roguish belligerency is
a common trait among travelers.
How can he take people
with him when he travels?
You really do have a battery.
Is that why you're here?
No, I don't care about the battery.
Well... of course I do.
All I want is a Library Card.
We're no longer accepting
new applications.
What do you know about niffins?
I was one for a time,
and this is all I can remember.
It's half of a puzzle.
The other pieces fell out of my head,
but... they could be inside your books.
You are suggesting
a trade of information?
More than that.
I wanna finish what I started:
a Grand Unified Theory of Magic.
But you're just a human
Magician with no magic now.
I'm afraid your experiences as a niffin
have already been documented
to our satisfaction.
It's in my book.
You don't want me to finish.
Is... is that it?
There is something you could do for us,
and, in exchange, we would give you
full access to our collection.
You're familiar with
the Quest for the Seven Keys?
Excuse me a moment.
Alice, what the hell?
Come on, we gotta go.
- What are you doing here?
- What am I doing here?
How do you just keep appearing?
What were you...
Alice, are you working with the Library?
Q, you have to go.
Okay, great, then let's go.
Alice, come on.
Q, please...
The bookish girl joins the Library.
Didn't see that coming.
Yeah, little bit of a bigger problem.
Quentin left without the key!
This is it, right?
An actual... answer?
Yes, I do want to make
a final statement.
I...
hate... Fillory.
It is a backwards,
malodorous shithole
full of animals who are smarter
than they're supposed to be
and humans who are so much dumber.
And what you'd call indoor plumbing,
we on Earth would call
a war crime.
But...
when I was drowning,
Fillory saved me,
and now it's my turn to save Fillory.
But I can't do that
if my head's in a basket,
so if it pleases the...
You guys...
I demand that this
trial/peasant uprising
be dismissed...
Your honorable wombat-ness.
What the shit is this?
Why is he talking to a marsupial?
- This is not at all relevant!
- Would you just chill?
- You're gonna piss her off again.
- Next!
How's Alice?
Uh, well, she's not my
favorite person at the moment,
but, um, the transfer worked,
so thank you.
Oh, well, I'm glad to hear it.
- Yeah.
- Uh... so you're...
Yeah, back to powered up.
Good...
because I've, uh, come here
to collect on that favor
that you owe me.
Oh, my God.
Yeah.
Side-effect from
the powder that I gave you.
- Um...
- Oh, don't worry.
No, you haven't used nearly enough.
No, you're safe.
Look, there is a treatment,
but it's big magic.
I... I can't do it on myself,
because it would just make things worse.
So...
Here's what we'll need.
My office, 3:00 p.m.
A fairy?
And I can't see her, because
I've never made a fairy deal?
- This is what they do...
- Okay?
They hide behind powerful people,
manipulate them into
doing terrible things...
Wait a minute, at Irene's house,
Penny said that he...
he thought that he saw something moving
that... that Q and I couldn't see.
There's more of them? Oh, no.
No, what I'm... what I'm saying is
I'm not so sure that they're
manipulating much of anything.
They were doing chores.
- Wait, what was Irene's fairy doing?
- Just...
standing there,
like she was waiting on Irene,
and her head was sort of bowed, but...
Bowed? Wait, that's...
I mean, that kind of
sounds like a servant.
You can't trust them.
I don't know why they'd be
acting that way, but...
Do you have slavery in Fillory?
If these fairies are slaves,
you'd be better off.
Fen...
no one is better off with slavery.
Look, I have this tiny spark of magic,
and it seems like when I use it
to do good things, to help people,
it... it grows.
I didn't ask for it,
and I can't get rid of it.
If I want it to be
anything but a burden,
I have to use it.
My daughter's dead because of them.
Fen, we need to know,
and I can't see her.
You need to talk to Irene's fairy.
Hey. What's your name?
Yes...
I can see you.
I'm... I'm not supposed to talk to you.
Why not?
You must answer me.
Irene will be very angry if you don't.
Of course. Of course.
Um... I'm sorry.
- Oh, shit, you are her slave.
- No.
Okay, Miss McAllistair keeps us
safe from bad Magicians.
She hides us.
In exchange for what?
How is it you can see me?
I made a deal.
Well, a deal was made on my behalf...
with a fairy.
But... there are no other fairies.
Oh, I'm late. Miss will be waiting.
Uh... can we...
talk again tomorrow?
Miss Irene won't be home.
My name is Skye.
No sign of fairies.
Then let's look in here first.
If, uh, we don't find Skye, we'll
have to break into the main house,
hope that Irene doesn't come home.
Fen, what is it? What do you see?
It's her. It's Skye. She's...
oh, God, they cut off her leg.
Hey...
It's what the powder's made of.
What happened to you?
Who did this?
Irene did.
They left.
The Mirror Bridge is gone.
Alice...
just talk to me. Come on.
I'm not Alice.
God damn it!
What is it?
Quentin and Poppy: sex scene.
That you kinda skimmed, prude.
Um, not that I'm complaining, but, um...
- Why am I doing this?
- What?
'Cause I can only go so long
feeling completely alone and worthless,
before I break down
and do something stupid.
Right. You're an idiot.
- Quentin?
- No, me!
Look, I get it.
You didn't want me
to bail on you, so you lied,
and then I bailed on you anyway.
Be mad. Don't be stupid.
I buried it. Sorry.
I spent so much of my life alone,
the thought of spending
the rest of time...
I thought you were my friend,
and I thought...
if you couldn't find
the key, eventually you'd...
I don't know...
What, decide to hang out
in your dumb tent?
I thought we'd spruce it up together.
Look...
don't ask me how I know this, but...
you are the only person
who cried when I died.
We are friends, and I appreciate you,
so, listen...
once you show me where the
key is buried, Sylvia...
is gonna take you
to the Library map room.
You are going to be very popular.
Well, um, I guess this is it.
Well, until the next time I die, anyway.
And I want the record to show
that I helped you get that key,
making this the second time
I saved your ass.
Oh, my gosh.
Wait... whoa, hey, whoa!
I need to... still need to get in there.
Sylvia?
- What did you do?
- I'm sorry.
Alice, what the hell?
Alice, are you working with the Library?
Q, please...
- Hey.
What was that?
It sounded like a dragon barfing.
We gotta get back to
the book chute. Come on.
Holy shit!
Did you... okay.
- Yeah.
- Okay, come on.
Oh, but Penny...
No, we don't have time. I'm sorry.
Shit.
- Synced and corrected by Shazi89 -
-- www.addic7ed.com --