Previously on The Magicians...
Before I got here, I
was in the hospital.
Quentin, I'd really
recommend further treatment.
Look, I've never threatened
to hurt myself or anybody else.
So you can't make me stay.
Brakebills is the first
place that feels right to me
that is not
literally a fairy tale.
Quentin!
I made the mistake of
thinking you were just psychic.
Do you know how
to close your mind?
'Cause I will show
you right now.
You are a Traveler.
You can actually
move between worlds.
Where you going, kitty cat?
I'm done here. For good. You
should be happy. Less competition.
Hedge witches, amateurs,
sad and desperate people.
That means level 50.
So you were...
Top bitch in New
York, for starters.
Get me everything
on this list, this week.
I don't know what
you're doing here, Jules.
Magic wasn't just handed to me.
People at Brakebills,
Jules, they can read minds.
They can fly. You
can do a party trick.
You were my best friend.
It's amazing I survived
as long as I did
not knowing that
I was a Magician.
I can't go back.
Oh...
Dude, you're in the
wrong... Or I'm in the wrong...
Uh...
Hey!
Big stuff. Hey.
You got them? I'm
dying. Where are they?
Where are they?
Jesus!
Where are they? Cut it out!
You give me happy pills,
me love you long time.
Eliot, they're looking
for you in arts and crafts.
Watercolors. Without
me, they're adrift.
Quentin, could I speak to you?
Quentin?
Okay, this is obviously a dream
where I realize I'm in a dream.
So you think your
life is a dream?
No, my life is my life, but this
is like a... This is a bad collage.
You, the hospital,
the dean's office,
the Brakebills, it's
all jumbled together.
So we're back to Brakebills.
Hopefully, soon.
Where you think you're a student
studying to be a Magician.
Okay, let's just skip the part
where you don't
believe me, okay?
Um...
Yeah, it's a little
chilly in here.
How about a miniature sun?
That'd be great.
I hate these dreams.
It's like your feet are stuck to
the floor, or you're paralyzed.
Wait, wait, wait.
You released me.
Remember, in the real hospital?
I remember what I
said. What was it? Uh...
"You can't keep me here. I
haven't hurt myself or anybody else."
You know that isn't true.
Well, none of this is true,
but I said that to you
in real life before Brakebills.
Send him in.
Quentin, do you remember why
the court ordered you to be here?
The court? I don't...
If this is a trial
dream, I am...
God, these things take forever.
Come in, Penny.
Show me again what you
found in Quentin's trash.
I don't want to get
nobody in trouble.
No, it's okay, Penny.
No one's in trouble.
Thank you, Penny.
Quentin, this is what happens
when you don't take
what we prescribe.
You start to hallucinate again
that you're a Magician,
you have powers.
It's all here.
Uh...
The house of cards,
Alice, Eliot, Margo,
the Physical Kids, The Beast.
I know this can all seem
very real, but it's not.
Brakebills is the hallucination.
This is the reality.
You're seeing this, right?
You're very, very sick.
Are you not seeing this?
Oh, Jesus!
I see you, Quentin, and
I'm very, very worried.
Oh, okay, they're gone.
The moths, they're...
They're gone.
There are no moths,
Quentin. There never were.
Ah!
Oh, I can't breathe!
Code red! Code red! Main office!
Don't let them see.
I heard they shot you up.
I'm kind of foggy.
No, no, no. Just
focus on me. Okay?
None of this is
real. Just us two.
And this.
Where are we?
I mean, what's going on?
You don't remember?
I was at school, I think, and...
And then I fell
asleep at a party,
and then I'm here.
Where none of that
ever happened, and...
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Oh, man! You came to find me.
I did?
To save me.
But first, we have
to break the illusion.
"The illusion"?
I crash-landed on this
planet 9.3 light years ago.
Alice? Wait.
You're a starship captain,
and you came to rescue me.
I, uh... No. Hang on.
But none of
this is real. It's...
We're trapped in a cage,
a menagerie.
Alice?
And they show us these illusions
to make us fall
in love and mate.
Alice, that's enough.
Give them back.
What, Dr. Fogg?
All of them, Alice. We
need them for bridge.
They collect us from all over the
galaxy to feed off our emotions.
No, that's not true. It's an
episode of Lost in Space.
Star Trek. What?
That's an episode of Star Trek.
It's an episode of Star Trek.
They finally got to you.
You belong to them now.
It's okay. I'll still
mate with you.
All right, that's enough.
Me, three!
That's enough.
Me, three.
Quentin, how are you?
Are you feeling any better?
I guess.
Good. Are you up
for seeing a visitor?
Hey, Q.
I mean, Yale's still kind of a
letdown. Still, in the best way.
I mean, you
would've... Well, you...
I mean, you will totally agree,
you know, once, you know, it's you.
When what? When I'm out?
It's just so much easier than
I... Than we expected, is all.
So you've been at Yale
these last few months...
And I've been here?
You don't remember?
This? No.
Okay.
James is sorry he
couldn't make it tonight,
but he'll be by next week.
You know, he had
to lock down a church.
Church?
Mmm-hmm. For the wedding.
Are you engaged?
It's okay.
No, it's not okay.
Seriously, it doesn't even
matter. It's not important.
It's a spell.
"A spell"?
We're all trapped in it,
and I'm the only one who knows.
Okay, look. I
know that I just...
I sounded like Alice
just then, but I...
Hey.
Um, I swear, I'm not crazy.
I want to understand, okay?
I want to help, Q.
Just tell me. No, no, no.
No. Okay, I can do this.
Oh, God, look!
Jules.
Jules, look. Look.
Are you seeing this?
Look!
You guys, are you
not seeing this?
Don't. What?
Look at me like that.
Q. Don't feel sorry
for me. Do not.
I'm not me, and you're not you,
and this is not happening.
Do you hear me?
This is not happening.
I'm not... I'm not here. I am
the one that got into Brakebills.
- I'm in Brakebills!
- Hey, you!
Keep your voice down.
I'm sorry. It's my fault. Um...
Sorry.
I'm gonna go, okay?
I'll be back Friday.
This can't be my life.
Jules, it can't.
I wanted to see the fireworks.
I really did.
Wait.
How did you know
they were fireworks?
What? If you couldn't see them,
how did you know
they were fireworks?
You told me.
I never said the word
"fireworks," Julia.
What's going on here?
Okay, did nobody see that?
See what?
You laughing at me.
Laughing at you?
What kind of a
friend would do that?
Exactly.
Goodbye, Quentin.
What...
All of them, one by one.
Begin.
I believe you, Quentin.
You are a Magician.
A very bad one.
One thing that's real.
You're always a raging dick.
Ellsworth Downs.
Ellsworth.
You know.
You know where to look, Quentin.
I can't show you.
I can't touch you.
It's very strong, this spell.
It is... It is a spell?
It's in the book, the book
is you. This is all you.
Me?
Uh, which book?
Jane?
Uh, I can't remember what, uh...
Jane, they gave me
pills, and I can't remember.
Jane!
No, no, no! Stop! Stop it! Stop!
No! The answer's in these books.
Jane said that...
These books are my
key to getting out of here.
Jesus.
Every time I talk,
I sound batshit.
Could I get some tape any place?
Tape isn't permitted.
Right, I know.
But why, again?
'Cause you can harm
yourself or others.
It's tape.
That can strangle, suffocate...
Okay, what if you
watched me the whole time?
No one has that kind of time.
I need to put these
pages back together.
You need to get
to music therapy.
Music is a way for us to
express and receive feeling
in a way that is safe and fun
and sometimes illuminating.
So, who'd like to begin?
Oh, God, please
not that one song.
Ah, I'm sorry. What
was that, Penny?
Oh, that one song?
Please, no. It gets in my
head, and it never leaves.
Oh, which song is that?
Michael Row the Boat Ashore.
#Agree.
Everything here is me.
All right, everyone,
why don't we kick it
off with the Beatles?
Helter Skelter!
Helter Skelter, please!
I was thinking Here Comes the...
I stay out too late
Got nothing in my brain
That's what people say
I go on too many dates
But I can't make them stay
At least that's what people
say That's what people say
But I keep cruising
Can't stop, won't stop moving
It's like I got this music in my
mind saying it's gonna be all right
'Cause the players gonna
play, play, play, play, play
He's doing this because
I made him take his pills!
And the haters gonna
hate, hate, hate, hate, hate
No! Dr. London!
Baby, I'm just gonna shake,
shake, shake, shake, shake
Shake it off Shake it off
I never miss a beat
I'm lightning on my feet
And that's what they don't
see That's what they don't see
I'm dancing on my own I
make the moves up as I go
And that's what they don't
know That's what they don't know
Hey, Penny. Good luck
getting that out of your head.
PTSD specialist
to ward room two.
I hear you were the hit of
music therapy today, Quentin.
Look, I think I know
what's going on here,
and I think I know
how to get help.
Well, help is why we're here.
No, it's not.
I don't mean to be rude, but
you're here because of a spell,
and I need to break the spell.
Quentin. And if I
can just reach Penny,
the real Penny, and if I
can get inside of his head...
Enough.
That's enough.
Can I please have some tape?
Do you remember the last
time you saw your father?
Dinner a few months ago. Why?
Dad?
Hello, Curly Q.
What happened to your face?
Did you run into a door?
You did that, Quentin.
Come on.
It's time you see something.
Look, I'm telling you, it wasn't
my dad. It was The Beast.
I never even touched
him! I used battle magic,
the same magic that I'm
gonna use to get out of here.
Are you ready? Come on. Come on!
What did you do to my powers?
I need my powers.
The Beast is here, okay?
He's coming for me. He's coming
for you. He is coming to kill us.
You have got to give
me back my power!
I've got to save you!
Ahh!
Do you remember that night?
Um...
Your father does.
Tell him, Ted.
He needs to hear it. He needs
to know the truth why he's here.
We were having dinner to celebrate
when you got into Yale, and...
In the middle of the restaurant,
you suddenly said there
were moths everywhere.
No.
And then you started
calling me "The Beast."
Mmm-mmm.
You're lying.
And then you picked up a knife.
Mmm-mmm. No.
I tried to stop you.
I grabbed you. I tried
to stop you from...
What? From what?
You tried to kill
your father, Quentin.
You need to stop
fighting this, Quentin.
The more you believe
in magic, Brakebills,
The Beast, the more harm you do.
Accept who you are
and what's put you here.
That's how you get
better, Quentin. I promise.
Hey, Q, seriously, talk to
me. Are you fucking with me?
Dude.
Uh, um...
Look, this'll all be
over soon, okay?
Just try not to
get buried under it.
I'm gonna talk to someone. Shit.
Play, play, play, play
Heartbreakers gonna break,
break, break, break, break
Players gonna play,
play, play, play, play
Shake it off Shake it off
Players gonna play,
play, play, play, play Hey!
Quit singing that stupid song!
Play, play, play
Damn it.
Quentin!
Oh, no.
Yeah, that's right.
I'm talking to you.
I told you, keep up
with that stupid song,
and I'd come right into
your brain and rip it out.
No, no, no. Here I am.
By the way, this is the most
pathetic loser dream ever.
Stop, okay? Just
stop. Please stop. Stop.
Please be knowing that dinner
will be served in five minutes,
and today, we are to
be serving chicken curry,
which is, of
course, my favorite.
You racist motherfucker.
You're not real.
Yeah, how's that? Real enough?
That hurt. Do it again, harder.
What kind of sick shit
are you about, Coldwater?
Harder.
Ow.
Nobody here can see you.
Yeah, 'cause there's
no "here," dumbass.
This is all in your
head. I'm in your head.
Now stop singing that song, so
I can go the fuck back to sleep.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait. Oh, my God. It worked.
I did that. I called you. I
called you with the song.
You called me?
I'm in trouble.
Seriously, help me.
What is today out there?
Wednesday.
So I've only been
gone for a night.
Am I asleep there somewhere?
I don't know what you do at
night, and I don't want to know.
Where are you?
Trying to sleep.
This is not a dream. It's a...
All of this, it's a spell.
Please, listen. Find me,
okay? Out there, find me.
I have to be conscious
to break the spell.
Okay, you have to wake up.
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up.
Wake up! Wake up! Wake up!
You, you will not be
shouting! End it now, buster.
Wake the hell up!
Okay. Good job.
Wow.
My whole body, every
part of my body is tingling.
I mean, you didn't
tell me it would...
Feel so good?
It's high-end designer
cooperative magic.
It does something to your cells
to channel all that juice.
Everyone gets stronger.
Um...
I just, um...
I didn't think Q
would fall in so deep.
This is nothing.
Uh, what does that mean?
Well, I mean he might want to take
his shoes off and get comfortable.
We cooked up a whopper here.
I don't really see
him getting out of it,
even with your boyfriend's help.
Mmm, I thought the idea was
to just mess with him.
My idea was to
fuck him up, hard,
and you loved it even harder.
Yeah, fuck him up, not kill him.
Wait, what? Kill him?
He's not gonna die. He just
might not actually ever wake up.
Oh, my God.
Hey, you are not going limp on
me here. This is game time, ladies.
You got the ball,
Kady. Don't drop it.
Now go put all that
sweet hotness to work.
Sorry.
Ellsworth.
Ellsworth Downs. Ellsworth...
Downs. Ellis...
Wirth-Downs, Ellis Wirth-Downs.
The Madness Maker.
Oh, God. Okay.
"In all of Fillory, one Magician
"could drive every
other Magician insane.
"An inventor of
puzzles with no solution
"and games where the
rules changed for no reason.
"He was called the
Madness Maker,
"but he had been
born Ellis Wirth-Downs.
"On his first
journey to Fillory,
"he played checkers
with a powerful witch.
"He cheated, and
her curse was simple.
"The only kind of magic he would
ever do again was game magic.
"Jane Chatwin knew
"his need to make
others suffer was only
"because he felt so
alone in his cursed state.
"Because the more Ellis played,
the more insane he became.
"But soon, Jane figured
out how to break this curse."
Thank you, Jane Chatwin.
"The Madness Maker's
curse was, uh..."
It's okay. It's okay. I know
this. I know this. I know this.
What did Jane say?
God, why can't I remember?
Okay, look, I am, like,
100% sure I invented you,
so if you could
please just disappear?
Look, it was a party.
He's probably
sleeping it off under
something or someone
or someone's thing.
Where you been?
I had to run into the city.
What's up?
Your lover man here thinks
our little Q got roofied last night.
Look, we covered the house.
Let's start checking the
lab, the libraries, whatever.
I know where he is.
He crawled in here and
passed out around 1:00.
Anyway, I've seen weirder.
Come on.
He's breathing.
That's something.
Let me try.
This is bad.
How bad?
"We need to tell the dean" bad.
Now what?
We wait.
When are you gonna
tell me what all this is for?
I did. Bigger, better magic.
Yeah, you just
never mentioned how.
I guess I could tell you now.
No, I don't feel like
it. Later, maybe?
How about never? That's
a growing possibility.
Hmm.
Yes, I thought so.
The spell is called
the Scarlatti Web.
We cannot break it. No one can.
Wait, he's not
gonna wake up ever?
I said "no one," not "nothing."
We need to summon the Matarese.
Quentin, I really thought
we were making progress.
I was wrong.
No! What are you...
Lower the wards, please.
Very good. And
now the south wards.
Dean Fogg following
the playbook.
The only thing that can break our
spell on your ex-BFF is a Matarese.
Evil bug spirit of
the underworld.
About the only way one of those
can get into this sugary wonderland
is to lower all the protective
wards and shields in the school,
letting any old
anyone waltz right in.
Welcome back to Brakebills.
Let's go steal their shit.
Careful.
That's the answer?
It shorts out the
cerebral cortex,
which should break
him out of this spell,
which should bring
him back, halfway.
Halfway?
The spell is like a prison
in the middle of the desert.
The Matarese breaks
you out of the prison,
but you have to get
yourself out of the desert,
and it is a lot
easier with a guide.
Penny, are you ready?
Quentin?
Quentin! Answer me!
The problem is in your
frontal lobe, Quentin.
Your emotions are in
complete control now,
overriding logic, reason,
even the will to live.
So this...
Is inserted into the eye socket.
No, no, no.
It's called a
transorbital lobotomy.
Dad!
Dad. Daddy.
No, no, no! Don't!
Dad, please, don't!
Daddy!
No, no, no! Please, don't.
I didn't mean to, I swear!
I'm sorry.
Stop! Stop talking.
Stop listening.
There are only three things
that are real. You, me, and...
That.
Get up. There are no straps.
This is not a hospital.
You are not crazy.
You can make it disappear.
Do it!
Quentin?
The old alma mater
hasn't changed a lick.
Wait, you went here?
Kicked out three
months before graduation.
So, what, this is revenge?
When you're here for that
long, they can't just erase you.
They take you into a special
room off the dean's office
and remove every
memory you make here.
Every single magical thing
you learned, amputated,
but those memories are stored.
Normally, there's a shield on this
door 100 Magicians couldn't break.
Now...
Keep a lookout.
Wait, what's going...
It isn't working.
I don't know. I went
there. I told him.
The Matarese did
its thing, and then
everything went black.
He's not gonna wake up. Ever.
No, Marina just has
to... Marina is a psycho!
You were his friend.
It's her spell. I can't...
No, I didn't sign
up for this shit.
No, you have to
go reverse it. Now.
Well, I can finally
reach you again.
But that's never been
the problem, has it?
My reaching you.
Will you please,
just for once...
No more riddles, okay?
Just tell me what to do.
It doesn't matter
what anyone tells you.
You make the web you're in.
You're the spider
and the fly, just like...
Look, I can help. I can give
you the exact wording of the spell.
It's too late.
It was just supposed
to be a joke.
Yeah, bullshit. You
did it to get even.
Fuck you! Somebody help him.
If I had the exact spell
wording one hour ago...
There's got to be something.
You have any idea
where he is right now?
Why would you do this?
She didn't.
Not by herself. Did you?
You sure you want to play?
No, I'm not sure of anything.
Except I'm tired... So tired.
Of?
Fighting all the time.
Becoming someone
that I actually want to be,
and then realizing that I...
Am nothing.
So you made the hospital,
conjured that terrible thing
you never did to your father.
Of course, you're exhausted.
And you can hide
from it all, forever,
in this lovely,
quiet, blank void.
But you also built a way out.
Otherwise, why
are he and I here?
"The Madness Maker didn't play
"for the joy of winning,
just the fear of losing.
"The real curse was, he only
played when he could win,
"which cut him off
from the surprise,
"horror, sadness,
and wonder of life."
Jane saw only
one way out for him.
Stop playing.
Start living.
Somebody woke up.
Took your damn time.
Somebody get him some brandy.
Flying in.
Wait.
Where's the hedge bitch?
Chop chop. They're
going back up.
You should've told
me that your friend
wasn't properly erased.
I know.
And you and Eliot never should've
taken on the hedge witches alone.
I know.
Quentin, do you really think
that the magic that we teach
means that you just get to
fly above right and wrong?
Magic does not solve problems...
It magnifies them. I
know that, too. Believe me.
I don't need to be taught
what magic is or isn't.
I need to be taught magic,
so that I can decide
what it is or isn't.
For me.
That was almost well put.
Good night, Quentin.
Oh, and Quentin,
I'm glad that you're
still here with us.
Me, too, actually.
Wow.
I kind of can't believe
I ever thought I knew
anything.
I'd like to share now,
some of it with some of you.
Wait. Wait. No. No.
I didn't get you out of there
because you pulled one over on me.
You and Kady bitched
out, but you'd talk.
She can't.
Oh, poor you and your taste
of honey worse than none at all.
You think Brakebills
cut you off from magic?
You don't know "cut off."
But, baby...
You will.