J U LIA: Previously on
The Magicians...
QUENTIN: Before I got here,
I was in the hospital.
Quentin, I'd really
recommend further
treatment.
Look, I've never
threatened to hurt
myself or anybody else.
So you can't
make me stay.
Brakebills is the first place
that feels right to me
that is not literally
a fairy tale.
Quentin!
I made the mistake of thinking
you were just psychic.
Do you know how
to close your mind?
'Cause I will
show you right now.
You are a Traveler.
SUNDERLAND: You can actually
move between worlds.
Where you
going, kitty cat?
I'm done here. For good.
You should be happy.
Less competition.
PENNY: Hedge witches,
amateurs, sad and
desperate people.
That means level 50.
So you were...
Top bitch in New York,
for starters.
Get me everything on
this list, this week.
QUENTIN: I don't know what
you're doing here, Jules.
JULIA: Magic wasn't
just handed to me.
People at Brakebills,
Jules, they can
read minds.
They can fly. You can
do a party trick.
You were
my best friend.
It's amazing I survived
as long as I did
not knowing that
I was a Magician.
I can't go back.
(SNIFFS)
(GROANS)
(EXHALES)
Oh...
(GASPS)
Dude, you're in the wrong...
Or I'm in the wrong...
Uh...
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Hey!
Big stuff. (CHUCKLES)
Hey.
You got them?
I'm dying. Where are they?
Where are they?
Jesus!
Cut it out!
You give me happy pills,
me love you long time.
Eliot, they're
looking for you
in arts and crafts.
Watercolors.
Without me,
they're adrift.
(SLAPS)
Quentin, could
I speak to you?
(MUTTERS INDISTINCTLY)
Quentin?
Okay, this is
obviously a dream
where I realize
I'm in a dream.
So you think your
life is a dream?
No, my life is my life,
but this is like a...
This is a bad collage.
You, the hospital,
the dean's office,
the Brakebills,
it's all jumbled together.
So we're back
to Brakebills.
Hopefully, soon.
Where you think
you're a student
studying to be
a Magician.
Okay, let's just
skip the part
where you don't
believe me, okay?
Um...
Yeah, it's a little
chilly in here.
How about
a miniature sun?
That'd be great.
(SIGHS)
(TAPPING)
I hate these dreams.
It's like your feet
are stuck to the floor,
or you're paralyzed.
Wait, wait, wait.
You released me.
Remember,
in the real hospital?
I remember what
I said. What was
it? Uh...
"You can't keep me here.
I haven't hurt myself
or anybody else."
You know that
isn't true.
Well, none of
this is true,
but I said that to you
in real life before
Brakebills.
(BEEP)
Send him in.
Quentin, do you remember
why the court ordered
you to be here?
The court? I don't...
If this is a trial
dream, lam...
God, these things
take forever.
Come in, Penny.
Show me again
what you found in
Quentin's trash.
I don't want to get
nobody in trouble.
No, it's okay, Penny.
No one's in trouble.
Thank you, Penny.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Quentin, this is
what happens
when you don't take
what we prescribe.
You start to
hallucinate again
that you're a Magician,
you have powers.
It's all here.
Uh...
The house of cards,
Alice, Eliot, Margo,
the Physical Kids,
The Beast.
I know this can
all seem very real,
but it's not.
Brakebills is
the hallucination.
This is the reality.
You're seeing
this, right?
You're very,
very sick.
(RATTLING)
Are you not
seeing this?
(RATTLING CONTINUES)
Oh, Jesus!
(GASPING)
I see you, Quentin,
and I'm very, very worried.
Oh, okay, they're gone.
The moths, they're...
(SIGHS)
They're gone.
There are no moths,
Quentin. There
never were.
(BUZZING)
Ah! (CHOKING)
(BODY THUDS)
(YELLING)
Oh, I can't breathe!
(QUENTIN GASPING)
Code red!
Code red! Main office!
Don't let them see.
I heard they shot you up.
(STAMMERS)
I'm kind of foggy.
No, no, no. Just
focus on me. Okay?
None of this is real.
Just us two.
And this.
Where are we?
I mean, what's going on?
You don't remember?
I was at school,
I think, and...
And then I fell
asleep at a party,
and then I'm here.
Where none of that
ever happened, and...
No,no,no,
no,no,no.
Oh, man!
You came to find me.
I did?
To save me.
But first, we have
to break the illusion.
"The illusion"?
I crash-landed
on this planet 9.3
light years ago.
DEAN: Alice?
Wait.
You're a starship captain,
and you came to
rescue me. (CHUCKLES)
I, uh... No. Hang on.
But none of this
is real. It's...
We're trapped in a cage,
a menagerie.
DEAN: Alice?
(GROWLS)
And they show us
these illusions
to make us fall
in love and mate.
(SNAP S)
Alice, that's enough.
Give them back.
What, Dr. Fogg?
All of them, Alice.
We need them for bridge.
(GRUNTS)
They collect us from
all over the galaxy
to feed off our emotions.
No, that's not true.
It's an episode
of Lost in Space.
Star Trek.
What?
That's an episode
of Star Trek.
It's an episode of Star Trek.
They finally got to you.
You belong to them now.
(GIGGLING)
It's okay. I'll still
mate with you.
(LAUGHING)
All right, that's enough.
Me, three!
That's enough.
Me, three.
(SIGHS, CLEARS THROAT)
Quentin, how are you?
Are you feeling any better?
I guess.
Good. Are you up
for seeing a visitor?
Hey, Q.
I mean, Yale's
still kind of a letdown.
Still, in the best way.
I mean, you would've...
Well, you...
I mean, you will
totally agree, you know,
once, you know, it's you.
When what? When I'm out?
It's just so much
easier than I...
Than we expected, is all.
So you've been at Yale
these last few months...
And I've been here?
You don't remember?
This? No.
Okay-
James is sorry he
couldn't make it tonight,
but he'll be
by next week.
You know,
he had to lock
down a church.
Church?
Mmm-hmm.
For the wedding.
Are you engaged?
(CHUCKLES)
It's okay.
No, it's not okay.
Seriously,
it doesn't even matter.
It's not important.
It's a spell.
“A
We're all trapped in it,
and I'm the only one
who knows.
Okay, look.
I know that I just...
I sounded like Alice
just then, but I...
Hey, (SNIFFS)
Um, I swear, I'm not crazy.
I want to understand,
okay?
I want to help, Q.
Just tell me.
No,no,no.
(GRUNTS) No.
Okay, I can do this.
(EXHALES)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(GASPS) Oh, God, look!
(GASPING)
Jules. (GASPING)
Jules, look. Look.
Are you seeing this?
Look!
You guys, are you
not seeing this?
(STAMMERS)
(PEOPLE MURMURING
INDISTINCTLY)
(QUENTIN GRUNTS)
Don't.
What?
Look at me like that.
Don't feel sorry
for me. Do not.
I'm not me,
and you're not you,
and this is not
happening.
Do you hear me?
This is not happening.
I'm not... I'm not here.
lam the one that
got into Brakebills.
I'm in Brakebills!
PENNY: Hey, you!
Keep your voice down.
I'm sorry.
It's my fault. Um...
Sorry.
I'm gonna go, okay?
I'll be back Friday.
This can't be my life.
Jules, it can't.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
I wanted to see the fireworks.
I really did.
Wait.
How did you know
they were fireworks?
What?
If you couldn't see them,
how did you know
they were fireworks?
You told me.
I never said the word
"fireworks," Julia.
What's going on here?
(LAUGHS)
Okay, did nobody
see that?
See what?
You laughing at me.
Laughing at you?
What kind of
a friend would do that?
Exactly.
Goodbye, Quentin.
What... (GASPS)
All of them,
one by one.
Begin.
I believe you, Quentin.
You are a Magician.
A very bad one.
One thing that's real.
You're always a raging dick.
(WHISPERS) Ellsworth Downs.
Ellsworth Downs.
Ellsworth.
(SIGHS)
JANE: (ECHOING) You know.
(SNIFFS)
You know where
to look, Quentin.
I can't show you.
I can't touch you.
It's very strong,
this spell.
It is... It is a spell?
It's in the book,
the book is you.
This is all you.
Me?
Uh, which book?
Jane?
Uh,I can%
remember what, uh...
Jane, they gave me pills,
and I can't remember.
Jane!
(GROANS)
(SIGHS)
(ECHOING) Jane!
(PAPER TEARING)
No,no,no!
Stop! Stop it! Stop!
No! The answer's in
these books.
Jane said that...
(LAUGHING)
These books are my key
to getting out of here.
Jesus.
Every time I talk,
I sound batshit.
(LAUGHING)
Could I get some
tape any place?
Tape isn't permitted.
Right, I know.
But why, again?
'Cause you can harm
yourself or others.
lfstape.
That can strangle,
suffocate...
Okay, what if
you watched me
the whole time?
No one has that
kind of time.
I need to put these
pages back together.
You need to get
to music therapy.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Music is a way
for us to express
and receive feeling
in a way that is
safe and fun
and sometimes
illuminating.
So, who'd like
to begin?
PENNY: Oh, God, please
not that one song.
Ah, I'm sorry.
What was that, Penny?
Oh, that one song?
Please, no.
It gets in my head,
and it never leaves.
Oh, which song is that?
Michael Row the Boat Ashore.
(WHISPERS) #Agree.
Everything here is me.
DR. LONDON:
All right, everyone,
why don't we kick it
off with the Beatles?
Helter Skelter!
Helter Skelter, please!
I was thinking
Here Comes the...
(SINGING) I stay out too late
Got nothing in my brain
That's what people say
I go on too many dates
But I can't make them stay
At least that's
what people say
That's what people say
(PIANO PLAYING)
But I keep cruising
Can't stop, won't stop moving
it's like i got this music
in my mind saying
it's gonna be all right
'Cause the players gonna play,
play, play, play, play
He's doing this
because I made
him take his pills!
And the haters gonna hate,
hate, hate, hate, hate
No! Dr. London!
Baby, I'm just gonna shake,
shake,shake,shake,shake
Shake it off
I never miss a beat
I'm lightning on my feet
And that's what they don't see
That's what they don't see
I'm dancing on my own
I make the moves up as I go
And that's what
they don't know
That's what they don't know
Hey, Penny. Good luck
getting that out of your head.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
MAN: (ON PA)
PTSD specialist
to ward room two.
I hear you were the hit
of music therapy today,
Quentin.
Look, I think I know
what's going on here,
and I think I know
how to get help.
Well, help is why
we're here.
No, it's not.
I don't mean to be
rude, but you're here
because of a spell,
and I need to
break the spell.
Quentin.
And if I can just reach Penny,
the real Penny,
and if I can get
inside of his head...
Enough.
That's enough.
Can I please have
some tape?
Do you remember
the last time you
saw your father?
(SIGHS)
Dinner a few
months ago. Why?
Dad?
Hello, Curly Q.
...
What happened
to your face?
Did you run into a door?
You did that, Quentin.
...
(SCOFFS)
Come on.
It's time you see
something.
Look, I'm telling you,
it wasn't my dad.
It was The Beast.
l never even touched him!
I used battle magic,
the same magic
that I'm gonna use
to get out of here.
Are you ready?
Come on. Come on!
(BANGING) What did you
do to my powers?
I need my powers.
The Beast is here, okay?
He's coming for me.
He's coming for you.
He is coming to kill us.
You have got to
give me back my power!
I've got to save you!
Ahh!
DR. LONDON: Do you
remember that night?
Um...
Your father does.
Tell him, Ted.
He needs to hear it.
He needs to know
the truth why he's here.
We were having
dinner to celebrate
when you got into Yale, and...
In the middle of
the restaurant,
you suddenly said
there were moths everywhere.
No.
And then you started
calling me "The Beast."
Mmm-mmm.
You're lying.
And then you
picked up a knife.
Mmm-mmm. No.
I tried to stop you.
I grabbed you.
I tried to stop you from...
What? From what?
You tried to kill
your father, Quentin.
(WHIMPERS)
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
You need to stop
fighting this, Quentin.
The more you believe
in magic, Brakebills,
The Beast,
the more harm you do.
Accept who you are
and what's put you here.
That's how you
get better, Quentin.
I promise.
Hey, Q, seriously, talk to me.
Are you fucking with me?
(BLOWS)
Dude.
(SNAPS)
Uh, um...
Look, this'll all
be over soon, okay?
Just try not to
get buried under it.
I'm gonna talk
to someone. Shit.
(SINGING)
Play, play, play, play
Heartbreakers gonna break,
break, break, break, break
Players gonna play,
play, play, play, play
Shake it off
Players gonna play,
play, play, play, Play
Hey!
Quit singing
that stupid song!
Play, play, play
(SNAPS)
Damn it.
Quentin!
(HUMMING)
Oh, no.
Yeah, that's right.
I'm talking to you.
I told you, keep up
with that stupid song,
and I'd come right
into your brain
and rip it out.
No,no,no.
Here I am.
By the way, this is
the most pathetic
loser dream ever.
Stop, okay? Just stop.
Please stop. Stop.
Please be knowing that
dinner will be served
in five minutes,
and today, we are
to be serving
chicken curry,
which is, of course,
my favorite.
You racist
motherfucker.
You're not real.
Yeah, how's that?
Realenough?
That hurt.
Do it again, harder.
What kind of sick
shit are you about,
Goldwater?
Harder.
(BANGS)
Ow.
(PANTING)
Nobody here can see you.
Yeah, 'cause there's
no "here," dumb-ass.
This is all in your head.
I'm in your head.
Now stop singing
that song, so I can go
the fuck back to sleep.
Wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
Oh, my God. ltworked.
I did that. I called
you. I called you
with the song.
You called me?
I'm in trouble.
Seriously, help me.
What is today
out there?
Wednesday.
So I've only been
gone for a night.
Am I asleep there
somewhere?
I don't know what
you do at night,
and I don't want to know.
Where are you?
Trying to sleep.
This is not a dream.
It's a...
All of this,
it's a spell.
Please, listen.
Find me, okay?
Out there, find me.
I have to be
conscious to
break the spell.
Okay, you have to wake up.
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up.
Wake up! Wake up!
Wake up!
You, you will
not be shouting!
End it now, buster.
Wake the hell up!
(GASPS)
Okay. Good job.
Wow. (SIGHS)
My whole body,
every part of my
body is tingling.
I mean, you didn't
tell me it would...
Feel so good?
It's high-end
designer cooperative magic.
(CHUCKLES)
It does something
to your cells
to channel all thatjuice.
Everyone gets stronger.
Um...
I just, um...
didn't think
Q would fall in so deep.
This is nothing.
Uh, what does that mean?
Well, I mean he might want
to take his shoes off
and get comfortable.
We cooked up
a Whopper here.
I don't really see
him getting out of it,
even with your
boyfriend's help.
Mmm, I thought
the idea was
to just mess with him.
My idea was to
fuck him up, hard,
and you loved it
even harder.
Yeah, fuck him up,
not kill him.
Wait, what?
Kill him?
He's not gonna die.
He just might not
actually ever wake up.
(SIGHS) on, my God.
Hey, you are not
going limp on me here.
This is game time, ladies.
You got the ball, Kady.
Don't drop it.
Now go put all that
sweet hotness to work.
(SLAPS)
Sorry.
Ellsworth.
Ellsworth Downs.
Ellsworth...
Downs. Ellis...
Wirth-Downs,
Ellis Wirth-Downs.
The Madness Maker.
on, God. Okay.
"In all of Fillory,
one Magician
"could drive every
other Magician insane.
"An inventor of
puzzles with no solution
"and games where the rules
changed for no reason.
"He was called
the Madness Maker,
"but he had been
born Ellis Wirth-Downs.
(EXHALES)
"On his first
journey to Fillory,
"he played checkers
with a powerful witch.
"He cheated,
and her curse was simple.
"The only kind of magic
he would ever do again
was game magic.
"Jane Chatwin knew
"his need to make
others suffer was only
"because he felt so
alone in his cursed state.
"Because the more Ellis
played, the more insane
he became.
"But soon, Jane figured out
how to break this curse."
Thank you, Jane Chatwin.
"The Madness
Maker's curse was, uh..."
It's okay.
It's okay. I know this.
I know this. I know this.
What did Jane say?
God, why can't I remember?
(FOOTSTEPS TAPPING)
Okay, look, lam, like,
100% sure I invented you,
so if you could please
just disappear?
Look, it was a party.
He's probably
sleeping it off under
something or someone
or someone's thing.
Where you been?
I had to run
into the city.
What's up?
Your lover man here
thinks our little Q
got roofied last night.
Look, we covered
the house.
Let's start checking the lab,
the libraries, whatever.
I know where he is.
He crawled in here
and passed out around 1:00.
Anyway, I've seen weirder.
Come on.
He's breathing.
That's something.
Let me try.
This is bad.
How bad?
"We need to
tell the dean" bad.
Now what?
We wait.
(SNAP S)
When are you gonna tell me
what all this is for?
I did. Bigger,
better magic.
Yeah, you just never
mentioned how.
I guess I could
tell you now.
No, I don't feel
like it. Later, maybe?
How about never?
That's a growing
possibility.
Hmm.
Yes, I thought so.
The spell is called
the Scarlatti Web.
We cannot break it.
No one can.
Wait, he's not gonna
wake up ever?
I said "no one,"
not "nothing."
We need to summon
the Matarese.
Quentin, I really thought
we were making progress.
I was wrong.
No! What are you...
DEAN: Lower the wards, please.
Very good.
And now the south wards.
Dean Fogg following
the playbook.
The only thing that can
break our spell on your
ex-BFF is a Matarese.
Evil bug spirit
of the underworld.
About the only way
one of those can get
into this sugary wonderland
is to lower all
the protective wards
and shields in the school,
letting any old
anyone waltz right in.
Welcome back
to Brakebills.
Let's go steal
their shit.
Careful.
(CHANTING SPELL)
That's the answer?
It shorts out
the cerebral cortex,
which should break
him out of this spell,
which should bring
him back, halfway.
Halfway?
The spell is like a prison
in the middle of the desert.
The Matarese breaks
you out of the prison,
but you have to get yourself
out of the desert,
and it is a lot
easier with a guide.
Penny, are you ready?
(CHOKING)
(GAGS AND SWALLOWS)
Quentin?
Quentin! Answer me!
The problem is in your
frontal lobe, Quentin.
Your emotions are in
complete control now,
overriding logic, reason,
even the will to live.
So this...
ls inserted into
the eye socket.
No,no,no.
It's called a transorbital
lobotomy.
Dad! (WHIMPERS)
Dad. Daddy.
(GRUNTS)
No, no, no! Don't!
(GASPS)
Dad, please, don't!
Daddy! (WHIMPERS)
No,no,no!
Please, don't.
I didn't mean to,
I swear!
(SOBBING) I'm sorry.
Stop! Stop talking.
Stop listening.
There are only three
things that are real.
You, me, and...
(GAGGING)
(COUGHING)
That.
Get up.
There are no straps.
This is not a hospital.
You are not crazy.
You can make
it disappear.
DO it!
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
(EXHALES)
(LIGHTS BUZZING)
PENNYI Quentin?
MARINA: The old alma mater
hasn't changed a lick.
JULIA: Wait, you went here?
Kicked out three
months before graduation.
So, what,
this is revenge?
When you're
here for that long,
they can't just erase you.
They take you
into a special room
off the dean's office
and remove every
memory you make here.
Every single magical thing
you learned, amputated,
but those memories
are stored.
Normally, there's a shield
on this door 100 Magicians
couldn't break.
Now...
(SNAP S)
Keep a lookout.
Wait, what's going...
(GASPS)
It isn't working.
PENNY: I don't know.
I went there. I told him.
The Matarese did
its thing, and then
everything went black.
He's not gonna
wake up. Ever.
No, Marina just has to...
Marina is a psycho!
You were his friend.
It's her spell.
I can't...
No, I didn't sign
up for this shit.
No, you have to
go reverse it. Now.
(GASPING)
Well, I can finally
reach you again.
But that's never been
the problem, has it?
My reaching you.
Will you please,
just for once...
No more riddles, okay?
Just tell me what to do.
It doesn't matter
what anyone tells you.
You make the web
youwein.
You're the spider
and the fly, just like...
Look, I can help.
I can give you the exact
wording of the spell.
It's too late.
It was just
supposed to be a joke.
Yeah, bullshit.
You did it to get even.
Fuck you!
Somebody help him.
If I had the exact spell
wording one hour ago...
There's got to
be something.
PENNY: You have any idea
where he is right now?
Why would you do this?
She didn't.
Not by herself. Did you?
JANE: You sure
you want to play?
No, I'm not sure
of anything.
Except I'm tired...
So tired.
Of?
Fighting all the time.
Becoming someone that
I actually want to be,
and then realizing
that I...
Am nothing.
So you made
the hospital,
conjured that terrible thing
you never did to your father.
Of course,
you're exhausted.
And you can hide
from it all, forever,
in this lovely,
quiet, blank void.
But you also built
a way out.
Otherwise, why are
he and I here?
"The Madness Maker didn't play
"for the joy of winning,
just the fear of losing.
"The real curse was,
he only played
when he could win,
"which cut him off
from the surprise,
"horror, sadness,
and wonder of life."
Jane saw only one
way out for him.
Stop playing.
Start living.
(GAGGING, RETCHING)
(COUGHING)
(GASPS)
Somebody woke up.
Took your damn time.
Somebody get him
some brandy.
Flying in.
Wait.
Where's the hedge bitch?
(PANTS) Chop chop.
They're going back up.
(LAUGHS)
You shou
d've told me
that your friend
wasn't properly erased.
I know.
And you and Eliot
never should've taken on
the hedge witches alone.
I know.
Quentin, do you
really think
that the magic that
we teach
means that you just
get to fly above
right and wrong?
Magic does not
solve problems...
It magnifies them.
I know that, too.
Believe me.
I don't need to be taught
what magic is or isn't.
I need to be taught magic,
so that I can decide
what it is or isn't.
For me.
That was almost well put.
Good night, Quentin.
Oh, and Quentin,
I'm glad that you're
still here with us.
Me, too, actually.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
Wow. (SIGHS)
WOW. (LAUGHING)
I kind of can't believe
lever thought I knew
anything. (CHUCKLES)
I'd like to share now,
some of it with
some of you.
(SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
Wait. Wait. No. No.
I didn't get you out
of there because you
pulled one over on me.
You and Kady bitched
out, but you'd talk.
She can't. (CHUCKLES)
Oh, poor you and
your taste of honey
worse than none at all.
You think Brakebills
cut you off from magic?
You don't know "cut off."
But, baby...
(WHOOSHING)
You Will.