ALICE: Previously
on The Magicians...
FRIAR JOSEPH: As a
Niffin, you made enemies.
One of them seeks
you... The Lamprey.
You're down to an
early warning device.
An alarm, if you will.
What is that, a joke?
Cancer. Call it cancer plus.
Every time you
leave this branch,
you go where time
moves normally,
and where time progresses...
So does my super cancer. I know.
I wanna do a spell. A cheat day.
I'm just putting
it all together.
Just tell me what you think,
and could you maybe
try a Russian accent?
Mayakovsky. That's a battery.
That holds magical current.
How many of those do you have?
My people need
help. They sure do.
I'll send you on an epic quest.
JULIA: The Tale
of the Seven Keys.
Jules, this is our quest.
And we're already on it.
QUENTIN: The Tale
of the Seven Keys.
Chapter one.
"Long ago, in a far-off kingdom,
"lived the daughter
of a brave knight.
"The knight had
always wanted a son
"to whom he might
pass on his skills.
"So, while father and
daughter loved one another,
"she often felt herself a
disappointment to him.
"One day, a witch
kidnapped the knight.
"The daughter pleaded
with her to return him.
"The witch said no,
but he could be rescued
"if the girl could
complete a quest.
"" There are seven
keys, ' said the witch.
"" Find them, and you can
open your father's prison...
"" The Castle At The
End of the World.'
"The witch told the daughter
the first key was to be found
"on an island
beyond her kingdom,
"so she sailed past
the Outer Islands.
"And while the voyage
was treacherous,
"her destination was more so,
"for nothing was as it
seemed on After Island."
Wow. Okay.
So, then...
QUENTIN: Then...
Jesus.
This book is more withholding
than my last girlfriend.
Right, so the first quest
is in Fillory.
Eliot's taking point.
Yeah, but we should
be there with him.
JOSH: Hell, yeah, we should.
Quests are not a solo op,
and thanks to Dean Fogg and
the world's biggest FedEx bill,
we've got the clock.
So all we need is magic.
Which is where
you come in, right?
Wrong. I mean, that
would be like trying
to power a Ferrari
on a drop of unleaded.
So we power this puppy how?
Mayakovsky. Yes.
Can I focus on something I
don't wanna punch in the face?
He had four batteries
in Brakebills South.
He said that's
all he had, but...
He's a lying drunk, so
of course he had more.
And he's been MIA since
magic got shut down.
And if he's roaming the
earth, he's using them.
If only to scam chicks.
Any ideas where?
No.
I mean, magic
might be dead, but...
Google isn't.
So...
We're out of dough.
Moolah.
Chedda.
Money, people.
Magic's gone.
We can't even control the
gold-shitting beetles anymore,
and now they've
declared themselves free
and disappeared.
We're about to be
a third world country
on a planet with two
and a half countries.
Yes, which is why the
Council and I are wondering
why we're spending so much money
on a very old ship.
Thank you for
asking, Queen Margo.
The Muntjac is the fastest
boat in our ancient, leaky fleet,
and the best way to
reach the Outer Islands,
where taxes haven't
been collected in...
46 years, 3 months, and 7 days.
So let's just be clear here
about how government works.
We can't do anything
without money.
Now, if there are any
dissenting opinions
as to my royal order,
I will remind the Council
that this is not a democracy.
Truer words never spoken.
And this meeting
is to inform all assembled
here what I intend to do.
We'll see.
(SOFT MUSIC PLAYING)
Me, either.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
(UTENSILS CRASHING)
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
Guys?
Is that a hedge witch bar?
Caught my eye.
What... Where'd you find this?
YouTube. Urban Freakfest.
Was just posted.
(BEAR ROARS)
WOMAN: Stop it, Mischa, no!
Okay, that's cool.
Point one,
Mayakovsky's first name...
Mischa. Right.
The "Joe" of Russia.
Point two, the
symbol of Russia...
A brown bear.
Point three... Recognize that?
Yeah, that does
kinda look like...
Yep. And point four...
(GLASS SHATTERING) (BEAR ROARS)
That bear is a dick.
Da.
(CRASHING) (SHOUTING)
(CATS MEOWING)
ALICE: How old is this one?
Moses is eight months.
That's too old.
What about...
First, I... Need to know
whether you have
fully accepted Jesus
as your savior.
Pardon?
ALICE: What about this one?
MAN: Hester is five months.
I'll take her.
(PURRING)
MAN: I do need
you to swear to me
that you'll protect this animal,
and Hester shall see no evil.
(DRILLING) (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(CLICKING)
(HISSING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(BEAR GROWLING)
So, wait, Mayakovsky
uses the last drops of magic
anywhere for a bar trick?
Or maybe someone did it to him.
Or the bear could
just be a bear.
Look, do you
recognize this place?
(SCOFFS)
You said you had
something else to show me?
(STAMMERING) Wait... How?
I don't know, but
it's all I can do,
which is almost worse
than nothing at all.
But if Mayakovsky
was in New York City
with a battery big enough
to turn himself into a bear,
maybe there are more.
And if Julia could get her hands
on one of those batteries...
Then maybe we could help Penny.
That is a hedge bar.
I was 86-ed, so just get us in.
Yeah, well, recent history
doesn't do much for your credibility
when it comes to
you, me, and a plan.
How sick is Penny? Fuck you.
Look, if Penny
doesn't need magic, go.
D. Hey.
Hey.
It's good to see you, K.
Yeah, you too.
So, the bear?
Yeah, that was weird. I mean...
I've seen weirder, but
not in a while.
It kinda gave me hope.
Yeah.
Do you remember what
happened right before?
Yeah, you could
smell it first, then feel it.
I mean, everyone in here could.
You know, it's like, you're
starving for two months
and all of a sudden, steak's
on the grill, you know?
The whole room started buzzing
and everyone zeroed in
on this drunk Russian guy
and the girl he came in with.
QUENTIN: Uh, is...
Was that, um...
Was that the guy? DONOVAN: Yeah.
Jeez, that guy's a prick.
JULIA: Wait, I'm sorry,
are you saying
that it's possible
he turned himself into a bear?
You know what? That
guy was so wasted.
I don't think he knew
what he was doing.
And the girl was
trying to control him,
but she wasn't exactly sober,
so it was a lot at once.
Anything else you can remember?
She was way too
young for that guy.
Wait, was that
her? Is that the girl?
Yeah, that's her. Yep.
All right, hey, I should
probably see her alone.
Well... Emily, even at her best,
which she's probably
not right now, is a little...
Crazy?
Vulnerable.
(PILLS RATTLING) (SIGHS)
(BELCHES)
Wow, that did not help at all.
Maybe just give it a sec.
I've given it a day. (LAUGHS)
'Course, I've been
drunk for about a week...
So there's that. Do
you want a beer?
Oh... You do.
You want one. Come on.
So, how did you guys
end up at that bar?
Oh, good story.
Well, last week,
Mischa just showed up
at my door... Very dramatic,
telling me how he was
free of the bond, he said,
and that he'd always loved me
and he always would.
Oh.
Well, that's great. Yeah!
So after, you know, a
couple hours in bed...
Just, like...
We decided to celebrate.
I remember the
first five or six bars,
a hotel, I think, or,
some kind of room.
Maybe it was an Uber. Anyway.
We got married.
You...
Wow. Do you like? (LAUGHS)
Congratulations.
Yeah, I think after
how bad it was before,
he felt like he had to
prove his love, you know?
He had to... He had to...
(IN RUSSIAN ACCENT)
Make it permanent.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Right.
So how did he become a bear?
Oh, you know, I don't know.
I mean, 'cause that's some
really powerful magic.
Considering that magic is dead.
Yeah.
Yeah, we met someone...
At a bar, someone he owed...
Something to.
Maybe a battery?
I don't know. Honestly.
It was a woman.
Yeah, I really had to pee,
so I hit the ladies', and I
heard all this screaming.
Next thing, he is... He is...
He's hulking out of his clothes,
and he's getting all hairy.
And he's now... He's
full bear, and he's...
Just tearing the place apart.
Right, but... So you think
it was that woman that...
If it was, and you find her,
could you rip her
fucking face off?
Because now I am
married to a zoo animal.
This better be good, Tick.
Majesty,
I know something of this vessel,
and I feel obligated to, uh,
warn you.
Can I please just enjoy the fact
that I have a beautiful
boat and I'm setting off
on a fabulous adventure
for just one second?
Of course, Sire.
ELIOT: Good.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Parade in my head complete.
Make it rain.
PICKWICK: First and foremost,
never forget this boat is
made from sentient trees
and therefore has, well,
a personality.
And, uh...
Your Majesty.
Admiral Lacker.
Admiral.
Welcome to the Muntjac, Sire.
There's no faster
boat in all of Fillory
and certainly none more
wise in the ways of seafaring.
Fast. Wise.
You hear that, Tick?
LACKER: If you'll follow me.
Nice trick.
The Muntjac designed herself
to explore, do
battle, and deceive.
She can carry threescore
most comfortably.
I sense she's most
excited for this journey.
(LOW RUMBLING)
Her heartwood, Sire.
(RHYTHMIC BEATING)
Happy to see us, I think.
ELIOT: I don't know, Tick.
Off your storm warning,
I was expecting a
Kanye-level diva,
but I'm not even getting
a whiff of atty-patty.
Don't be fooled, Sire.
To use your parlance,
this boat can be a bit of an...
Ass-ditch. (CHUCKLES)
Ass-ditch?
Ass-trench?
Grave? No.
Hole. Asshole!
(SCREAMS) Oh!
(PICKWICK EXCLAIMS)
You all right there, Tick?
Fine, Majesty.
ELIOT: We'll require
a master swordsman.
Bingle should be more
than adequate, Sire.
The one who won't talk?
My understanding is he feels
any conversation
impedes concentration,
which, as a swordsman,
is unmatched,
with 72 kills and
never a scratch on him.
Well, you can't
argue with success.
Or a swordsman who won't talk.
Going somewhere, dear wife?
On the voyage with you.
After all, I found the boat.
And I'm forever grateful,
but I do not think
this is a good idea.
Why?
It's perhaps a
concept you're a little
too distracted to get.
It's an excellent idea.
I should know. It was mine.
Any particular reason?
Yes.
But I don't actually
need one, do I?
It'll be wonderful, won't it?
The sea, the sky. Us.
So romantic.
Additionally... Oh, Jesus.
I require someone I
trust to accompany you.
We call her Frail Human.
Fray for short.
Say hello, Fray.
I'd like you to
meet your daughter.
What? No.
ELIOT: Mmm-mmm. FEN: No.
No. Our child is a baby.
In the fairy realm,
time folds in on
itself and accelerates.
Fray, I'd like you to meet
your father and mother.
I think it's best
that you both know
I serve and am devoted
only to my queen.
And I feel nothing
for either of you.
(LAUGHS) (LOG CLATTERS)
Ugh. God.
What a cliché.
The baby that becomes a teenager
practically overnight?
Right?
Angel. Twilight.
Buffy. Technically,
Buffy's sister was never a baby.
She just appeared out of nowhere
and oh, my God.
Two months without
dick, I sound like Quentin.
The point is,
only a creature from
the land TV forgot
would think anybody would fall
for how shocking
and original this is.
So you don't think
Fray is your daughter?
(SCOFFS) Do you
see any resemblance?
I see your wife swooning.
Three hours ago, my
wife was burping a log.
Still.
She has a quality.
Called unearned imperiousness.
Your defining characteristic.
Until you earned it.
Don't tell me you're
falling for this shit.
I mean, look, I'm just saying.
On the off chance she is yours,
you're not gonna strand her
or lock her up or
throw her overboard.
I will do any of the above
and worse if she disobeys me.
Disobeys what,
Father? Jesus fuck!
(CLEARS THROAT)
Never do that.
Mmm! Bingle.
You take good care of your
king and his crew, okay?
Mmm-hmm.
(SIGHS SHARPLY)
Now, one last thing.
What you're doing
is very heroic.
Now, I mean that.
But what's the difference
between a live hero
and a dead moron?
Food tasters?
No.
One dumb decision.
So when it's be brave
or be smart...
You know which one, okay?
A woman. That's not a lot.
Except someone
has big magic, so...
Or had.
It could've all got used
up on Mayakovsky.
No, I don't think so.
The hedges,
they're all going
crazy with rumors
that magic is happening
all over the city.
Central Park sex magic make-out
sessions devolving into orgy.
Fuck. Why didn't I ever do that?
And at St. Brennan's,
someone conjured a dinosaur.
Yeah, I mean,
both places, the rumor
is, it's a female Magician.
White, 30s, a
little off her rocker.
Okay, well we should
split up and cover both.
Yeah.
You're taking sex
magic, aren't you?
Let's go.
BOY: It was awesome.
Wait. What was, hon?
What magazine do
you write for again?
National Geographic.
A dinosaur, right
there in the courtyard.
You wouldn't happen to know
what kind of
dinosaur, would you?
One of the kids drew a
picture of what we all wanted.
We made it up,
and she made it real.
And how big?
And how hungry...
Medium. And it's a herbivore.
That's good to know.
We named it Androsaurus.
So it looks like half
man, half dinosaur?
How'd you know?
Well, andro, it's Greek for...
I think I need to see
some credentials.
(DISTANT ROARING)
CHILD: Dinosaur!
CHILD 2: There it is!
WOMAN: Wait, wait. Stop.
Get away from the window!
(ROARING)
Come on.
Come on. What?
Maybe it'll go to
whoever conjured it.
Come on. Slow down!
KADY: Let's go!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
I honestly wake up in the
morning and pretty much
nothing I think is going
to happen, happens.
Shh! Shut up. (ROARING)
(FAINT SNARLING)
JOSH: Okay, just
don't go so fast.
Better?
Well,
I have nothing left to
puke, so technically I'm...
Aye, aye.
You should get some rest.
In a bit.
Fen.
I know you have
your doubts, but...
She has your eyes.
In that she has
two facing forward,
yes, she's got my eyes.
She's ours.
I feel it.
You don't?
I want to. I do.
But all I know is that
she is huge for a two-month-old.
Look, she is a spy
for the Fairy Queen.
It's probably better if
she's not our daughter.
All my life, I've wanted
a family of my own.
And I know this isn't ideal.
We've missed so
much with her, but...
It's not her fault.
She needs the one thing
in life she's never had.
Manners?
Love.
(WOMEN MOANING)
Hi, excuse me,
I was just... I don't
mean to interrupt.
Oh! No, no. I'm...
I'm not interested.
But thanks for the offer though.
That's very kind.
Hi, I know this might
be a little awkward,
maybe not the best time.
No, I was just wondering
if maybe you had seen someone.
Hi, sorry.
I just wanted to ask
if maybe one of you...
All right, super helpful.
Appreciate... Whoa.
No, no, no, no, no. On.
You okay? Yeah.
Yeah. Okay.
Okay. I don't...
I don't know what just happened.
I'm just gonna...
I feel...
Let's do a lap.
ELIOT: I still don't
think it's a good idea
for you two to come along.
Our first family trip.
Oh, God.
Are you crying?
I hereby declare After Island
a province of Fillory!
(PERSON COUGHS)
Hello.
I'm your new king.
No need to bow or cheer.
I have an extremely
healthy self-image.
Where's your leader?
Governor? Mayor?
Tin pot dictator?
Father Poe is in
prayer, preparing.
For? The attack.
By?
The... The monster.
Of course.
WOMAN: Husband,
we should offer our
king refreshment.
Let's just get back
to the monster thing
for just one second.
It... It tries to kill
us every few days.
That's troubling.
Father Poe will
protect us, as always.
Now he'll protect you as well.
Do you like roasted boar?
Just stop it. No means no.
Come on.
Alice?
Shit. Alice, hey.
How did you... What
are you doing here?
Same as you, I guess.
Following all this crazy magic,
hoping it leads to
Mayakovsky's batteries.
(PEOPLE MOANING)
By yourself?
Took four of us to...
Well, you are Alice Quinn.
Yeah, whoever that is now.
Can I just say something? No!
(PEOPLE MOANING)
Okay.
One question.
(MEOWS)
I needed a pet.
Is that so weird?
All right,
everybody who's doing what
you're doing to each other,
stop immediately, or
you will be arrested.
Hey. Hey.
Did you get anything?
Uh, so,
this was cast by
a woman, clearly,
although the muggles
didn't know that.
They said she was talking
about the loss of magic,
and the need for wonder.
Okay, did you get a name, or...
No, just that she was asking
where the nearest
building was to jump off of.
The old post office on 58th.
How do you know that?
Abandoned building, easy
roof access, and great views.
It was the number
one midtown spot
when I was into that kind
of thing as a possibility.
(INAUDIBLE)
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Father Poe.
I understand you have
a bit of a monster issue.
I'd be happy to send
my navy, but first,
I'm looking for something.
(WHISPERING) A golden key.
It can't be that easy.
I'm sorry, Sire,
it's impossible for
me to give you this.
Oh, well... (CLEARS THROAT)
As your new monarch,
I'm afraid I have to insist.
It's the only thing
keeping us alive.
(RUSTLING)
MAN: It's coming back!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Holy shit.
Call 911.
Wait, are you... Q!
Q, what are you...
(ROARING)
POE: Majesty, I urge you.
Hide!
(GROWLING)
(ROARING)
(PRAYING INDISTINCTLY)
(PANTING)
Hey! Hey, hey, hey! Hey!
Quentin?
Professor Lipson?
Hey, it's nice to see you, um...
Stop!
(PANTING HEAVILY)
(CHANTING) (ROARING)
Oh, Jesus. It's Lipson.
Who?
Please.
You don't wanna do this.
(PANTING HEAVILY)
Not after you just made
such beautiful magic.
Magic is dead.
No, but it's not, and you
proved that today, right?
With Mayakovsky's battery.
It's not his.
It's mine.
Yes, of course, of course it is.
Do you think that he
could make this without me?
Where do you think he got
the living metal in Antarctica?
Me. Me.
Everything he asked
for, I gave him everything.
The fucking bastard!
Yes, God, totally.
I told him...
I was the one that told him
that this day would come,
that it wouldn't last.
And that was so smart.
We all... We
should've seen that.
And then he walks in there
with that fucking
slut, that whore!
Calling her his wife?
The goddamn world is ending!
And all we have is each other,
and he does this to me now!
Look, he is the worst, and
he got what he deserved,
but I get what you
did. You were raging
against the dying of the light.
Yes. Yes.
We really didn't know
how good we had it, did we?
We whined and complained
about everything
that magic couldn't do
because we couldn't see
that a world without it was
dark and mean and pointless.
Yeah. Exactly.
QUENTIN: Whoa,
no, no! Please, please.
(PEOPLE GASPING)
It was me. It was
my fault, okay?
And I'm going to fix it.
Look, we've already...
We've started...
You can't fix this, Quentin.
It's over. It's over.
This. This is all there is.
And I used it to
give joy to sick kids,
and to bring love to strangers
who were dead inside.
And you know
what? I hope he sees.
I hope he sees and
knows that I used all of it
for something that
he would never use!
Look, he got what
he deserved, okay?
Honestly, I think that it was
brilliant turning him into a bear.
A bear? What? What
are you talking about?
In the bar, when you met him,
and he brought Emily,
and he gave you that,
and you turned him in...
God, I don't know what
you're talking about.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SCREAMS) (PEOPLE GASP)
(SCREAMING) Quentin, let me go!
Let me go!
Quentin!
Yeah, then we
lost it on Madison.
I still think it went
into that falafel place.
No, you were hungry.
So was he.
And it was a
vegan falafel place,
so, herbivore. Logic. Whatever.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
KADY: Hello?
He's what? Where?
Okay, not to be a
cold-hearted bastard,
but I'm a cold-hearted bastard.
The battery?
Well, that's just unfair.
There's something that...
I told Lipson that I
thought it was great
that she turned
Mayakovsky into a bear,
and she had no idea
what I was talking about.
Well, yeah, because
she's insane.
Well, I just,
I don't think that she did it.
Then who did?
Someone else at the bar.
Who had another battery?
Yeah, but is...
Oh, God.
(CAT SNARLING)
What... (CAT HISSING)
(INDISTINCT POLICE
CHATTER ON RADIO)
Sorry, Officer.
Our friend's cat was sick
and exploded.
You know, like they do.
(COUGHING)
Is it dead?
It can't be killed.
How do you know?
She's right.
It's a shadow bat.
It's not really alive,
so it can't be killed.
We have them in the Fairy Realm.
Husband.
No. No!
He didn't get inside.
I couldn't save him.
I'm sorry.
Now you see.
I can never give you this key.
Hey, open the door.
We know you have the battery...
What happened?
You're not as
quick as your friend.
She took it.
Alice?
Kady.
She's the only one
who hits that hard.
Wait, you had the
battery the whole time?
Of course I did.
So, wait, so,
you turned Mayakovsky
into a bear? Mmm-hmm.
Isn't he your husband?
Which is the only
reason I didn't kill him.
Where's Kady?
I kinda missed it
'cause I was on the ground.
Bleeding.
My child,
you do not grieve alone.
I, the Father, grieve with you.
You do not des...
WOMAN: Get away from him!
POE: Please.
Tell her not to do that.
Fray!
(WHISPERING INAUDIBLY)
Pardon me for one second.
You sure?
I've seen the wounds
the shadow bat makes.
The fangs are serrated.
The wounds are messy.
And much...
Bigger.
And as the daughter
of a blademaker,
I'm telling you
a blade killed the villager.
Okay, so I'll go to Brakebills.
Q, you try the restaurant
where she works,
and Josh, you wanna
take her apartment?
Look, I just need to know
the action plan, okay?
If I do find her, do I,
what, just grab the battery?
Even if she's using it
at that exact moment
to save Penny?
And even if saving Penny
means the battery's dead?
Or the battery has
enough juice to save Penny
and help us, she just
doesn't want me to have it.
I mean, which I totally
get, from her perspective.
Only I'm not her, I'm me,
and I'm trying to fix the whole
fuckness that is the universe.
Look, let's just find
her, and then we'll
figure out all the moral Jenga.
Said he needed to see you.
I tried to get him to come
inside, but he wouldn't.
Thanks, Maggie.
Should I call an ambulance? No.
No, no, no. Thanks.
I can handle this.
Okay. PENNY: Hi.
God, what the fuck, dude?
I just...
I felt like it was
my time, and I...
I just wanted to be
with you when I...
No, no.
No, you're not going to, okay?
Holy shit. Yeah.
Come on.
Let's get you out of here.
(CROWD EXCLAIMS)
What is the meaning of this?
Excellent question.
I have an idea.
Let's test it out.
(GROANING SOFTLY)
Bingle? (CLEARS THROAT)
Kill him.
(CROWD GASPS) Or...
Do it.
Do what?
One more word
and you'll be dead.
But I'll still have
the key, so...
Do it.
(CHANTING IN OTHER LANGUAGE)
(GROWLING) (PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Guys!
Your new king
commands you to stay put!
(ROARING)
(CROWD SCREAMING)
Gee, Father.
Weren't you scared?
It's illusion magic.
He's been using it
to make you all afraid.
There is no monster.
Well, I guess he
kinda qualifies,
because how many of you
have died at the
hands of your priest
to make him your
uncontested leader and hero?
MAN: My friend lost his life.
Reminds me of what a
good friend once told me.
What's the difference
between a hero and a moron?
One bad decision.
No.
No! No!
He's lying.
He's lying to you!
(SCREAMING) No! No!
No!
I know you're behind me.
Thank you, by the way.
We wouldn't have been
able to figure it out without...
You didn't do it.
Do what?
What you told my
queen you came to do...
Collect taxes... You
just came for that key.
Why?
It's gold.
And magic.
Maybe the only magic anywhere.
What could be more
valuable than that?
I'm not sure I believe you.
And I can't believe I
finally get to say this.
Don't talk back to
your father and me.
That felt nice, didn't it?
I am here to assure
that... My turn.
Go to your room.
We're a family.
Well, we are certainly
fucked up enough to be.
Holy shit.
Hey.
Help you?
(GROWLS) (QUENTIN GRUNTS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GROANS)