JULIA: Previously
on The Magicians...
JOSH: What are we going to do?
MARGO: We got to kill the Dark King.
Fillory can never be free so
long as the Dark King reigns.
Surprised?
You must stop this,
whatever the cost.
Well, the cost is blowing
up the entire planet.
Which is... A decent option?
So you're saying
we can use the Ark,
rescue the people, blow up
Fillory and stop the Dark King?
JULIA: Do these fiends...
Do they succeed in stealing the
people and building a new world for them?
I made no mention
of a new world.
It is you. You and your
friends are the invading force.
What about the World Seed?
From Q's page? If we could find it,
we could use it to build a
new world. A new Fillory.
We're looking for the Couple.
If it was anything else.
But they have something we need.
The World Seed.
The most valuable
object in the multiverse.
Which is why I
wanted to steal it.
We spent months constructing a
map. We called it our Heist Book.
Here.
ALICE: Is that Gavin
from the Library?
What happened to you?
Marina hired me
to rob the Couple.
She didn't tell us that
the plan was suicidal
without the Harmonic
Convergence.
You twats stopped the Convergence.
There wasn't enough magic.
Marina sent us in anyway.
Give me the page.
(SNIPPING) (SCREAMS)
Okay, you win.
(GASPS) It's yours.
Bottling our
emotions, literally.
(ALL GASP SHARPLY)
This must be what undergoing
the Vulcan ritual of Kalanaur is like.
I like your sweater.
Are you saying that to be cruel?
No, I saw no
reason not to share.
(ALL INHALING)
(GROANS)
I planned my whole
outfit around that bottle!
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING) Ow.
(MURMUR OF CHATTER)
God, shut up.
What's happening to you
looks just like what
happened to my mom.
The episodes didn't stop when
I was born. They got worse.
The Circumstances control panel?
We figured if the Couple is
going to use the World Seed,
they need clean magic, So,
without this, they are stuck.
The Couple just got
the last thing they need.
They have the Seed,
the page and the Panel.
We gotta tell the others. They
need to steal that Seed now.
MARINA: Okay, guys.
This is a horrible story.
I really hate telling it, and
I'm only going to say it once.
(SIGHS)
The Nave Hotel...
Current home of the
Couple for two reasons.
One, the house rules.
Per a jamming spell, you
can't do any battle magic.
Wards prevent traveling in
and out, cell phones don't work,
and if you're caught
with any kind of weapon,
or engage in any
sort of physical beef
or try to scam the hotel or
any of its guests, bye-bye.
Idea being, The Nave is the magical
world's number-one safe space,
which is strictly
enforced by the Bellhops.
Arguing is allowed.
Physical altercation is not.
MARINA: The creepy dicks are golems
who've been enchanted to be empaths.
Goodbye, ladies.
MARINA: They have to see you,
but if they can and you radiate the
kind of micro-aggressions they sense,
you get the boot... Or worse.
We were up to some major
no good, so we steered clear.
In the basement, reason two
the Couple settled at The Nave.
The vault.
Famously impenetrable.
Except, I thought, vulnerable
during the Harmonic Convergence,
which you fucked
into a cocked hat.
Hence, the safe
crack was slow going.
But punching a hole in the
anti-Traveler wards was right on sched.
Meanwhile, I was running
it all from a safe distance.
Or trying to.
That place has some killer
protections against magical spyware.
GAVIN: Marina?
Marina? Looks like I'm in.
(LAUGHS)
Crikey, it is
dick-shrivel cold in here.
Long story, unbearable, there
was no World Seed in the vault.
(MAN GRUNTS) (THUD)
(MAN GROANS)
MARINA: And then, because
the vault took so long to crack
without the Harmonic
Convergence,
it all went horribly
pear-shaped.
(BLOW LANDS)
And we know what that
meant for poor Gavin.
(GRUNTING)
So, boosting anything from that hotel
without the Harmonic Convergence?
Is a shit show.
What makes you ducklings
think you can do any better?
Well, for one thing,
you had bad information.
Remind me who in the
Disney princess fuck you are?
She's someone who can read this.
It turns out it's a form of
Fillorian used in Ember worship.
I really should've
recognized it.
So, according to the page,
the World Seed can only live
when the temperature is 99
degrees with 99% humidity.
The vault was freezing.
There's no way the Couple
would keep it there. It would die.
This is so you guys.
Top info. Too late.
Wrong.
'Cause now we know
where the Seed isn't,
so us guys are doing this. Yup.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
PENNY: No. JULIA: Look,
I get this is hard, okay?
Julia, No. But we have
to do everything we can
in our power to make sure
that our child has a
better mother than you did.
He already does. She might.
If we can find out what
happens to Traveler moms.
And the only one that
we can talk to is yours.
I don't even know
where she is. I do.
Connecticut. According
to the locator spell.
Okay, you realize you are
getting more intense every day
and impossible to argue
with, and it is kind of scary.
Hormones, dude. Enjoy the ride.
So I lensed the
outside of the hotel,
and this room is 30 degrees
hotter than all the others.
It's got to be where the Couple
has the World Seed stashed.
Also, there's someone in there,
probably a guard.
Brava!
But stealing the Seed means
taking it out of that hot house.
How do you transport
it without killing it?
Now you tell me. I don't know.
But the Couple did.
Magnus Dellacorte.
Top Hedge, West Coast.
Best friends, George
and Paloma Ball.
(SCOFFS) The Balls.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Explains why they
go by the Couple.
Magnus lost two things the
night of his 53rd birthday party.
His life, to a coronary,
and the World Seed,
both courtesy of the Couple,
who aren't such good
friends but badass bandits.
But how did they
get the Seed out?
Five minutes in the
open air and it's dead.
Paloma's wearing couture.
Maybe they kept it warm
with their white-hot taste.
Except that bag. It's a Birkin
knock-off. And a shit one.
Really? Looks kind
of fancy. To you.
Which is why you're so adorable.
Maybe the bag is homemade?
ZELDA: Some kind of...
incubator they cooked up.
To keep the Seed toasty.
Good job, class.
ELIOT AND KADY: Hmm.
MARINA: Couple's suite.
MARGO: We make sure
they aren't there, we break in,
find the incubator bag,
which'll definitely be on site
because Paloma would never
wear it unless it was to steal the Seed.
Might be criminal Tiffany's,
but it's fashion Walmart.
We go to temperature control. We
crank the Seed Room down to freezing.
The guard freaks out. Cell
phones don't work in The Nave,
so he has to call the Couple
on a land line, which is dead.
Because I cut it.
He goes full pant-shit,
has to find the Couple.
Opens the Seed Room
door. JOSH: Runs out.
We're right there. MARGO:
With the homemade hot pocket,
we drop the Seed in, and jet.
The guard'll see you.
Three against one. Bellhops?
We pull the fire alarm, blend into
the emotional pandemonium, exit.
With a nod to Fantastic
Beasts. One problem.
What's happening in the
basement needs to be timed
to the second with what's
happening in the Seed Room.
Take too long and the
Seed'll freeze to death.
And with all
communications jammed,
how is each team supposed
to know what to do and when?
Well, there's the
conductor spell.
Created by a conductor
who was going blind.
So he and his orchestra
could still communicate.
Wouldn't all those voices
be kind of confusing?
Each musician only hears the
conductor, but never one another.
I'm totally sure I don't understand,
and totally sure it's going to work.
Why wouldn't it set off
the hotel protections?
The spell was
designed to help artists,
so by nature, it's innocuous.
You'll be the conductor, then?
I would,
but I don't know
the hotel, not like...
So, wait, not only are we
breaking into a hotel of horrors,
but our conductor has
to be a psychopath?
Sociopath, technically.
And you wrote my
Word As Bond yourself.
What happened to that arrogant
self-confidence you're so famous for?
(SIGHS QUIETLY)
Oops. Right.
Look, if you're too scared
to pull your weight...
I'm fine. As long as Zelda's
there to keep an eye on you.
(SOFTLY) Okay.
That should adjust
for Circumstances.
Remember, you have
to keep hold of the baton.
If you let go, it
breaks the spell.
Shall we test it?
Okay, kids, get ready
to be my sock puppets.
MAN: (MUFFLED)
What is this sorcery?
Woman in my
head, reveal yourself.
ZELDA: He must have
been in range of the spell.
So I have to run a heist
with a pig in my head?
What the shit with the gun?
It is to put in the
hands of a hero
who will do what is
just and necessary.
Which is?
Assassinate she who
plots to destroy Fillory.
Julia Wicker.
(ALL EXCLAIM) What
the hell is wrong with you?
Wait, is this thing loaded?
Well, of course it is!
Just... All right, get out. You know
what? How about we cook you?
MARGO: You hear me,
bacon? MARINA: It's hilarious.
No, no. Please, people. The
fate of my world is at stake.
Gentlemen, please,
control your spinsters.
(WOMEN EXCLAIM)
(CLAMORING)
Give me the gun.
(UPBEAT ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
JOSH: Guys? Are
you seeing this, too?
(SINGING) I can't
take another heartache
Though you say you're my friend
I'm at my wits' end
You say your love is bona fide
But that don't coincide
With the things that you do
And when I ask you
to be nice, you say
You've gotta be cruel to be kind
In the right measure
Cruel to be kind
It's a very good sign
Cruel to be kind Means
that I love you, baby
You've gotta be cruel
You've gotta be cruel to be kind
Well, I do my best
to understand, dear
But you still mystify
And I want to know why
I pick myself up off the ground
To have you knock me back down
Again and again
And when I ask you
to explain, you say
ALL: You've gotta
be cruel to be kind
In the right measure
Cruel to be kind
It's a very good sign
Means that I love you, baby
You've gotta be cruel
You've gotta be cruel to be kind
Baby
(MUSIC STOPS)
You see? This is why I don't
hang out with you people.
But on the bright side,
we were pitch-perfect.
(SNORTS)
(LAUGHING)
(JOSH CHUCKLES)
I will kill Julia. You have my
solemn word as a devout Catholic.
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
A hero has risen.
With a most excellent
singing voice.
Huh.
Well, we'll karaoke in Fillory.
Because it's definitely not
getting destroyed. (CHUCKLES)
(BIDS FAREWELL IN
SPANISH) (CHUCKLING)
I think I speak for the group
in wondering why the fuck
did we all just chorus line?
Yeah, and I heard all of you
in my head, not just Marina.
Yeah. What the hell? KADY:
What in the world was that?
Our Circumstances are unstable.
Our collective surge of emotion
must have broken down
some of the spell's barriers.
And as for the singing, well, it
was designed by a conductor,
and music is the purest
manifestation of feeling.
So let me get this straight.
Every time we have a feeling,
we're gonna go full-on Glee?
That doesn't seem ideal
for, you know, a heist.
Wait, do you guys remember
when we were learning battle magic?
If the spell's gonna make us break out
into song every time we get worked up,
why don't we
emotion-bottle ourselves?
'Cause that went
so well the last time.
No, no, that's good.
Might also help avoid
Bellhop detection.
No emotions for them to sense.
So repress the
overwhelming urge to sing
while stealing shit.
It's eight grade all over again.
(INDISTINCT PA CHATTER)
Um, hi, I'm looking
for a patient.
Name? Neela Adiyodi.
Oh. There must be some mistake.
I'm Neela Adiyodi.
I spent my whole life thinking
my mom was a basket case.
You're telling me she's fine.
She was fine with me. We
need to see how she is with you.
Look,
I won't pretend I can even
imagine what this is like for you.
But you won't be alone.
(GRUNTING)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(YELPS)
We're in.
Marina, you copy?
Loud and clear. (SIGHS)
How you guys feeling? We're not.
Pete,
you're up. Oh.
(EXHALES HEAVILY)
Look, everyone in the
know knows about you guys.
And what exactly do they know?
The best is barely good enough.
That's what I deal in. Art,
spells, totems, best of the best.
You've got six minutes.
It's too bad.
I just ordered a bottle
of 2005 Haut-Brion
that will take at least
half an hour to decant.
Thirty-six minutes, then.
This the one?
(SQUELCHING) That's...
Very moist.
Guys?
The Couple's been translating
the World Seed page.
But wrong.
Grab it.
And we're Fogg-ed.
MARINA: Guys? What is going on?
(WHISPERS INDISTINCTLY)
Should I wait here
for you guys, or...
Sir, there's a problem.
Is that my suitcase?
You told the Couple that this
is a bottle of 2005 Haut-Brion,
when in fact it's
Two Buck Chuck.
That constitutes deceit, a
violation of hotel protocol.
You'll be checking
out immediately.
(BUTTON CLICKING)
Abort. Fogg 17 showed
up. He's got Team Incubator.
(SIGHS) That's catastrophic.
We should rescue them. Yup.
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
Hello.
Management has been alerted to
the presence of unauthorized guests.
ELIOT: Oh. Please
present your key cards.
(SMACKS LIPS)
We are late, sorry.
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH CHOKING)
Hello? Jesus, Alice. What's
going on? Answer me.
Eliot? Kady?
Get off of him. Get off of him!
(GASPS)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) I wish I was smarter
I got so lost on the shore
I wish I was taller
Things really matter to me
And I'm still so afraid
Yes, I'm still so afraid
On my own
That was interesting.
(CLEARS THROAT)
ELIOT: Empath overload.
I doubt it will last.
Alice? Let's go.
(SIGHS)
Okay. Guess Alice
had a little moment.
(GASPS) Get your
shit together, people.
Ah.
What do we have here?
Ah, Christ. You brought the gun.
Strong choice. Thanks.
Thank you, Henry.
George, my pleasure.
On our new world, you
can have your own island.
No, I want my own
goddamn country.
Fine.
There won't be a new world.
Really?
Your translation of
the page is wrong.
You're going to end up killing
the Seed. How would you know?
Smart girl. Keep going.
I'm Fillorian. I can
translate the page correctly.
I'll even help you grow the
Seed, if you spare my friends.
I'm so sorry. I can't
control it. I'm sorry.
ELIOT: Your weaponized
emotional baggage
turned out to be a
weirdly good thing.
MARINA: So, Fen pulled a stall.
She's headed to the Seed
Room with the Couple.
Josh and Margo are still
in their suite with Fogg.
Can you get them free?
Kady, if you can take out Fogg
alone, I think I can help Alice.
Good luck.
(ELIOT CLEARS THROAT)
Alice. Do you trust me?
What are you doing?
(SNIFFS) Just a little sip.
To the confusion of our enemies.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(RATTLES)
(SIGHS)
Alice, whatever it is,
whatever you're feeling,
you can just tell me.
(FLESH SQUISHES)
I just can't stop thinking
about what he did to me.
(SIGHS)
So... So useless. So stupid.
(MELLOW ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) In this proud
land we grew up strong
We were wanted all along
I was taught to
fight Taught to win
I never thought I could fail
Don't give up 'Cause
you have friends
Don't give up
You're not beaten yet
I know you can make it good
Though I saw it all around
Never thought that
I could be affected
Thought that we'd be last to go
It is so strange
the way things turn
Rest your head
You worry too much
It's going to be all right
When times get rough
You can fall back on us
Don't give up
Please don't give up
Got to walk out of here
I can't take any more
Gonna stand on that bridge
Keep my eyes down below
Whatever may come
And whatever may go
That river's flowing
Don't give up 'Cause
you have friends
Don't give up You're
not the only one
Don't give up
BOTH: No reason to be ashamed
You still have us
BOTH: Don't give up now
We're proud of who you are
Don't give up
You know it's never been easy
ALL: Don't give up
'Cause I believe there's a place
There's a place where we belong
No!
It's bad enough I have to sing.
(MUSIC STOPS)
First thing you have to do is explain
why you want to build a new world.
To you? To the Seed.
It's alive, and
in order to grow,
it needs to know exactly
what you want and why.
The Seed will know if you
lie and will refuse to grow.
We've made powerful
enemies here on Earth.
And one cursed us,
making us... Unable
to have children.
But on a new world beyond
the reach of our enemies,
we hope to have a family.
Uh, okay. I have to admit, that's
not a motive I could've guessed.
But do you really think
you'd make the best parents?
Hi, Mom.
William?
You're going to be a father.
That's... That's wonderful.
It's why I'm here.
I need to know, um,
everything you went through.
When did you start
hearing voices?
About three months
into the pregnancy.
At first, they thought it
was a chemical imbalance
but after you were born,
I started to get worse.
They said the stress
of parenting brought on
a latent psychological disorder,
probably one I'd inherited.
The first time I had
to send you away...
(SIGHS)
I hear myself say that and
I still can't believe I did it.
I'm so sorry. Mom, I'm okay.
I need you to tell me
everything you can.
The voices went
away when you did.
And when you came
back, so did they.
Every time you came back,
there was less and
less of a little boy.
Mom, this isn't about me.
I wanted so much to raise you,
love you, protect you.
But what you needed
protection from was me.
What?
Mom?
Uh, I'm sorry,
someone's calling me.
What is it? What do you need?
Mom, there's no one calling you.
Of course there is. It
must be one of my patients.
There's more of them.
You don't hear them?
They're screaming.
I don't.
Oh, no. No.
(SOBBING) No, no,
not again. Please, stop.
MARINA: You need to hurry
it up, Kady. Just be careful.
Guys? It's Kady.
We have a problem.
(DEAN LAUGHS)
Let me guess. Camouflage potion?
Liquid explosive? Ah.
Good old chloroform, hmm?
(SNIFFS) Huh.
Goddamn Scotch. (LAUGHS)
But not just any Scotch.
Isabella Islay's Single Malt.
God damn it. Who
knew you had taste?
Wait, no, I need that.
Are you a drunk now?
Well, congratulations. Let me
help you get back on the wagon.
(GRUNTS) Now, why don't
you save us all some trouble
and tell me where the
rest of your colleagues are.
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(CLEARS THROAT)
God damn it. What
did you put in this?
A pharmaceutical I bought
off a very helpful bartender.
Street name, Archie.
(STIFLED MUTTERING)
JOSH: What just happened?
I just sent him on a
trip to the Etheric Realm.
Where rules prevent
Henry Fogg from leaving.
Here's hoping they're too
high to notice there's a new one.
Nice work. Okay,
Alice and Eliot?
If you're done with the singing.
You sure you're okay? No.
But I can do this.
MARINA: Great.
Now, everything's fine,
but medium-sized
bump in the road.
Pete just called from a
cell phone outside the hotel.
He got caught doing a very
Pete scam, and they booted him.
The suitcase? Went with him.
There goes our escape
route. (CLEARS THROAT)
I'm almost annoyed.
(SIGHS)
I might have an idea.
(PAPER RUSTLING)
Open the window.
(SIGHS) Let's hope that works.
Well, that was a disaster.
Let's go before I
check myself in here.
Hang on, look.
When she's alone,
everything's normal. But...
But when you show up...
My Traveler shit doesn't
work, and I still mess her up?
Functional or not,
you're still you.
So it's...
It's gonna be the same
for you and the baby?
Unless we figure out what it is
and find a way to cut it.
MARINA: Okay, Alice and Eliot
are en route to the basement.
Kady, Josh, Margo,
get ready to move.
Standing by, Marina.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
If it's the pig again,
we're having pork chops.
You gotta be shitting me.
ZELDA: I beg your pardon?
Oh, hey, babe. What are
you... What are you doing here?
I knew it. Knew what?
I put a locator spell
on the Heist Book.
And since you've been MIA for
two days, I figured I'd find you with it
doing exactly what you
promised you'd never do again.
Look, babe, it's not what it looks
like. (CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
I mean, it is, but...
God, I'm an idiot.
Listen, babe, people's
lives are on the line.
You're doing that thing
where you call me babe
a bunch of times... Yeah.
Which is exactly how I
know that you're lying.
Okay, this is not the time.
And it's also not about you.
So...
(SNAPS)
(SHOUTS) The
fuck did you just do?
Marina, do you copy?
Are we good to go?
She's offline.
Fair to say, "Act out"?
NEELA: I know you mean well,
Julia, but I really can't talk right now.
Look, can I just show
you something, please?
Where'd you get this?
You see that cord
thing between you?
What's going on?
You're not crazy, Neela.
Look, magic is real.
I'm a Magician.
And so is your son.
But he's a rare breed with this
link that they have to their mothers.
Every time they're close by,
their abilities start to
bleed over. Stop, stop, stop.
Just stop.
My baby has the
same abilities as Penny,
which means it causes
the same problems.
Oh, this isn't happening.
This is happening.
Look, I swear. I
know I'm asking a lot,
but if you could just take a
chance and let me help you,
you could have your son back.
You'd get to know
your grandchild.
Wouldn't that be worth it?
I can't.
I can't go through
this again. It'll kill me.
Tell William I'm sorry.
MARINA: How many times do I
have to tell you? The heist is not for me.
Right, and you're not
fucking the sexy Librarian.
Her? Don't be ridiculous.
Oh, my, no. But thank you.
How can I believe
anything that you say?
It took a fucking
spell for you to care
about anyone other
than yourself. I do care.
But I'm also pretty done
bending over backwards for you.
So you either get on board with the
"me" who's me, or you can fuck off.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Good. Thanks.
Uh, I finally know
where we stand.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Are... Are you all right?
Fix the goddamn baton.
Look, I know this was
maybe worse than you thought,
but now we've got a
shot at fixing it. Yeah.
Penny, she asked me
to give you something.
(SUCKS TEETH)
Don't turn down the
temperature without Marina,
if the others
aren't ready, it'll...
Kill the Seed. I know. Mmm-hmm.
ELIOT: (SIGHS) But it wouldn't
hurt to find the right control...
Step away from
the equipment, sir.
Oh, my. This is bad.
Jesus, Eliot, what now?
Hello, Marina. Glad
you're back with us.
I just need to take
care of this Bellhop.
Did you lower the
temperature? Eliot?
(PUNK ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) Twenty-twenty-
twenty four hours to go-oh-oh
I wanna be sedated
Nothing to do
Nowhere to go-oh-oh
BOTH: I wanna be sedated
Just get me to the airport
Put me on a plane
Hurry, hurry, hurry
Before I go insane
I can't control my fingers
I can't control my brain
BOTH: Oh, no-oh-oh, oh-oh
Twenty-twenty-twenty
four hours to go
I wanna be sedated
Nothing to do Nowhere to go
Just put me in a wheelchair
Get me on a plane
Hurry, hurry, hurry
Before I go insane
I can't control my fingers
I can't control my brain
Oh, no-oh-oh, oh-oh...
ELIOT: Done. Okay.
Team World Seed, you're up.
(PUNK ROCK MUSIC CONTINUES)
Chug yours!
Twenty-twenty-twenty
four hours to go
I wanna be sedated
KADY AND JOSH:
Nothing to do Nowhere to go
I wanna be sedated
Just put me in a wheelchair
Get me to the show
Hurry, hurry, hurry
Before I go loco
I can't control my fingers
I can't control my toes
ALL: Oh, no-oh-oh, oh-oh...
Go!
(GRUNTS) (MUSIC STOPS)
PALOMA: George.
I love your blades.
You're a strange
girl. Thank you.
If you don't give us the
correct translation soon,
you'll be a strange,
fingerless girl.
(CLICKING)
Paloma.
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
(GASPS)
You do that, the Bellhops
will just rip you to shreds.
Yeah, no. We kind of
found their Kryptonite.
Well, I'm fine
slitting her throat.
Yeah, me, too.
Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Everybody just calm down, okay?
Nobody needs to
die. Except the Seed,
if we keep standing
around talking.
See, our friends
cranked the AC in here.
So unless you
wanna kill the Seed,
back off, and let us
put it in the bag, stat.
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING) Oh, Christ.
Well, now we've
all got a problem.
(CHUCKLES DRYLY)
Guys, hey. Let's not
die. Or kill the Seed.
Kady, Ball, drop your knives.
Phew.
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
Now, I think I
have a fair solution.
Hands. Come on.
(PALOMA SHRIEKS)
(GEORGE GROANING)
(GRUNTING)
JOSH: Oh!
(GROANING)
FEN: I got the Seed.
Swallow, sunshine.
PALOMA: We need
to call an ambulance.
The Seed.
(GASPING)
(HIGH-PITCHED) It's fine.
MARGO: But where
the hell is the Seed, Fen?
(CONTINUES IN HIGH
PITCH) I've fucking got it, Margo!
Guys, Alice has an
exit. Get to the roof.
KADY: Come on, let's go!
(GEORGE GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
(PUNK ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
BOTH: (SINGING) Ba
ba baba Baba ba baba
I wanna be sedated
ALL: Ba ba baba Baba ba baba
(MUSIC STOPS)
(LOCK CLICKS)
(SIGHS) Bellhops figured
out earplugs. We gotta move.
Fen, where the fuck is the Seed?
And why are you
running so weird?
The Seed is somewhere
warm. Very humid. Even moist.
Oh, whoa! Uh...
Come on. JOSH: We
got to get out of here.
Here, in here.
So what's the escape plan?
It's more of an escape plea.
(BELLS JINGLING DISTANTLY)
MAN: Ho ho ho, motherfuckers!
ALL: (SINGING) Cruel to
be kind in the right measure
Cruel to be kind,
it's a very good sign
Cruel to be kind
Means that I love you, baby
You've gotta be cruel to be kind