Previously on The Magicians...
I'm a Librarian.
Currently on the lam
from a billion-year contract.
Sylvia, what'd you do?
I'm sorry.
Just let me see it again. - No.
Not till you tell me what
you were doing in the Library.
I'm stuck in the Fairy
Realm. How can I see you?
Lets you see into
other worlds, it's rad.
You're the absolute worst
rulers Fillory has ever had.
Honey, you don't
have to listen to Tick.
You can just do your own thing.
Turn around, head
home, relax, whatevs.
It's the excretion of a
very rare magical creature.
This magic.
I mean, it looks
different. It feels different.
Oh, God, they cut off her leg.
You clean their homes.
You cook their food.
And they take your leg
and grind it into powder
to snort so they
can do magic tricks.
I wanna help you
get out of here.
The necklace.
It kills them when
they use magic.
So you're just okay with letting
Kady take the Fifth Key, huh?
I'm not letting her do anything.
But when I ask you about
the book, you freak out.
Hey, Kady, I...
Please leave a
message at the tone.
Hey, uh, it's Quentin.
Call me back, please.
Look, she probably
took it because...
Because you trust a heroin
addict more than you trust me.
At least I know what Kady wants.
What does that mean?
She wants to talk to Penny.
But you, I don't...
First, you don't wanna
help us with the quest.
Then, suddenly, you want magic
so badly that you nearly kill yourself.
That's not fair.
None of that is fair.
Okay, well, then what is it?
Do you...
Are you with us? Do
you want magic back?
Of course I want magic.
Okay, well, then what changed?
Why now?
As opposed to when, huh?
When you asked me if I
wanted to go on a quest
five minutes after my dad died?
Would you be ready to
go on a fucking adventure?
Alice, I'm just...
You know, and are you the
only one who's allowed to be
ambivalent and depressive and...
And scared and hate themselves?
But I just have to be
sure of everything, huh?
Fuck you, Quentin.
Uh... Sorry.
I was just trying
to get through.
Sorry.
We can fight about
this after the quest.
Just let me see the stupid book.
Whoa.
There's something
she's not telling me.
You really think it was a
good idea to give her the book?
I don't know.
She helped us with the last key.
And we're probably gonna
need her for the next one, so...
The book says that the Sixth Key
is in the Throne
Room at Whitespire.
Oh, shit.
Wait, that's where
Margo and Eliot...
Just got overthrown violently?
Yeah.
I need an aspirin.
Thank you.
I'll never take magic
for granted again.
Yeah.
Me neither.
Uh, look,
there's something I have to
finish here before I can leave.
I can't go knowing
that the fairies are...
Jules, do what you gotta do.
Just be careful, okay?
You too.
Okay, so Skye's telling the
others what happened to her
and that we wanna
help them escape.
But that can't happen until
we get their necklaces off.
There's an emoji of a dagger.
Todd was right, this truly
is the universal language.
I need you to focus.
I can't find anything on these necklaces,
and I need to know how they work.
Can't you see I'm busy?
Fen.
Look, I know what the fairies
did to you in Fillory was fucked up.
And I'm sorry about that, but...
Yeah...
That's my response.
Is that a gif of a
crab with a knife?
It's how I feel.
Is it "gif" or "jif"?
Please. I need your help.
Fairies just make my skin crawl.
Okay, and how does
slavery make you feel?
So what you're saying is
that you want a fairy necklace
to examine? Yes.
One that isn't already
attached to a fairy's neck.
Fine, but don't
expect me to pretend
like I don't hate fairies.
You don't have to.
We know about your fairies.
There's one
standing right there.
Fen's family had a problem with
them, so I'm trying to help fix it.
I hate them. Their black eyes.
Their long fingers.
Their mushrooms.
"Mushrooms"?
They make the
air thick and musty,
like a bear's undercarriage.
And what was the deal that
you made with these fairies?
Oh, I didn't make a deal.
One was made for
me by... By her family.
See, they were tricked.
Interesting.
And here I thought that the
fairies under my protection
were the last of their kind.
I wish.
They're everywhere
in Fil... Fillmore.
Fillmore.
It's, um... It's a small
farming town in the Midwest.
And what about you, Julia?
How is it that you can see them?
I made a deal with
a younger fairy.
Visibility for a Snickers bar.
And just how
young was this fairy?
I don't know, actually.
Still trying to catch one.
Which is why we
wanted to ask you,
how are the ones here,
you know, so docile?
Well, I assume that you've noticed that
all of my fairies have this silver collar.
You mean, their necklace?
Necklaces, yeah.
They are cute, aren't they?
They're to help keep things
from getting out of control.
You'll need one.
You can get it from
my Uncle Edwin.
But I'm gonna need
something in return.
Of course. If your
rash is back...
I'll need you to
bring me a fairy.
Penny, during orientation,
weren't you trained on how to
properly reshelve the books?
We got a billion years, Howard.
Just keeping shit interesting.
So, uh, Penny.
My book club is looking
for new members.
Interesting people.
And I thought of you.
Why? 'Cause I'm brown?
And shackled?
You know this looks
bad for the Library, right?
Oh, no. We are not...
We shackle people of
all races and colors here.
Not better, Howard.
What I meant was...
I read your book. The hell?
I had unresolved feelings about
my death and your hand in it.
You killed yourself.
Am I misremembering the
part where you handed me
the cursed book that
directly led to that?
So the least you can
do is join my book club.
Kathy always brings
cupcakes. They're amazing.
Fuck off, Howard.
Participation helps ease
the transition, Penny.
Give it a think.
Fasten it around
the neck to activate it.
Then it will instantly kill
a fairy if they use magic.
Should deter them
from even trying.
Of course, you have to
actually catch a fairy first.
Oh, I'm sure I'll
figure something out.
So, how does it work?
I mean, what's it powered
by? Considering there's...
That would be a family secret.
Okay. Uh, but... Once it's
on, how will I know it's secure?
Has a fairy ever
broken out of one?
Dust.
This is Dust.
I've had him since I was 16.
But he's been in the
family much longer.
How long?
Over 400 years, sir.
He may not look it, but
he's our oldest Fairy.
Tell Irene her
guest has a collar.
Yes, sir.
There's really only one
way to take them off.
I have a machine that does it.
So don't worry, they're secure.
Great.
Thank you so much
for all your help.
Today is not my day.
I get that you're mad,
okay? But just hear me out.
Okay? You turned me in, Sylvia.
Look, when magic went out,
shit got really bad up
there for my family, okay?
My... My brothers, my... My
uncles, my dad, they all got whacked.
And went where?
To the Underworld?
Where you are?
All my people are
up there, Sylvia.
I can't travel, I
can't astral project,
I can't do shit 'cause of you.
My family isn't in the
Underworld, Penny.
They moved on.
To where?
I mean, I'm not sure.
The Underworld is
just a way station, really.
You hang around for a bit, and then
the bureaucracies that be move you on.
But I don't know
what or where that is.
So your family just left you?
Yeah, Dad's always
sucked at waiting,
so he pulled some
strings and cut the line.
But these contracts that
we sign with the Library
are fucking ironclad,
so I can't go anywhere
until I finish my billion years.
When the Library
put a bounty on you,
it brought me a million years
closer to my family, Penny.
And I'm sorry.
I know that that
doesn't fix anything...
Yeah, you're right.
It fixes shit.
I spoke to a few of the others.
They don't believe me.
If I hadn't done the magic, if
I hadn't felt what happened,
I don't think I would
believe me either.
Okay, Skye.
You've got to keep trying.
How? What should I say?
Look, I don't know, but I found
a way to take off the collars.
Edwin's got a
machine in the lab.
It won't matter. They're scared.
The thought of escape
is like a death wish.
But... There is one more thing.
Several of Ms. Irene's
family have arrived.
Many of them
brought their fairies.
To Brakebills?
Why?
I don't know.
Skye.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
If Skye can't convince them
to run, what are we gonna do?
We introduce them
to someone scarier.
I'm on a flying boat!
Okay, so the Sixth Key
is in the Throne Room?
Where Tick's waiting with a serrated
spoon to just saw off our heads?
Tick isn't at
Whitespire, though.
He's up north, near Loria.
The Throne Room is empty,
but we need to move fast.
So the book says
that the Sixth Key
will only reveal itself in
the light of two half-moons,
which is a thing that
happens in Fillory.
Like two black and
white cookies split apart
to form one giant white cookie.
A cookie moon.
Mmm-hmm.
Anyway, so it... It's gonna be super
bright, um, and it happens tonight, so...
Wait, why is Tick up near Loria?
Fillory's at war. What?
The fuck?
I know, we are literally questing
through a war-torn country.
So epic.
And who exactly
are we at war with?
The Lorians and the Floaters.
Yeah, we heard about it when
we were passing through town.
That cock's high king for three
seconds and it all goes to shit.
I need to send a bunny to Idri.
Yeah, I'll send one
to that Stone bitch.
Wait, what about the Key?
Q, you just told us
Fillory is getting spit-roasted
by invading forces.
Without us.
Okay, can I say something
obvious, yet potentially controversial?
We are no longer the
Kings and Queens of Fillory.
Says who?
Fillory, when they
overthrew you.
Mmm. Well, they were misguided,
and scared, and they
needed scapegoats.
At some point, you either
have to choose to follow through
on something,
or just, well, die.
Look, we chose this.
You captain the Key Quest,
Coldwater, and we'll stop war.
Ooh, ooh, could you drop us off
at Whitespire after it gets dark?
They have that balcony.
We could just rappel
down into the Throne Room.
It would be dope.
Get ready to tuck and roll, bitches,
'cause this boat don't do complete stops.
Yes, once fairies
lived on Earth.
But not in hundreds of years.
Not since we fled to Fillory
because human Magicians
nearly hunted
us into extinction.
I had no idea.
Of course not.
Short memory is a
privilege of the oppressor.
I'm sorry.
So you'll understand my disbelief then
when a human tries to lure me to Earth
with tales of a lost
tribe that can't exist.
But they're not...
I've heard enough.
Wait.
You're not listening.
I'd rather remove your tongue.
Maybe your teeth.
You choose.
Go ahead.
You have already
taken so much from me.
What's a few teeth?
You've got two sentences.
Choose wisely.
I hate fairies.
So why would I come here, to
a place where you stole my toes
and I lost my child,
if it wasn't true?
Then why would
you do this for me?
It's not for you.
It's for them.
They're still fairies.
But they're nothing like you.
They're more like
traumatized children.
And as a mother, despite
what you did to me,
they deserve a chance to live.
So get off your...
Whatever it is fairies have for
rear butts, and do something.
They need their queen.
What part of the Library is
"Secrets Taken to the Grave"?
Oh, so now you're talking to me?
I'm... I'm kidding. Chill.
Uh, it's some weird
research division
that the Library made in
partnership with the people
who run the Underworld.
Librarians like us aren't
even allowed to go in there.
What the hell do they
do to these people?
Oh, it's like primal therapy for
people who are about to move on.
You go and unload your bullshit
and it lightens your conscience.
I'm sure my dad's
was a nightmare.
This is all part of that
"Underworld is a way station" shit?
Yeah, they, like, jot
down everything of note,
and then at the end you
get a metrocard out of here.
You're telling me there's a
subway out of the Underworld?
Well, it's more
like this giant, long,
pig-type creature that
you, like, climb into,
and then it takes you
wherever you need to go next.
Why the hell are we still here?
Why haven't we
hijacked that long pig?
Because it only shows up
when someone has a metro card
and is ready to move on.
Our contracts will
never let us move on.
Nobody's ever gonna
give us metrocards, Penny.
Not like them.
Okay, so in this chapter
the daughter, she
finally becomes the knight
that she set out to be, and
right after she's knighted,
her shield catches a moonbeam
and it reflects it back. Uh...
What're you doing? Guys, guys.
Reminder, there are still
guards patrolling around, so...
The book says the moonlight has to
hit three keystones to reveal the key.
There's three doors, three keystones,
and none of them are near a window.
Okay, so we set up some mirrors,
and bounce around some moonlight,
and then we're back on track,
Enjoying the Quest?
Yeah, if that's
what the book says.
You know it does.
Hey.
Look, it's a perfect
metaphor for your relationship.
Not ready to laugh...
Yet. That's fine.
You want me to put
on a slave collar?
It's the only way we can get you
in direct contact with Irene's fairies.
Or I could just cut off all
the McAllistairs' heads.
For all we know, the McAllistairs
can trigger the collars remotely.
And just like that...
Every collared
fairy will be dead.
We need to be stealth. Smart.
Tell me,
what's smart about
rendering myself defenseless
and then entrusting my
life to a powerless Magician?
You're god-touched.
That's one way to put it.
But it also means
I can protect you.
It doesn't mean
that I trust you.
I get it. For good reason.
Why would you trust
any human on Earth?
But Fen and I are
risking our lives.
So we need you to trust us.
Or don't.
And we can just
do this on our own.
Without you.
She's right.
I'm not sure how,
but we will find a way.
What is it that
you want from us?
Not sure I understand.
She's healing a
mother's wound, but you...
Why go so far, Julia?
Let's just say being
god-touched is a mixed bag.
But I choose to do
something with that.
It means something.
Helping those fairies,
saving them, with you.
And this collar.
This had better work.
She really is stunning.
How many more of them are there?
Hard to say, really.
They're not all that friendly.
And where did you say
your friend is from again?
The Midwest.
No, I mean what town is she...
Excuse me.
Fairly well-behaved, actually,
considering she's feral.
Guess I got lucky, huh?
Uh, that's a much faster
turnaround than we agreed on.
You know what, it'll be a push,
but I think I can get
it to you all by then.
The others will take
some convincing...
Looks like we're
working through dinner.
You know what to do with her.
Especially if
time is against us.
My apologies, I'm having
family over for dinner.
But we'll talk later?
About the other fairies?
Of course.
Shit.
It's true.
What Julia said. You're real.
You're a queen.
She's a queen.
Of the free fairies.
Never bow your head.
For anyone.
Collar breaker, collar
breaker, where are you?
Ready the chair. I need
to check the equipment.
Yes, sir.
They're saying
they want everything.
Our entire supply.
Look, I know that it sounds risky,
but there is a limited time to this offer.
- If we don't...
- Risky? No.
Reckless. Leave us.
Though we've been separated
by time and great distance,
we are the same.
We are spun from
divine inspiration.
Blessed.
We are the living
embodiment of magic.
I may have secured a new source.
Of fairies? How?
Ask Edwin. He's seen her.
So I've come to
restore your strength.
To help you understand
the glory of who you are.
Your suffering is my suffering.
Your injustice, mine.
Where is Edwin? Edwin?
Edwin is working.
And when we are finally free,
we are gonna hunt down
every last living slaver,
gouge out their eyes,
cut out their tongues,
and hang them by
their own entrails.
You may feel a
pinch, but if you relax,
it'll be brief.
You want us to pull back
our advancements on Fillory?
This is ridiculous.
All we're really asking is
that you pause the invasion.
You both know that the
only reason Eliot and I
are in this mess is because
of fairy meddling bullshit.
And as soon as we clear this
up with the people of Fillory...
Deposed rulers don't
get their thrones back.
They exile themselves.
Or die at the hands of the mob.
Is this how you talk
to all your allies?
"Allies"?
My dear, I have yet to see
any proof that your marriage
to my son was ever
even consummated.
I made his little life
flash before his eyes.
Are you sure that
wasn't from the toad bite?
You saw it?
Of course I did. I'm his mother.
Wow, that's a lot to process.
In any case, I have no faith in
either of you reclaiming your thrones.
We will continue our
advancement on Fillory.
I'm afraid Loria
declines as well.
With magic gone, Loria has
the advantage over Fillory.
It makes no sense to withdraw
when I know we'll succeed.
I have to do what's
best for my people.
And what about our engagement?
You're no longer king, Eliot.
So it's no longer valid.
King Idri, are you saying you
have yet to take a husband?
My son's marble
has yet to be polished.
You mossy, pimping bitch.
Will you excuse
us for two seconds?
As much as I would love
to roll your smother-in-law
off our boat, it won't prevent either
one of them from invading Fillory.
We need to split those two
up before your man's arranged
to marry my child bride.
And our best plan is...
We offer them magic.
What the...
Fen!
I just watched
him help kill a fairy.
And there isn't a machine
that removes their collars,
just a machine that
removes their heads.
What?
All right, we just need
to figure something out.
There's nothing.
Fairy deals cannot be broken.
Wait, the magic that controls
the collars, they're fairy deals?
Edwin said you're
the oldest of the fairies.
Does that mean that you were
the one who made the deal?
Yes.
How could you do that
to your own people?
Hundreds of years ago,
Magicians had hunted us
out of existence nearly.
Then my Queen found
passage to a new world.
Several of us volunteered to
bind ourselves to the collars
and the McAllistairs.
A deal that would keep
them from following.
We thought we'd sacrifice
the few for the many.
But as my generation died,
and younger generations
were born into this life,
I lost faith in that sacrifice.
Or in the belief that my Queen
had made it to the other side.
She did.
My mother, your Queen, led
us to Fillory, where I was born.
And we were able to
create a home there.
All because of your sacrifice.
You never should have come.
Because now you
can never go back.
There is a way to break
a fairy deal, isn't there?
It doesn't matter.
"Doesn't matter"?
Of course it does.
I will not do it.
Our deals are the foundation of
our culture and key to our survival.
You are their queen.
You came here to save them.
If you don't, what's the point?
Fairies are known for
honoring their deals.
When we break them,
we lose the people's trust
and our limited leverage,
which we need for survival.
Without that, we are
weak and vulnerable.
It would be better for all of us
for me to take it to the grave.
Which will be soon enough!
Against the wall.
Dust, we're on a schedule.
Do not go with him.
What did I just say?
I won't let you do this.
I do not have time for this.
Stop! No!
What the fuck?
You guarantee that
this is the best decision
- for our family?
- I guarantee it.
Do not make me regret
my decision, Irene.
Oh, Vincent, when have I
ever steered this family wrong?
Cheers.
To us. To a new future. Cheers.
Shit.
It seems like those Secrets
dicks really made you earn it.
Any idea where you're going
now that you're moving on?
No, they... They
didn't really say.
Well, who'd you talk to?
Was it Fran? Oh, she's...
She's the one that just got
those two lazy eyes and...
Never really know which one to
focus on 'cause they're both moving.
I... I had, uh...
I couldn't really see
his face under his hood,
but he had... He
had glowing red eyes.
Oh. What... What does that mean?
Oh, you must have done
some horrible shit in your time.
Wait, wait... Uh,
where am I going?
Is it hell?
If only.
At least hell is warm.
There's a place worse than hell?
Oh, and way more creative with what
they plug all of your openings up with.
I'm not ready.
I'm not ready to go anywhere.
Hello, Penny.
Let's chat.
I've missed this.
But it doesn't change anything.
You know what
Margo's doing right now?
She's convincing the Stone
Queen that we'll get magic back.
Because we will.
And she's
threatening her with it.
If I'm lying, invade
later and kill me.
But if I'm not, do
you really wanna fight
righteously pissed off
Magicians who can finger-blast
your entire army
into fucking compost?
And is that your
strategy as well,
to threaten me?
I'd be well within my rights,
given that your army
is about to attack us.
But, no, I'm not
threatening you.
I am promising you...
What, exactly?
On the off-chance this is true,
what're your plans for taking
back control of the thrones?
Once we give back magic to the
people, we won't have to take anything.
Hell, they'll be begging
us to take back our thrones.
Our Magicians can identify
anyone with magical talent.
And it's likely that many
of your people have it
without the
education to know it.
So we'll educate them.
Soon you could have
magic as powerful as ours.
I usually like to keep a
certain amount of distance
between myself
and the residents,
but you are just so
fucking fascinating.
What?
I've never seen anyone
fight their destiny so hard
while simultaneously
propelling themselves towards it.
I mean, you narrowly
escaped death.
Twice.
And then still snuck
into the Underworld.
Who does that?
Yeah, I still have
no idea who you are.
Hades.
"Hades."
Like the god?
Shh!
I told you, low profile.
Okay, so what the hell
are you doing talking to me?
Look, is this about the metro...
No, it's not about that.
It's much more big picture.
Let's talk about your
future as a Librarian.
Or not.
This is about
that quest, isn't it?
Let me tell you
something about that.
It doesn't matter.
Easy for a god to say.
Spoiler alert, magic
always comes back.
It may take a millennia
and your entire species
verging on the brink
of extinction, but it will.
Because ultimately,
magic's a carrot gods use
to keep humans in check.
It's a lot to take in, I know.
My point is, your
life as a human,
it's like your memories
before the age of three.
This quest, your friends...
In a thousand years,
hazy at best.
Your life starts
now, after death.
And, yes, I realize the
phrasing is confusing.
Okay, what... What is this?
Is this some kind of fucked-up
punishment for
stealing a metrocard?
Hardly.
There are a lot of places
you could've ended up
that aren't nearly as
nice as the Underworld.
Shackled to a trolley
reshelving books?
We're in the greatest
Library in the entire universe
with almost an
eternity to explore it.
And if you want the
shackles off, go to Howard.
So I have to join a
book club to free myself?
All anyone's offering you
is a chance to participate
and be part of something.
You've got that whole loner
thing, but it's obviously a front.
Ever since that trip to
Savannah with your real mom,
you've been desperate
to prove your worth.
Yeah, okay, you and
everyone else down here
that's read my book, what,
you just think you know me?
But it's why you're always
sacrificing yourself for people, right?
To remind them how
important you are to the group?
If you're that desperate to
move on and maybe somehow
fumble your way
back to your old life,
I won't stop you.
But I'm telling you, Penny,
if you stay down here,
you've got an amazing
destiny ahead of you.
You've just gotta
choose it first.
And that should be
the last keystone, right?
I don't understand.
Would you stop...
You keep acting
like this is your book.
Maybe 'cause I've been on the
quest for more than two minutes...
Guys, snoop-and-poop
voices. Please.
You're hiding something from me.
Why don't you just ask me
what you wanna ask me?
Guys, seriously, I just
got out of a fantasy prison,
and I don't wanna
end up in a real one.
Are you working for the Library?
Yes.
Surprisingly honest. That's...
Are you trying to stop us?
No.
They wanna help us.
They want magic back
as badly as you do.
Well, I find that a
little hard to believe,
given what they did to
Harriet and Victoria and Penny.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa. What about Victoria?
You're welcome.
Yeah, you boned me,
but you also saved my life.
And I left you alone
when I shouldn't have.
Christ, okay, just go
see your family already...
No, I... I don't... I
don't understand.
What's to understand?
They helped me.
They wanna help us.
How is any of that bad?
Sorry, are you
smoking right now?
I was stoked to go on this quest
and hang with you guys, but...
My ex is dead, and you two
are setting my ball hairs on end.
I need this.
I'm just glad I was a genius
who stashed high-end party treats all
over while I was substitute high king.
If the Library wanted to
help, why hide it from me?
Why not just tell me?
Because I know you.
And I know how you'd
react. And you did.
Guys.
Guys!
I know where the Sixth Key is.
Where?
I'm sorry that we couldn't
save more of your kind.
Had it not been for
you, they'd all be dead.
I choose to be grateful.
I won't tell anyone about
what you did tonight.
It's too late.
There are consequences
to broken deals.
Our word will mean nothing.
I'm sorry.
Of all the humans that
have ever sought me out,
you're the only one who
didn't do it for personal gain.
If more were like you, we
might have been able to coexist.
We still can.
We could at least try.
You and your companions
are on a quest, correct?
For seven keys?
Yes.
We have one of the
keys in the Fairy Realm.
But it's what created and
sustains the Fairy Realm.
Without the key, everything collapses,
which is why we can never give it to you.
Howard.
What's your stupid
book club reading?
Gill and Stacey. Greatest
love story ever written.
He's handsome and tough and misunderstood,
but... But with a heart of gold.
And she is a driven woman just
trying to make it in a man's world.
So good.
I'm... I'm sure it is.
Penny, meet Kathy.
Kathy, Penny.
'Sup?
He 'supped me.
It's just like I
always imagined.
Penny, try one of
Kathy's cupcakes.
I promise you won't regret it.