Previously on The Magicians...
I'm a Librarian.
Currently on the lam from
a billion-year contract.
Sylvia, what'd you do?
I'm sorry.
- Just let me see it again.
- No.
Not till you tell me what you were
doing in the Library.
I'm stuck in the Fairy Realm.
How can I see you?
Lets you see
into other worlds, it's rad.
You're the absolute
worst rulers Fillory has ever had.
Honey, you don't have to
listen to Tick.
You can just do your own thing.
Turn around, head home,
relax, whatevs.
It's the excretion of
a very rare magical creature.
This magic.
I mean, it looks different.
It feels different.
Oh, God, they cut off her leg.
You clean their homes.
You cook their food.
And they take your leg
and grind it into powder
to snort so they can do
magic tricks.
I wanna help you
get out of here.
The necklace.
It kills them
when they use magic.
So you're just okay with letting
Kady take the Fifth Key, huh?
I'm not letting her do anything.
But when I ask you about
the book, you freak out.
Hey, Kady, I...
Please
leave a message at the tone.
Hey, uh, it's Quentin.
Call me back, please.
Look, she probably
took it because...
Because you trust a heroin
addict more than you trust me.
At least I know what Kady wants.
What does that mean?
She wants to talk to Penny.
But you, I don't...
First, you don't wanna help us
with the quest.
Then, suddenly, you want magic
so badly that you nearly kill yourself.
That's not fair.
None of that is fair.
Okay, well, then what is it?
Do you...
Are you with us?
Do you want magic back?
Of course I want magic.
Okay, well, then what changed?
Why now?
As opposed to when, huh?
When you asked me
if I wanted to go on a quest
five minutes after my dad died?
Would you be ready
to go on a fucking adventure?
Alice, I'm just...
You know, and are you the only
one who's allowed to be
ambivalent and depressive and...
And scared and hate themselves?
But I just have to be sure
of everything, huh?
Fuck you, Quentin.
Uh... Sorry.
I was just trying
to get through.
Sorry.
We can fight about this
after the quest.
Just let me see the stupid book.
Whoa.
There's something
she's not telling me.
You really think it was a good idea
to give her the book?
I don't know.
She helped us with the last key.
And we're probably gonna
need her for the next one, so...
The book says that the Sixth Key
is in the Throne Room
at Whitespire.
Oh, shit.
Wait, that's where Margo
and Eliot...
Just got overthrown violently?
Yeah.
I need an aspirin.
Thank you.
I'll never take magic
for granted again.
Yeah.
Me neither.
Uh, look,
there's something I have to
finish here before I can leave.
I can't go knowing that
the fairies are...
Jules, do what you gotta do.
Just be careful, okay?
You too.
Okay, so Skye's telling the others
what happened to her
and that we wanna
help them escape.
But that can't happen until
we get their necklaces off.
There's an emoji of a dagger.
Todd was right, this truly is
the universal language.
I need you to focus.
I can't find anything on these necklaces,
and I need to know how they work.
Can't you see I'm busy?
Fen.
Look, I know what the fairies
did to you in Fillory was fucked up.
And I'm sorry about that, but...
Yeah...
That's my response.
Is that a gif of a crab
with a knife?
It's how I feel.
Is it "gif" or "jif"?
Please. I need your help.
Fairies just make my skin crawl.
Okay, and how does slavery
make you feel?
So what you're saying is
that you want a fairy necklace
- to examine?
- Yes.
One that isn't already
attached to a fairy's neck.
Fine, but don't expect me
to pretend
like I don't hate fairies.
You don't have to.
We know about your fairies.
There's one
standing right there.
Fen's family had a problem with them,
so I'm trying to help fix it.
I hate them. Their black eyes.
Their long fingers.
Their mushrooms.
"Mushrooms"?
They make the air thick
and musty,
like a bear's undercarriage.
And what was the deal that
you made with these fairies?
Oh, I didn't make a deal.
- One was made for me by...
- By her family.
See, they were tricked.
Interesting.
And here I thought that the fairies
under my protection
were the last of their kind.
I wish.
- They're everywhere in Fil...
- Fillmore.
Fillmore.
It's, um... It's a small farming town
in the Midwest.
And what about you, Julia?
How is it that you can see them?
I made a deal
with a younger fairy.
Visibility for a Snickers bar.
And just how young
was this fairy?
I don't know, actually.
Still trying to catch one.
Which is why
we wanted to ask you,
how are the ones here,
you know, so docile?
Well, I assume that you've noticed that
all of my fairies have this silver collar.
You mean, their necklace?
Necklaces, yeah.
They are cute, aren't they?
They're to help keep things
from getting out of control.
You'll need one.
You can get it
from my Uncle Edwin.
But I'm gonna need
something in return.
Of course.
If your rash is back...
I'll need you to bring me
a fairy.
Penny, during orientation,
weren't you trained on how to
properly reshelve the books?
We got a billion years, Howard.
Just keeping shit interesting.
So, uh, Penny.
My book club is looking
for new members.
Interesting people.
And I thought of you.
Why? 'Cause I'm brown?
And shackled?
You know this looks bad
for the Library, right?
Oh, no. We are not...
We shackle people of
all races and colors here.
Not better, Howard.
What I meant was...
- I read your book.
- The hell?
I had unresolved feelings about
my death and your hand in it.
You killed yourself.
Am I misremembering
the part where you handed me
the cursed book that directly
led to that?
So the least you can do is
join my book club.
Kathy always brings cupcakes.
They're amazing.
Fuck off, Howard.
Participation helps ease
the transition, Penny.
Give it a think.
Fasten it around the neck
to activate it.
Then it will instantly kill
a fairy if they use magic.
Should deter them
from even trying.
Of course, you have to
actually catch a fairy first.
Oh, I'm sure I'll figure
something out.
So, how does it work?
I mean, what's it powered by?
Considering there's...
That would be a family secret.
Okay. Uh, but... Once it's on,
how will I know it's secure?
Has a fairy ever
broken out of one?
Dust.
This is Dust.
I've had him since I was 16.
But he's been in the family
much longer.
How long?
Over 400 years, sir.
He may not look it,
but he's our oldest Fairy.
Tell Irene
her guest has a collar.
Yes, sir.
There's really only one way
to take them off.
I have a machine that does it.
So don't worry, they're secure.
Great.
Thank you so much
for all your help.
Today is not my day.
I get that you're mad, okay?
But just hear me out.
- Okay?
- You turned me in, Sylvia.
Look, when magic went out,
shit got really bad up there
for my family, okay?
My... My brothers, my... My uncles,
my dad, they all got whacked.
And went where?
To the Underworld?
Where you are?
All my people
are up there, Sylvia.
I can't travel,
I can't astral project,
I can't do shit 'cause of you.
My family isn't
in the Underworld, Penny.
They moved on.
To where?
I mean, I'm not sure.
The Underworld is just
a way station, really.
You hang around for a bit, and then
the bureaucracies that be move you on.
But I don't know what
or where that is.
So your family just left you?
Yeah, Dad's always sucked
at waiting,
so he pulled some strings
and cut the line.
But these contracts
that we sign with the Library
are fucking ironclad,
so I can't go anywhere
until I finish my billion years.
When the Library put
a bounty on you,
it brought me a million years
closer to my family, Penny.
And I'm sorry.
I know that
that doesn't fix anything...
Yeah, you're right.
It fixes shit.
I spoke to a few of the others.
They don't believe me.
If I hadn't done the magic,
if I hadn't felt what happened,
I don't think
I would believe me either.
Okay, Skye.
You've got to keep trying.
How? What should I say?
Look, I don't know, but I found
a way to take off the collars.
Edwin's got a machine
in the lab.
It won't matter. They're scared.
The thought of escape
is like a death wish.
But... There is one more thing.
Several of Ms. Irene's family
have arrived.
Many of them
brought their fairies.
To Brakebills?
Why?
I don't know.
Skye.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
If Skye can't convince them
to run, what are we gonna do?
We introduce them
to someone scarier.
I'm on a flying boat!
Okay, so the Sixth Key
is in the Throne Room?
Where Tick's waiting with a serrated
spoon to just saw off our heads?
Tick isn't at Whitespire,
though.
He's up north, near Loria.
The Throne Room is empty,
but we need to move fast.
So the book says
that the Sixth Key
will only reveal itself
in the light of two half moons,
which is a thing that happens
in Fillory.
Like two black and white
cookies split apart
to form one giant white cookie.
A cookie moon.
Mmm-hmm.
Anyway, so it... It's gonna be super
bright, um, and it happens tonight, so...
Wait, why is Tick up near Loria?
- Fillory's at war.
- What?
The fuck?
I know, we are literally questing
through a war-torn country.
So epic.
And who exactly
are we at war with?
The Lorians and the Floaters.
Yeah, we heard about it when
we were passing through town.
That cock's high king for three seconds
and it all goes to shit.
I need to send a bunny to Idri.
Yeah, I'll send one
to that Stone bitch.
Wait, what about the Key?
Q, you just told us.
Fillory is getting spit-roasted
by invading forces.
Without us.
Okay, can I say something obvious,
yet potentially controversial?
We are no longer the Kings
and Queens of Fillory.
Says who?
Fillory, when they
overthrew you.
- Mmm.
- Well, they were misguided,
and scared,
and they needed scapegoats.
At some point, you either have
to choose to follow through
on something,
or just, well, die.
Look, we chose this.
You captain the Key Quest,
Coldwater, and we'll stop war.
Ooh, ooh, could you drop us off
at Whitespire after it gets dark?
They have that balcony.
We could just rappel down
into the Throne Room.
It would be dope.
Get ready to tuck and roll, bitches,
'cause this boat don't do complete stops.
Yes, once fairies
lived on Earth.
But not in hundreds of years.
Not since we fled to Fillory
because human Magicians
nearly hunted us
into extinction.
I had no idea.
Of course not.
Short memory is a privilege
of the oppressor.
I'm sorry.
So you'll understand my disbelief then
when a human tries to lure me to Earth
with tales of a lost tribe
that can't exist.
- But they're not...
- I've heard enough.
Wait.
You're not listening.
I'd rather remove your tongue.
Maybe your teeth.
You choose.
Go ahead.
You have already taken
so much from me.
What's a few teeth?
You've got two sentences.
Choose wisely.
I hate fairies.
So why would I come here,
to a place where you stole my toes
and I lost my child,
if it wasn't true?
Then why would you do this
for me?
It's not for you.
- It's for them.
- They're still fairies.
But they're nothing like you.
They're more like
traumatized children.
And as a mother,
despite what you did to me,
they deserve a chance to live.
So get off your...
Whatever it is fairies have
for rear butts, and do something.
They need their queen.
What part of the Library is
"Secrets Taken to the Grave"?
Oh, so now you're talking to me?
I'm... I'm kidding. Chill.
Uh, it's some weird
research division
that the Library made
in partnership with the people
who run the Underworld.
Librarians like us aren't even
allowed to go in there.
What the hell do they do
to these people?
Oh, it's like primal therapy for
people who are about to move on.
You go and unload your bullshit
and it lightens your conscience.
I'm sure my dad's
was a nightmare.
This is all part of that "Underworld is
a way station" shit?
Yeah, they, like, jot down
everything of note,
and then at the end you get
a metrocard out of here.
You're telling me there's a subway
out of the Underworld?
Well, it's more like
this giant, long,
pig-type creature that you,
like, climb into,
and then it takes you
wherever you need to go next.
Why the hell are we still here?
Why haven't we hijacked
that long pig?
Because it only shows up when
someone has a metro card
and is ready to move on.
Our contracts will never
let us move on.
Nobody's ever gonna give us
metrocards, Penny.
Not like them.
Okay, so in this chapter
the daughter,
she finally becomes the knight
that she set out to be,
and right after she's knighted,
her shield catches a moonbeam
and it reflects it back. Uh...
- What're you doing?
- Guys, guys.
Reminder, there are still
guards patrolling around, so...
The book says the moonlight has to
hit three keystones to reveal the key.
There's three doors, three keystones,
and none of them are near a window.
Okay, so we set up some mirrors,
and bounce around some moonlight,
and then we're back on track,
Enjoying the Quest?
Yeah, if that's what
the book says.
You know it does.
Hey.
Look, it's a perfect metaphor
for your relationship.
Not ready to laugh...
Yet. That's fine.
You want me
to put on a slave collar?
It's the only way we can get yo
in direct contact with Irene's fairies.
Or I could just cut off
all the McAllistairs' heads.
For all we know, the McAllistairs can
trigger the collars remotely.
And just like that...
Every collared fairy
will be dead.
We need to be stealth. Smart.
Tell me,
what's smart about
rendering myself defenseless
and then entrusting my life
to a powerless Magician?
You're god-touched.
That's one way to put it.
But it also means
I can protect you.
It doesn't mean
that I trust you.
I get it. For good reason.
Why would you trust
any human on Earth?
But Fen and I are
risking our lives.
So we need you to trust us.
Or don't.
And we can just do this
on our own.
Without you.
She's right.
I'm not sure how,
but we will find a way.
What is it that you want
from us?
Not sure I understand.
She's healing
a mother's wound, but you...
Why go so far, Julia?
Let's just say being god-touched
is a mixed bag.
But I choose to do something
with that.
It means something.
Helping those fairies,
saving them, with you.
And this collar.
This had better work.
She really is stunning.
How many more of them are there?
Hard to say, really.
They're not all that friendly.
And where did you say
your friend is from again?
The Midwest.
No, I mean what town is she...
Excuse me.
Fairly well-behaved, actually,
considering she's feral.
Guess I got lucky, huh?
Uh, that's a much faster
turnaround than we agreed on.
You know what, it'll be a push,
but I think I can get
it to you all by then.
The others will take
some convincing...
Looks like we're
working through dinner.
You know what to do with her.
Especially if time
is against us.
My apologies, I'm having
family over for dinner.
But we'll talk later?
About the other fairies?
Of course.
Shit.
It's true.
What Julia said. You're real.
You're a queen.
She's a queen.
Of the free fairies.
Never bow your head.
For anyone.
Collar breaker, collar breaker,
where are you?
Ready the chair.
I need to check the equipment.
Yes, sir.
They're saying
they want everything.
Our entire supply.
Look, I know that it sounds risky,
but there is a limited time to this offer.
- If we don't...
- Risky? No.
Reckless. Leave us.
Though we've been
separated by time and great distance,
we are the same.
We are spun
from divine inspiration.
Blessed.
We are the living embodiment
of magic.
I may have secured a new source.
Of fairies? How?
Ask Edwin. He's seen her.
So I've come to restore
your strength.
To help you understand
the glory of who you are.
Your suffering is my suffering.
Your injustice, mine.
- Where is Edwin?
- Edwin?
Edwin is working.
And when we are finally free,
we are gonna hunt down
every last living slaver,
gouge out their eyes,
cut out their tongues,
and hang them
by their own entrails.
You may feel a pinch,
but if you relax,
it'll be brief.
You want us to pull back
our advancements on Fillory?
This is ridiculous.
All we're really asking is
that you pause the invasion.
You both know that the only reason
Eliot and I
are in this mess is because
of fairy meddling bullshit.
And as soon as we clear this up
with the people of Fillory...
Deposed rulers don't get
their thrones back.
They exile themselves.
Or die at the hands of the mob.
Is this how you talk
to all your allies?
"Allies"?
My dear, I have yet to see
any proof that your marriage
to my son was ever
even consummated.
I made his little life
flash before his eyes.
Are you sure that wasn't
from the toad bite?
You saw it?
Of course I did. I'm his mother.
Wow, that's a lot to process.
In any case, I have no faith in
either of you reclaiming your thrones.
We will continue
our advancement on Fillory.
I'm afraid Loria declines
as well.
With magic gone, Loria has
the advantage over Fillory.
It makes no sense to withdraw
when I know we'll succeed.
I have to do what's best
for my people.
And what about our engagement?
You're no longer king, Eliot.
So it's no longer valid.
King Idri, are you saying you have
yet to take a husband?
My son's marble
has yet to be polished.
You mossy, pimping bitch.
Will you excuse us
for two seconds?
As much as I would love
to roll your smother-in-law
off our boat, it won't prevent either
one of them from invading Fillory.
We need to split those
two up before your man's arranged
to marry my child bride.
And our best plan is...
We offer them magic.
What the...
Fen!
I just watched him help
kill a fairy.
And there isn't a machine
that removes their collars,
just a machine that removes
their heads.
What?
All right, we just need to
figure something out.
There's nothing.
Fairy deals cannot be broken.
Wait, the magic that controls
the collars, they're fairy deals?
Edwin said you're the oldest
of the fairies.
Does that mean that you were
the one who made the deal?
Yes.
How could you do that
to your own people?
Hundreds of years ago,
Magicians had hunted us
out of existence nearly.
Then my Queen found passage
to a new world.
Several of us volunteered to
bind ourselves to the collars
and the McAllistairs.
A deal that would keep them
from following.
We thought we'd sacrifice
the few for the many.
But as my generation died,
and younger generations
were born into this life,
I lost faith in that sacrifice.
Or in the belief that my Queen
had made it to the other side.
She did.
My mother, your Queen,
led us to Fillory, where I was born.
And we were able
to create a home there.
All because of your sacrifice.
You never should have come.
Because now you can never
go back.
There is a way to break
a fairy deal, isn't there?
It doesn't matter.
"Doesn't matter"?
Of course it does.
I will not do it.
Our deals are the foundation
of our culture and key to our survival.
You are their queen.
You came here to save them.
If you don't, what's the point?
Fairies are known
for honoring their deals.
When we break them,
we lose the people's trust
and our limited leverage,
which we need for survival.
Without that, we are weak
and vulnerable.
It would be better for all of us
for me to take it to the grave.
Which will be soon enough!
Against the wall.
Dust, we're on a schedule.
Do not go with him.
What did I just say?
I won't let you do this.
I do not have time for this.
Stop! No!
What the fuck?
You guarantee
that this is the best decision
- for our family?
- I guarantee it.
Do not make me regret
my decision, Irene.
Oh, Vincent, when have I ever
steered this family wrong?
Cheers.
To us. To a new future. Cheers.
Shit.
It seems like those Secrets
dicks really made you earn it.
Any idea where you're going
now that you're moving on?
No, they...
They didn't really say.
Well, who'd you talk to?
Was it Fran? Oh, she's...
She's the one that just got
those two lazy eyes and...
Never really know which one
to focus on 'cause they're both moving.
I... I had, uh...
I couldn't really see
his face under his hood,
but he had...
He had glowing red eyes.
- Oh.
- What... What does that mean?
Oh, you must have done some
horrible shit in your time.
Wait, wait...
Uh, where am I going?
Is it hell?
If only.
At least hell is warm.
There's a place worse than hell?
Oh, and way more creative with what they
plug all of your openings up with.
I'm not ready.
I'm not ready to go anywhere.
Hello, Penny.
Let's chat.
I've missed this.
But it doesn't change anything.
You know what Margo's doing
right now?
She's convincing the Stone Queen
that we'll get magic back.
Because we will.
And she's threatening her
with it.
If I'm lying,
invade later and kill me.
But if I'm not,
do you really wanna fight
righteously pissed off Magicians
who can finger-blast
your entire army
into fucking compost?
And is that
your strategy as well,
to threaten me?
I'd be well within my rights,
given that your army
is about to attack us.
But, no,
I'm not threatening you.
I am promising you...
What, exactly?
On the off-chance this is true,
what're your plans for taking back
control of the thrones?
Once we give back magic to the people,
we won't have to take anything.
Hell, they'll be begging us
to take back our thrones.
Our Magicians can identify
anyone with magical talent.
And it's likely that many of
your people have it
without the education
to know it.
So we'll educate them.
Soon you could have magic
as powerful as ours.
I usually like to keep
a certain amount of distance
between myself
and the residents,
but you are just
so fucking fascinating.
What?
I've never seen anyone
fight their destiny so hard
while simultaneously propelling
themselves towards it.
I mean,
you narrowly escaped death.
Twice.
And then still snuck
into the Underworld.
Who does that?
Yeah, I still have no idea
who you are.
Hades.
"Hades."
Like the god?
Shh!
I told you, low profile.
Okay, so what the hell
are you doing talking to me?
Look, is this about the metro...
No, it's not about that.
It's much more big picture.
Let's talk about your future
as a Librarian.
Or not.
This is about that quest,
isn't it?
Let me tell you something
about that.
It doesn't matter.
Easy for a god to say.
Spoiler alert,
magic always comes back.
It may take a millennia
and your entire species
verging on the brink
of extinction, but it will.
Because ultimately,
magic's a carrot gods use
to keep humans in check.
It's a lot to take in, I know.
My point is,
your life as a human,
it's like your memories
before the age of three.
This quest, your friends...
In a thousand years,
hazy at best.
Your life starts now,
after death.
And, yes, I realize
the phrasing is confusing.
Okay, what... What is this?
Is this some kind of fucked-up
punishment for stealing
a metrocard?
Hardly.
There are a lot of places
you could've ended up
that aren't nearly as nice
as the Underworld.
Shackled to a trolley
reshelving books?
We're in the greatest Library
in the entire universe
with almost an eternity
to explore it.
And if you want the shackles off,
go to Howard.
So I have to join a book club
to free myself?
All anyone's offering you
is a chance to participate
and be part of something.
You've got that whole loner thing,
but it's obviously a front.
Ever since that trip to Savannah
with your real mom,
you've been desperate
to prove your worth.
Yeah, okay,
you and everyone else down here
that's read my book, what,
you just think you know me?
But it's why you're always
sacrificing yourself for people, right?
To remind them how important
you are to the group?
If you're that desperate to
move on and maybe somehow
fumble your way
back to your old life,
I won't stop you.
But I'm telling you, Penny,
if you stay down here,
you've got an amazing destiny
ahead of you.
You've just gotta
choose it first.
And that should be
the last keystone, right?
I don't understand.
Would you stop...
You keep acting
like this is your book.
Maybe 'cause I've been on the quest for
more than two minutes...
Guys, snoop-and-poop voices.
Please.
You're hiding something from me.
Why don't you just ask me
what you wanna ask me?
Guys, seriously, I just got out of
a fantasy prison,
and I don't wanna end up
in a real one.
Are you working for the Library?
Yes.
Surprisingly honest. That's...
Are you trying to stop us?
No.
They wanna help us.
They want magic back
as badly as you do.
Well, I find that
a little hard to believe,
given what they did to Harriet
and Victoria and Penny.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What about Victoria?
You're welcome.
Yeah, you boned me,
but you also saved my life.
And I left you alone
when I shouldn't have.
Christ, okay, just go see
your family already...
No, I... I don't...
I don't understand.
What's to understand?
They helped me.
They wanna help us.
How is any of that bad?
Sorry, are you smoking
right now?
I was stoked to go on this quest
and hang with you guys, but...
My ex is dead, and you two are
setting my ball hairs on end.
I need this.
I'm just glad I was a genius
who stashed high-end party treats
all over while I was substitute high king.
If the Library wanted to help,
why hide it from me?
Why not just tell me?
Because I know you.
And I know how you'd react.
And you did.
Guys.
Guys!
I know where the Sixth Key is.
Where?
I'm sorry that we couldn't
save more of your kind.
Had it not been for you,
they'd all be dead.
I choose to be grateful.
I won't tell anyone
about what you did tonight.
It's too late.
There are consequences
to broken deals.
Our word will mean nothing.
I'm sorry.
Of all the humans that
have ever sought me out,
you're the only one who didn't
do it for personal gain.
If more were like you,
we might have been able to coexist.
We still can.
We could at least try.
You and your companions
are on a quest, correct?
For seven keys?
Yes.
We have one of the keys
in the Fairy Realm.
But it's what created
and sustains the Fairy Realm.
Without the key, everything collapses,
which is why we can never give it to you.
Howard.
What's your stupid
book club reading?
Gill and Stacey.
Greatest love story ever written.
He's handsome and tough and misunderstood,
but... But with a heart of gold.
And she is a driven woman just trying
to make it in a man's world.
So good.
I'm... I'm sure it is.
Penny, meet Kathy.
Kathy, Penny.
'Sup?
He 'supped me.
It's just like
I always imagined.
Penny, try one of
Kathy's cupcakes.
I promise you won't regret it.