Previously on The Magicians...
I'm a librarian.
Currently on the lam from
a billion year contract.
- Sylvia, what'd you do?
- I'm sorry.
- Just let me see it again.
- No.
Not till you tell me what you
were doing in the Library.
I'm stuck in the Fairy
Realm. How can I see you?
Let's you see into other
worlds, it's rad.
You're the absolute worst rulers
Fillory has ever had.
Honey, you don't have to listen to Tick.
You can just do your own thing.
Turn around, head home, relax, whatevs.
It's the excretion of a
very rare magical creature.
This magic.
I mean, it looks different.
It feels different.
Oh, God, they cut off her leg.
You clean their homes.
You cook their food.
And they take your leg
and grind it into powder
to snort so they can do magic tricks.
I wanna help you get out of here.
The necklace.
It kills them when they use magic.
So you're just okay with letting Kady
- take the Fifth Key, huh?
- I'm not letting her do anything.
But when I ask you about
the book, you freak out.
Hey, Kady, I...
Please leave a message at the tone.
Hey, uh, it's Quentin.
Call me back, please.
Look, she probably took it because...
Because you trust a heroin
addict more than you trust me.
At least I know what Kady wants.
What does that mean?
She wants to talk to Penny.
But you, I don't...
First, you don't wanna
help us with the Quest.
Then, suddenly, you want magic so badly
- that you nearly kill yourself.
- That's not fair.
None of that is fair.
Okay, well, then what is it?
Do you...
Are you with us? Do you want magic back?
Of course I want magic.
Okay, well, then what changed?
Why now?
As opposed to when, huh?
When you asked me if I
wanted to go on a Quest
five minutes after my dad died?
Would you be ready to go
on a fucking adventure?
- Alice, I'm just...
- You know, and are you
the only one who's allowed to be
ambivalent and depressive and...
And scared and hate themselves?
But I just have to be
sure of everything, huh?
Fuck you, Quentin.
Uh, s... sorry.
I was just trying to get through.
Sorry.
We can fight about this after the Quest.
Just let me see the stupid book.
Whoa.
There's something she's not telling me.
You really think it was a good idea
to give her the book?
I don't know.
She helped us with the last key.
And we're probably gonna need
her for the next one, so...
The book says that the Sixth Key is
in the Throne Room at Whitespire.
Oh, shit.
Wait, that's where Margo and Eliot...
Just got overthrown violently? Yeah.
Oh.
I need an aspirin.
Whoa.
Thank you.
I'll never take magic for granted again.
Yeah.
Me neither.
Uh, look,
there's something I have to
finish here before I can leave.
I can't go knowing that
the fairies are...
Jules, do what you gotta do.
- Just be careful, okay?
- Yeah.
You too.
Okay, so Skye's telling
the others what happened to her.
And that we wanna help them escape.
But that can't happen until
we get their necklaces off.
Oh.
There's an emoji of a dagger.
Todd was right, this truly
is the universal language.
I need you to focus.
I can't find anything
on these necklaces,
and I need to know how they work.
Can't you see I'm busy?
Fen.
Look, I know what the fairies did
to you in Fillory was fucked up.
And I'm sorry about that, but...
Yeah...
That's my response.
Is that a gif of a crab with a knife?
It's how I feel.
Is it "gif" or "jif?"
Please. I need your help.
Fairies just make my skin crawl.
Okay, and how does
slavery make you feel?
So what you're saying is that
you want a fairy necklace
- to examine?
- Yes.
One that isn't already
attached to a fairy's neck.
Fine, but don't expect me to pretend
like I don't hate fairies.
You don't have to.
We know about your fairies.
There's one standing right there.
Fen's family had a problem with them,
so I'm trying to help fix it.
I hate them. Their black eyes.
Their long fingers. Their mushrooms.
Mushrooms?
They make the air thick and musty,
like a bear's undercarriage.
And what was the deal that
you made with these fairies?
Oh, I didn't make a deal.
- One was made for me by...
- By her family.
See, uh, they were tricked.
Interesting.
And here I thought that the
fairies under my protection
were the last of their kind.
I wish.
- They're everywhere in Fil...
- Fillmore.
Fillmore.
It's, um... it's a small
farming town in the Midwest.
And what about you, Julia?
How is it that you can see them?
I made a deal with a younger fairy.
Visibility for a Snickers bar.
And just how young was this fairy?
I don't know, actually.
Still trying to catch one.
Which... which is why
we wanted to ask you,
how are the ones here,
you know, so docile?
Well, I assume that
you've noticed that, uh,
all of my fairies have
this silver collar.
You mean, their necklace?
Necklaces, yeah.
They are cute, aren't they?
They're to help keep things
from getting out of control.
You'll need one.
You can get it from my Uncle Edwin.
But I'm gonna need something in return.
Of course. If your rash is back...
I'll need you to bring me a fairy.
- Synced and corrected by medvidecek007 -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Penny, during orientation,
weren't you trained on how
to properly re-shelve?
We got a billion years, Howard.
Just keeping shit interesting.
So, uh, Penny.
My book club is looking for new members.
Interesting people.
And I thought of you.
Why?
'Cause I'm brown?
And shackled?
You know this looks bad
for the Library, right?
Oh, no. We are not...
We shackle people of all
races and colors here.
Not better, Howard.
What I meant was...
- I read your book.
- The hell?
I had unresolved feelings about my death
and your hand in it.
You killed yourself.
Am I misremembering the
part where you handed me
the cursed book that
directly led to that?
So the least you can do
is join my book club.
Kathy always brings cupcakes.
- They're amazing.
- Fuck off, Howard.
Participation helps ease
the transition, Penny.
Give it a think.
Fasten it around the
neck to activate it.
Then it will instantly kill
a fairy if they use magic.
Should deter them from even trying.
Of course, you have to
actually catch a fairy first.
Oh, I'm sure I'll figure something out.
So, how does it work?
I mean, what's it powered by?
Considering there's...
That would be a family secret.
Okay. Uh, but...
once it's on, how will
I know it's secure?
Has a fairy ever broken out of one?
Dust.
This is Dust.
I've had him since I was 16.
But he's been in the family much longer.
How long?
Over 400 years, sir.
He may not look it,
but he's our oldest Fairy.
Tell Irene her guest has a collar.
Yes, sir.
There's really only one
way to take them off.
I have a machine that does it.
So don't worry, they're secure.
Great.
Thank you so much for all your help.
- Today is not my day.
- I get that you're mad, okay?
- But just hear me out.
- You turned me in, Sylvia.
Look, when magic went out,
shit got really bad up
there for my family, okay?
My... my brothers, my...
my uncles, my dad,
- they all got whacked.
- And went where?
To the Underworld? Where you are?
All my people are up there, Sylvia.
I can't travel, I can't astral project,
I can't do shit 'cause of you.
My family isn't in the
Underworld, Penny.
They moved on.
To where?
I mean, I'm not sure.
The Underworld is just
a way station, really.
You hang around for a bit, and then
the bureaucracies that be move you on.
But I don't know what or where that is.
So your family just left you?
Yeah, Dad's always sucked at waiting,
so he pulled some strings
and cut the line.
But these contracts that
we sign with the Library
are fucking ironclad,
so I can't go anywhere
until I finish my billion years.
When the Library put a bounty on you,
it brought me a million years
closer to my family, Penny.
And I'm sorry. I know that
that doesn't fix anything...
Yeah, you're right.
It fixes shit.
I spoke to a few of the others.
They don't believe me.
If I hadn't done the magic,
if I hadn't felt what happened,
I don't think I would believe me either.
Okay, Skye.
You've got to keep trying.
How? What should I say?
Look, I don't know,
but I found a way to
take off the collars.
Edwin's got a machine in the Lab.
It won't matter. They're scared.
The thought of escape
is like a death wish.
But...
There is one more thing.
Several of Ms. Irene's
family have arrived.
Many of them brought their fairies.
To Brakebills?
Why?
I don't know.
Skye.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
If Skye can't convince them
to run, what are we gonna do?
We introduce them to someone scarier.
I'm on a flying boat!
Okay, so the Sixth Key
is in the Throne Room?
Where Tick's waiting
with a serrated spoon
to just saw off our heads?
Tick isn't at Whitespire, though.
He's up north, near Loria.
The Throne Room is empty,
but we need to move fast.
So the book says that the Sixth Key
will only reveal itself in
the light of two half moons,
which is a thing that
happens in Fillory.
Like two black and white
cookies split apart
to form one giant white cookie.
A cookie moon.
Mm-hmm.
Uh, anyway,
so it... it's gonna be super bright,
um, and it happens tonight, so...
Wait, why is Tick up near Loria?
- Fillory's at war.
- What?
The fuck?
I know, we are literally Questing
through a war-torn country.
So epic.
And who exactly are we at war with?
The Lorians and the Floaters.
Yeah, we heard about it when
we were passing through town.
That cock's High King for three seconds
- and it all goes to shit.
- I need to send a Bunny to Idri.
Yeah, I'll send one to that Stone bitch.
Wait, what about the key?
Q, you just told us,
Fillory is being spit-roasted
by invading forces.
Without us.
Okay, can I say something obvious,
yet potentially controversial?
We are no longer the Kings
and Queens of Fillory.
Says who?
Fillory, when they overthrew you.
- Mm...
- Well, they were misguided,
and scared, and they needed scapegoats.
At some point, you either have
to choose to follow through
on something, or just,
well,
die.
Look, we chose this.
You captain the Key Quest, Coldwater,
and we'll stop war.
Ooh, ooh, can you drop
us off at Whitespire
after it gets dark?
They have that balcony.
We could just rappel down
into the Throne Room.
It would be dope.
Get ready to tuck and roll, bitches,
'cause this boat don't
do complete stops.
Yes, once fairies lived on Earth.
But not in hundreds of years.
Not since we fled to Fillory
because human Magicians
nearly hunted us into extinction.
I had no idea.
Of course not.
Short memory is a privilege
of the oppressor.
I'm sorry.
So you'll understand my disbelief then
when a human tries to lure me to Earth
with tales of a lost
tribe that can't exist.
- But they're not...
- I've heard enough.
Wait.
You're not listening.
I'd rather remove your tongue.
Maybe your teeth.
- You choose.
- Go ahead.
You have already taken so much from me.
What's a few teeth?
You've got two sentences.
Choose wisely.
I hate fairies.
So why would I come here,
to a place where you stole my toes
and I lost my child, if it wasn't true?
Then why would you do this for me?
It's not for you.
- It's for them.
- They're still fairies.
But they're nothing like you.
They're more like traumatized children.
And as a mother, despite
what you did to me,
they deserve a chance to live.
So get off your...
Whatever it is fairies
have for rear butts,
and do something.
They need their Queen.
What part of the Library
is "Secrets Taken to the Grave"?
Oh, so now you're talking to me?
I'm... I'm kidding. Chill.
Uh, it's some weird
research division
that the Library made in
partnership with the people
who run the Underworld.
Librarians like us aren't
even allowed to go in there.
What the hell do they
do to these people?
Oh, it's like primal therapy
for people who are about to move on.
You go and unload your bullshit
and it lightens your conscience.
I'm sure my dad's was a nightmare.
This is all part of that
"Underworld is a way station" shit?
Yeah, they, like, jot
down everything of note,
and then at the end you get
a metro card out of here.
You're telling me there's a
subway out of the Underworld?
Well, it's more like this giant, long,
pig-type creature that
you, like, climb into,
and then it takes you
wherever you need to go next.
Why the hell are we still here?
Why haven't we hijacked that long pig?
Because it only shows
up when somebody has
a metro card and is ready to move on.
Our contracts will never let us move on.
Nobody's ever gonna give
us metro cards, Penny.
Not like them.
Okay, so in this chapter
the Daughter, she finally
becomes the Knight
that she set out to be, and
right after she's knighted,
her shield catches a moonbeam
and it reflects it back.
- What're you doing?
- Guys, guys.
Reminder, there are still
guards patrolling around, so...
The book says the moonlight has to hit
three keystones to reveal the key.
There's three doors, three keystones,
and none of them are near a window.
Okay, so we set up some mirrors,
and bounce around some moonlight,
and then we're back on track?
Enjoying the Quest?
- Yeah, if that's what the book says.
- Ou know it does.
Hey.
Look, it's a perfect metaphor
for your relationship.
Not ready to laugh...
Yet, that's fine.
You want me to put on a slave collar?
It's the only way we can get you
in direct contact with Irene's fairies.
Or I could just cut off all
the McAllistairs' heads.
For all we know, the McAllistairs
can trigger the collars remotely.
And just like that...
Every collared fairy will be dead.
We need to be stealth. Smart.
Tell me,
what's smart about rendering
myself defenseless
and then entrusting my life
to a powerless Magician?
You're god-touched.
That's one way to put it.
But it also means I can protect you.
It doesn't mean that I trust you.
I get it. For good reason.
Why would you trust any human on Earth?
But Fen and I are risking our lives.
So we need you to trust us.
Or don't.
And we can just do this on our own.
Without you.
She's right.
I'm not sure how, but
we will find a way.
What is it that you want from us?
Not sure I understand.
She's healing a mother's
wound, but you...
Why go so far, Julia?
Let's just say being
god-touched is a mixed bag.
But I choose to do something with that.
It means something.
Helping those fairies,
saving them, with you.
And this collar.
This had better work.
She really is stunning.
How many more of them are there?
Hard to say, really.
They're not all that friendly.
And where did you say your
friend is from again?
- The Midwest.
- No, I mean what town is she...
Huh, excuse me.
Fairly well-behaved, actually,
considering she's feral.
Guess I got lucky, huh?
Uh, that's a much faster
turnaround than we agreed on.
You know what, it'll be a push,
but I think I can get
it to you all by then.
The others will take some convincing...
Looks like we're working through dinner.
You know what to do with her.
... especially if time is against us.
My apologies, I'm having
family over for dinner.
But we'll talk later?
About the other fairies?
Of course.
_
- _
- Shit.
It's true.
What Julia said.
You're real.
You're a queen.
She's a queen.
Of the free fairies.
Never bow your head.
For anyone.
Collar breaker, collar breaker,
where are you?
- Ready the chair.
- I need to check the equipment.
Yes, sir.
They're saying they want everything.
Our entire supply.
Look, I know that it sounds risky,
but there is a limited
time to this offer.
- If we don't...
- Risky? No.
Reckless. Leave us.
Though we've been separated
by time and great distance,
we are the same.
We are spun from divine inspiration.
Blessed.
We are the living embodiment of magic.
I may have secured a new source.
Of fairies? How?
Ask Edwin. He's seen her.
So I've come to restore your strength.
To help you understand
the glory of who you are.
Your suffering is my suffering.
Your injustice, mine.
- Where is Edwin?
- Edwin?
Edwin is working.
And when we are finally free,
we are gonna hunt down
every last living slaver,
gouge out their eyes,
cut out their tongues,
and hang them by their own entrails.
You may feel a pinch, but if you relax,
it'll be brief.
You want us to pull back our
advancements on Fillory?
This is ridiculous.
All we're really asking is
that we pause the invasion.
You both know that the only
reason Eliot and I are
in this mess is because of
fairy meddling bullshit.
And as soon as we clear this up
with the people of Fillory...
Deposed rulers don't get
their thrones back.
They exile themselves.
Or die at the hands of the mob.
Is this how you talk to all your allies?
Allies?
My dear, I have yet to see
any proof that your marriage
to my son was ever even consummated.
I made his little life
flash before his eyes.
Are you sure that wasn't
from the toad bite?
You saw it?
Of course I did. I'm his mother.
Wow, that's a lot to process.
In any case, I have no
faith in either of you
reclaiming your thrones.
We will continue our
advancement on Fillory.
I'm afraid Loria declines as well.
With magic gone, Loria has
the advantage over Fillory.
It makes no sense to withdraw
when I know we'll succeed.
I have to do what's best for my people.
And what about our engagement?
You're no longer king, Eliot.
So it's no longer valid.
King Idri,
are you saying you have
yet to take a husband?
My son's marble has yet to be polished.
You mossy, pimping bitch.
Will you excuse us for two seconds?
As much as I would love
to roll your smother-in-law
off our boat, it won't prevent either
one of them from invading Fillory.
We need to split those
two up before your
man's arranged to marry my child bride.
And our best plan is...
We offer them magic.
What the...
Fen!
I just watched him help kill a fairy.
And there isn't a machine
that removes their collars,
just a machine that removes their heads.
What?
All right, we just need
to figure something out.
There's nothing.
Fairy deals cannot be broken.
Wait, the magic that
controls the collars,
they're fairy deals?
Edwin said you're the
oldest of the fairies.
Does that mean that you were
the one who made the deal?
Yes.
How could you do that
to your own people?
Hundreds of years ago,
Magicians had hunted us
out of existence nearly.
Then my Queen found
passage to a new world.
Several of us volunteered
to bind ourselves to the collars
and the McAllistairs.
A deal that would keep
them from following.
We thought we'd sacrifice
the few for the many.
But as my generation died,
and younger generations
were born into this life,
I lost faith in that sacrifice.
Or in the belief that my Queen
had made it to the other side.
She did.
My mother, your Queen,
led us to Fillory, where I was born.
And we were able to create a home there.
All because of your sacrifice.
You never should have come.
Because now you can never go back.
There is a way to break a
fairy deal, isn't there?
- It doesn't matter.
- Doesn't matter?
Of course it does.
I will not do it.
Our deals are the
foundation of our culture
and key to our survival.
You are their Queen.
You came here to save them.
If you don't, what's the point?
Fairies are known for
honoring their deals.
When we break them,
we lose the people's trust
and our limited leverage,
which we need for survival.
Without that, we are
weak and vulnerable.
It would be better for all of us
for me to take it to the grave.
Which will be soon enough!
Against the wall.
Dust, we're on a schedule.
Do not go with him.
What did I just say?
I won't let you do this.
I do not have time for this.
Stop! No!
What the fuck?
Ah!
You guarantee that this
is the best decision
- for our family?
- I guarantee it.
Do not make me regret
my decision, Irene.
Oh, Vincent, when have I ever
steered this family wrong?
Cheers.
- To us. To a new future.
- Cheers.
Oh.
Ahh!
Shit.
It seems like those Secrets
dicks really made you earn it.
Any idea where you're going
now that you're moving on?
No, they, uh... They didn't really say.
Well, who'd you talk to?
Was it Fran? Oh, she's...
She's the one that just got
those two lazy eyes and...
Never really know which one to focus on
'cause they're both moving.
I... I had, uh...
I couldn't really see his
face under his hood,
but he had... He had glowing red eyes.
- Oh.
- What... what does that mean?
Oh, you must have done some
horrible shit in your time.
Wait, wait, uh, whe... where am I going?
Is it hell?
If only.
At least hell is warm.
There's a place worse than hell?
Oh, and way more creative
with what they plug
all of your openings up with.
I'm not ready.
I'm not ready to go anywhere.
Hello, Penny.
Let's chat.
I've missed this.
But it doesn't change anything.
You know what Margo's doing right now?
She's convincing the Stone Queen
that we'll get magic back.
Because we will.
And she's threatening her with it.
If I'm lying, invade later and kill me.
But if I'm not, do you
really wanna fight
righteously pissed off
Magicians who can finger-blast
your entire army into fucking compost?
And is that your strategy as well?
To threaten me?
I'd be well within my rights,
given that your army
is about to attack us.
But no, I'm not threatening you.
- I am promising you...
- What exactly?
On the off chance this is true,
what're your plans for taking
back control of the thrones?
Once we give back magic to the people,
we won't have to take anything.
Hell, they'll be begging us
to take back our thrones.
Our Magicians can identify
anyone with magical talent.
And it's likely that many
of your people have it
without the education to know it.
So we'll educate them.
Soon you could have magic
as powerful as ours.
I usually like to keep
a certain amount of
distance between myself
and the residents,
but you are just so fucking fascinating.
What?
I've never seen anyone fight
their destiny so hard
while simultaneously propelling
themselves towards it.
I mean, you narrowly escaped death.
Twice.
And then still snuck
into the Underworld.
Who does that?
Yeah, I still have no idea who you are.
Hades.
- Like the god?
- Shh.
I told you, low profile.
Okay, so what the hell are
you doing talking to me?
- Look, is this about the metro...
- No, it's not about that.
It's much more big picture.
Let's talk about your
future as a Librarian.
Or not.
This is about that Quest, isn't it?
Let me tell you something about that.
It doesn't matter.
Easy for a god to say.
Spoiler alert...
Magic always comes back.
It may take a millennia
and your entire species
verging on the brink of
extinction, but it will.
Because ultimately,
magic's a carrot gods use
to keep humans in check.
It's a lot to take in, I know.
My point is, your life as a human,
it's like your memories
before the age of three.
This Quest, your friends,
in a thousand years,
hazy at best.
Your life starts now,
after death.
And yes, I realize the
phrasing is confusing.
Okay, what... what is this?
Is this some kind of fucked up
punishment for stealing a metro card?
Hardly. There are a lot of
places you could've ended up
that aren't nearly as
nice as the Underworld.
Shackled to a trolley re-shelving books?
We're in the greatest Library
in the entire universe
with almost an eternity to explore it.
And if you want the
shackles off, go to Howard.
So I have to join a book
club to free myself?
All anyone's offering you
is a chance to participate
and be part of something.
You've got that whole loner thing,
but it's obviously a front.
Ever since that trip to
Savannah with your real mom,
you've been desperate
to prove your worth.
Yeah, okay, you and
everyone else down here
that's read my book... what,
you just think you know me?
But it's why you're always sacrificing
yourself for people, right?
To remind them how important
you are to the group?
If you're that desperate to
move on and maybe somehow
fumble your way back to your old life,
I won't stop you.
But I'm telling you, Penny,
if you stay down here,
you've got an amazing
destiny ahead of you.
You've just gotta choose it first.
And that should be the
last keystone, right?
I don't understand.
Would you stop...
You keep acting like this is your book.
Maybe 'cause I've been on the Quest
for more than two minutes...
Guys, snoop-and-poop voices. Please.
You're hiding something from me.
Why don't you just ask me
what you wanna ask me?
Guys, seriously, I just got
out of a fantasy prison,
and I don't wanna end up in a real one.
Are you working for the Library?
Yes.
Surprisingly honest. That's...
Are you trying to stop us?
No.
They wanna help us. They want
magic back as badly as you do.
Well, I find that a
little hard to believe,
given what they did to Harriett
and Victoria and Penny.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What about Victoria?
You're welcome.
Yeah, you boned me, but
you also saved my life.
And I left you
alone when I shouldn't have.
Christ, okay, just go see
your family alread...
No, I... I don't... I don't understand.
What's to understand? They helped me.
They wanna help us. How
is any of that bad?
Sorry, are you smoking right now?
I was stoked to go on this
Quest and hang with you guys, but...
My ex is dead, and you two are
setting my ball hairs on end.
I need this.
I'm just glad I was a genius
who stashed high-end
party treats all over
while I was Substitute High King.
If the Library wanted to help,
why hide it from me?
Why not just tell me?
Because I know you.
And I know how you'd react. And you did.
Guys.
Guys!
I know where the Sixth Key is.
Where?
I'm sorry that we couldn't
save more of your kind.
Had it not been for you,
they'd all be dead.
I choose to be grateful.
I won't tell anyone about
what you did tonight.
It's too late.
There are consequences to broken deals.
Our word will mean nothing.
I'm sorry.
Of all the humans that
have ever sough me out,
you're the only one
who didn't do it for personal gain.
If more were like you,
we might have been able to coexist.
We still can.
We could at least try.
You and your companions
are on a Quest, correct?
For seven keys?
Yes.
We have one of the keys
in the Fairy Realm.
But it's what created
and sustains the Fairy Realm.
Without the key, everything collapses,
which is why we can
never give it to you.
_
Howard.
What's your stupid book club reading?
Gill and Stacey...
Greatest love story ever written.
He's handsome and tough
and misunderstood,
but... but with a heart of gold.
And she is a driven woman
just trying to make it in
a man's world. So good.
I'm su... I'm sure it is.
Penny, meet Kathy.
Kathy, Penny.
Sup?
He supped me.
It's just like I always imagined.
Penny, try one of Kathy's cupcakes.
I promise you won't regret it.
- Synced and corrected by medvidecek007 -
- www.addic7ed.com -