Previously on The Magicians...
We found a key, too.
The ghost said it has the power
to reveal things
that are hidden.
I'm a hidden thing.
I'm Hyman.
When I first got stuck
in the astral plane,
I spent months
trying to push things.
I never got anywhere.
Until I tried being the thing.
Holy zerts! You did it!
The farmers are hesitant
because you're asking
them to throw out food
- and replace it with, uh...
- Inedible mushrooms.
I got it. I just need it done.
On Earth we tend to meet the
people we're gonna marry first.
Surely you've heard of the
Tribe of The Floating Mountain.
It is my duty and honor
to take the place
of my late brother.
Why do you have magic?
JULIA: I don't know.
I'd do anything to get it back.
If I could give it
to you, I would.
What if you could?
Whoo. Sorry.
Okay.
Last I checked, we're
looking for a spell,
not starting an eBay store.
There's this old hedge
story I once heard
about some sort
of electrical transfer
Marina used to steal
magic from some poor faun.
People still talk about it.
Just look.
So, you want us
to reverse engineer
a hedge witch urban
legend using kids' toys?
I mean, aluminum wiring's
been scant since the '90s,
so unless you
have a better idea...
Do you feel anything?
No.
Go again?
Oh, as long as I know
How to love I
know I'll stay alive
Why did that just
turn on by itself?
Oh, my God.
I've got all my love to give
And I'll survive
Give me your hand.
Wait. Stop.
Do not do this.
Did you just use that
fish as a doorbell?
I've been trying to warn
you guys for, like, an hour.
Being the fish button is the first
thing in this entire room that's worked.
What are you trying
to warn us about?
This spell.
I've seen it in person.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
Couple months back
on a book-stealing job,
I saw a group of
magically-starved idiots
do the transfer,
and by the end of it,
everyone was on fire.
Trust me. Fogg was right.
It's a bad idea.
Wait a minute. Did you
just say Fogg was right?
Oh...
Fuck me.
You have magic.
And you're just now telling me?
Don't take this the wrong way,
but you've been a little drunk.
And unreliable. Yes.
I'm drunk, but I
am entirely reliable.
Um, maybe we should
get back to Marina's spell.
It wasn't Marina's
spell. It's mine.
She stole it from
my private collection.
And if any of you had
attended my annual colloquia
on prohibited magic,
you would know
that its proper name
is the Voltaic Transfer.
It is incredibly delicate.
We know that, but... But what?
But you want to rid yourself
of the one thing we all
so desperately want?
If you understood what...
You understand.
I'm a Magician with no magic.
A dean without a school.
Just a blind, unemployed
black man in America.
Which, shockingly, was actually
being kept 38% more tolerant
through a series of enchantments
which have now died.
In case you hadn't noticed
or perhaps maybe you weren't
in a position to need to.
Okay, you're really drunk.
So what?
What does it matter?
Alice, of all people,
you should know better
than to attempt this.
You want to blow
yourselves up? Is that it?
Um... Just give me one second.
Okay.
Uh, they'll hold
for a day or two,
but then Alice
can recharge them.
After we finish the transfer.
I know. Everything is fucked.
I'm sorry. It's not your fault.
Julia.
Yeah, well, it's not
not my fault either, so...
What you two utter idiots need,
if you don't want to die,
is the flesh of a
magical creature
to act as a sort
of semiconductor.
A potent energy-drainer.
An incubus.
If this is about the whole
marriage not being
consummated yet,
don't worry, it'll happen.
Oh, no, no, no. You
misunderstand me, my dear.
See, I've heard a rumor
about your adviser,
the Pickwick? Sighted
in a certain corridor,
taking scrapings from the wall.
He's just a
compulsive redecorator.
You might be interested to
know that we both have been
plotting against
our mutual friend.
Hmm.
No idea what
you're talking about.
Margo.
You can trust me.
The misguided actions of my son
have soured both sides
of our arrangement.
I've acquired a weapon forged
in the foundries of Stonehaven.
When the time is right,
we could use it to
kill the Fairy Queen.
Hi. Oh, hell, no.
Move.
Hang your sheets out the
window afterwards, dear.
Guards! Guards!
Don't even think
about closing it. No!
Guards!
Let me out!
I don't give a shit if you
have to find someone
to sell those shares short.
I need them today.
So the incubus is a
hedge fund manager?
Plus 5%.
And not one more cent,
you piece of monkey shit.
Just remember what Fogg said.
Be respectful, no matter what.
You got two minutes.
Henry Fogg said
that you might be able
to help us power our spell.
Uh... We just... We
need to use your thing.
My what? Your... Your thing.
Your... Your business.
Sorry?
Your little friend. Uh, I
mean... Your big friend.
Well, I'm sure your friend
is perfectly proportioned
to your body.
I was just saying... Your penis.
Yep, we need to use your
penis to power our spell.
And we know that
you need it too.
So that's why we'll
build the spell around it.
It'll be completely painless
and should only
take a couple minutes.
I can't believe that
actually worked!
Wha... What actually worked?
I planted this joke
on Fogg 25 years ago.
I had him totally convinced
that I had a magic Johnson.
Wait, so you... You
don't have a magic...
Of course not.
That's ridiculous. No, it's not.
I mean, you're an incubus.
Isn't sex, like, your thing?
Gods no.
I don't even like sex.
Stress is a much better
way to drain people's energy.
May I?
Oh, and you.
You got a lot of it, I can tell.
Delish.
You give me a few
more hits of this,
and I'll give you something
that'll actually
power your spell.
Is that your tail? Yeah.
Yeah, I grow a new
one every spring.
Welcome back.
I see you've misplaced
your wife and child.
You'd be shocked how
easy it is to misplace people
when your mind's on tax
collection and annexation
and unforeseen
seafaring confusion.
I'll immediately sail back
out there and find them,
of course... No, you won't.
I have a bigger problem
I need you to solve.
The Stone Queen has locked
Margo and Fomar in the dungeon.
Wait. What? Why?
She thinks it will get the
marriage consummated,
but ultimately I need
the union officialized
just as much as the Floaters do.
Listen, pro tip.
Let Margo out of
there immediately.
You know her. Force
isn't going to work.
True. Force may not work.
But the clever coercion on
the part of a trusted friend.
I am not going to coerce Margo
into having sex
with a 15-year-old.
Have you never
heard of statutory rape?
Fomar isn't a statue.
That is not what...
Forget it. You will solve
this problem for me.
And if I refuse?
I've been searching
for a new keepsake.
Several bits will do.
Fine, but I have a
feeling Queen Margo
is going to be a
little bit difficult.
I know!
You hate me for killing Micah.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
It's just, in our culture,
younger sons can't
marry or inherit property.
Most of us wind up
serving in the Crag
Guard or dying in battle.
Is this supposed to
make me feel bad for you?
No.
So, do you want to take a break?
Let me touch your maiden peaks?
Do you want me to cut your
hands off and have them made
into a decorative,
whimsical planter?
How are we supposed
to become one flesh
if you won't let me touch you?
We're not. But you're my wife.
Oh, please.
You don't need a wife.
You need a pile of
socks and a sex-ed class.
What's a sex class? Who's Ed?
It's something they
make you do on Earth.
It makes you never wanna.
How about I show you?
Vaginas.
The leading cause
of death in men.
They spread disease.
They explode during childbirth.
But worst of all, they
bleed. Every month.
In fact, mine's
doing it right now.
Well, that's okay. I like blood.
But do you like teeth?
Sorry I'm late.
You okay?
Enjoying being a palace
guard in your own palace?
This uniform is,
like, really sweaty.
Yeah, I know, but it beats
having the Fairy
Queen's hand up your ass.
Last thing we need
is another puppet king.
Okay, key quest. Hit me.
Uh, okay, so I'm
pretty sure that
the fourth key is somewhere
in this stretch of
ocean called The Abyss.
Um, it's an uncharted
region of Fillory
where it's, like, sort
of permanently night.
Um...
But, you know, we get to go
on a quest on a magical
boat, so it doesn't totally suck.
Yeah. I wish I could.
Believe me, but duty calls
a dozen different ways.
And I can't leave
Margo. Right, of course.
Sorry. No.
I was looking forward to going
on a boating quest with you.
Who wouldn't?
Think about it. You
can take Benedict.
Go be life partners with
someone else for a little bit.
But you'll be able to do the...
Thing on the prow of a ship
you've been waiting
your whole life to do.
What thing? You know, the thing.
Whoo!
Sorry. Sorry.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Being on a mission is a
hell of an antidepressant.
You notice that, Benedict?
Well, now that you mention it.
Whoa.
We're entering The Abyss, Sire.
It'll be darkness from here on.
Thank you.
So how long until
we can keep going?
As soon as we find safe
passage, Your Majesty.
Is someone out there?
Help!
Is someone out there? Help!
God, I think there's
someone out there on a raft.
You okay?
Wow, wow, wow. You just
saved the shit out of me.
Poppy Kline.
Draconologist, postgraduate
fellow, and field researcher
at your service.
Holy shit. You're
from Brakebills?
Yeah.
So, Brakebills students
are kings and queens now?
Yeah. Shit.
I've been stuck in The
Abyss way too long.
How did you end
up out here anyway?
I came with some other students.
Oh, hey, sorry. I can... Uh...
Spring Break, Class of 2016?
Didn't turn out so well for us,
but that is a
whole 'nother story.
Wait, sorry.
Do you know, um...
If the next two words out
of your mouth are "Josh"
and "Hoberman," we
just became best friends.
No way. He's still alive?
I mean, as far as I know.
Oh, that's amazing.
So how does a Brakebills student
wind up alone on a raft?
Get a girl a drink. I'll
tell you the whole story.
All right.
Your Majesty.
An urgent message
from Prince Ess of Loria.
Wasn't Ess in the dungeon?
High Queen Margo let him go
as he was innocent
of all charges.
Oh, right. Yeah.
Sorry about that.
I figured out the problem.
Humans don't mate in captivity.
What Margo and Fomar
need is a honeymoon.
An hour's ride
north, there is a forest
with naturally-occurring
aphrodisiacs
that's guaranteed to get
that marriage consummated.
Fine.
But if you fail...
I know, I know.
New keepsakes. Fingers, ears.
Try your spleen.
Okay. Go.
Fieldwork was my thing at
Brakebills, and well, dragons.
Love them.
Wait, so what
happened to your ship?
Oh. Wrecked.
Off the coast of
the Truthwaters.
I spent two years
on that little picket.
And, bam. Over in an instant.
That was three weeks ago.
You survived for three
weeks on a raft by yourself?
Yeah, it was rough.
Especially without magic.
Do you know anything
about why the hell
it just went out? I mean...
I just hope someone's fixing it.
That someone is, um, sort of me.
I'm on a quest, right,
for these golden keys.
Right, so there's seven of them.
Wait, wait, wait,
wait. Golden keys?
Like...
Holy shit. How did you...
Short version?
Stole it.
Mid-voyage we wound
up on this random island,
just, like, covered in treasure.
A dragon breeding
ground which is like...
Ah. Spontaneous orgasm.
I mean, places
like this are so rare.
There are only two
species of dragon
that even build treasure-nests.
Anyway, this was in one of them
with a bunch of cool stuff.
But the thing that got me was
I could feel something
coming off it.
Yeah. Even now.
It's somehow not dead, right?
And, you know, the dragons
were all horny and distracted,
so I just took it.
Just like that?
I'm a person of
questionable ethics.
Here.
It's yours, from one
quester to another.
Wow. Thank you.
So do you know what it does?
I mean, each one sort
of has a unique thing.
I don't know.
Maybe you can
figure it out. Yeah.
Uh... Here's to that.
You wanna? Yeah. Oh.
Okay. Well, here goes nothing.
Ugh. Man, one of your
wires is coming loose.
You're gonna kill yourselves!
Oh, my God. I
can't... Golly Moses.
You're right. They're
gonna kill themselves.
Don't you have some
shower to go haunt?
Oh, no one's
showering right now.
Except Fogg, and he's asleep.
Jesus, that man needs
help. Is he all right?
Just a bit zozzled, I think.
He was quite naked.
Remarkably well-preserved.
Guess it's possible
to age gracefully.
Oh, my God.
Fuck, man. I can't watch this.
See? This is what I
love about you, Penny.
You act like you don't care,
but really, you care
most in this whole story.
Yeah, then... Then
why is everyone acting
like I'm not a part
of it anymore?
Maybe it's time to
blouse this popsicle stand.
You mean, leave? Why not?
Go find a story to watch
that doesn't make
you so depressed.
Oh, I think they did it.
I'm having a good time.
Mmm.
You just wait a second,
I'm gonna close...
Rise and shine, princess.
Who?
The real question, dipshit,
is how you managed
to black out after,
what, five drinks?
Why do you always have
to embarrass yourself?
I don't...
Okay.
Um...
Seriously.
You hold your liquor
like a kindergartner.
Sorry, um, can you... Are
you... Are you seeing this?
Nobody cares, dude.
They all have actual
jobs, unlike you.
Right, okay.
No problem.
What the fuck did you
do? Okay, I can explain.
What is this key?
Just calm down.
It's all right.
There's another me.
And he's mean, and
no one else can see him.
Nothing about this is all right.
Okay, listen. Here's the deal.
The key does have
a power. No shit.
It takes the
darkest parts of you
and makes a kind
of... Well, you met it.
It's kind of like a
depression monster?
Looks like you, talks like you.
But don't worry, it
can't actually hurt you.
Unless... Unless?
Unless it gets in your head
and convinces
you to hurt yourself.
Well... But you'll be fine.
It only affects the last
person who touched the key.
So just pass it along
to someone else.
That's what we did. Who's we?
My former shipmates.
After I stole the key,
we passed it from
person to person
until we, you know,
ran out of options.
What does that mean,
you ran out of options?
Um...
Hit an iceberg?
I happened to be holding
the key when we sank
'cause the rest of 'em
just couldn't handle it.
You have to be, like,
a badass about it,
and what can I say?
They were weak. Okay, I'm sorry.
Exactly how many of them
survived the key before you?
Hmm. Maybe, like, half?
This key made half
of your shipmates
kill themselves, and
you gave it to me?
Yeah. But don't worry.
They were all pretty
psychologically damaged already.
You'll be fine. You're
so happy and positive.
No. No, no.
I'm not. This is like...
It's like we're on a boat, okay?
This is not how I usually am.
You're usually a wet
blanket, self-pitying,
party pooping dickwad.
Shut up!
You better pass that along fast.
What? No! Not if there is a 50%
chance of it killing
the next person.
Okay.
Right, yep. I'll
just hold on to it.
Until we get back to Whitespire.
I can do that. Your choice.
I mean, we're stuck in The Abyss
till we found our way out.
It could be days.
It could be weeks.
But hey. Don't stress.
You might be fine. You won't be.
You know what?
I have come up against
you before, asshole.
Maybe a little more subtly,
but you and I both know
that I've got a black belt.
So come at me.
The problem is your hair.
I know you're just
trying to hide your face,
but it really only
makes it worse.
Seriously, have you ever noticed
that your face sort
of looks like a foot?
If feet had frown lines?
I mean, you're definitely
aging prematurely,
which is a symptom of
early-onset Alzheimer's.
Which, funny, both
your grandparents had.
And you will definitely
get it so then you'll be
a senile frowny foot-face.
Jesus. Fuck.
This is pointless.
You can't run me off.
You can't eat me off.
You can't drink me off.
You can't jerk me off.
God, you're so vulgar.
We had a thing going,
and you... You made it
unnecessarily gross.
You sick of the
shallow, petty stuff?
I get it.
The thing is, I
start on the outside,
and I work my way into the core.
The part of you that
kept magic from Julia
when you could have helped her,
that is what set
her on that path.
You got your best
friend sexually assaulted.
And let's talk about
what happened to Alice.
You ruined her.
And she is never going
to be the girl that she was.
You killed her, and she
is never coming back.
How many people have to
pay the price for your heroics?
Just stop!
You are willing to destroy
everyone around you
to find something that
makes you feel okay.
But you are never
gonna feel okay.
No, stop. You're
trying to get in my head.
Quentin.
I am your head.
You know I'm right
because I am you.
To Mr. and Mrs... Fomar.
Fomar.
Bottoms up.
In my culture, the
woman always drinks first.
Drink the wine, Margo.
I don't wanna drink the wine.
What I wanted was for
you to handle this, Eliot.
You'll feel better if you just
drink the wine, Margo.
So, um...
Do we have sex in the carriage?
Or do we have sex outside?
Or do... I'm not
having sex with you.
You psychotic fetus.
Ever.
Either I just killed
him with my rage
or you drugged his wine.
And to think...
You doubted me.
To think.
I just spent three days
locked in a dungeon with him.
Okay. Yes, and that sucks.
But we have a problem,
possibly much bigger
than sleeping beauty over here.
The fairies are up to something
in the Northern Orchards.
They evacuated the
villagers weeks ago
and haven't let
another human in since.
Except Ess came through
on his way from Loria,
and he saw some crazy shit.
Rivers running red,
three-eyed fanged toads,
mutant plant life,
Chernobyl-level shit.
I think the fairies might be
poisoning the ecosystem.
Great, well, now I
can't be mad at you.
Thanks.
I know, I wanted to fight, too,
so that we could make up
and on the other side of it,
we could just... Be us again?
Who are we now, El?
We used to be glamorous,
amazing mega-bitches.
And now?
We have depth and character.
Let's decide...
We'll find us again
once we're done saving Fillory.
Okay?
Duty calls.
Let's go see about
these orchards.
Which are...
No longer here.
Nothing is going to
save you. Not Brakebills.
Not Fillory. Not a quest.
Just do it.
Kill yourself.
Make it stop.
You know the way out.
King Quentin, no!
No, I wasn't. I was just...
I thought I saw
something. Your Majesty,
if I may, I understand
what you're contemplating.
I thought about it too.
Though I have never
spoken about it, of course.
Why not?
Well, you know what parents
teach you about emotions.
That you should bottle them
up and never talk about them
and turn them into
maps, for example.
Jesus, Benedict.
Okay, we should talk about this.
If it please you,
Sire, but first,
why don't we step away
from the edge of the boat?
Yeah. I don't really
trust myself right now.
You know, in old days,
when sailors would go mad,
the crew would tie
them to the mast.
Isn't that funny?
Oh, my God. Tie me to the mast.
No... No, Your
Majesty. No, do it.
Okay, swear to me,
no matter what I say,
that you will not untie me
until we get to Whitespire.
Very well. I won't.
Thank you.
It worked.
Oh, I see the transfer worked.
It's still small, I can feel
that, but I'm gonna grow it.
I hope you'll be careful.
I will be.
You know that fixing my glasses
won't fix me.
Yeah, but they make all of this
one speck less shitty.
It smells like the fairy realm.
We're so far north.
The climate should be cold
and dry, not hot and moist.
Yeah, well, they're
such moisture freaks.
All that spritzing and bathing.
You know, it's...
It's like they're afraid
to dry out in Fillory
or something.
Oh, my God.
The fuckers are terraforming.
They're turning our kingdom
into a mushroom steam bath.
That is not okay. No.
Definitely not.
That mushroom just moved.
Really? Should I pluck it?
I'm gonna do it.
Margo, don't.
Oh.
Uh...
It's a fairy embryo.
Really? These are eggs, El.
I mean, really?
The fairies aren't
just terraforming.
They're growing an army.
Oh, fuck.
I think these fairies might
actually qualify as Big Bads.
I mean, think about
all the crazy shit
they've kept us busy with.
Earthworms, adolescent
slug mash, turtle semen.
This is all just a thin
frosting of whimsy
on a cupcake of conspiracy.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
This is a full-scale invasion.
We need a plan bigger than
just assassinating the Queen.
We need... We need... We
need... We need... We need...
We need... Margo?
Margo?
Kidnapping. Hostages. Leverage.
Don't ask questions,
go! Go! What the fuck?
Go, go!
It's a bitch, right?
Imagine being stuck
on a raft with that thing.
Have you tried distracting it?
For some reason, mine
was really into seagulls.
Wonder if that's
because I'm into seagulls?
Please, fuck off.
Look, I'm sorry I
passed you the key.
I really thought
you could handle it.
This is me handling it.
No, no, you're right.
I wish we'd thought
of tying ourselves up.
That first day, we
passed it around randomly.
That killed three
of us off quick.
Called it Bloody Tuesday.
We figured out it affects
some people right away.
Others, it takes
time to wear down.
You want me to take
the key for a while?
Give you some relief?
No.
I don't trust you not to
pass it on to someone else.
And I need it.
For the quest. Fine.
Be a suffer-martyr.
Look, the keys don't
just make you suffer.
They help sometimes, too.
Like with the keyholes
and shit like that.
Keyholes, like...
Like in the walls or clocks.
Don't ask me how it works.
So... So where do
the keyholes go?
To Earth or the
Neitherlands or wherever.
Wait, wait. Are you serious?
Stop it. What are you doing?
I've been stuck here
in Fillory this whole time
when I could have gone home?
Hey. No, Poppy, stop it.
Poppy, no. Stop.
Poppy!
I told you you
should've killed yourself.
Okay.
Okay, we just have
one outstanding problem.
You kind of still need
to fuck your husband.
Don't worry. I got this.
Let's just say Ess was right
about the toads in these parts.
They've got three
eyes? No, baby.
They've got fangs.
Oh! Oh, something
bit my manhood.
Congratulations,
son. You just had sex.
The first time's always painful.
It's all those teeth
they've got down there.
But, hey, you were amazing.
What?
I like to watch.
Wanna go again?
Hmm?
Benedict!
Benedict, help!
Your Majesty? Oh,
my God, Benedict.
Okay, untie me.
Sire, you said not to untie you.
No. No, no, no, no, no.
Please, come on. Okay, look.
I'm not trying to kill myself.
Poppy took the
key, and she is trying
to use it to get back to Earth.
Just... Okay, go
find her yourself.
Just whatever you do, do
not let her leave with that key.
Yes, Your Majesty.
God.
No! Stop!
Hey, did you get it?
I'm sorry, Your Majesty.
I'm a terrible failure.
Okay. It's okay.
We'll get the key back somehow.
Benedict.
Hey, hey. Benedict.
Whoa, Benedict, no. Hey, listen.
Whatever it's telling
you to do, do not do it.
I'm sorry.
Benedict, no!
Mmm. Yummy.
Oh.
Oh, as long as I
know how to love
I know I'll stay alive
I've got all my life to live
I've got all my love to give
And I'll survive, hey, hey
Penny, what's wrong?
Just saying goodbye. What?
Goodbye? Where are you going?
Just away.
Away... Wait.
Fuck, I hate this thing.
Um, I don't understand.
Is this because of what
happened with Kady?
No. Okay.
Is it because we
did the transfer?
No. Look, I gotta go.
Wait, will you just talk
to me for a second?
You know what, we
barely know each other.
Don't suddenly act like you
care just 'cause I'm going.
I'm not acting.
I do care. I don't
want to see you go.
I don't want to see you give up.
Give up? Yeah.
You're the one who had
magic, and you gave it away.
What's your plan?
Go back to law school?
Live off your trust fund?
Actually, no, my plan
was to take five minutes
and try to remember
what life was like
without a god or a quest.
Or some dead
asshole bothering me.
And, I don't know,
frankly beyond that,
it's none of your business.
'Cause you have
nothing beyond that.
Penny wants to say goodbye.
You're leaving? I
can't do this anymore.
I can't be a ghost person
in my own life, okay?
Why don't I just
make you a new body?
Like Mayakovsky did for me.
A-plus job getting
rid of me, gorgeous.
Is this just a dream?
That time you fell out of
the tree when you were 12.
The bone in your arm
healed in six little weeks.
How come your fear
of heights never did?
I'm not the bone.
I'm the terror.
I do love how you keep trying.
And trying.
And trying. And trying.
I have not been punched
that hard since Burning Man.
Where is he? Where did he go?
Why does it smell like barbeque?
Benedict is dead, and
best-case scenario,
the dragon shits the key
into the bottom of the ocean.
Um, Quentin. Don't talk to me.
Please, I mean it. Okay.
Just... Just one thing
and I swear I will
never talk to you again.
What?
Dragons don't shit.
Okay, great, fun fact. Thanks.
No one knows
exactly how it works,
but what they ingest
goes elsewhere.
They're gatekeepers, you know?
They don't just make portals.
They are portals.
So, actual best-case scenario...
The key went to the Underworld.
Mmm.
Oh, my God.
If you're here, I'm practicing
an Osseus Confervium.
Bone-knitting.
First step to
building a new body.
I know you can't
see me, but I'm here.
Thanks for giving
a shit about me.
Alice?
Alice, you okay? Alice?
God, Alice. Alice!
God, this is... Where's...
Alice!
Okay, okay, God. Come on.
Come on, someone's
got to hear this, please.
Oh, as long as I
know how to love
I know I'll stay alive
I've got all my life to live
I've got all my love to give
And I'll survive, hey, hey
It took all the strength
I had not to fall apart
Kept trying hard to mend
the pieces of my broken heart