Previously on The Magicians...
Okay, what is this place?
Brakebills University.
You've been offered
a preliminary exam
for entry into the
graduate program.
Regrettably, you
failed the written exam.
Can I start over?
There's this voice. Everyone
else comes with a lot of static,
but him, he's clear
as a fucking bell.
You were hearing The
Beast? I was getting duped.
I'm Stanley. I'm your mentor.
Travelers are rare.
Where are we? The Neitherlands.
The place between
all other places.
My friend's life is in danger, and
I need to talk to you about Joe.
Joe? Oh! I love Joe.
Wait, so you know your
way around the Neitherlands?
How can I help?
We are pushing the boundaries
of what is magically possible.
We are the best
Magicians we know.
Silver can literally fly to the
moon but Menolly is dying.
Bender's trying to stay
off a ledge every day.
You're trying to...
Summon a god.
I'm a member of the Order,
the keepers of the
libraries of the Neitherlands,
the greatest repository
of knowledge.
Here it is. Wait,
Martin? That's...
Okay, is there anything
in there about The Beast?
Go back to the part where you
literally popped in on them banging.
We were casting a spell.
No judgment.
Saved your life.
All right, so there might be
a solution here, a weapon.
It sounds like if
we could find it,
we could use it
to kill The Beast.
El! Jesus!
It's 11:00 in the morning.
I'm listening.
So, Martin's desperate
'cause the Plover
figured out a way
to change physically,
which opened up a whole
new class of spellwork,
which meant that, pretty soon, he'd
be able to follow Martin into Fillory.
Yeah, so Martin got a line on
an enchanted knife, the Leo.
Uh...
Yeah, "powerful enough to tear
through the fabric of magic itself."
Like kill a God,
so qualified to murder a fairly
invincible mutant Magician.
That's the same god
that made the Virgo Blade.
Fucking love that guy.
Yeah, so Martin tracked
down the knife maker,
asked him if he could make
him one, and the guy said,
uh...
"Yeah, I can."
And then what?
Uh, well, that's the
end of the pages.
Yeah, nothing happened.
If Martin killed The Beast, would
we be here now talking about him?
Yeah, but here's the thing.
"So, little did Martin know, he
would fail to recover the blade,
"which would remain
hidden for decades,"
which means it could still be
sitting somewhere waiting for us.
Right, in Fillory, the
place where The Beast is.
Ergo, fuck that.
Hey.
Here's a crazy idea.
Plover wants the button back.
Why don't we just give it to him?
I don't think that's
a very good plan.
That's a monumentally
shitty plan.
I don't know.
Those Neitherland thugs
work for The Beast, right?
So, what if we hand
them the button,
thereby giving The
Beast what he wants,
thereby rendering
ourselves harmless,
thereby he leaves us alone.
Right 'cause handing the key to the
multiverse to a monster is a really...
That's a good idea, Eliot.
Beats getting vivisected.
Speak for yourself.
If his whole hard-on's
locking down travel
to Fillory so he
keeps it all to himself,
I'm still a problem.
Look, you can hide literally
anywhere in the universe.
The rest of us do
not have that luxury,
so let's not kick our only
semi-functional idea out of bed.
Okay, stop.
This affects all of us, so
those in favor of striking a deal...
Sorry. It's the right move.
Because you still seem, I
don't know, gloomy about it.
I can't believe you're not.
Penny's been gone for a week.
Which is like an hour in
the Neitherlands, right?
It means nothing.
What if it works?
Then it works. The Beast
leaves us alone. Great.
You're just upset 'cause you
may never get to go to Fillory.
No, that would be stupid.
Quentin. Why would I want to go?
The child-molesting demon, who
incidentally wrote my favorite books,
is there waiting to kill us.
Come on. We're late for PA.
Oh, my God.
No!
Please, wake up!
Margo, how did this happen?
We should have
listened to you, Q.
You think you're
hiding, don't you?
Sleep tight, Quentin Coldwater.
No way in hell we're doing
that fucking spell again.
You okay? Oh, my God.
Yeah, I'm just a little shaky.
I don't like dying.
No kidding.
You are Margo. You are fabulous.
You are under the influence
of a probability spell.
I am fabulous, aren't I?
Yeah.
What happened to you?
Beast ripped my head
off in the Neitherlands.
So much for
negotiating my freedom.
All right, this was a dead end.
Well, I hate to say I told
you so, but you know what?
Actually, I don't. I
don't. I don't hate that.
This is the last one. It's dead.
We're not learning anything new.
In every scenario, The
Beast comes next week.
There was one time we didn't
all die. When we went to Fillory.
No. Everything went white.
It's not necessarily better...
Well, I agree with Quentin.
That's because he blows you.
Seriously, eight tries. We get
seven deaths, one mysterious. I...
Give me that. I don't
think that we have a choice.
No, I'm choosing to get
the fuck away from all of you.
Hello, old friend. Been a while.
Do say you missed me a little.
Fuck you.
Let me cut to the chase.
You will deliver yourself to me.
Do it now, or do it when you've
gone so mad you have nothing left
because I'm going to
make it very, very loud.
Here's the deal. People used
to petition gods all the time
to bestow power, to work
stuff that we'd never dream of.
Now, they're it.
Biggest source there is.
At least, they were,
question being...
Where the hell are they now?
Exactly. No one's
spoken to a god
in centuries. They disappeared.
I believe that we can find
a way to contact them again
to get the kind of
help they used to give.
It's time, Richard.
Contact how?
Humans aren't
their only children.
There are others who are
older and might know more.
Magical creatures.
You mean like
vampires and unicorns?
I think unicorns
are a myth, but yes.
Find something high up
enough in the hierarchy,
they might actually remember
when gods and humans
were on speaking terms.
And there's a huge cross-section
of them right here in the city.
Yeah, because
they want to use us.
Look, you're right.
Most of them know nothing other
than hunger, thirst, and how to hide,
but it's a food chain.
We start at the bottom.
We work our way up till we find
someone who can help us get to them.
How long have you been at this?
A while.
I won't lie. You know,
it's been tough going.
Bender, show them.
Mostly bloodsuckers,
useless junkies,
but sometimes you can get
a lead onto something else.
After they talk your ear
off for, like, 12 hours.
Those leads admittedly
keep petering out,
but I think we have an
ace up our sleeve now.
Julia.
What?
That prayer I gave you, you
know, doesn't work for everyone.
Actually, you're the first.
I don't understand...
I know you're not
gonna like to hear this,
but I gave you a test.
Why?
I'm not religious.
I'm not anything.
We don't know why some
people are god-touched.
There's no rhyme or reason.
Karma, DNA, luck of the draw.
But it's you, Julia.
I think if we send you on the
hunt, we're gonna get some results.
I don't know. Penny
was pretty clear.
What are we planning?
Nothing yet. Just discussing
how we're all probably gonna die
before we even set
foot in Fillory because
the Neitherlands are
full of mercenaries.
Sounds like a problem.
Point is, we need some
serious battle magic.
But that stuff's illegal.
I'm fucking with you. I'm in.
I'm in, too. I heard
the word "illegal."
Oh, Alice, there's a note for you
from admin. I see you've got a call.
Mom, please, just calm
down. I can't understand you.
You what?
I'm so sorry.
I have to go. I'll call
you as soon as I can.
It's Joe.
He killed himself.
What?
I have to talk to Penny.
My mom says he was hearing
voices, and it was getting worse,
and that the voices
were threatening him.
He's a Traveler. He was a
Traveler, and I just thought...
I know what
happened to her friend.
It's The Beast. Shit.
I got it under control.
Penny, maybe you
should think about
the possibility that
he's targeting you guys.
I mean, you're like
a walking button...
Think you're telling
me anything new?
Sorry. I should go. I...
Penny, where are you gonna go?
We can find a way to help you.
I'm sorry. I've got
to talk to someone.
Stanley, man, you there?
Penny. I was wondering
when you were gonna show up.
You been hearing him, too?
He knows everything
there is about me.
My son's home address, describes
my granddaughter's every freckle.
Look, man, he's targeting us
because we can hear
him, because we can travel.
I mean, he wants all the roads
in and out of his fortress on lock.
No shit.
Like I want to
travel to a blue state.
Never mind other worlds.
What do we do?
I got a plan, and there's
nothing he can do to stop me.
Yeah? What's the plan?
Watch and trust me.
This removes all his leverage.
He can't make me
do a damn thing.
Where did you get this? Is
this, like, from World War II?
I tripped and fell on it locked in
a drawer in Sunderland's office.
My Japanese is a little
rusty, but I think that this says
Magic Misairu
Magic missile?
That's like straight-up
Dungeons & Dragons. Oh. Okay.
Uh...
Do you want to... Okay. Move.
Your Popper 43 is off.
Huh?
- What if we got guns?
- What?
No! No, look, this is
basic Prime Directive.
Fillory is a pristine,
non-industrialized society. You can't...
Yes, very pristine. It's been taken
over by a kiddie-diddling mutant.
Yeah, and that's
not Fillory's fault.
Great. Let's go native.
Scale of one to 10, how are
you with a broadsword, Quentin?
This should've worked.
Could of, should of, would of.
I mean, we've all done
battle magic before, right?
One time or another.
Eliot, you...
Twisted Mike's neck like a doll?
Yeah, and it was
shockingly easy.
I don't have an
explainer for you.
Yeah, and it just sort
of came puking out.
Well, where did you learn it?
I know who we need to talk to.
Tonight, Penny, or I kill
the girl in the dungeon.
Quentin.
No. Whatever it is, just no.
Look, we need your help.
We're trying to locate your ex.
Penny, please. I know, but
this is really that important.
It feels jacked to be doing a
mirror spell in here, seriously.
Just focus. It's not working!
Because she's a good Magician,
and she doesn't want to be found.
Look, Penny, I know you don't
really want to find her, but...
The reflection's changing.
You're welcome.
Penny!
Come with us!
I know this place.
That's Julia's apartment.
Shit.
Okay.
Hi.
Could we come in?
Julia's not here. She won't
be back for a couple hours.
Yeah, we're here to
talk to you, actually.
Okay. Um...
Please! Please give
him what he wants!
I think that's an
insanely stupid idea.
You don't just go fight
someone stronger on his turf.
We know. We have
a plan for The Beast.
We just need to make
sure we have enough
under our belt to
even make it to him.
Let's just say
you're very likely
to be mugged in
the Neitherlands.
I'm sorry. I can't
teach it to you.
Look, most people can't do
battle magic, except in crazy spurts.
Like "baby trapped
under a car" type shit.
But you can do it on cue.
Yeah, 'cause I
studied it for years.
Give us the CliffsNotes.
Fine. Meditate every
day for, like, a decade.
And spells only work if
you channel 100% clean.
Great. So we're stuck
with our dicks in our hands.
Look, there is this
thing Hedges use,
but I really wouldn't
recommend it.
Okay. Now we're listening.
She bleeds so
easily, poor little thing.
Fuck!
I barely touched her.
Hey.
Look...
So...
How is she? Julia, I mean.
Why do you care after
what she did to you?
Okay. It's none
of your business.
You know, that's
not how it works.
Giving a shit about someone
that you give a shit about
doesn't just evaporate the
second that they fuck up.
So why don't you just admit that
you want to ask me about Penny?
Okay, fine. Look, Julia is good.
Great, actually.
We're working on something that
could help a lot of people, so it's good.
Okay, now you.
Is he okay?
Yeah, he's extra broody, but...
You know, it's
Penny. He's fireproof.
He's like cockroaches. He'll
survive the nuclear winter.
You can end it.
Shut up.
Just end it.
Shut up. Oh, shut the hell up!
Stop it. GIRL: Please help me!
Please help me!
You should thank Alice
Quinn. She found you.
Get on with the lecture.
I've overdosed once.
No, twice,
if you count the time I
took so much Prozac,
I developed tardive dyskinesia.
But that was an accident.
The crack, that was a
straight OD, no chaser.
You smoked crack?
I've done things that would
make you hide under a blankie.
So just tell me
what's happening.
A voice from another world
has a thing for Travelers.
So it's an assault.
It's a nice mild term for it.
This goes on the
base of your neck.
It blocks the flow to
your head like a dam.
You didn't think of
giving this to me sooner?
It's not approved.
It wears down the mind's
own ability to defend itself.
It's just a temporary fix until we
can put you on a stricter regimen.
I don't have time for this.
Penny, you will
never have a home.
You will never
have a real family.
Your gifts will take this
from you, over and over.
So when someone cares
enough to reach out a hand,
just drop the bullshit attitude
and take what they're
offering while you can.
Bottling our
emotions, literally.
Kady says we shouldn't use these
for more than three
hours at a time, right?
That it's too hard
on the system,
and when the feelings come
back, it's extremely intense.
Yeah, yeah. Don't
lean on the bottle.
But, meanwhile, we get to
go full Spock with battle magic.
I don't like it.
Um, it's the perfect cheat.
I didn't say I wasn't gonna
do it. I said I didn't like it.
You look...
Damn handsome for someone
who just had a heart attack?
What can I say?
Genetically blessed.
What are those?
What do you care? I thought
you wanted nothing to do with us.
I changed my mind.
I'll go to Fillory
on one condition.
That girl you saw
in the dungeon?
Yeah, we'll get her out.
Deal.
This somehow doesn't feel like a
place where anyone knows anything.
Apparently this
guy's old as dirt.
Got to start
somewhere. Who knows?
'Cause you can't hold
back What you can't attract
The subtle attention of time
If you see her, just let me know
I plan to make this woman mine
Girls.
Agency sent you?
You Bjorn?
I asked for blondes.
I heard about you
from a girl who got fired
from the blood bank on
67th about a year ago.
Apparently, she wasn't
stealing for herself.
Tracy sold me out?
What did you give her?
Honestly, 20 bucks,
so I don't think
that was true love.
What do you want? I'm busy.
Look, we just have
a few questions.
We'll pay.
Twenty whole
dollars, rich bitch?
Whose is it?
Mine, so it's the cleanest
thing in this room.
We want to petition a god.
A god? You mean like a god?
Nobody's doing that stuff anymore,
sweetheart. God's inside you.
Come on, I told you...
Asked and answered.
Come on. Come on. Give me.
Give me a name.
Some other thing like you.
That's offensive. I'm
a person. I'm a person.
We're not a club.
They're all horrible. Pixies
are dicks. Lycans are rapists.
And shape shifters, they all
headed west back in the '50s.
Thank you for that
color commentary.
Do you want this or
not? Give me a name.
Okay, okay. Okay, I got one.
Sort of pretty.
This must be what undergoing
the Vulcan ritual of Kolinahr is like.
I like your sweater.
Are you saying that to be cruel?
No. I like your sweater.
I saw no reason not to share.
Well, then,
shall we go fuck some shit up?
Yes. Yes.
Yes, definitely.
Definitely, yes.
Just remember,
if this is a lamia,
we're dealing with
a high-level psychic.
Yeah.
What are you saying to me?
I'm not saying anything to you.
Who do you think you
are? I just want a quarter.
Hey.
Chickadee!
Mom?
It's so good to see you.
I'm so, so sorry.
Baby, I missed you so much.
Kady, step back,
okay? It's not your mom.
I'm not an idiot, Julia.
Julia.
I forgive you.
I know what you are.
I'm trying to give you a gift.
Both of you. You need me.
My mom is dead,
bitch. Drop the act.
If you can read
my mind, you know
that we both have
knives in our pockets,
dipped in gold and silver
and coated in shark's blood.
Jesus, that's overkill.
We weren't sure which
legends were true.
I hate Ivy League girls.
Then tell us what
we want to hear,
and I'll get that
one out of your hair.
What? What do I have for you?
Look at this place. Look at me.
Lamiae were
servants of a goddess.
Back before the
birth of fire, maybe.
We want to petition her.
That's so cute.
But that's not what you want.
I know what you really want.
To be whole.
Like you were on that day
that you split into two Julias
and you got in that
elevator and lost everything.
Shut up.
I can give you that.
Get out of my head.
Fine. I'll be blunt.
She's dead.
They're all dead.
Call the gods all you want.
There's no one to hear you.
Let's go. Come on.
Anyway, "God is dead"
seems to be the consensus.
I don't accept that.
Well, the Lamia
seemed pretty convinced.
She was a bitter, half-starved
monster living in filth.
The gods have abandoned
her. It doesn't mean they're gone.
We have another
rock to turn over?
Not yet.
So then, what? I mean...
I don't know, Julia.
I mean, what do you want
me to say? "I give up"?
"Forget about ever really fixing
anything"? No, we keep trying, okay?
At least I do. You do
whatever you want.
Well, I'm not going anywhere.
I mean, this is my house.
You're bleeding a little.
That explains the burning pain.
Is that a Traveler thing?
It's a hearing voices thing.
Well, I guess that beats
whatever you were snorting.
Marginally.
That was an
unadulterated success.
Pity we have to put them back.
Agreed. Feelings are bullshit.
Let's just get this over with.
Right. Bottoms up.
Whoa!
Oh!
Quentin. Quentin,
you know I love you.
I love you so much, like so
much. You know that, right?
Yeah, I do, 'cause I feel
like I'm kind of, like, all alone.
Why aren't we
friends anymore, El?
We're best friends.
Can we be honest for
five seconds, please?
Honestly, I'd rather not.
You don't care about me.
That is stupid.
We are going to Fillory
to save everything.
It'll all be fine, like
before, except even better.
Now, catch up.
This is Daddy's
third drink, Bambi.
Jesus.
My head. I couldn't even sleep.
They were a bad
idea, the bottles.
I hate everything.
I hate air right now.
You have diagnosed depression.
Shouldn't be bottling you
up, you could... Kill myself?
I'm sure Plover
would get to me first.
I think we should try
mastering it without the bottles.
I'm sure you probably could.
I'm talking about all of us.
Not all of us are you, Alice.
Okay, you're hung over. I don't
think you meant that like it sounded.
I'm sorry. Yes. I just... I feel like
sometimes you don't hear yourself.
All I said was that I
think we should try...
This is what that looks like.
I am trying as hard as I can.
Okay.
If you're not dead...
So I'm listening.
Whatever... I'm here.
I want to do good.
Please.
Hey.
Troops coming?
Still at the cottage studying.
What are you doing?
Trying to get off the bottle.
Me, too. Any luck?
Not yet.
That wine bottle knows
its days are numbered.
Sit. Get Zen.
Every warrior in history
learned how to do it.
I bet plenty of them
were hot messes.
We can do this.
Julia.
Not so dead, am I?
Nothing was wasted, Julia.
Ever.
Everything has served
to pull you closer to me.
Find me.
Near the bridge,
there's a man who has
served me 1,000 years.
Bring him three gifts.
He'll show you the way.
Then I will come to you,
my beautiful daughter.
Holy shit.
This is a definite
wobble, right?
Hey. Hey.
I brought this for you,
in case you want it.
Not yet.
It's been three
and a half hours.
We're late.
It was worth it.
To being bosses.
Ha!
Okay.
Remember that spring at the
foot of the mountains in Fillory?
It was Chatwin's Torrent.
Thought you didn't
remember the books.
Rupert was wounded, right?
Till the spring healed his leg?
You think it's real?
Some of the good
parts have to be.
At least, I hope so.
Why?
Because I probably
have liver damage.
On that note, we're out of wine.
Fine, I'll go.
Cheers.
Jesus, you two.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Thanks for reminding
me it's there.
Okay, it's your turn.
You can do it.
We are going to Fillory.
Oh, my God.
You're Toto, and
you are Dorothy.
Yeah.
And I am flying Muppets.
One step.
Meerkats. Two step.
No, wait. That's not it.
And I think he passed out.
Finally.
You know he was... He was
talking about Chatwin's Torrent.
Let's be honest.
There's a lot more wrong
with Eliot than a broken leg.
Yeah, but the spring
didn't just fix Rupert's leg.
It healed him.
All of him.
Here's the thing about you, Q.
You actually believe in magic.
So does everyone.
No.
We all knows it's real,
but you believe in it.
You just love it,
pure and simple.
You know, I've never
loved something like that.
That's not true.
Maybe Fillory can fix him
'cause he's really not okay,
and he just doesn't care.
It's okay.
We're gonna do whatever we can.
I promise.