QUENTIN: Previously on
The Magicians...
ELIOT: This school
exists for a single
and timeless purpose,
to reveal your
innate abilities
and hone them to
the highest degree.
Holy shit.
I'm doing this.
THE BEAST: Quentin Coldwater.
There you are.
All we can do is
make them Magicians.
That's not enough.
Marina didn't
betray my mom.
She cleaned up
her mess.
Cut to now, Marina
gets to demand
that l steal shit
10 times a week.
But you know who has
a ton of new stuff?
Marina.
Run!
OPERATOR: 911,
what's your emergency?
You are a Traveler.
It's a terrible,
life-destroying burden.
(GASPING)
I designed it myself.
It works by binding
your body to Earth.
ELIOT: You must bare
yourself in the presence
of another magical adept
and expose your utmost truth.
I'm falling
in love with you.
I flirted with
you that first day
because you looked
useful, and you were.
We stole a lot
of shit, so there it is.
It's all a lie.
Hey-
Alice,
... (GASPS)
(HONKING)
(GEESE HONKING)
(SIGHS)
(SIGHS) ME thinks it was
some kind of very rare
brain hemorrhage.
Your friend have a history
of that kind of thing?
She wasn't my friend.
Then why are you crying?
I don't know.
Anyway, you're free to go.
Somebody waiting out
here to pick you up.
Says she's your sister.
(WIND HOWLING)
QUENTIN: That happened, right?
We flew
here to Antarctica?
(CHUCKLES)
I don't want to
lose it.
HOW it felt.
I... It...
The sky, it...
It's like you could
feel it inside the air.
Part of it,
all of it, like...
Everything fit
all by itself.
Penny, can we...
Birds.
I never shit so
much in my life.
But at least I got to
eat bugs, so that...
Now snow.
God, I hate snow.
Hey, you were told
to report here, right?
By that TA or whatever?
Uh...
Yeah. I saw him herd
another six or seven
kids into the library.
So what is this then?
We're here to
study with Mayakovsky.
Who I hear is crazy.
MAYAKOVSKY: You heard wrong.
Sit.
I do not ask and I
do not order twice.
I hate you.
I hate all of you.
And you know why?
(PAPER FLAPPING)
It's the Hammer
Charm of Legrand.
We know this.
I hate all of you
because you
don't know anything.
You learn magic like
parrot learns Shakespeare,
tricks for birdseeds.
You are all clever pets.
You.
Sultry-But-Damaged.
What is the Hammer
Charm of Legrand?
It's, um...
It's the...
One day your looks
will be gone like that
and unless there's
a brain behind
those batting eyelashes
you will be selling
oranges at an off-ramp.
It's a spell that makes
nails go into boards
perfectly straight.
(CLATTERS)
You think you know
how to do this,
I assure you, you do not.
(CHANTING SPELL)
(SNAPS FINGERS)
Your voices are
your enemies.
A great Magician...
And as you gaze
into your mirrors
in the coming years,
you may recall that
I was the last great
Magician you ever saw.
A great Magician is magic
in his bones, blood,
heart, and dick.
Or lady parts.
Whatever.
Begin.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Does this say, "lbiza"?
Yes, but this
screams, "
biza."
(LAUGHING)
Hey, so Ibiza...
ls a place...
That we're going to.
I'm hearing Encanto Oculto
this year is gonna be,
like, off the chain,
but you have to be invited
by people who've been.
(SIGHS)
And you guys
have both been.
Twice.
Right.
Margo, you look
so beautiful.
(STAMMERS)
I can't even...
I got this.
Tell me your name again.
Todd.
Here's the thing.
Encanto Oculto is
a solid week of sun,
drugs, and magical art.
Time stops, reality bends,
and you fuck five times a day.
On a bad day.
(CHUCKLES)
It sounds awesome.
It is, Todd.
It is awesome,
but honestly,
you'd end up in
a corner alone.
Bitter. Bumming
everyone out.
Like last year
at the bacchanal.
Poor... Wait,
what was his name?
Um... Hmm.
Todd.
How weird is that?
Todd, you don't
want to end up like
the other Todd.
What happened to him?
He just wasn't
meant to be there.
He moped and
whined and brought
everything down.
Okay, we were a little
wrecked, and for fun,
someone,
someone not us...
No, not us.
...turned Todd into a pig.
And we ate him.
(LAUGHS)
Wait, are you guys
messing with me right now?
Okay-
Well, I'm just gonna...
I'm gonna...
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Oh, my God.
Okay, focus.
Last thing, the regalo.
The re-what now?
The gift to the elders
footing the bill
for the debauchery.
Right. What did we get
them last year?
An actual,
working bag of dicks.
Right. It was lame.
You got anything?
YOu?
I wrote something down.
These TA's were
whispering,
so I figured it
had to be good.
They were talking about...
Yes. "How to make
magical gin."
Mmm. Gin and tonic.
Strong, classic.
No one kicks
that out of a party.
Me likey.
Good, but this you hatey.
I only got part of the spell.
We have to dig out
the rest in the library.
(GROANS)
(SIGHS)
Why don't you two
just fuck?
No?
Then try this,
work!
I'm fine, okay?
I'm just... (SIGHS)
I got hooked up with
some sketchy people,
but I'm fine.
Okay?
I'll get to this
tomorrow.
Blood's not going
to come out of
that sweater.
You should
just throw it out.
Okay, thanks.
For getting me home.
I'll call you.
I'm staying.
What?
To make sure
you're okay.
You really don't
have to do that, I'm...
The blankets
still here?
Yup.
(SIGHS)
What is this?
It's Arabic.
I flunked Arabic.
I got an A.
Well, partly because
I paid for
the exam answers
in nipple clamps.
Bag of dicks is
sounding awful good.
Copy that.
Whoa.
She means "Hi."
Are you guys trying
to translate Arabic?
Because I aced it here.
I mean, it was a couple
years ago, but...
Yeah. Mmm-hmm.
Cry for help.
Answered.
Mike.
Eliot.
Margo.
(WOOD CRACKS)
(EXHALES)
(PANTING)
Yes, yes.
By all means,
congratulate yourselves.
You are both
such winners.
(BOARDS CLATTERING)
(CLATTERING)
Possibly your first
intelligent communique.
You should have been
rendered mute long ago.
Now you're probably
wondering, "What next?"
(GROANS)
Bujo
d's Nail Extraction,
that's what.
You need help.
“Help-ll
You can't keep
going like this.
You have no idea what
you're talking about.
(SIGHS) Jules.
Please.
This is just like Daddy.
Daddy was a drunk.
He was crazy. I'm not.
James told us
he's worried.
James?
Well, let me bring
you up to speed.
James doesn't
remember me at all.
He called last month.
Said the reason
you dropped out
was your recovery.
Well, so much for
anonymous, right?
He cares, Julia.
So do I.
It's why I left
eight messages.
I mean, if I had known
that you were...
Mom knows you
got arrested.
She has to keep this
out of the papers.
She just got elected
to the board of the Met
and is trying to
close on a new co-op.
Of course she is.
She said you're
gonna get help, or...
Or what?
You tell her that I'm
not Daddy. I'm not crazy.
She's not sticking me
someplace to rot where
she stuck him.
She's not gonna
let go of this.
Well, I'm sorry,
what can she do?
You know,
I'm an adult.
Who disappeared,
confessed to being
on drugs, got arrested.
You think she doesn't
go to the opera
with 10 judges who would
happily commit you?
She's Mom.
(WHISPERING)
Fucking bitch.
Right down to
her lizard pumps.
But I'm not.
I love you
and I can keep
her away
and get you help.
(SIGHS)
Just please let me.
I called a place.
They can take
you tomorrow.
A u?
You remain
because you passed.
Barely.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
You may now speak.
You remain silent?
Perhaps you're
teachable after all.
Good.
As that which
you will now learn,
few know and even
fewer understand.
Mind control.
And these
are your first
subjects.
QUENTIN: Uh...
Isn't that kind of
unethical?
I mean, even if they're
bugs, they're alive.
They have free will.
We've been taught
not to try to control
living things.
How was your
lunchtoday?
Excellent boeuf
bourguignon, no?
And how much free will
was exerted by the cow?
Mind control is in
everything, everywhere.
We make only one choice,
are you the controller
or controlled?
You do not like
the moth, I see.
(CHUCKLES)
Good.
That which
you hate or fear,
will motivate
you to enslave it.
Ah.
My favorite.
You're psychic?
You're also Traveler?
Yeah.
What idiot marked you
there? Don't tell me.
A well-meaning educator.
It's saving my life.
It's chaining you to
a rock. You are free.
More free than almost
anyone in this universe
or any other. Ah.
Where you think
you're sticking that?
They told you
not to travel, eh?
Too unpredictable,
too hard to control...
Yeah, because it is.
I got zero control.
I don't even have
a decent sense
of direction.
ls like telling eagle
to fear heights.
I teach you to soar.
Yes?
ELIOT: So... So, wait. Um...
So you know Rick?
Oh, my God,
Rick is great.
This magic gin better
make us see unicorns
that fart rainbows.
Guys, we have a lot
of work to do here.
Just bang.
Now!
Okay, that was weird.
Describe.
Yeah, I was in my
hometown in Florida.
Weird. Dull. Again.
Yes?
Uh, desert.
Earth?
Yeah.
Maybe Afghanistan.
There were guys
with guns.
I think I saw a drone.
Again.
(GASPS)
Fucking volcano!
Jesus.
Which you survived.
Gold star.
Well, you seem to be
the only ones who
can't complete the task.
In one case, surprising.
The other...
We try something new.
The rings are wired to zap.
Bug flies into ring.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
(BOTH GROAN)
Jesus.
Your fate is now tied
to the lowest form
of sentient life.
I deem that appropriate.
(SIGHS)
Let's just get one.
Okay.
Upper left.
Okay-
Yeah.
It's working.
Okay-
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Yes! Yes!
(LAUGHING)
Whoa, lam so...
Oh, my God,
I'm so sorry.
It's okay. It's okay.
Sorry.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Whoa. Ah.
Quentin!
(COUGHS)
(STAMMERS) I don't...
I'm sorry,
really sorry.
Jesus.
lsthatvodka?
You want me to
flunk him so you
can pass this test
with flying colors
alone?
No, sir.
I tried.
Again.
No.
(LAUGHING)
Yes! Yeah!
QUENTIN: on, my God.
Where's the joy?
The fun?
Why are you both
determined to be
so fucking bland?
Wait, are you
flunking us?
Sadly, I cannot.
Rest. Eat.
Meet me in
the entry at 5:00.
PENNY: I almost, uh...
I almost died today
and I realized I
didn't want to die
without knowing, so...
If you feel like
telling me, I'm here.
I don't have to
tell you anything.
I just have to
drop my wards.
Let you "m.
You can see everything.
Come on in.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(OVERLAPPING WHISPERS)
Your mom.
Jesus,she“.
And she's the only
person you love
in the world.
Not anymore.
(THUDDING)
(LAUGHING)
(THUMPING)
(GROANING)
(LAUGHING)
(THUMPING)
ELIOT: Oh!
I'm thinking.
You're too pretty.
(LAUGHS)
Okay, listen, listen.
What?
What if this Marina?
Okay, what if
she got this...
What if she got
some serious shit?
I mean, like, really dope,
one-of-a-kind magic.
Maybe it'd buy you
out. For good.
It'd have to be
pretty amazing.
It is.
I've seen it.
Where?
Mayakovsky's office.
(LAUGHS)
I'd just like to point
out that for the record,
you guys basically
did nothing except
each other.
Todd was more
helpful than you.
Don't. I'm just
using you for effect.
You're right, Margo.
I'm sorry.
Listen, I really hope
we get a chance to
get to know each other.
We'll give it
a whirl after Ibiza.
Maybe.
Enough, ladies.
Shall we magic some gin?
Please.
(CLATTERS)
(RUMBLING)
(AIR HISSING)
(SIGHS) Well, that
was underwhelming.
(RUMBLING)
Oh, yeah, smart guy?
Todd, ice, olives, stat!
ELIOT: Oh, no.
Oh, shit.
Not gin,
SJ-i-n.
This summons a djinn.
D-j-i-n-n.
A genie?
Cool.
Shut up,Todd.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
ELIOT: Wait, this
could be great.
I mean, if he grants
wishes for real,
and we bring him
to Ibiza, I mean,
that's a fuckin‘ regalo!
(LAUGHING)
Okay, this genie
totally gets me.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
(YELLING)
Whoa!
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLES)
The fuck?
Remove your clothes.
Oh, come on.
You think this is
the worst it can
be for you?
(SCOFFS)
Do it.
(WIND HOWLING)
(BOTH PANTING)
Being out there without fur...
It's brutal.
With fur...
It's nice.
(MOANING)
Uh...
This isn't gonna
be weird, is it?
It doesn't have to be.
How am I supposed
to know? This was
your idea.
The genie looked at you.
He was talking to you.
I don't even
know what he said.
TODD: It was Arabic.
He said, "Yes, Mistress,
I understand,"
and then something
I didn't get,
and then, "l will do
exactly that to him."
To him. To Mike.
What did you
tell him to do?
You were right there.
I didn't say a word.
TODD: You didn't have to.
You uncorked him.
He could read
your thoughts.
That is fucking rude.
God damn it, Margo.
Okay, just...
Nothing bad.
I just wanted Mike
to go back to where
he came from.
What does that even mean?
It would be the place
where you first
saw him, maybe?
Let's go.
Oh, okay.
You wished
my boyfriend away.
Boyfriend?
He's a random cock.
You are unbelievable
sometimes.
Other people aren't
supposed to get
between us.
He didn't get
I want him
with us, maybe.
But...
What's so special about him?
Really?
What makes him
more interesting
than the last 10?
Uh, guys?
Mike?
Jesus.
Get up.
(ELIOT SIGHS)
What the actual...
Whoa. (GRUNTS)
He'll only
listen to you.
Stop.
(GASPING)
Whoa.
Put him back, Margo.
You don't have to
say anything. Just...
Fine. Shit.
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
Ugh.
Huh.
Oh, God. Shh.
(MIKE GROANS)
ELIOT: Okay, baby, come here.
I don't get this part.
My full wish, that
Mike would go back
to where he came from
and suck on
some other knob.
So literal.
Swag.
Good enough to
trade you out
of Marina's hold?
Small enough
for bird flight.
I'll go mix some
paste for the spell.
A few minutes,
we're flying again.
(BOTH MOANING)
Go.
(LAUGHS)
(SIGHS)
(WIND HOWLING)
Your mental wards
are quite strong,
Sultry-But-Damaged.
I couldn't read anything
until you dropped
them for Penny.
Then I saw it all.
You have suffered
much for your mother.
And I'm afraid
it's not over.
Your mother is dead.
A spell of some
kind gone wrong.
I only learned
yesterday through
the school
and only just now
realized who she
was to you.
How it all fit
together.
You are now free of Marina.
But also
they know everything
at Brakebills.
Who you are, what you've done.
You cannot go back.
I was forced.
Brakebills is not
a forgiving place.
You deserve better
than their punishment,
which would be
extreme.
You're planning to
fly tonight with Penny.
You need to think
about his future as well.
His gifts are a curse.
Without training and practice,
they could kill him.
What am I supposed to do?
What we all do each moment.
Decide.
No.
(WIND HOWLING)
Eliot, come on.
We're gonna miss
the opening orgy.
You're not even dressed.
(SIGHS)
I'm not going.
Fuck.
You're still mad?
No.
I mean, yes,
but that's not why.
I... Mike, lbiza's not
really his thing...
It's ours.
And will be again.
Along with the million
other things that
are just us.
I only have one Bambi.
You're gonna miss me
so hard, you won't be
able to get it up.
That's probably true.
(SLAPS)
Todd?
Todd.
It's your lucky decade.
Pack a swimsuit.
Seriously?
Ground rules,
you need to fit in,
so don't talk.
Um...
See that she hydrates,
wears sunblock,
and waxes.
Mama's down south
can getjungly.
And you're in
charge of the genie.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(FLUTTERING)
Hey-
Come back to bed.
Be right there.
(WIND HOWLING)
QUENTIN: Hey, where's Kady?
Who gives a shit?
Alice, Quentin.
I got you both to
drop your fears
and inhibitions.
For that you should
be eternally grateful,
but I give you more.
I give you your
life's purpose.
Go and live to
prove me wrong.
Love each other,
be honest and kind,
faithful and happy,
and then,
come back here in 50 years
with your perfect family
and gloat over
my frozen corpse.
You're welcome.
Quentin.
Why?
Why the fox?
Why not mollusk
or firefly? Why?
The fox knows
and I knew
everything I needed
to survive was me
and it's not just
to survive,
but to be happy.
I was
happy-
The fox is in you now,
both of you.
Feedit
You really are
a great teacher.
I know.