NARRATOR: Previously on
The Magicians...
THE BEAST: Let's just nip
this all in the bud.
You were a paramedic.
Call me Eliza.
I was there that day to make
sure that you got here.
We flew here to Antarctica?
So what is this then?
We're here to
study with Mayakovsky.
Remove your clothes. Do it.
A few minutes,
we're flying again.
They know everything at
Brakebills, what you've done.
You cannot go back.
Hey, where's Kady?
Who gives a shit?
Run!
You can't keep
going like this.
I called a place.
They can take you tomorrow.
A "place"?
Mike.
Eliot.
What's so special about him?
It's a little
something I invented.
Oh.
I'd take a beer
if you've got one.
Beer?
You are lucky you're pretty.
(LAUGHS)
QUENTIN: Eliot.
You're back.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Hooray!
Oh, thank God.
How do you always have
drinks waiting for us? Uh...
Just a good host,
I guess.
Guys, um, this is
my friend, Mike.
He graduated a few years ago
and lives in New York,
and Margo tried to kill him
with a Djinn, but we fixed it.
This is Alice,
that's Quentin.
They are nerds.
I could kind of tell.
How was Brakebills South?
Did anyone freeze to death?
Uh... I mean, it was...
(CLEARS THROAT)
lt was eventful. l...
Why is your face
making that face?
Oh, my God.
They totally had sex. Yup. Yeah.
No, nothing happened. I
mean, it just happened.
You got drunk on Mayakovsky's
lichen vodka and you seduced him.
Maybe I seduced her.
Please. And, sweetie,
getting drunk and porking a dungeon
master is nothing to be ashamed of.
Uh, "Porking"?
I was looking
at the pork butt.
ALICE: I'm going to go
take a nap
and pretend that this entire
conversation never happened.
Okay.
Uh, um... I...
Nice meeting you.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, eyes on
the pork butt, mister.
He's pretty.
I know.
But I called dibs on him.
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, ignore Eliot. He's...
You know,
just being Eliot.
Don't.
I thought "nap"
was code.
Can we just talk about this
seriously for a second?
What we did was stress and
circumstances, and pheromones.
The first time,
but not the next four.
You were counting?
Of course
I was counting.
Maybe Eliot was right.
We may as well have been
drunk or high, or...
I'm not under
the influence right now.
Yes, we are, Q.
I can still smell you,
but like, Fox-you,
and I'm pretty sure
you can still smell me.
That could have
a lot to do
with the fact that we
haven't bathed in weeks.
Are you in love with me?
I, uh... l don’t know.
Even if you fell
down on your knees
and proclaimed your,
you know...
I know it wasn't
really you.
I think that we need to
spend some time apart
so we can know what's
real and what's Fox.
WOMAN". When they were lost,
ancient sailors used the
stars to find their way,
but, for you,
they're an obstacle
because they
change circumstances
so they can really
bone your casting.
When you're factoring the
position of the Pleiades,
you want to
keep in mind...
(WATER SPLASHING)
Whoa!
Whoa. (CHUCKLES)
Sorry, I'll just, uh...
I'll leave you to your
little sewing circle.
There's a syllabus, Penny“.
(SIGHS)
...and you're supposed
to be studying...
Haven't you heard...
Haven't you...
You're supposed to be
studying astral projection.
Now, here's what I know.
I feel like less of a pussy if I don't
cower in fear of my own ability.
I mean, if I supposed to
ever be able to travel,
like, really travel
between worlds, I need...
I need to be
able to master this
earthbound small
potato shit first.
Is something else
going on?
I know that you
were close with Kady.
Not as close
as you'd think.
You know, I...
I have a great idea.
I mean, you're so
worried about me,
why don't you
come travel with me?
You teach me,
and I know there's a few
things I could teach you, too.
I don't think that
would be appropriate.
Oh, I totally agree.
When do we leave?
You're going to be
late for your next class.
(SCOFFS)
DEAN FOGG: Your first
semester at Brakebills
was dedicated to learning
the fundamentals of magic.
We gave you the tools.
Now, it is time
for you to use them.
Look inside your bags.
Your course load
will double.
Astronomy,
botany, just to name a few.
Study groups
are mandatory.
QUENTIN: Gretchen.
Hey, uh, so I heard that you, uh, sleep
with a Mister Spock body pillow.
No judgment. I just...
I myself,
I have a full collection
of Leonard Nimoy's spoken
word albums on vinyl.
You interested?
Quentin, what are you...
Gretchen,
well, basically begged me
to switch groups
with her and, um...
Sorry. I wore
extra deodorant, though.
Yeah. It's strong.
So, are we
the whole study group?
(SNIFFS)
Hell is real,
and it smells
like Axe body spray.
(RABBIT SQUEALS)
(GRUNTS)
JULIA: "Dear Quentin.
"Thought you should
know I gave up magic.
"You were right.
"Thanks for nothing
"and go fuck yourself."
Who's your pen pal?
Leave before I
start screaming.
Easy.
I just came here to talk.
I'd say let's grab
a drink and hash it out,
(WHISPERING) ...but I feel
like that's a no-no here.
Why don't you talk about
what you did to Hannah?
I was protecting
myself from a thief
and I wish I hadn't
been put in that position.
Is this an amends letter?
Yes. Some of us are
capable of making them.
Okay.
Try this.
I'm sorry, Julia.
I don't let in a lot of people.
And the ones I do...
It's got to be some kind of
kindred spirit thing happening.
I actually like you.
And this?
This is not what I wanted.
You mean
what you wrote?
You're giving it up?
Well, let's short-circuit
this whole thing.
You stay
out of my ass
and there's no blood feud
necessary on my end.
But come after me,
and I will kill you and
everyone that you care about.
Well,
the ones that
are left, anyway.
(CHUCKLES)
Such a bitch.
And you're weak.
Why apologize to him?
He's the one who
should be in here, not you.
FOGG: Take your time,
Professor.
You're good to go.
Okay, Henry.
Go ahead
and try something.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(EXHALES)
Take it slow.
(GROANS)
Okay.
It might take
a few tries, Henry.
There are physical therapy
exercises... Uh...
When I was
four years old,
with no instruction
or help from anyone,
I taught myself magic.
I will do so again.
ELIOT: This is a disaster!
QUENTIN: What's wrong? I
have nothing to wear.
You think that might be,
I don't know, hyperbole?
I am not emotionally prepared for
Mike to see me in repeat outfits.
I think this might
be a Margo problem.
Obviously, Quentin,
but she's shacked up
with some artiste
at Encanto Octulo,
and, so, I'm stuck
with you.
Honestly, all vests
look the same to me.
I made a horrible
mistake asking you to help.
Please, leave.
I was here first.
I've never really seen you
care about something.
Things aren't
usually worth caring about.
With some limited, but
very important exceptions.
Very limited.
But seriously, leave.
And those of you who don't
know me way too well already,
I'm Richard,
I'm the chaplain here.
And I will try to make
my thing today brief.
No matter why
you started using,
if you try hard enough,
you can get clean.
You can change everything
about your circumstances,
but the one thing that
won't have changed is you.
Same head,
same heart, same mistakes.
Now, we don't like
to hear it,
but we need something
or someone to lean on
that is bigger
than ourselves.
Just say it.
God.
Well, that's one way
of putting it.
You know, there is a word for
when you lean on something,
a crutch.
(CHUCKLES)
Replacing drugs
or booze or porn,
or whatever with
a "Higher Power"
is just swapping one
crutch out for another.
That is a bummer way
of looking at things.
Why don't you just tell
these people the truth?
Maybe we just need to accept the
world for what it actually is.
Uh...
What about making the world
what we want it to be?
You know, with a little
effort, a little faith.
Give a man hope and a
nickel, you got a nickel.
(CHUCKLES)
Who said that?
Some dick.
Wow!
So, what do you
believe in?
It doesn't have to
be God or whatever,
but something bigger
than you.
QUENTIN:
I don't understand.
ALICE: The idea is you look
at the list of ingredients
and try to figure out
what the spell does.
Yeah.
Maybe, we should move on.
If we wait for the simpleton,
we'll be here all night.
Okay, if you understand,
then explain it.
It's a healing spell.
I've seen the welwitsch-whatever
in the infirmary.
Actually,
trick question.
It's a
Welwitschia mirabilis.
The leaves are used for both, healing
spells and for doing exotic curses.
I thought it was a fern.
Which is why I
brought flash cards.
Of course you did.
Thank you, Alice.
Could you not...
Could you... For one minute,
could you not
give her googly eyes?
I don't know what you're,
uh, implying or inferring.
Brakebills South
didn't have a lot of things.
Livable weather,
edible food, cable TV.
But you know
what it did have?
Windows.
So if you thought no
one saw your little,
little
extracurricular activities,
you'd be very mistaken foxes.
I was above average for a fox.
Okay, I've studied
enough for one day.
Thank you for that. It ain't
my fault or my problem.
For the record, you do see that
you're doing wrong, though?
I don't need your help.
But if I hypothetically did...
Man, you act like a stalker,
and then go out of your way to
deny that you're interested.
Either, grow a pair or she'll
find someone who already did.
Wow!
Not done.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
(SCOFFS)
Only downside is
it burns off all the alcohol.
Looks amazing.
Yeah, you don't have
to kill yourself for me.
It was no trouble.
I'm... I'm already deeply
impressed, you know?
And, I mean, I feel like I should
be doing stuff like this for you,
but I don't really know how.
Oh, don't be silly.
I guess I'm just waiting
for the part in all of this
where I start to bore you.
You don't bore me. I don't
think that you could bore me.
I don't know
about music and wine,
and, frankly,
any country not named Texas.
Texas is a state.
Not when you're from Texas.
Um...
Come here.
Where do you think
I come from?
I don't know.
Someplace with money?
Well, we did have money
'til Grandmama
gambled it all away,
and now all we
have are titles.
That was a joke.
I was born in Indiana.
On a farm.
My parents are farmers.
Indiana? I... I thought you...
Of course you did.
Becoming me was the greatest
creative project of my life.
So...
FYI, no one else here knows,
except for Margo,
and that's only because
she was my secrets
partner in the Trials.
Everyone else,
I kind of let
them go on thinking
I grew up summering
with Kennedys, etcetera.
Thank you.
For what?
Just you.
Um, well...
Here I am.
Yeah.
Here you are.
Hi.
Hey.
(GRUNTS)
(EXHALES)
(SHATTERING)
I checked the position
of Cepheus three times,
I did the whole invocation,
this stupid plant should be
seven feet tall by now.
What?
What happened to you and Kady?
You guys were inseparable.
She gets through the Trials,
she passes all of Mayakovsky's
tests and then she's just...
She didn't give
me an itinerary.
Man, I don't get it.
You act like you're
this panty-whisperer,
and your girl disappears and you
don't even know where she is.
You see her, tell her
she owes me 20 bucks.
Can I help you?
What?
Not you.
Uh, hey, Mike.
Sorry. I got... I got
a little turned around, um...
Could you tell me
which way the cottage is?
Yeah. It's like...
(GRUNTS)
Shit.
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH GRUNT)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
Oh, my God. Are you okay?
Whoa!
(GROANS)
Help! Help! Somebody help!
Get a transfusion ready, get the
Reidlinger Stones warmed up.
FOGG: Can you mend
the wound?
It's deep, but
it's not impossible.
The weapon.
We need the weapon.
Quentin.
Mike. Mike has it.
I need to see
the knife to know.
Yes, yes, yes, I know.
QUENTIN: To know what?
Find him. Now.
Mike is, uh,
Eliot's boyfriend, I guess.
He was trying to kill me
before Penny
jumped in the way.
Could it have anything
to do with The Beast?
Why would it?
Because it makes more sense than
somebody new trying to kill me.
Well, right now there are
far too many possibilities.
We will certainly ask Mr.
McCormick when we find him.
Quentin.
Is Penny okay?
He's in surgery. I don't know.
I just heard.
Everyone's really scared.
Yeah, I would've told you, but Fogg
wouldn't let us leave the building until...
Until they find Mike.
They did find him.
Professor Sunderland and March
found him trying to open a portal
near the Welters stadium.
Oh...
Where are they taking him?
Have you ever been
in this room before?
It was designed at
the turn of the century
for a set of incredibly
delicate experiments.
Mechanisms within the walls
prevent any spell-casting.
It is, in fact, a clean room.
It was not intended
for this purpose,
but it will do.
(SCOFFS)
Where is the weapon
that you used?
I don't know.
Were you specifically
targeting Penny and Quentin?
I was in Brooklyn.
Then I was here.
I don't know!
Professor...
Dean.
Henry, look, I...
Okay.
Okay, look.
Look, you know me, right?
I was your student
for three years.
You know that I couldn't.
I know you did!
No. You can't go in there.
What did he say?
Nothing useful.
You're just gonna
leave him in there?
I'm not letting him go.
No, I mean,
that's inhuman.
There is procedures for
dealing with magical crimes.
A circuit court system. They're
sending in a representative.
What will they do with him?
They have facilities.
But the exact punishment,
it depends.
On what?
On whether Penny lives.
This reeks of mind control.
Wait, there was something
wrong with his eyes.
They weren't entirely human,
that could be...
I've looked at every scenario
there is to think of.
Spell gone wrong,
doppelganger,
and, yes, gentlemen,
even mind control.
But there is always
the chance that he did this,
intentionally.
(GRUNTS)
Good morning.
Painkillers would be nice.
Your surgery was
very successful.
Your wounds are closed.
Just one or two weeks of...
Hey. You're not
ready to walk around yet.
I was stabbed, woman,
I'm gonna find
the motherfucker who...
(GRUNTS)
Get Professor
Lipson down here!
(PANTING)
What?
It's spreading too
quickly to be an infection.
The wound is cursed. Whatever it
is, it's growing under the skin.
He's lucky it's not
near any vital organs.
The necrotizing tissue...
Necrotizing?
Oh, cell death
within the tissue.
LIPSON: If it touches something
important... How do you fix it?
(SIGHS) Without seeing
the knife, I...
I have no idea.
I hate magic.
QUENTIN: I mean, why us?
You, I get.
I think about stabbing you all the time.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
That was 100% not a joke.
You realize that knife
was coming at me
before you jumped
in the way of it, right?
I owe you,
like, a Wookiee life debt.
Get a knife.
I'll stab you right now.
(SIGHS)
I keep thinking...
The Beast.
lt makes sense.
And yet it doesn't.
This Mike prick
isn't from Fillory.
Yeah.
Hey, do you want me to...
Uh... ls there anyone
you want me to call?
Parents, siblings,
parole officer?
I'm good.
No, Quentin.
She cared, she'd be here.
No visitors.
Two minutes.
What could he possibly say that
would make you feel any better?
I'm not here to feel better.
Please?
I was supposed to
have a date last night.
I got all dressed up.
I'm sorry.
All this stuff they're saying
I did, I don't remember.
You were blacked out.
Were you blacked
out when we met?
(FAINT MUSIC PLAYING
OVER HEADPHONES)
No, I don't want
to buy a bible.
(CHUCKLES)
What safe house were you in?
I recognized your ink.
You see it more often than you'd
think in a place like this.
You're a Hedge?
No. Classically
trained, myself.
There's a special
school called Brakebills.
You heard of it?
Yeah. Well...
I sort of checked myself
in here to get
away from magic, so...
Look, you think magic
is some terrible vice,
so bad that you need rehab to get clean.
It's not.
Magic isn't heroin, Julia.
It's a gift.
Oh, God, please don't
say "From God."
I'm not the guy outside of the
YMCA yelling at people to repent.
Then what are you, Richard?
Okay, what we call "magic" is
a set of tools,
leftover from Creation.
Think about it.
(SCOFFS)
The power to bend reality,
to make and unmake.
Won't God be pissed we touched
His tools without asking?
(CHUCKLES)
God... Gods, really,
they don't do
things by accident.
The tools were
left for us to find.
Right.
But, what I'm saying,
you don't have
to take my word for it.
See it for yourself.
WOMAN: Please!
You can't keep doing this to me!
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(SIGHS)
Penny?
It's just a headache.
I brought you your homework.
Why?
Fair point.
But if it were me, I'd be
glad to talk to somebody else
who wasn't a Healing student.
And since Kady's not here...
Oh, this is pity.
No.
(EXHALES) Well, kind Of.
I mean, she had shit to do elsewhere.
It's... I'm good.
Great.
I am.
I said great.
I get it.
People are
generally disappointing.
Yeah, be ready to pull a
ripcord at a moment's notice.
Like if you're messing around
with some loser who's
too obsessed with kids' books to
acknowledge he even sees you.
Ripcord.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Are you okay?
Can I do anything to help?
You want to help me?
Go to my room
and find the bag of pills
that's stashed under my desk.
Pills for what?
For... I'm a Traveler freak
who hears voices and I do a little
or a lot of self-medicating
to get them to shut
their scream-holes.
Penny.
Uh...
Alice, I don't need
any judgment.
No, Penny.
Oh. Okay.
That's... That's not great.
ALICE: Can someone
get Quentin?
Now!
This is not what I pictured.
It's from the fourth Fillory book.
(GROANS)
I read them all for research.
Yeah, Jane, um, she was alone
in Fillory for the first time
when she was attacked
by a Lorian assassin.
What's Lorian? Uh,
they're the bad guys.
Uh, from
a neighboring kingdom.
It's actually
really interesting
because Fillory is both,
the name of the land mass
and also the one of
the sovereign states...
Quentin, focus, please.
Uh,yeah.
Um, so the Lorian, uh, stabbed Jane
with something called a Virgo Blade.
And, uh, rose vines
grew from the wounds.
So, this seems to be the
way-grosser, (GRUNTS)
less whimsical
version of that.
Uh, this guy, Honeyclaw,
he was taking care of Jane.
Honeyclaw?
Yeah. A talking bear.
Oh, Jesus.
Honeyclaw said that the vines
would keep growing and growing
until they strangled her
heart, um, but Jane survived.
Penny, I know how to fix this.
Is that a turban?
No, it's your hair.
Sewing is not really my thing.
How is a voodoo doll
supposed to help me?
Uh, so, in the books,
Jane carries this doll around
with her everywhere she goes,
and it looks just like her.
Uh, and so they realized that
the curse of the Virgo Blade
would accept
the doll as a substitute.
So we burn a doll?
(SIGHS)
Okay, what else does
your dumb book say?
Henry.
It is considered good form to
announce oneself to blind people.
My glasses only show me
your outline, vaguely.
In my defense, I was raised
by wolves for a time.
The knife that
Penny was stabbed with
is from Fillory.
Something called
the Virgo Blade.
And you are familiar?
Yes.
This is a first.
You should've called
for me much sooner.
Quentin's the most at risk,
but if Penny dies...
This is your mess, Eliza.
Clean it up.
Then get as far away from
my university as possible.
Do you understand?
Mr. Coldwater, I don't have
a lot of time at the moment.
It is The Beast, isn't it?
And he's from Fillory,
which is real.
Of course Fillory is real.
You've known that since you were a child.
It's why you're here.
Okay, but there's no
Beast in the books.
The books are a child's
drawing of Fillory.
The real thing is stranger.
Yeah, it's full of psychopathic
monsters who are trying to kill me.
You want to know
what The Beast wants?
I'll tell you exactly.
He wants control of Fillory and
all the doors that lead there.
Maybe, he thinks
you'll find one of them.
I'm not a Traveler.
There are other ways.
I gave you a book about it.
Fillory and Further, Book Six?
I told you, I lost it.
And nothing lost
was ever found?
Wait, there's, uh...
What about Penny? There's got
to be something we can do.
You need to read
between the lines, Quentin.
Jane's doll wasn't special
because it looked like Jane.
ELIZA: It was special because
of where it came from.
Jane's mother gave it to her
before she died.
It was all she took
with her to Fillory.
Her only reminder of her
family and her life on Earth.
It was her most
precious possession.
What we love can be as
important to us as our lives.
So, the curse
accepted the doll
as a proper sacrifice
in place of Jane's heart.
I know you have
more questions.
After you save your friend.
I found a way to break the curse.
I just need a... Penny!
Hey, asshole, I need to know
your most precious possession.
He's been out of it for,
like, 20 minutes.
Then it's too late.
(SIGHS)
I beseech and devote myself.
I plead and promise myself
to you,
She of the Grain,
that you will raise
me up above the chaff.
Amen?
When I met you
How are we supposed to know
what's important?
I don't know. Penny doesn't
have that much stuff,
we'll just to through it.
Pictures. Yeah, maybe it's something
from his childhood, his family.
He doesn't ever
talk about them.
Doesn't mean he
doesn't care about them.
Penny's not the
most sentimental type.
Well, maybe he carefully
crafts that image,
I don't know.
Everyone is sentimental.
(SIGHS) You're projecting.
You're projecting!
Okay.)'-
I'm getting a definite
circus clown vibe here.
Q, this is it.
You think Penny's most prized
possession is his Adderall?
If I had voices telling me all day long
to do dark magic and, I don't know,
the pills were the one thing
that made them stop,
they'd be pretty precious.
You can always get more pills.
They're fungible.
You're fungible.
Okay, what's yours, hmm?
That's kind of a personal
question for two people
who aren't supposed
to be in the same room?
What's yours?
A quilt that my grandmother
made me when I was little.
It's covered in cats.
Fillory and Further,
Book One, first edition.
I worked all summer
before eighth grade to get it.
It's predictable, I know.
Predictable's
not bad, Quentin.
Hey.
What about this?
A candy bar wrapper?
It's from Brakebills South. This is
the last place that he saw Kady.
Quentin, I don't think Penny
even cares that she's gone.
Believe me, he does.
What was that?
That you gave me?
Did it work?
It didn't feel like I
was doing a casting,
it felt like a casting
was being done on me.
It's because it's not a spell,
it was a prayer.
To what?
Local harvest deity.
Friendly,
and a little one-trick.
You're lucky she answered.
She's pretty shy.
It's like touching
a bare wire.
More energy than
I've ever felt.
It felt good.
It felt dangerous.
The reason you treat
magic like a drug,
is because the people
that taught it to you
act like drug dealers.
They buy it and they sell it,
and they fight
and they fuck for it.
But that's not
the only way to live.
That's the only
way I've ever seen.
I'm a very good Magician
and I do this.
There are good
people out there, Julia.
People trying to learn about the
world and make it a better place.
Now, you could be
one of those people,
you could be a dealer,
you could stay here,
be nothing.
You get to choose.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
If I give you something,
you think you can get it
into Brakebills for me?
(SCOFFS)
Don't bother with
the performance.
Even with these wards,
I can see right through you.
I wouldn't dream
of fooling you.
I have far bigger
dreams than that.
Very clever,
targeting someone
outside the campus
protections.
Graduate with an alumni key.
Attractive, to a certain sort.
It won't work next time.
There won't be a next time.
You can't hide
in Fillory forever.
Lock as many
doors as you want,
there's always a door to
Fillory when you need one.
Nothing's changed.
Still the same determined
little Jane Chatwin.
You know I never wanted this.
You forced my hand.
I wish it could be any other way.
(LAUGHING)
I picked the Virgo Blade
especially for you, Jane.
Little twinge of nostalgia.
Penny's going to live
and this meat puppet of yours
is going to a Salvadorian
prison in the morning.
All that scheming, wasted.
I could walk out of
here anytime I like.
If you can leave anytime,
then what are you waiting for?
Oh, I was waiting
for you.
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
Help me!
(GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
Oh, my God. Wait, wait, wait.
(GRUNTS)
(INDISTINCT CHANTING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Dean Fogg.
What do we do?
I don't know.
Fuck that.
Eliza is dead. I...
When The Beast comes back,
what are we...
She is the only one who could
actually give me answers.
There are no answers, Quentin.
Because we have no idea
what's going to happen next.
Most likely outcome,
especially now that he's
gotten Eliza out of the way,
you die,
your friends die,
we all die,
very bloody.
And all of this,
will have been for nothing.
(DOOR OPENS)
Are you okay?