NARRATOR: Previously on
The Magicians...
THE BEAST: Let's just nip
this all in the bud.
You were a paramedic.
Call me Eliza.
I was there that day
to make sure
that you got here.
We flew here to Antarctica?
So what is this then?
We're here to
study with Mayakovsky.
Remove your clothes. Do it.
A few minutes,
we're flying again.
They know
everything at Brakebills,
what you've done.
You cannot go back.
Hey, where's Kady?
Who gives a shit?
Run!
You can't keep
going like this.
I called a place.
They can take you tomorrow.
A u?
Mike.
Eliot.
What's so special about him?
It's a little
something I invented.
Oh.
I'd take a beer
if you've got one.
Beer?
You are lucky
you're pretty.
(LAUGHS)
QUENTIN: Eliot.
You're back.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Hooray!
Oh, thank God.
How do you always
have drinks waiting for us?
Uh...
Just a good host,
I guess.
Guys, um, this is
my friend, Mike.
He graduated a few years ago
and lives in New York,
and Margo tried to
kill him with a Djinn,
but we fixed it.
This is Alice,
that's Quentin.
They are nerds.
I could kind of tell.
How was Brakebills South?
Did anyone freeze to death?
Uh... I mean, it was...
(CLEARS THROAT)
It was eventful. I...
Why is your face
making that face?
Oh, my God.
Yeah.
They totally had sex.
Yup.
No, nothing happened.
I mean,
itjust happened.
You got drunk on
Mayakovsky's lichen vodka
and you seduced him.
Maybe I seduced her.
Please. And, sweetie,
getting drunk and
porking a dungeon master
is nothing to be ashamed of.
Uh, "Porking"?
I was looking
at the pork butt.
ALICE: I'm going to go
take a nap
and pretend that
this entire conversation
neverhappened.
Okay-
Uh, um... I...
Nice meeting you.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, eyes on
the pork butt, mister.
He's pretty.
I know.
Butlcaﬂed
dibs on him.
(CHUCKLES)
Hey, ignore Eliot. He's...
You know,
just being Eliot.
Don't.
I thought"nap"
was code.
Can we just talk
about this seriously
for a second?
What we did was
stress and circumstances,
and pheromones.
The first time,
but not the next four.
You were counting?
Of course
I was counting.
Maybe Eliot was right.
We may as well have been
drunk or high, or...
I'm not under
the influence right now.
Yes, we are, Q.
I can still smell you,
but like, Fox-you,
and I'm pretty sure
you can still smell me.
That could have
a lot to do
with the fact that
we haven't bathed
in weeks.
Are you in love with me?
I, uh... I don't know.
Even if you fell
down on your knees
and proclaimed your,
you know...
I know it wasn't
really you.
I think that we need to
spend some time apart
so we can know what's
real and what's Fox.
WOMAN". When they were lost,
ancient sailors
used the stars
to find their way,
but, for you,
they're an obstacle
becausethey
change circumstances
so they can really
bone your casting.
When you're factoring
the position
of the Pleiades,
you want to
keep in mind...
(WATER SPLASHING)
Whoa!
Whoa. (CHUCKLES)
Sorry, I'll just, uh...
I'll leave you to your
little sewing circle.
There's a syllabus,
Penny“.
(SIGHS)
...and you're supposed
to be studying...
Haven't you heard...
Haven't you...
You're supposed
to be studying
astral projection.
Now, here's what I know.
I feel like less of a pussy
if I don't cower in
fear of my own ability.
I mean, if I supposed to
ever be able to travel,
like, really travel
between worlds, I need...
I need to be
able to master this
earthbound small
potato shit first.
ls something else
going on?
I know that you
were close with Kady.
Not as close
as you'd think.
You know, I...
I have a great idea.
I mean,
you're so worried
about me,
why don't you
come travel with me?
You teach me,
and I know
there's a few things
I could teach you, too.
I don't think that
would be appropriate.
Oh, I totally agree.
When do we leave?
You're going to be
late for your next class.
(SCOFFS)
DEAN FOGG: Your first
semester at Brakebills
was dedicated to learning
the fundamentals of magic.
We gave you the tools.
Now, it is time
for you to use them.
Look inside your bags.
Your course load
will double.
Astronomy,
botany, just to name a few.
Study groups
are mandatory.
QUENTIN: Gretchen.
Hey, uh, so I heard
that you, uh, sleep with
a Mister Spock body pillow.
No judgment. I just...
I myself,
I have a full collection
of Leonard Nimoy's
spoken word albums
on vinyl.
You interested?
Quentin, what are you...
Gretchen,
well, basically begged me
to switch groups
with her and, um...
Sorry. I wore
extra deodorant, though.
Yeah. It's strong.
So, are we
the whole study group?
(SNIFFS)
Hell is real,
and it smells
like Axe body spray.
(RABBIT SQUEALS)
(GRUNTS)
J U LIA: "Dear Quentin.
"Thought you should
know I gave up magic.
"You were right.
"Thanks for nothing
"and go fuck yourself."
Who's your pen pal?
Leave before I
start screaming.
Easy.
I just came here to talk.
I'd say let's grab
a drink and hash it out,
(WHISPERING) ...but I feel
like that's a no-no here.
Why don't you talk about
what you did to Hannah?
I was protecting
myself from a thief
and lwish I hadn't
been put in that position.
ls this an amends letter?
Yes. Some of us are
capable of making them.
Okay-
Try this.
I'm sorry, Julia.
I don't let in
a lot of people.
And the ones I do...
It's got to be some kind of
kindred spirit
thing happening.
I actually like you.
And this?
This is not what I wanted.
You mean
what you wrote?
You're giving it up?
Well, let's short-circuit
this whole thing.
You stay
out of my ass
and there's no
blood feud necessary
on my end.
But come after me,
and I will kill you
and everyone
that you care about.
Well,
the ones that
are left, anyway.
(CHUCKLES)
Such a bitch.
And you're weak.
Why apologize to him?
He's the one who
should be in here, not you.
FOGG: Take your time,
Professor.
You're good to go.
Okay, Henry.
Go ahead
and try something.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(EXHALES)
Take it slow.
Okay.
(GROANS)
It might take
a few tries, Henry.
There are physical
therapy exercises...
Uh...
When I was
four years old,
with no instruction
or help from anyone,
I taught myself magic.
I will do so again.
ELIOT: This is a disaster!
QUENTIN:
What's wrong?
I have nothing to wear.
You think that might be,
I don't know, hyperbole?
I am not
emotionally prepared for Mike
to see me in repeat outfits.
I think this might
be a Margo problem.
Obviously, Quentin,
but she's shacked up
with some artiste
at Encanto Octulo,
and, so, I'm stuck
with you.
Honestly, all vests
look the same to me.
I made a horrible
mistake asking you to help.
Please, leave.
I was here first.
I've never really
seen you care
about something.
Things aren't
usually worth caring about.
With some limited,
but very important
excepﬁons.
Very limited.
But seriously, leave.
And those of you
who don't know me
way too well already,
I'm Richard,
I'm the chaplain here.
And I will try to make
my thing today brief.
No matter why
you started using,
if you try hard enough,
you can get clean.
You can change everything
about your circumstances,
but the one thing
that won't have
changed is you.
Same head,
same heart, same mistakes.
Now, we don't like
to hear it,
but we need something
or someone to lean on
that is bigger
than ourselves.
Just say it.
God.
Well, that's one way
of putting it.
You know, there is a word
for when you
lean on something,
a crutch.
(CHUCKLES)
Replacing drugs
or booze or porn,
or whatever with
a "Higher Power"
is just swapping one
crutch out for another.
That is a bummer way
of looking at things.
Why don't you just tell
these people the truth?
Maybe we just need to
accept the world for
what it actually is.
Uh...
What about making the world
what we want it to be?
You know, with a little
effort, a little faith.
Give a man hope
and a nickel,
you got a nickel.
(CHUCKLES)
Who said that?
Some dick.
Wow!
So, what do you
behevein?
It doesn't have to
be God or whatever,
but something bigger
than you.
QUENTIN:
I don't understand.
ALICE: The idea is
you look at the list
of ingredients
and try to figure out
what the spell does.
Yeah.
Maybe, we should move on.
If we wait for the simpleton,
we'll be here all night.
Okay, if you understand,
then explain it.
It's a healing spell.
I've seen
the welwitsch-whatever
in the infirmary.
Actually,
trick question.
It's a
Welwitschia mirabilis.
The leaves are used
for both, healing spells
and for doing exotic curses.
I thought it was a fern.
Which is why I
brought flash cards.
Of course you did.
Thank you, Alice.
Could you not...
Could you... For one minute,
could you not
give her googly eyes?
I don't know what you're,
uh, implying or inferring.
Brakebills South
didn't have a lot of things.
Livable weather,
edible food, cable TV.
But you know
what it did have?
Windows.
So ifyou thought no
one saw your little,
little
extracurricular activities,
you'd be very mistaken foxes.
I was above average for a fox.
Okay, I've studied
enough for one day.
Thank you for that.
It ain't my
fault or my problem.
For the record, you do see
that you're
doing wrong, though?
I don't need your help.
But if I hypothetically did...
Man, you act like a stalker,
and then go out of your way
to deny that
you're interested.
Either, grow a pair
or she'll find
someone who already did.
Wow!
Not done.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
(SCOFFS)
Only downside is
it burns off all the alcohol.
Looks amazing.
Yeah, you don't have
to kill yourself for me.
It was no trouble.
I'm... I'm already deeply
impressed, you know?
And, I mean,
I feel like I should be
doing stuff like this for you,
but I don't really know how.
Oh, don't be silly.
I guess I'm just waiting
for the part in all of this
where I start to bore you.
You don't bore me.
I don't think that
you could bore me.
I don't know
about music and wine,
and, frankly,
any country not named Texas.
Texas is a state.
Not when you're from Texas.
Um...
Come here.
Where do you think
I come from?
I don't know.
Someplace with money?
Well, we did have money
'til Grandmama
gambled it all away,
and now all we
have are titles.
That was a joke.
I was born in Indiana.
On a farm.
My parents are farmers.
Indiana? I... I thought you...
Of course you did.
Becoming me was
the greatest
creative project of my life.
So...
FYI, no one else here knows,
except for Margo,
and that's
only because
she was my secrets
partner in the Trials.
Everyone else,
I kind of let
them go on thinking
I grew up summering
with Kennedys, etcetera.
Thank you.
For what?
Just you.
Um, well...
Here I am.
Yeah.
Here you are.
Hi. Hey-
(GRUNTS)
(EXHALES)
(SHATTERING)
I checked the position
of Cepheus three times,
I did the whole invocation,
this stupid plant should be
seven feet tall by now.
What?
What happened to you and Kady?
You guys were inseparable.
She gets through the Trials,
she passes all of
Mayakovsky's tests
and then she's just...
She didn't give
me an itinerary.
Man, I don't get it.
You act like you're
this panty-whisperer,
and your girl disappears
and you don't even
know where she is.
You see her, tell her
she owes me 20 bucks.
Can I help you?
What?
Not you.
Uh, hey, Mike.
Sorry. I got... I got
a little turned around, um...
Could you tell me
which way the cottage is?
Yeah. It's like...
(GRUNTS)
Shit.
(GRUNTING)
(BOTH GRUNT)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
Oh, my God. Are you okay?
Whoa!
(GROANS)
Help! Help! Somebody help!
Get a transfusion ready,
get the Reidlinger
Stones warmed up.
FOGG: Can you mend
the wound?
It's deep, but
it's not impossible.
The weapon.
We need the weapon.
Quentin.
Mike. Mike has it.
I need to see
the knife to know.
Yes, yes, yes, I know.
QUENTIN: To know what?
Find him. Now.
Mike is, uh,
Eliot's boyfriend, I guess.
He was trying to kill me
before Penny
jumped in the way.
Could it have anything
to do with The Beast?
Why would it?
Because it makes more sense
than somebody new
trying to kill me.
Well, right now there are
far too many possibilities.
We will certainly
ask Mr. McCormick
when we find him.
Quentin.
ls Penny okay?
He's in surgery. I don't know.
I just heard.
Everyone's really scared.
Yeah, I would've told you,
but Fogg wouldn't let us
leave the building until...
Until they find Mike.
They did find him.
Professor Sunderland
and March found him
trying to open a portal
near the Welters stadium.
Oh...
Where are they taking him?
Have you ever been
in this room before?
It was designed at
the turn of the century
for a set of incredibly
delicate experiments.
Mechanisms within the walls
prevent any spell-casting.
It is, in fact, a clean room.
It was not intended
for this purpose,
but it will do.
(SCOFFS)
Where is the weapon
that you used?
I don't know.
Were you specifically
targeting Penny and Quentin?
I was in Brooklyn.
Then I was here.
I don't know!
Dean.
Professor...
Henry, look, I...
Okay-
Okay, look.
Look, you know me, right?
I was your student
for three years.
You know that I couldn't.
I know you did!
No. You can't go in there.
What did he say?
Nothing useful.
You're just gonna
leave him in there?
I'm not letting him go.
No, I mean,
that's inhuman.
There is procedures
for dealing with
magical crimes.
A circuit court system.
They're sending in
a representative.
What will they do with him?
They have facilities.
But the exact punishment,
it depends.
On what?
On whether Penny lives.
This reeks of mind control.
Wait, there was something
wrong with his eyes.
They weren't entirely human,
that could be...
I've looked at
every scenario
there is to think of.
Spell gone wrong,
doppelganger,
and, yes, gentlemen,
even mind control.
But there is always
the chance that he did this,
intentionally.
(GRUNTS)
Good morning.
Painkillers would be nice.
Your surgery was
very successful.
Your wounds are closed.
Just one or two weeks of...
Hey. You're not
ready to walk around yet.
I was stabbed, woman,
I'm gonna find
the motherfucker who...
(GRUNTS)
Get Professor
Lipson down here!
(PANTING)
What?
It's spreading too
quickly to be an infection.
The wound is cursed.
Whatever it is,
it's growing under the skin.
He's lucky it's not
near any vital organs.
The necrotizing tissue...
Necrotizing?
Oh, cell death
within the tissue.
LIPSON: If it touches
something important...
How do you fix it?
(SIGHS) Without seeing
the knife, I...
I have no idea.
I hate magic.
QUENTIN: I mean, why us?
You, I get.
I think about
stabbing you all the time.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
That was 100% not a joke.
You realize that knife
was coming at me
before you jumped
in the way of it, right?
I owe you,
like, a Wookiee life debt.
Get a knife.
I'll stab you right now.
(SIGHS)
I keep thinking...
The Beast.
It makes sense.
And yet it doesn't.
This Mike prick
isn't from Fillory.
Yeah.
Hey, do you want me to...
Uh... ls there anyone
you want me to call?
Parents, siblings,
parole officer?
I'm good.
No, Quentin.
She cared, she'd be here.
No visitors.
Two minutes.
What could he possibly
say that would make
you feel any better?
I'm not here to feel better.
Please?
I was supposed to
have a date last night.
I got all dressed up.
I'm sorry.
All this stuff
they're saying I did,
I don't remember.
You were blacked out.
Were you blacked
out when we met?
(FAINT MUSIC PLAYING
OVER HEADPHONES)
No, I don't want
to buy a bible.
(CHUCKLES)
What safe house were you in?
I recognized your ink.
You see it more
often than you'd think
in a place like this.
You're a Hedge?
No. Classically
trained, myself.
There's a special
school called Brakebills.
You heard of it?
Yeah. Well...
I sort of checked myself
in here to get
away from magic, so...
Look, you think magic
is some terrible vice,
so bad that you need
rehab to get clean.
It's not.
Magic isn't heroin, Julia.
It's a gift.
Oh, God,
please don't
say "From God."
I'm not the guy
outside of the YMCA
yelling at people to repent.
Then what are you, Richard?
Okay, what we call "magic" is
a set of tools,
leftover from Creation.
Think about it.
(SCOFFS)
The power to bend reality,
to make and unmake.
Won't God be pissed
we touched His
tools without asking?
(CHUCKLES)
God... Gods, really,
they don't do
things by accident.
The tools were
left for us to find.
Right.
But, what I'm saying,
you don't have
to take my word for it.
See it for yourself.
WOMAN". Please!
You can't keep
doing this to me!
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(SIGHS)
Penny?
It's just a headache.
I brought you your homework.
Why?
Fair point.
But if it were me,
I'd be glad to
talk to somebody else
who wasn't a Healing student.
And since Kady's not here...
Oh, this is pity.
No.
(EXHALES) Well, kind Of.
I mean, she had shit
to do elsewhere.
It's... I'm good.
Great.
lam.
I said great.
I get it.
People are
generally disappointing.
Yeah, be ready
to pull a ripcord
at a moment's notice.
Like if you're messing around
with some loser who's
too obsessed with kids'
books to acknowledge
he even sees you.
Ripcord.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Are you okay?
Can I do anything to help?
You want to help me?
Go to my room
and find the bag of pills
that's stashed under my desk.
Pills for what?
For... I'm a Traveler freak
who hears voices
and I do a little
or a lot of self-medicating
to get them to shut
their scream-holes.
Penny.
Uh...
Alice, I don't need
anyjudgment.
No, Penny.
Oh. Okay.
That's... That's not great.
ALICE: Can someone
get Quentin?
Now!
This is not what I pictured.
It's from the fourth
Fillory book.
(GROANS)
I read them all for research.
Yeah, Jane, um, she was alone
in Fillory for the first time
when she was attacked
by a Lorian assassin.
What's Lorian?
Uh, they're
the bad guys.
Uh, from
a neighboring kingdom.
It's actually
really interesting
because Fillory is both,
the name of the land mass
and also the one of
the sovereign states...
Quentin, focus, please.
Uh,yeah.
Um, so the Lorian, uh,
stabbed Jane with something
called a Virgo Blade.
And, uh, rose vines
grew from the wounds.
So, this seems to
be the way-grosser,
(GRUNTS)
less whimsical
version of that.
Uh, this guy, Honeyclaw,
he was taking care of Jane.
Honeyclaw?
Yeah. A talking bear.
Oh, Jesus.
Honeyclaw said that the vines
would keep growing and growing
until they strangled
her heart, um,
but Jane survived.
Penny, I know how to fix this.
ls that a turban?
No, it's your hair.
Sewing is not really my thing.
How is a voodoo doll
supposed to help me?
Uh, so, in the books,
Jane carries this
doll around with her
everywhere she goes,
and it looks just like her.
Uh, and so they realized that
the curse of the Virgo Blade
would accept
the doll as a substitute.
So we burn a doll?
(SIGHS)
Okay, what else does
your dumb book say?
Henry.
It is considered good form
to announce oneself
to blind people.
My glasses only show me
your outline, vaguely.
In my defense,
I was raised by
wolves for a time.
The knife that
Penny was stabbed with
is from Fillory.
Something called
the Virgo Blade.
And you are familiar?
Yes.
This is a first.
You should've called
for me much sooner.
Quentin's the most at risk,
but if Penny dies...
This is your mess, Eliza.
Clean it up.
Then get as far
away from my university
as possible.
Do you understand?
Mr. Goldwater, I don't have
a lot of time at the moment.
It is The Beast, isn't it?
And he's from Fillory,
which is real.
Of course Fillory is real.
You've known that
since you were a child.
It's why you're here.
Okay, but there's no
Beast in the books.
The books are a child's
drawing of Fillory.
The real thing is stranger.
Yeah, it's full of
psychopathic monsters
who are trying to kill me.
You want to know
what The Beast wants?
I'll tell you exactly.
He wants control of Fillory
and all the doors
that lead there.
Maybe, he thinks
you'll find one of them.
I'm not a Traveler.
There are other ways.
I gave you a book about it.
Fillory and Further, Book Six?
I told you, I lost it.
And nothing lost
was ever found?
Wait, there's, uh...
What about Penny?
There's got to be
something we can do.
You need to read
between the lines, Quentin.
Jane's doll wasn't special
because it looked like Jane.
ELIZA: It was special because
of where it came from.
Jane's mother gave it to her
before she died.
It was all she took
with her to Fillory.
Her only reminder
of her family
and her life on Earth.
It was her most
precious possession.
What we love can be as
important to us as our lives.
So, the curse
accepted the doll
as a proper sacrifice
in place of Jane's heart.
I know you have
more questions.
After you save your friend.
I found a way to
break the curse.
I just need a... Penny!
Hey, asshole, I need to know
your most precious possession.
He's been out of it for,
like, 20 minutes.
Then it's too late.
(SIGHS)
I beseech and devote myself.
I plead and promise myself
to you,
She of the Grain,
that you will raise
me up above the chaff.
Amen?
When I met you
How are we supposed to know
what's important?
I don't know.
Penny doesn't have
that much stuff,
we'll just to through it.
Pictures. Yeah, maybe
it's something from
his childhood, his family.
He doesn't ever
talk about them.
Doesn't mean he
doesn't care about them.
Penny's not the
most sentimental type.
Well, maybe he carefully
crafts that image,
I don't know.
Everyone is sentimental.
(SIGHS) You're projecting.
You're projecting!
Okay-
I'm getting a definite
circus clown vibe here.
Q, this is it.
You think Penny's most prized
possession is his Adderall?
If I had voices telling me
all day long to do dark magic
and, I don't know,
the pills were the one thing
that made them stop,
they'd be pretty precious.
You can always get more pills.
They're fungible.
You're fungible.
Okay, what's yours, hmm?
That's kind of a personal
question for two people
who aren't supposed
to be in the same room?
What's yours?
A quilt that my grandmother
made me when I was little.
It's covered in cats.
FiIIory and Further,
Book One, first edition.
I worked all summer
before eighth grade to get it.
It's predictable, I know.
Predictable's
not bad, Quentin.
Hey-
What about this?
A candy bar wrapper?
It's from Brakebills South.
This is the last
place that he saw Kady.
Quentin, I don't think Penny
even cares that she's gone.
Believe me, he does.
What was that?
That you gave me?
Did it work?
It didn't feel like I
was doing a casting,
it felt like a casting
was being done on me.
It's because it's not a spell,
it was a prayer.
TO what?
Local harvest deity.
Friendly,
and a little one-trick.
You're lucky she answered.
She's pretty shy.
It's like touching
a bare wire.
More energy than
I've ever felt.
It felt good.
It felt dangerous.
The reason you treat
magic like a drug,
is because the people
that taught it to you
act like drug dealers.
They buy it and they sell it,
and they fight
and they fuck for it.
But that's not
the only way to live.
That's the only
way I've ever seen.
I'm a very good Magician
and I do this.
There are good
people out there, Julia.
People trying to learn
about the world and make
it a better place.
Now, you could be
one of those people,
you could be a dealer,
you could stay here,
be nothing.
You get to choose.
(HEAVY BREATHING)
If I give you something,
you think you can get it
into Brakebills for me?
(SCOFFS)
Don't bother with
the performance.
Even with these wards,
I can see right through you.
I wouldn't dream
of fooling you.
I have far bigger
dreams than that.
Very clever,
targeting someone
outside the campus
protections.
Graduate with an alumni key.
Attractive, to a certain sort.
It won't work next time.
There won't be a next time.
You can't hide
in Fillory forever.
Lock as many
doors as you want,
there's always
a door to Fillory
when you need one.
Nothing's changed.
Still the same determined
little Jane Chatwin.
You know I never wanted this.
You forced my hand.
I wish it could
be any other way.
(LAUGHING)
I picked the Virgo Blade
especially for you, Jane.
Little twinge of nostalgia.
Penny's going to live
and this meat puppet of yours
is going to
a Salvadorian prison
in the morning.
All that scheming, wasted.
I could walk out of
here anytime I like.
If you can leave anytime,
then what are you waiting for?
Oh, I was waiting
for you.
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
Help me!
(GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
Oh, my God. Wait, wait, wait.
(GRUNTS)
(INDISTINCT CHANTING)
(HEAVY BREATHING)
Dean Fogg.
What do we do?
I don't know.
Fuck that.
Eliza is dead. I...
When The Beast comes back,
what are we...
She is the only one
who could actually
give me answers.
There are no answers, Quentin.
Because we have no idea
what's going to happen next.
Most likely outcome,
especially now
that he's gotten
Eliza out of the way,
you die,
your friends die,
we all die,
very bloody.
And all of this,
will have been for nothing.
(DOOR OPENS)
Are you okay?