Previously on The Magicians...
They're filling in the
endings of our books.
I'm sorry about your
friend's books, but...
Just go while you
still have the chance.
Technically, I have sexually
transmitted lycanthropy.
The other Josh told
me something terrible
was going to happen to him.
It was called "The Quickening."
It's going to happen to me, too.
I'm... A full-on goddess.
I'm not connected
to anything anymore.
My dad and I used to
build model airplanes.
You got your hands on this,
and it ended up in 20 pieces.
Magic's gone. I went into
remission a week later.
You turned your back on
what happens to your dad.
It's a voicemail from my mom.
Will you sit here for a minute?
Yeah.
I know Bacchus. He's a friend.
Then you'll poison him.
You know what's incredible?
How you can be such a good friend
and such a terrible friend
at the exact same time.
Gods are so tricky.
They took this part of
me that knew things.
How long has he been there?
Since we got back from Fillory.
He brought you back? I
was as surprised as you.
Meanwhile, you are
baking. Condolence muffins.
For Quentin?
His dad just passed away.
And a bullshit yuppie pastry
is gonna help him with that?
A muffin is not a
pastry. It's a quickbread.
What the hell is wrong with you?
I had to help The Monster murder a
friend of mine, and I'm not happy about it.
From the looks
of it, neither is he.
Well, I don't get
why he's depressed.
He got what he wanted.
Where's Darth Eliot?
She's gonna get us all killed.
I have examined this
over and over again,
and it still won't
reveal itself to me.
Why can't I remember anything?
I don't know. Total
drag, I get you.
But that's kind of what goes
along with a human body.
Aches, pains,
can't remember shit.
And since you're done with
your whole deal, I was thinking...
What deal are you talking about?
We led you to Bacchus.
You killed him.
So now that we're done-sies...
Don't speak to me of done-sies.
Only Bacchus is done-sies.
I'm just saying, you
got your vengeance.
Might wanna try another body.
Maybe a non-human one.
I don't know.
See if it helps with the
whole remembering thing.
I'm good.
Fuck.
You look like you could
use a big ball of carbs.
Jesus tits, this is a
good ball of carbs.
I thought you were pissed at me.
Oh, I'm not gonna pretend
I'm happy about Bacchus,
but I'm still sorry about Eliot.
Josh? Are you okay?
Oh.
Oh...
You want me to come?
I'm gonna miss the funeral.
I missed everything
leading up to it.
There's nothing you can say
to my mom that'll change that.
Well, I could say
that it's not your fault.
The way she sees
it, she's the grown-up
and I'm still making the
same kid mistakes I always did.
You break things.
I break things.
Parents are the worst.
What about you?
Oh, you know.
I was gonna look through
all the stolen books
Marina has stashed around.
See if I could find out
why I'm indestructible
yet can't do magic.
What about Penny? He
still, uh, sweating you?
He's not sweating me. Oh, right.
He's just following you around
with that "I'm totally into you,
"but I'm not gonna say
anything about it" vibe.
Quentin. What? I'm just saying.
Maybe he could help
you with the research.
You're a dick.
I am a dick.
Hey, uh... Penny
23. Look at that.
That sounded real natural.
Why are you skittish as fuck?
Am I? That's... No.
What's in the bag?
Oh, nothing.
You got blood on
your face. What?
Yeah, look in the mirror.
Oh, no, no, no, no, don't.
It's not what it looks like.
Oh! It looks like a dead animal.
Okay, maybe it is
what it looks like.
Is this 'cause of The
Quickening? I don't know.
Well, it's something. Look,
I don't know what to do.
Well, I was pretty damn
clear about one thing, wasn't I?
- You stay away from...
- Hey, guys.
Julia. Hey.
Hey, did Marina stash
any books in here?
What? Uh... Books? No, I...
I think in the... Yeah.
The other room?
Yeah, just not in the
subject I'm looking for.
About god problems.
You know, like, where did they
go for magical medical advice?
Why don't I help
you look, you know?
Uh, what about the
Maenads? The... The Maenads?
The followers of Bacchus'.
They're kind of high
priestess/nurses of the gods.
They were always
at Bacchus' parties
and when he would get too
wrecked, which was always,
they pulled him out and
gave him a divine B12 shot or...
Wait, wait, so The Monster killed
Bacchus but didn't touch the Maenads?
They're probably
still in Fillory.
They were pretty
attached to him.
Oh, I... I can take you.
Yeah, that'd be great.
Um, thanks, Josh.
Yeah.
You get this Quickening
bullshit figured out right now.
Okay.
I didn't think I passed it
on. You never said anything.
Oh, I'm sorry. Were you
waiting for me to tell you?
You never disclosed your status
to me in the first place.
Because you were
so understanding,
I thought you knew.
Uh, it was a little bit of a
low point for me, that night.
Oh, well, great to hear.
I don't mean you.
I was going through
a bad divorce.
You're the first person
who really seemed to get
what I was going through.
Fine, whatever. Look...
Look, I just need your help.
What is going on with me?
With us? The Quickening?
Well, I don't really
know everything.
You're a goddamn cryptozoology
professor. What do you know?
Lycanthropy is
technically a curse.
Transformations are
tied to the lunar cycle
and behavioral changes
are mostly non-lethal,
except during The Quickening.
Well, that sounds
pretty, pretty bad.
Oh, luckily, it only happens
every 30 years or so.
In the 48 hours leading up, all
lycanthropes experience urges
starting in the form of
nightmares or even waking dreams.
What is the curse
trying to make me do?
Have traditional sex
with an uninfected person
or kill them. Jesus K. LeChrist.
The urges increase as the
moon moves towards its aphelion.
The climax, as it were, and
the lycanthropic high point
of lupinity or wolf-ness.
I took your class, Helen. I
know what lupinity means.
Why can't I just lock
myself up in a cage
until The Quickening passes?
Because that won't
satisfy the urge.
You need to have sex or kill
or you'll rip your own guts out.
That's how the curse
is ensured to spread.
It's quite clever, actually.
Oh, yeah, real clever
how I'm going to rape
or murder someone
in the next two
days, no matter what.
If you try to suppress it, it's
always possible you'll do both
or commit suicide.
Just, you know, to have
all the options on the table.
What the hell am I going to do?
What... What are we going to do?
Have you considered
Tinder? What? No.
Because I have a
really, really bad STD
and that sort of kills the
desire to sleep with anyone.
So forget... Mmm-hmm.
Wait.
Did you do that?
Yes. And it worked.
That is why I am not
going crazy right now. Huh.
Oh, you are very charming, Josh.
I'm sure you'll have no
trouble finding someone
to dance with before, you know,
the wolf makes a choice for you.
Good luck, Josh.
The Librarians don't
know I've been living here.
Apologies for the mess.
Oh, and, uh, for how
I brought you here.
I didn't mean to be rough.
I just wanted to get you out
of sight before you got caught.
You do remember me,
don't you? I'm Christopher...
Plover.
You're the child molester
who's directly responsible
for Martin Chatwin
becoming The Beast.
I also wrote some
very popular books.
How did you end up here anyway?
Oh, that's a long
and boring story.
The important thing is
we can help each other.
See, I need an extra
pair of hands. No.
And yet I know very well
that you could use my help.
You're trying to escape
The Order, aren't you?
From the looks
of it, we both are.
You didn't leave with
Santa Claus. Why not?
I get sleigh-sick. You
can say what you want.
But I know the real reason... Oh,
please don't touch that. Please.
The real reason
you stayed behind.
You were looking for your
book, yours and your friends'.
Do you have them?
The books are in
the Revision Room.
But I happen to
know where that is.
So you help me with my little
something, and I'll take you there.
Deal?
I don't know why your
father made so many of them.
He liked planes.
A creative outlet.
He's dead, Mom. We
can stop criticizing him.
I didn't want to be here at all, you
know, but there was no one else.
Molly is furious.
You know how she felt about Ted.
I know, I'm sorry, I...
I was traveling and
my phone died and I...
You're the only
millennial I know
who isn't buried
in his phone 24/7.
Are we going to do this again?
What was wrong with him, huh?
People make
friends. That's normal.
He was normal. I divorced
him, he was so normal,
so where are his
goddamn friends?
There was no one at the funeral.
I don't know.
Did he ever date?
Never mind. I
don't want to know.
Okay, so we pack these boxes.
Yeah, unless you want
to keep all this junk.
I found a guy upstate. He'll
take them off your hands,
but you have to get
it done by tomorrow.
I... I got it. Okay,
just, um, be careful.
Don't break anything.
Christ on a goddamn
communion wafer.
It's like I'm caught in a
real-life game of marry-fuck-kill,
only "marry" is off the table.
What are you gonna do about
it? I have no goddamn clue.
Why do you think I'm sitting
here with my head in my hands,
the traditional Hoberman
despair position?
Okay, then here's a plan.
We're going to
fix this bullshit.
I don't want to add to
your problems, Margo.
So 'cause of that,
you're gonna sit back
and just let this
shit happen to you?
Huh?
This ain't prom night,
and the only thing
I know for sure
is you're not going to fix
anything if you nutsack out on me.
I won't nutsack out.
Good. That's
what I want to hear.
Because we are going to
find a way out of this thing,
or we're gonna die trying.
I'm starting to see why no one's
ever beaten this curse. It's like herpes.
Cockroach-in-a-nuclear-war-level
impossible to stomp out.
Well, I found some shit on a
ritual from an Indonesian tribe.
It's supposed to prevent
supernatural transformations.
Or maybe cause them.
My Indonesian sucks.
Uber alert.
You know, these surge
prices are really getting out of...
Oh, no. Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Okay, surge prices piss me
off, too, but are you all right?
I've always been upfront
about my L-positive status
with any potential partners
before anything happens.
What's that have to do
with Uber? Isaac wasn't.
Oh.
So how many people
did Isaac do doggy-style?
Just one, and I'm going
to go warn her now.
Uh-huh. Yup! What a Monday!
So this book is used
to help me locate
different worlds via
a cooperative spell?
It is called The World Book.
Yes, I can read. So it's
like the encyclopedia.
More like an atlas. What
world are you looking for?
One where I can be
happy, where I can belong.
No, it's not what you think.
I'm not interested in that.
I just want to go somewhere
where I can do no harm.
I'll never do that again.
I swear on my life.
Yeah, well, I don't
know if I believe you.
I spent years being
tortured by Martin,
plenty of time to
think on my actions
and regret them.
Did you never unintentionally
hurt someone you love, Alice?
I never molested a child.
But, yes, I've
done things I regret.
Don't you deserve happiness? No.
Oh, come on, don't be so hard
on yourself. We all deserve it.
I don't think you do.
I don't particularly
care what you think.
You need my help
finding the Revision Room.
So either you help
me with this spell,
or you're on your own.
Who are you? Hi, uh, I'm Josh.
I'm Isaac's friend.
Isaac.
He hooked up with
you that one time.
Oh.
Right.
Look, it's a really
bad time right now.
Oh, uh, no, Isaac really wanted
me to talk to you about something,
and it's kind of an emergency.
So can I come in, please?
How do you know Isaac again?
Oh, uh...
He and I met at Jewish camp.
This is kind of weird. I mean,
why did he send a friend
instead of, like,
calling me himself?
He's got, uh, laryngitis.
So he can't text?
And he broke all of his fingers.
Anyhoo, I've got to talk to
you about Isaac's problem,
which he's embarrassed because
he came down with something,
and he's afraid that you
might have caught it from him.
Caught what? Oh, just a
herpes-like thing.
He gave me herpes? I
believe I said "herpes-like."
Well, what the hell is it?
The only way to know
if you got it is to sort of
go through the symptoms and see
if you've been experiencing them.
Okay, Josh from Jewish camp,
I'm going to
discuss genital warts
and discharge with
you 'cause we just met.
Jesus Christ. Fuck my life!
Look, have you maybe not
been feeling yourself lately?
Not really. And I'm
beginning to wonder
why I let you in,
in the first place.
Great, and, uh, have you
maybe been having dreams
that are weird and violent?
Maybe.
Right, well, this last one
might sound a little crazy,
but have you maybe been unable
to control yourself around guys?
Get out of my apartment.
Oh, wait. No, no,
no. This wasn't me
trying to freak you
out. Seriously, get out!
Okay, please, just let me
help you. I just want to help.
It's been a really
hard couple of days.
I've been totally
freaking, like...
What's wrong with me?
I know what you mean,
and it's completely normal,
and I assure you,
this is not your fault.
That's so good to hear. I mean,
how could I even do
that to someone else?
It's a total mess in there.
Uh, a mess? Uh, where? Mmm-hmm.
Jesus tits. It's
not that bad, is it?
Is it possible for an entire
forest to do the walk of shame?
Seriously, nature is not
supposed to be this sticky.
Uh-oh.
You think she's who
we're looking for?
Whoa, whoa! Wait,
wait! Don't! Why not?
Because you have
something to live for?
I'm a Maenad. The god
that I'm here to serve is dead.
I literally have
nothing to live for.
But thanks, thanks for the
less than basic understanding
of my life's purpose.
No, no, no! Wait! Don't,
please. We need your help.
Shoshana.
Shoshana. We need
your help, Shoshana.
Hmm?
Peach Schnapps.
Bacchus left that for
the talking bears to find.
Okay, so how about a toast?
Right? Ba... Bacchus
would've wanted us to drink.
God, like, so much. Yeah.
Okay, so to Bacchus.
To Bacchus.
Oh, God, it smells like pee
sangria. I don't give a shit. Drink it.
To, uh, Bacchus! Bacchus.
Whoo!
Oh, that's good shit.
Um, I was a goddess
and I gave away my power,
and now I can't use magic.
Only I'm indestructible.
So maybe you can help me
understand what is going on.
You were a goddess?
Yeah.
If all these other Maenads
hadn't run through the poison
wine like a bunch of bitches,
I wouldn't even
be in this situation!
Well, maybe if you
help us, we can...
Oh...
I'm sorry. What are
you... What are you doing?
I'm trying to read your aura.
Maybe we can just get the
pine cone out of my face?
Okay. That's what I thought.
Inconclusive.
I do know a ritual that could
help diagnose you further.
But, um, it's pretty intimate.
Um, okay. I can live with that.
Yeah, the only thing
is I... I can't perform it.
Uh, why not?
Well, I don't believe in you.
I can help interpret,
but you need someone
who believes in you,
okay, who worships you,
body and soul,
to perform the ritual.
Anyone come to mind?
Fine, I'll help.
Jesus R.R. Christ.
An innocent girl is a murderer
'cause I couldn't
get to her in time.
Oh, put your tit back in
your training bra, wolf boy.
We don't really know
how innocent this girl was.
Sleeping with her Uber driver
sounds like she had a
death wish to begin with.
You're not helping. Drink.
Is this a potion? It's alcohol.
Good enough.
While you were busy
with your domestic issues,
I managed to translate
this Indonesian ritual,
and good news is this
is first-year Brakebills
multi-culti elective crap.
So we can definitely pull it off
without breaking the magic bank.
Only prob is finding
one exotic ingredient.
Uh, what type of exotic
are we talking about here?
We need a living Komodo
dragon so we can cut out its heart,
and I heard a rumor Kanye keeps
one in his New York apartment.
That sounds on-brand. Let's go.
Uh, wait. I have to
give you something.
It's loaded with silver bullets.
The Quickening has started
to do weird things to me and...
Well, if I wolf-out,
you might need to stop me.
It's not gonna come to that.
I promise.
Now come on. Let's
go steal Kanye's lizard.
As you can see, rather
hard to get in unseen.
Not if you can bend light.
Regardless, stealing
the books isn't really
the biggest issue, is it?
If the Library discovers they're
gone, they're gonna come after you.
Yeah, but if they read my book,
they'll know
exactly where I'll be.
Yes, but what if
they read your book
and still had no idea
where you were?
What are you proposing?
When I was writing The Wandering
Dune, I was also studying magic.
Now, I kept blowing deadlines
until I found a spell
for automatic writing.
Now, you feed it a premise and
it constructs an airtight storyline.
I gather they use it in
Hollywood all the time.
That explains Netflix.
How does this spell work?
Why, we steal the
manuscripts, pull the endings,
cast a spell on them,
and then replace them
just before they take them
away to bind them as books.
Voilà. Oh, you'll
be very surprised
how your stories turn out.
Let me guess.
You'll show me how to do the spell
if I help you with the World Book?
Well, that only
seems fair, doesn't it?
Look, do you want
my help or not?
Mom, I told you I'd have this
done by tomorrow, so just...
Jesus.
Hello?
I found these in your
dead father's fridge.
They're not quite what
I'd hoped they'd be.
You finished with
the killing yet?
With the, uh...
What?
Your father's dead. I thought,
perhaps, you'd get angry and kill things.
That's what I'd do.
It's not really what people do.
Nowadays, anyway.
You're not going
to kill anything?
Interesting.
Frozen peas?
Nope. No, thanks.
Let's go, then.
I'm bored of this food.
Can I just have a few
minutes to finish this?
This is important to you?
Yeah, it is.
This is a very interesting game,
the loving your dead dad game.
I don't understand it.
It's not a game. It...
There must be someone
who's important to you,
who you... Who you miss.
I don't remember.
But perhaps you're right.
I could learn
something from this.
I'll let you play this game.
I will sit still, and I
won't kill anything
and I'll watch you while you...
You think about
your dead father?
Is that what you're doing?
Yeah. Kind of.
This is the weirdest
thing I've ever done.
But maybe it'll be fun.
I... She wasn't lying.
This is pretty intimate.
Yeah, well,
you're not the one who has to
strip naked and be anointed with oil.
Are you sure you
want to do this?
I don't really see
another way, do you?
Wait. Um...
Maybe there is
another way? Uh...
Something a little less painful?
Painful? Not painful. Um...
You know I'm not broken, right?
I'm not some flower or
a delicate piece of glass.
I'm a person, and people heal.
Yeah, look, I... I'm just not
very comfortable with the way
this is going down, you know?
Yeah, well, this
isn't really about you.
So maybe you could
just get over yourself.
I'm trying.
It's nothing you
haven't seen before.
Ta-da.
I guess I should start.
I guess you should. Yeah.
I do what I want
Don't do what I'm told
What I'm told
Been riding on the edge
With your heart in a chokehold
Heart in a chokehold
Maybe I'm a lost cause
What's wrong?
I, uh...
I got to go up front.
Won't do what I'm told
Are you asking if you
can touch my boobs?
I am asking you if I
can touch your boobs.
You can touch my boobs.
Just don't break them.
Ha-ha.
You should know You
should know You should know
Oh
What?
No, it's just... It's cold.
Oh, I'm sorry. I can warm it up.
I don't know how to
give you my love, babe
'Cause I'm too
good at messing it up
Maybe I could change
By now you should
know everything is strange
It's weird for me,
too, you know.
Give you my love
I don't know how
to give you my love
You ready to wash my feet?
Now what? Scream!
Now eat it! Uh...
It's not bad, actually.
I told you, vulnerable is
not technically endangered.
I think I'm going to be sick.
Don't you dare throw
up that lizard heart.
We killed a vulnerable creature
to save your ass.
It better not be for nothing.
Not to mention that is not the
way I thought I'd meet Kanye.
It's actually less messed up
than the way I thought it'd be.
Oh, yeah.
You want me, Josh?
You know what would
be hot right now?
If you just took me
right here in this car.
Stop the car! What is it?
Pull the car over
right fucking now!
No, no!
Son of a clit!
The ritual didn't work.
Oh, is that why you screamed
and ran out of the car?
Just let me in, okay?
Why? So you can
wolf-hump me to death?
No, I wanted to do things,
but you're safe now, okay?
It passed. How?
I kind of turned a
tree into a werewolf,
if you know what I'm saying.
Oh, got it.
It's not a permanent solution.
But it's enough to
keep the urges off
until we get to
where we're going.
You mind telling me
where that is, maple dick?
Brakebills.
I thought this
would be interesting.
It's not.
I'm almost done. Just...
A little while longer
and then we can go.
Why did you do that?
Slightly more interesting.
No.
Stop it!
I don't understand.
Your father is dead, right?
So these belong to
you now, do they not?
Yes, they belong to me.
What is your point?
Why are you doing any of this?
Because I told my
mom I would, okay?
Jesus Christ, I can't believe
I'm having to explain this.
Why does your mother have
such strange power over you?
Because once, when I was a kid,
I broke an ashtray.
And now she still fucking thinks
that I break everything.
Because...
Basically, your parents never
change how they see you.
No matter what.
So if they can't change
how they see you,
then why does it matter?
Because sometimes
I think she's right.
Things break around me.
Alice, my dad,
all of goddamn magic.
Then break them on purpose.
They're your planes.
You can do what
you want with them.
Maybe you'll feel better.
I don't mean to be rude,
but here I am helping as promised
without an assurance you'll do the same.
Jesus, you're relentless.
Okay, fine. I'll help
you with your spell.
Yet you seem to
hate yourself for it.
I mean, you can
understand my worry.
I don't have to
be happy about it.
A word of advice.
If you want to survive,
stop torturing yourself.
Maybe you could do with
a little more self-hatred.
And fewer Mr. Rogers vests.
You think that what you've done
and who you are, are the same thing.
When they don't match
up, you hate yourself.
Alice, they'll never match up.
You don't know
anything about me.
I know what it feels like
to be unable to change
no matter how much I want to.
Children don't care if you
contradict yourself, you know?
Perhaps that's a bad
example coming from me,
but I'm just trying to help.
Please just stop doing...
What is it?
The end of Quentin's book.
He's going to die.
Isn't that how all books end?
His ends next week.
And as requested,
the water my feet
were bathed in.
That's pretty murky.
Okay, judgey.
What's it mean?
It's too early to say.
This is very
interesting, though.
I thought you said you
didn't have any power.
No. I don't. I... I can't do
magic. Those aren't the same.
Oh, this,
this is real weird.
You weren't bullshitting me
when you said you were
a goddess, were you?
No, but how... How can I be a
goddess if I don't have any power?
Maybe you think
you don't, but...
I have never seen
anything like this before.
So we're good now?
You're not gonna kill yourself?
No, I can't now.
I have a new deity to follow.
Oh, boy.
I think you're overreacting.
I could've sexually
assaulted you or ate you.
I don't honestly know how
things would've turned out.
It's no reason to give up.
There's got to be a solution.
I've got, what, a couple hours
before The Quickening takes over,
and I'm sorry if that makes
me a wimp or whatever,
but I don't want to
rape or murder anyone.
Oh, come on.
There are plenty of people
who deserve to be killed.
I can think of a half
dozen at Brakebills alone.
If you can just keep
your twat together,
I'm sure I can get at least
one of them down here.
I mean, Todd totally owes me.
He doesn't owe you
his life. Doesn't he?
I can't do it, Margo.
Well, you can't do nothing,
because you'll die in this cage.
At least I can live with that.
I mean, not live exactly,
but you... You get
what I'm saying.
This is bullshit.
You're just throwing
your life away.
I was thinking more
like noble sacrifice.
Screw your noble sacrifice!
What is it with you boys
and your noble sacrifice?
I'm not gonna let you do it.
Well, it's not your choice.
You can't fix me, okay?
Some things are just broken,
and there's nothing
you can do about it.
Said the quitter
right before he quit.
You think I want to die?
Of course I fucking don't!
But... But I don't see a way out of
this, and frankly you not giving up
is making what I
have to do harder.
You want to do something stupid?
Fine by me.
What the hell are you doing?
Something stupider.
This isn't a joke, Margo. I... I'm
not going to be able to control myself.
I might kill you or...
Or... Or what?
Fuck me?
Margo.
This curse isn't curable.
I don't want you
to go through this.
The... The Quickening
is... Why not?
Because...
I like you.
I like you, too.
And I'm not gonna lose
another friend today, okay?
I can't make you kill someone,
but I can consent.
Damn.
The Quickening makes
you a really good kisser.
I know.
That was more cathartic
than I thought it would be.
It was kind of fun, wasn't it?
It feels good after you
deal with death, doesn't it?
A little.
Still hurts,
but eventually it
hurts a little less.
Uh-huh.
I'm going to need your
help to search for more gods.
You'll be more useful
to me if you feel better,
so you should know that
your friend Eliot is dead.
You can smash more
things if you want.
And then we'll go
get something to eat.
Sound good?
I cannot believe
you just did that.
I rocked your
world. Get over it.
Oh, no, you... That was great.
It's just you can't have
sex now with anyone
who isn't L-positive
without infecting them.
You know, so...
Since when is P-in-the-V sex
the pinnacle of what
one or two or three or five
or an animal can do together?
I mean, it's not
even on my top 10.
I guess I see your point there.
All the same,
what are you gonna do
about The Quickening?
How... How are you
gonna handle that?
In what, 30 years?
No way I'm gonna live that long.
And if I do, Todd
totally owes me.
You're joking, right?
You're joking.
So what is this? This is...
This is just casual, right?
We're not... You know?
I saved your
fucking life, bitch.
Casual that.
Thanks, Margo.
I'm sorry we couldn't
figure out a way to help,
you know...
I am, too.
I would have done
anything to save him.
But I think he might
actually be gone.
I felt the moment his soul died.
It only hurt for a second.
I promise he didn't suffer.
You'll come around.
I know it.
Let's take it right back
Hello?
But we never look back
No, we only look forward
To all the new pain
And violence that we blame
No, we never look back
No, we only look forward
Hello?
With all our fate
Hearts broken from the start
Is anybody there?
Margo!
Only to be held tall
By the writing on the wall
We don't need no
premonitions, no
Let's take it right back
To where it all began
But we never look back
No, we only look forward
To all the new shame
And waste of what we gain