Previously on
The Magicians...
The following books have been removed
from circulation for revisions...
They're filling
in the endings of our books.
I'm sorry about
your friend's books, but...
Just go while you still
have the chance.
Technically, I have sexually
transmitted lycanthropy.
The other Josh
told me something terrible
was going to happen to him.
It was called
"The Quickening."
It's going to happen
to me, too.
- I'm...
- A full-on goddess.
I'm not connected
to anything anymore.
My dad and I used
to build model airplanes.
You got your hands on this,
and it ended up in 20 pieces.
Magic's gone. I went into
remission a week later.
You turned your back
on what happens to your dad.
It's a voicemail from my mom.
Will you sit here
for a minute?
Yeah.
I know Bacchus. He's a friend.
Then you'll poison him.
You know what's incredible?
How you can be such a good friend
and such a terrible friend
at the exact same time.
Gods are so tricky.
They took this part of me
that knew things.
How long
has he been there?
Since we got
back from Fillory.
- He brought you back?
- I was as surprised as you.
- Meanwhile, you are baking.
- Condolence muffins.
For Quentin?
His dad
just passed away.
And a bullshit yuppie pastry
is gonna help him with that?
A muffin is not a pastry.
It's a quickbread.
What the hell
is wrong with you?
I had to help The Monster murder
a friend of mine, and I'm not happy about it.
From the looks of it,
neither is he.
Well, I don't get
why he's depressed.
He got what he wanted.
Where's Darth Eliot?
She's gonna
get us all killed.
I have examined this
over and over again,
and it still won't
reveal itself to me.
Why can't I
remember anything?
I don't know.
Total drag, I get you.
But that's kind of what goes
along with a human body.
Aches, pains,
can't remember shit.
And since you're done with your whole deal,
I was thinking...
What deal
are you talking about?
We led you to Bacchus.
You killed him.
- So now that we're done-sies...
- Don't speak to me of done-sies.
Only Bacchus
is done-sies.
I'm just saying,
you got your vengeance.
Might wanna try another body.
Maybe a non-human one.
I don't know.
See if it helps with
the whole remembering thing.
I'm good.
Fuck.
You look like you could use
a big ball of carbs.
Jesus tits,
this is a good ball of carbs.
I thought
you were pissed at me.
Oh, I'm not gonna pretend
I'm happy about Bacchus,
but I'm still
sorry about Eliot.
Josh?
Are you okay?
Oh.
Oh...
You want me to come?
I'm gonna miss the funeral.
I missed everything
leading up to it.
There's nothing you can say
to my mom that'll change that.
Well, I could say that
it's not your fault.
The way she sees it,
she's the grown-up
and I'm still making
the same kid mistakes I always did.
- You break things.
- I break things.
Parents are the worst.
What about you?
Oh, you know.
I was gonna look through
all the stolen books
Marina has stashed around.
See if I could find out
why I'm indestructible
yet can't do magic.
What about Penny?
He still, uh, sweating you?
- He's not sweating me.
- Oh, right.
He's just following you around
with that "I'm totally into you,
"but I'm not gonna say
anything about it" vibe.
- Quentin.
- What? I'm just saying.
Maybe he could help you
with the research.
You're a dick.
I am a dick.
Hey, uh... Penny 23.
Look at that.
That sounded real natural.
Why are you skittish as fuck?
Am I? That's... No.
What's in the bag?
Oh, nothing.
- You got blood on your face.
- What?
Yeah, look in the mirror.
Oh, no, no, no, no, don't.
It's not what it looks like.
Oh! It looks like
a dead animal.
Okay, maybe it is
what it looks like.
- Is this 'cause of The Quickening?
- I don't know.
- Well, it's something.
- Look, I don't know what to do.
Well, I was pretty damn clear
about one thing, wasn't I?
- You stay away from...
- Hey, guys.
Julia. Hey.
Hey, did Marina stash
any books in here?
- What?
- Uh... Books? No, I...
- I think in the... Yeah.
- The other room?
Yeah, just not in the subject
I'm looking for.
About god problems.
You know, like, where did they
go for magical medical advice?
Why don't I help you look,
you know?
- Uh, what about the Maenads?
- The... The Maenads?
The followers of Bacchus'.
They're kind of high priestess/nurses
of the gods.
They were always
at Bacchus' parties
and when he would get
too wrecked, which was always,
they pulled him out and gave
him a divine B12 shot or...
Wait, wait, so The Monster killed Bacchus
but didn't touch the Maenads?
They're probably
still in Fillory.
They were
pretty attached to him.
Oh, I... I can take you.
Yeah, that'd be great.
Um, thanks, Josh.
Yeah.
You get this Quickening bullshit
figured out right now.
Okay.
I didn't think I passed it on.
You never said anything.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Were you waiting for me to tell you?
You never disclosed
your status
to me in the first place.
Because you were
so understanding,
I thought you knew.
Uh, it was a little bit of a low point
for me, that night.
Oh, well, great to hear.
I don't mean you.
I was going through
a bad divorce.
You're the first person
who really seemed to get
what I was going through.
Fine, whatever.
Look... Look, I just need your help.
What is going on with me?
With us? The Quickening?
Well, I don't really
know everything.
You're a goddamn cryptozoology professor.
What do you know?
Lycanthropy is technically
a curse.
Transformations are tied
to the lunar cycle
and behavioral changes
are mostly non-lethal,
except during
The Quickening.
Well, that sounds
pretty, pretty bad.
Oh, luckily, it only happens
every 30 years or so.
In the 48 hours leading up,
all lycanthropes experience urges
starting in the form of nightmares
or even waking dreams.
What is the curse
trying to make me do?
Have traditional sex with
an uninfected person
- or kill them.
- Jesus K. LeChrist.
The urges increase as the moon
moves towards its aphelion.
The climax, as it were,
and the lycanthropic high point
of lupinity
or wolf-ness.
I took your class, Helen.
I know what lupinity means.
Why can't I just
lock myself up in a cage
until The Quickening passes?
Because that won't
satisfy the urge.
You need to have sex or kill
or you'll rip your own guts out.
That's how the curse
is ensured to spread.
It's quite clever, actually.
Oh, yeah, real clever
how I'm going to rape
or murder someone
in the next two days,
no matter what.
If you try to suppress it,
it's always possible you'll do both
or commit suicide.
Just, you know, to have
all the options on the table.
What the hell
am I going to do?
What... What are
we going to do?
- Have you considered Tinder?
- What? No.
Because I have
a really, really bad STD
and that sort of kills
the desire to sleep with anyone.
- So forget...
- Mmm-hmm.
Wait.
Did you do that?
Yes. And it worked.
- That is why I am not going crazy right now.
- Huh.
Oh, you are
very charming, Josh.
I'm sure you'll have
no trouble finding someone
to dance with before,
you know,
the wolf makes
a choice for you.
Good luck, Josh.
The Librarians don't know
I've been living here.
Apologies for the mess.
Oh, and, uh, for how
I brought you here.
I didn't mean
to be rough.
I just wanted to get you out of sight
before you got caught.
You do remember me,
don't you? I'm Christopher...
Plover.
You're the child molester
who's directly responsible
for Martin Chatwin
becoming The Beast.
I also wrote some
very popular books.
How did you
end up here anyway?
Oh, that's a long
and boring story.
The important thing is
we can help each other.
- See, I need an extra pair of hands.
- No.
And yet I know very well
that you could use my help.
You're trying to escape
The Order, aren't you?
From the looks of it,
we both are.
You didn't leave with Santa Claus.
Why not?
- I get sleigh-sick.
- You can say what you want.
But I know the real reason...
Oh, please don't touch that. Please.
The real reason
you stayed behind.
You were looking for your book,
yours and your friends'.
Do you have them?
The books are
in the Revision Room.
But I happen to know
where that is.
So you help me with my little something,
and I'll take you there.
Deal?
I don't know why your father
made so many of them.
He liked planes.
A creative outlet.
He's dead, Mom.
We can stop criticizing him.
I didn't want to be here at all, you know,
but there was no one else.
Molly is furious.
You know how
she felt about Ted.
I know, I'm sorry, I...
I was traveling and my phone died and I...
You're the only
millennial I know
who isn't buried
in his phone 24/7.
Are we going
to do this again?
What was wrong with him, huh?
People make friends.
That's normal.
He was normal.
I divorced him, he was so normal,
so where are
his goddamn friends?
There was no one
at the funeral.
I don't know.
Did he ever date?
Never mind.
I don't want to know.
Okay, so we pack
these boxes.
Yeah, unless you want
to keep all this junk.
I found a guy upstate.
He'll take them off your hands,
but you have to
get it done by tomorrow.
- I... I got it.
- Okay, just, um, be careful.
Don't break anything.
Christ on a goddamn
communion wafer.
It's like I'm caught in a real-life game
of marry-fuck-kill,
only "marry"
is off the table.
- What are you gonna do about it?
- I have no goddamn clue.
Why do you think I'm sitting
here with my head in my hands,
the traditional
Hoberman despair position?
Okay, then
here's a plan.
We're going to
fix this bullshit.
I don't want to add
to your problems, Margo.
So 'cause of that,
you're gonna sit back
and just let this shit
happen to you?
Huh?
This ain't prom night,
and the only thing
I know for sure
is you're not going to fix anything
if you nutsack out on me.
I won't nutsack out.
Good. That's what
I want to hear.
Because we are going to find
a way out of this thing,
or we're gonna die trying.
I'm starting to see why no one's ever
beaten this curse. It's like herpes.
Cockroach-in-a-nuclear-war-level
impossible to stomp out.
Well, I found some shit on a ritual
from an Indonesian tribe.
It's supposed to prevent
supernatural transformations.
Or maybe cause them.
My Indonesian sucks.
Uber alert.
You know, these surge prices
are really getting out of...
Oh, no. Oh, no,
no, no, no, no.
Okay, surge prices piss me off, too,
but are you all right?
I've always been upfront
about my L-positive status
with any potential partners
before anything happens.
- What's that have to do with Uber?
- Isaac wasn't.
Oh.
So how many people
did Isaac do doggy-style?
Just one, and I'm going
to go warn her now.
Uh-huh. Yup! What a Monday!
So this book
is used to help me locate
different worlds via
a cooperative spell?
It is called
The World Book.
Yes, I can read.
So it's like the encyclopedia.
- More like an atlas.
- What world are you looking for?
One where I can be happy,
where I can belong.
No, it's not what you think.
I'm not interested in that.
I just want to go somewhere
where I can do no harm.
I'll never do that again.
I swear on my life.
Yeah, well, I don't know
if I believe you.
I spent years
being tortured by Martin,
plenty of time
to think on my actions
and regret them.
Did you never unintentionally
hurt someone you love, Alice?
I never molested a child.
But, yes, I've done
things I regret.
- Don't you deserve happiness?
- No.
Oh, come on, don't be so hard on yourself.
We all deserve it.
I don't think you do.
I don't particularly
care what you think.
You need my help finding
the Revision Room.
So either you help me
with this spell,
or you're on your own.
- Who are you?
- Hi, uh, I'm Josh.
I'm Isaac's friend.
Isaac.
He hooked up with you
that one time.
Oh.
Right.
Look, it's a really
bad time right now.
Oh, uh, no, Isaac really wanted me
to talk to you about something,
and it's kind of an emergency.
So can I come in, please?
How do you
know Isaac again?
Oh, uh...
He and I met
at Jewish camp.
This is kind of weird.
I mean, why did he send a friend
instead of, like,
calling me himself?
- He's got, uh, laryngitis.
- So he can't text?
And he broke
all of his fingers.
Anyhoo, I've got to talk to you
about Isaac's problem,
which he's embarrassed because
he came down with something,
and he's afraid that you might have
caught it from him.
- Caught what?
- Oh, just a
herpes-like thing.
- He gave me herpes?
- I believe I said "herpes-like."
Well, what the hell is it?
The only way to know
if you got it is to sort of
go through the symptoms and see
if you've been experiencing them.
Okay, Josh
from Jewish camp,
I'm going to discuss
genital warts
and discharge with you
'cause we just met.
Jesus Christ. Fuck my life!
Look, have you maybe not been
feeling yourself lately?
Not really. And I'm
beginning to wonder
why I let you in,
in the first place.
Great, and, uh, have you
maybe been having dreams
that are weird and violent?
Maybe.
Right, well, this last one
might sound a little crazy,
but have you maybe been unable
to control yourself around guys?
Get out of my apartment.
Oh, wait. No, no, no.
This wasn't me
- trying to freak you out.
- Seriously, get out!
Okay, please, just let me help you.
I just want to help.
It's been a really
hard couple of days.
I've been totally freaking,
like...
- What's wrong with me?
- I know what you mean,
and it's completely normal,
and I assure you,
this is not your fault.
That's so good to hear.
I mean,
how could I even do that
to someone else?
It's a total mess in there.
- Uh, a mess? Uh, where?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Jesus tits.
- It's not that bad, is it?
Is it possible for an entire forest
to do the walk of shame?
Seriously, nature is not
supposed to be this sticky.
Uh-oh.
You think she's
who we're looking for?
- Whoa, whoa! Wait, wait! Don't!
- Why not?
Because you have
something to live for?
I'm a Maenad.
The god that I'm here to serve is dead.
I literally have
nothing to live for.
But thanks, thanks for the less
than basic understanding
of my life's purpose.
No, no, no! Wait! Don't, please.
We need your help.
Shoshana.
We need your help, Shoshana.
Hmm?
Peach Schnapps.
Bacchus left that
for the talking bears to find.
Okay, so how
about a toast?
Right? Ba... Bacchus would've
wanted us to drink.
God, like, so much. Yeah.
Okay, so to Bacchus.
To Bacchus.
- Oh, God, it smells like pee sangria.
- I don't give a shit. Drink it.
- To, uh, Bacchus!
- Bacchus.
Whoo!
Oh, that's good shit.
Um, I was a goddess
and I gave away my power,
and now I can't use magic.
Only I'm indestructible.
So maybe you can help me
understand what is going on.
You were a goddess?
Yeah.
If all these other Maenads
hadn't run through the poison
wine like a bunch of bitches,
I wouldn't even
be in this situation!
Well, maybe if you help us,
we can...
Oh...
I'm sorry. What are you... What are you doing?
I'm trying to read your aura.
Maybe we can just
get the pine cone out of my face?
- Okay.
- That's what I thought.
Inconclusive.
I do know a ritual that could
help diagnose you further.
But, um, it's pretty intimate.
Um, okay.
I can live with that.
Yeah, the only thing is
I... I can't perform it.
Uh, why not?
Well, I don't believe in you.
I can help interpret,
but you need someone
who believes in you,
okay, who worships you,
body and soul,
to perform the ritual.
Anyone come to mind?
Fine, I'll help.
Jesus R.R. Christ.
An innocent girl is a murderer
'cause I couldn't
get to her in time.
Oh, put your tit back
in your training bra, wolf boy.
We don't really know
how innocent this girl was.
Sleeping with
her Uber driver
sounds like she had
a death wish to begin with.
- You're not helping.
- Drink.
- Is this a potion?
- It's alcohol.
Good enough.
While you were busy with
your domestic issues,
I managed to translate
this Indonesian ritual,
and good news is
this is first-year Brakebills
multi-culti elective crap.
So we can definitely pull it off
without breaking the magic bank.
Only prob is finding
one exotic ingredient.
Uh, what type of exotic
are we talking about here?
We need a living Komodo dragon
so we can cut out its heart,
and I heard a rumor Kanye keeps one
in his New York apartment.
- That sounds on-brand.
- Let's go.
Uh, wait. I have to
give you something.
It's loaded
with silver bullets.
The Quickening has started
to do weird things to me and...
Well, if I wolf-out,
you might need to stop me.
It's not gonna come to that.
I promise.
Now come on.
Let's go steal Kanye's lizard.
As you can see,
rather hard to get in unseen.
Not if you can bend light.
Regardless, stealing
the books isn't really
the biggest issue,
is it?
If the Library discovers they're gone,
they're gonna come after you.
Yeah, but if they
read my book,
they'll know exactly
where I'll be.
Yes, but what if
they read your book
and still had no idea
where you were?
What are you proposing?
When I was writing The Wandering Dune,
I was also studying magic.
Now, I kept
blowing deadlines
until I found a spell
for automatic writing.
Now, you feed it a premise
and it constructs an airtight storyline.
I gather they use it in
Hollywood all the time.
That explains Netflix.
How does this spell work?
Why, we steal the manuscripts,
pull the endings,
cast a spell on them,
and then replace them
just before they take them away
to bind them as books.
Voilà. Oh, you'll be
very surprised
how your stories turn out.
Let me guess.
You'll show me how to do the spell
if I help you with the World Book?
Well, that only
seems fair, doesn't it?
Look, do you want
my help or not?
Mom, I told you I'd have this
done by tomorrow, so just...
Jesus.
Hello?
I found these in your
dead father's fridge.
They're not quite what
I'd hoped they'd be.
You finished
with the killing yet?
With the, uh...
What?
Your father's dead. I thought, perhaps,
you'd get angry and kill things.
That's what I'd do.
It's not really
what people do.
Nowadays, anyway.
You're not going
to kill anything?
Interesting.
Frozen peas?
Nope. No, thanks.
Let's go, then.
I'm bored of this food.
Can I just have
a few minutes to finish this?
This is important to you?
Yeah, it is.
This is a very
interesting game,
the loving
your dead dad game.
I don't understand it.
It's not a game. It...
There must be someone
who's important to you,
who you... Who you miss.
I don't remember.
But perhaps you're right.
I could learn
something from this.
I'll let you play
this game.
I will sit still,
and I won't kill anything
and I'll watch you
while you...
You think about
your dead father?
Is that what
you're doing?
Yeah. Kind of.
This is the weirdest thing
I've ever done.
But maybe it'll be fun.
I... She wasn't lying.
This is pretty intimate.
Yeah, well,
you're not the one who has to strip naked
and be anointed with oil.
Are you sure
you want to do this?
I don't really see
another way, do you?
Wait. Um...
Maybe there is
another way? Uh...
Something a little
less painful?
- Painful?
- Not painful. Um...
You know
I'm not broken, right?
I'm not some flower
or a delicate piece of glass.
I'm a person,
and people heal.
Yeah, look, I... I'm just not
very comfortable with the way
this is going down, you know?
Yeah, well, this isn't
really about you.
So maybe you could
just get over yourself.
I'm trying.
It's nothing you
haven't seen before.
Ta-da.
I guess I should start.
- I guess you should.
- Yeah.
I do what I want
Don't do what I'm told
What I'm told
Been riding on the edge
With your heart in
a chokehold
Heart in a chokehold
Maybe I'm a lost cause
I...
What's wrong?
I, uh...
I got to go up front.
Won't do what I'm told
Are you asking
if you can touch my boobs?
I am asking you
if I can touch your boobs.
You can touch my boobs.
Just don't break them.
Ha-ha.
You should know You should know
You should know
Oh
What?
No, it's just... It's cold.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I can warm it up.
I don't know how
to give you my love, babe
'Cause I'm too good
at messing it up
Maybe I could change
By now you should know
everything is strange
It's weird for me,
too, you know.
Give you my love
I don't know how
to give you my love
You ready
to wash my feet?
- Now what?
- Scream!
Now eat it!
Uh...
It's not bad, actually.
I told you, vulnerable is
not technically endangered.
I think I'm going
to be sick.
Don't you dare throw up
that lizard heart.
We killed
a vulnerable creature
to save your ass.
It better not
be for nothing.
Not to mention that is not the way
I thought I'd meet Kanye.
It's actually
less messed up
than the way
I thought it'd be.
Oh, yeah.
You want me, Josh?
You know what
would be hot right now?
If you just took me
right here in this car.
- Stop the car!
- What is it?
Pull the car over
right fucking now!
No, no!
Son of a clit!
The ritual didn't work.
Oh, is that why you screamed
and ran out of the car?
Just let me in, okay?
Why? So you can
wolf-hump me to death?
No, I wanted to do things,
but you're safe now, okay?
- It passed.
- How?
I kind of turned
a tree into a werewolf,
if you know
what I'm saying.
Oh, got it.
It's not a permanent solution.
But it's enough
to keep the urges off
until we get to
where we're going.
You mind telling me
where that is, maple dick?
Brakebills.
I thought this
would be interesting.
It's not.
I'm almost done. Just...
A little while longer
and then we can go.
- Why did you do that?
- Slightly more interesting.
No.
Stop it!
I don't understand.
Your father is dead, right?
So these belong
to you now, do they not?
Yes, they belong to me.
What is your point?
Why are you
doing any of this?
Because I told my mom
I would, okay?
Jesus Christ, I can't believe
I'm having to explain this.
Why does your mother have such
strange power over you?
Because once,
when I was a kid,
I broke an ashtray.
And now
she still fucking thinks
that I break everything.
Because...
Basically, your parents never
change how they see you.
No matter what.
So if they can't
change how they see you,
then why does it matter?
Because sometimes
I think she's right.
Things break around me.
Alice, my dad,
all of goddamn magic.
Then break them
on purpose.
They're your planes.
You can do what
you want with them.
Maybe you'll feel better.
I don't mean to be rude,
but here I am helping as promised
without an assurance you'll do the same.
Jesus, you're relentless.
Okay, fine.
I'll help you with your spell.
Yet you seem
to hate yourself for it.
I mean, you can
understand my worry.
I don't have to be
happy about it.
A word of advice.
If you want to survive,
stop torturing yourself.
Maybe you could do with
a little more self-hatred.
And fewer Mr. Rogers vests.
You think that what you've done
and who you are, are the same thing.
When they don't match up,
you hate yourself.
Alice, they'll never match up.
You don't know
anything about me.
I know what it feels like
to be unable to change
no matter how much
I want to.
Children don't care
if you contradict yourself, you know?
Perhaps that's
a bad example coming from me,
but I'm just trying to help.
Please just stop doing...
What is it?
The end of Quentin's book.
He's going to die.
Isn't that how
all books end?
His ends next week.
And as requested,
the water my feet
were bathed in.
That's pretty murky.
Okay, judgey.
What's it mean?
It's too early to say.
This is very interesting,
though.
I thought you said
you didn't have any power.
- No. I don't. I... I can't do magic.
- Those aren't the same.
Oh, this,
this is real weird.
You weren't bullshitting me
when you said you were
a goddess, were you?
No, but how... How can I be a goddess
if I don't have any power?
Maybe you think
you don't, but...
I have never seen anything
like this before.
So we're good now?
You're not gonna
kill yourself?
No, I can't now.
I have a new deity to follow.
Oh, boy.
I think
you're overreacting.
I could've sexually assaulted
you or ate you.
I don't honestly know how
things would've turned out.
It's no reason to give up.
There's got to be a solution.
I've got, what, a couple hours
before The Quickening takes over,
and I'm sorry if that makes me
a wimp or whatever,
but I don't want to rape
or murder anyone.
Oh, come on.
There are plenty of people
who deserve to be killed.
I can think of a half dozen
at Brakebills alone.
If you can just keep
your twat together,
I'm sure I can get at least
one of them down here.
I mean,
Todd totally owes me.
- He doesn't owe you his life.
- Doesn't he?
I can't do it, Margo.
Well, you can't do nothing,
because you'll die
in this cage.
At least I can live with that.
I mean, not live exactly,
but you...
You get what I'm saying.
This is bullshit.
You're just throwing
your life away.
I was thinking more
like noble sacrifice.
Screw your noble sacrifice!
What is it with you boys
and your noble sacrifice?
I'm not gonna let you do it.
Well, it's not your choice.
You can't fix me, okay?
Some things are just broken,
and there's nothing
you can do about it.
Said the quitter
right before he quit.
You think I want to die?
Of course I fucking don't!
But... But I don't see a way out of this,
and frankly you not giving up
is making what
I have to do harder.
You want to do
something stupid?
Fine by me.
What the hell are you doing?
Something stupider.
This isn't a joke, Margo. I... I'm not
going to be able to control myself.
I might kill you or...
- Or...
- Or what?
Fuck me?
Margo.
This curse isn't curable.
I don't want you
to go through this.
- The... The Quickening is...
- Why not?
Because...
I like you.
I like you, too.
And I'm not gonna lose
another friend today, okay?
I can't make you
kill someone,
but I can consent.
Damn.
The Quickening makes you
a really good kisser.
I know.
That was more cathartic
than I thought it would be.
It was kind of fun,
wasn't it?
It feels good after you deal
with death, doesn't it?
A little.
Still hurts,
but eventually it hurts
a little less.
Uh-huh.
I'm going to need your help
to search for more gods.
You'll be more useful to me
if you feel better,
so you should know that
your friend Eliot is dead.
You can smash
more things if you want.
And then we'll go
get something to eat.
Sound good?
I cannot believe
you just did that.
I rocked your world.
Get over it.
Oh, no, you...
That was great.
It's just you can't
have sex now with anyone
who isn't L-positive
without infecting them.
You know, so...
Since when is
P-in-the-V sex
the pinnacle of what one
or two or three or five
or an animal can do together?
I mean, it's not even
on my top 10.
I guess I see
your point there.
All the same,
what are you gonna do
about The Quickening?
How... How are you
gonna handle that?
In what, 30 years?
No way I'm gonna
live that long.
And if I do,
Todd totally owes me.
You're joking, right?
You're joking.
So what is this? This is...
This is
just casual, right?
We're not...
You know?
I saved your
fucking life, bitch.
Casual that.
Thanks, Margo.
I'm sorry we couldn't
figure out a way to help,
you know...
I am, too.
I would have done
anything to save him.
But I think he might
actually be gone.
I felt the moment
his soul died.
It only hurt
for a second.
I promise he didn't suffer.
You'll come around.
I know it.
Let's take it right back
Hello?
But we never look back
No, we only look forward
To all the new pain
And violence that we blame
No, we never look back
No, we only look forward
Hello?
With all our fate
Hearts broken from the start
Is anybody there?
Margo!
Only to be held tall
By the writing on the wall
We don't need
no premonitions, no
Let's take it right back
To where it all began
But we never look back
No, we only look forward
To all the new shame
And waste of what we gain