Previously on "The Magicians"...
"The following books
have been removed
from circulation
for revisions."
They're filling in the endings
of our books.
I'm sorry about
your friend's books, but...
Just go while you
still have the chance.
Technically, I have sexually
transmitted lycanthropy.
The other Josh told me
something terrible
was going to happen to him.
It was called the Quickening.
It's going to happen to me too.
I'm a full-on goddess.
[SCREAMING]
I'm not connected
to anything anymore.
My dad and I used
to build model airplanes.
Get your hands on this and you
ended up in 20 pieces.
Magic's gone. I went into
remission a week later.
You turned your back on what
happens to your dad.
It's a voicemail from my mom.
Let me sit here for a minute.
♪♪
I know Bacchus.
He's a friend.
Then you'll poison him.
You know what's incredible?
How you can be
such a good friend
and such a terrible friend
at the exact same time.
Gods are so tricky.
They took this part of me
that knew things.
[SAD MUSIC]
How long has he been there?
Since we got back from Fillory.
He brought you back?
I was as surprised as you.
[DINGING]
Meanwhile, you are baking.
Condolence muffins.
For Quentin?
His dad just passed away.
And a bullshit yuppie pastry
is gonna help him with that?
A muffin is not a pastry.
It's a quickbread.
What the hell is wrong with you?
I had to help the Monster
murder a friend of mine
and I'm not happy about it.
From the looks of it,
neither is he.
Well, I don't get why
he's depressed.
He got what he wanted.
Where's Darth Eliot?
She's gonna get us all killed.
I have examined this over
and over again,
and it still won't reveal
itself to me.
Why can't I remember anything?
I don't know.
Total drag, I get ya.
But that's kind of what goes
along with a human body.
Aches, pain,
can't remember shit.
And since you're done
with your whole deal,
I was thinking...
What deal are you talking about?
We led you to Bacchus.
You killed him.
So now that we're done-sies...
Don't speak to me of done-sies.
Only Bacchus is done-sies.
I'm just saying
you got your vengeance.
Might wanna try another body.
Maybe a non-human one.
I don't know.
See if it helps with
the whole remembering thing.
I'm good.
[FIRE FLARING]
Fuck.
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
♪♪
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
You look like you could use
a big ball of carbs.
♪♪
Jesus' tits!
This is a good ball of carbs.
I thought you were pissed at me.
Oh, I'm not gonna pretend
I'm happy about Bacchus,
but I'm still sorry about Eliot.
♪♪
[HEART BEATING]
[HEART BEATING FASTER]
[GROANING]
Josh?
Are you okay?
[YELLING]
[SCREAMING]
[PANTING]
Oh.
[SQUISHING]
[RETCHING]
[EERIE MUSIC]
♪♪
You want me to come?
I'm gonna miss the funeral.
I missed everything
leading up to it.
There's nothing you can say
to my mom that'll change that.
Well, I could say that
it's not your fault.
The way she sees it,
she's the grown-up
and I'm still making the same
kid mistakes I always did.
You break things.
I break things.
[CHUCKLING]
Parents are the worst.
What about you?
Oh, you know.
Gonna look through all
the stolen books
Marina has stashed around.
See if I could find out
why I'm indestructible
yet can't do magic.
What about Penny?
He still, uh, sweating you?
He's not sweating me.
Oh, right.
He's just following you around
with that "I'm totally into you
but I'm not gonna say anything
about it" vibe.
Quentin!
What? I'm just saying.
Maybe he could help you
with the research.
You're a dick.
I am a dick.
[UPBEAT MUSIC]
♪♪
Hey, uh, Penny 23!
Look at that.
That sounded real natural.
Why are you skittish as fuck?
Am I? That's... no.
What's in the bag?
Oh, nothing.
You got blood on your face.
What?
Yeah, look in the mirror.
Oh, ah, no-no-no-no-no!
Don't!
It's not what it looks like!
Oh! It looks like
a dead animal.
Okay, maybe it is
what it looks like.
Is this 'cause
of the Quickening?
I don't know.
Well, it's something.
Look, I don't know what to do.
Well, I was pretty damn clear
about one thing, wasn't I?
You stay away from...
Hey.
Julia! Hey!
Hey, did Marina stash
any books in here?
What?
Uh, books? No, I...
I think in the...
The other room?
Yeah, just not in the subject
I'm looking for.
About God problems.
You know, like where did they go
for magical medical advice?
Well, why... why don't I
help you look, you know?
Uh, what about the Maenads?
The... the Maenads?
The, uh, followers of Bacchus.
They're kind of high
priestess/nurses of the Gods.
They were always
at Bacchus' parties
and when he would get
too wrecked, which was always,
they pulled him out and gave
him a divine B12 shot or...
Wait, wait, so the Monster
killed Bacchus
but didn't touch the Maenads?
Well, they're probably
still in Fillory.
They were pretty attached
to him.
Oh, I... I can take you.
Yeah, that'd be great.
Uh, thanks, Josh.
Yeah!
You get this Quickening
bullshit figured out right now.
[CHUCKLING] Okay.
I didn't think I passed it on.
You never said anything.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Were you waiting for me
to tell you?
You never disclosed your status
to me in the first place.
Because you were
so understanding,
I thought you knew.
Uh, it was a little bit of
a low point for me,
that night.
Oh, well, great to hear.
I don't mean you!
I was going through
a bad divorce.
You're the first person
who really seemed to get
what I was going through.
Fine, whatever. Look... look,
I... I just need your help.
What is going on with me?
With us?
The Quickening?
Well, I don't really know
everything.
You're a goddamn
Cryptozoology professor.
What do you know?
Lycanthropy is
technically a curse.
Un, transformations are tied
to the lunar cycle
and behavioral changes
are mostly non-lethal...
except during the Quickening.
Well, that sounds
pretty, pretty bad.
Oh, luckily it only happens
every 30 years or so.
In the 48 hours leading up,
all Lycanthropes
experience urges
starting in the form
of nightmares
or even waking dreams.
What is the curse trying
to make me do?
Have traditional sex with
an unaffected person
or kill them.
Jesus K. LeChrist.
The urges increase as
the moon moves towards
its aphelion.
The climax, as it were,
and the lycanthropic high point
of lupinity or wolf-ness.
I took your class, Helen.
I know what lupinity means.
Why can't I just
lock myself up in a cage
until the Quickening passes?
Because that won't
satisfy the urge.
You need to have sex or kill or
you'll rip your own guts out.
That's how the curse
is ensured to spread.
It's quite clever actually.
Oh, yeah, real clever.
I'm going to rape
or murder someone
in the next two days
no matter what.
If you try to suppress it,
it's always possible
you'll do both
or commit suicide.
Just, you know, to have all
the options on the table.
What the hell am I going to do?
What... what are we going to do?
Have you considered Tinder?
What? No!
Because I have
a really, really bad STD
and that sort of kills the
desire to sleep with anyone.
So forget... wait.
Did you do that?
Yes.
And it worked.
That is why I am
not going crazy right now.
Huh.
Ugh, well, you are
very charming, Josh.
I'm sure you'll have
no trouble finding someone to
dance with before, you know,
the wolf makes a choice for you.
Good luck, Josh.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
♪♪
The librarians don't know
I've been living here.
Apologies for the mess.
Oh, and, uh,
for how I brought you here.
I... I didn't mean to be rough.
I... I just wanted to get you out
of sight before you got caught.
You do remember me, don't you?
I'm... I'm Christopher...
Plover.
You're the child molester
who's directly responsible
for Martin Chatwin
becoming The Beast.
I also wrote some
very popular books.
How did you end up here anyway?
Oh, that's a long, boring story.
The important thing is
we can help each other.
See, I need an extra pair
of hands.
No.
And yet, I know very well
that you could use my help.
You're trying to escape
The Order, aren't you?
From the looks of it,
we both are.
You didn't leave with
Santa Claus.
Why not?
I get sleigh-sick.
You can say what you want.
But I know the real reason...
Oh, please don't touch that.
Please.
The real reason
you stayed behind.
You were looking for your book.
Yours and your friend's.
Do you have them?
The books are in
the Revision Room.
But I happen to know
where that is.
So you help me with
my little something
and I'll take you there.
Deal?
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
♪♪
I don't know why your father
made so many of them.
He liked planes.
[SOFT CHUCKLING]
A creative outlet.
He's dead, Mom.
We can stop criticizing him.
I didn't want to be here
at all, you know,
but there was no one else.
Molly is furious.
You know how she felt about Ted.
I know, I'm sorry, I...
I was traveling
and my phone died and I...
You're the only millennial
I know
who isn't buried in
his phone 24/7.
Are we going to do this again?
[SIGHING]
What was wrong with him, huh?
People make friends.
That's normal.
He was normal.
I divorced him,
he was so normal, so...
where are his goddamn friends?
There was no one at the funeral.
I don't know.
[CHUCKLING]
Did he ever date?
Never mind.
I don't want to know.
Okay, so we pack these boxes.
Yeah, unless you want
to keep all this junk.
I found a guy upstate.
He'll take them off your hands,
but you have to get it done
by tomorrow.
I... I got it.
Okay, just, um...
Be careful.
Don't break anything.
Christ on a goddamn
communion wafer.
It's like I'm caught in
a real-life game
of Marry-Fuck-Kill,
only "marry" is off the table.
Well, what are you gonna do
about it?
I have no goddamn clue.
Why do you think I'm sitting
here with my head in my hands,
the traditional Hoberman
despair position?
Okay, then here's a plan.
We're going to fix
this bullshit.
I don't want to add
to your problems, Margo.
So 'cause of that,
you're gonna sit back
and just let this shit happen
to you?
Huh?
This ain't prom night,
and the only thing I know
for sure
is you're not going
to fix anything
if you nutsack out on me.
I won't nutsack out.
Good.
That's what I want to hear.
Because we are going to find
a way out of this thing
or we're gonna die trying.
[SIGHING]
I'm starting to see why no
one's ever beaten this curse.
It's like herpes!
Cockroach-in-a-nuclear-war-
level impossible to stomp out.
Well, I found some shit
on a ritual
from an Indonesian tribe.
It's supposed to prevent
supernatural transformations.
Or maybe cause them.
My Indonesian sucks.
[TEXT PINGING]
Uber alert.
You know, these surge prices
are really getting out of...
Oh, no.
Oh, no-no-no-no-no.
Okay, surge prices
piss me off, too,
but are you all right?
I've always been upfront
about my L-positive status
with any potential partners
before anything happens.
What's that have to do
with Uber?
Isaac wasn't.
Oh!
So how many people
did Isaac do doggy-style?
Just one and I'm going
to go warn her now.
Uh-huh, yup!
What a Monday!
So this book is used
to help me locate
different worlds
via a cooperative spell?
It is called
"The World Book."
Yes, I can read.
So it's like the encyclopedia.
More like an atlas.
What world are you looking for?
One where I can be happy,
where I can belong.
[SIGHING]
No, it's not what you think.
I'm not interested in that.
I... I just want to go somewhere
where I can do no harm.
I'll never do that again.
I swear on my life.
Yeah, well, I don't know
if I believe you.
I spent years
being tortured by Martin,
plenty of time to think
on my actions
and regret them.
Did you never unintentionally
hurt someone you love, Alice?
I never molested a child.
But, yes,
I've done things I regret.
Don't you deserve happiness?
No.
Oh, don't be so hard
on yourself.
We all deserve it.
I don't think you do.
Well, I don't particularly
care what you think.
You need my help finding
the Revision Room.
So either you help me
with this spell
or you're on your own.
[KNOCK AT DOOR]
Who are you?
Hi, uh, I'm Josh.
I'm Isaac's friend.
Isaac.
He hooked up with you
that one time.
Oh.
Right.
Look, it's a really bad time
right now.
Oh, uh, no, Isaac really
wanted me to talk to you
about something
and it's kind of an emergency.
So can I come in, please?
How do you know Isaac again?
Oh, uh...
Uh, he and I met at Jewish camp.
This is kind of weird.
I mean, why did he send a friend
instead of, like,
calling me himself?
He's got, uh, laryngitis.
So he can't text?
And he broke all of his fingers.
Anyhoo, I've got to talk to you
about Isaac's problem,
which he's embarrassed because
he came down with something
and he's afraid that you might
have caught it from him.
Caught what?
Oh, just a...
Herpes-like thing.
He gave me herpes?
I believe I said herpes-like.
Well, what the hell is it?
The only way to know
if you got it is to, sort of,
go through the symptoms
and see if you've been
experiencing them.
Okay, Josh from Jewish camp,
I'm going to discuss
genital warts
and discharge with you
'cause we just met.
Jesus Christ.
Fuck my life!
Look, have you maybe not
been feeling yourself lately?
Not really.
And I'm beginning to wonder
why I let you in
in the first place.
Great, and, uh, have you
maybe been having dreams
that are weird and violent?
Maybe.
Right, well, this last one
might sound a little crazy,
but have you, maybe,
been unable to control yourself
around guys?
Get out of my apartment.
Oh, wait. No-no-no.
This wasn't... I mean...
Seriously, get out!
Okay, please,
just let me help you.
I just want to help.
It's been a really hard
couple of days.
I've been totally freaking,
like...
What's wrong with me?
I know what you mean
and it's completely normal
and I assure you,
this is not your fault.
That's so good to hear.
I mean,
how could I even
do that to someone else?
It's a total mess in there.
[CHUCKLING]
Uh, a mess?
Uh-huh.
Uh, where?
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
♪♪
Jesus' tits.
It's not that bad, is it?
[GENTLE MUSIC]
Is it possible for an entire
forest to do the walk of shame?
Seriously, nature is not
supposed to be this sticky.
[DOG BARKING]
Uh-oh, you think she's
who we're looking for?
Whoa, whoa!
Wait, wait! Don't!
Why not?
Because you have something
to live for?
I'm a Maenad.
The God that
I'm here to serve is dead.
I literally have nothing
to live for.
But thanks... thanks for the less
than basic understanding
of my life's purpose.
No, no, no! Wait!
Don't, please.
We need your help.
Shoshana.
We need your help, Shoshana.
Hmm?
Peach Schnapps.
Bacchus left that for
the talking bears to find.
Okay, so how about a toast?
Right? Ba... Bacchus would've
wanted us to drink.
God, like, so much.
Yeah.
Okay, so to Bacchus.
To Bacchus.
God, it smells like pee sangria.
I don't give a shit.
Drink it.
To, uh, Bacchus!
Bacchus.
Whoo!
[SOBBING]
Oh, that's good shit.
Um, I was a goddess
and I gave away my power
and now I can't use magic.
Only I'm indestructible.
So maybe you can help me
understand what is going on.
You were a goddess?
Yeah.
[SIGHING]
If all these other Maenads
hadn't run through the poison
wine like a bunch of bitches,
I wouldn't even be
in this situation!
Well, maybe if you
help us we can...
[HOWLING]
[SHRIEKING]
I'm sorry.
[PANTING HEAVILY]
What are you...
What are you doing?
I'm trying to read your aura.
[BARKING, HOWLING]
Maybe we can just get
the pinecone out of my face?
Okay.
That's what I thought.
Inconclusive.
I do know a ritual that could
help diagnose you further.
But, um, it's pretty intimate.
Um, okay.
I can live with that.
Yeah, the only thing is
I... I... I can't perform it.
Uh, why not?
I don't believe in you.
I can help interpret,
but you need someone
who believes in you,
okay, who worships you,
body and soul,
to perform the ritual.
Anyone come to mind?
[GENTLE MUSIC]
♪♪
Fine, I'll help.
Jesus R.R. Christ.
An innocent girl is a murderer
'cause I couldn't get
to her in time.
Oh, put your tit back in
your training bra, wolf boy.
We don't really know
how innocent this girl was.
Sleeping with her Uber driver
sounds like she had
a death wish to begin with.
You're not helping.
Drink.
Is this a potion?
It's alcohol.
Good enough.
While you were busy with
your domestic issues,
I managed to translate
this Indonesian ritual
and good news is this is
first-year Brakebills
multi-culti elective crap.
So we can definitely pull it off
without breaking the magic bank.
Only prob is finding
one exotic ingredient.
Uh, what type of exotic
are we talking about here?
We need a living Komodo dragon
so we can cut out its heart,
and I heard a rumor Kanye keeps
one in his New York apartment.
That sounds on-brand.
Let's go.
[SIGHING]
Uh... uh, wait.
I have to give you something.
It's loaded with silver bullets.
The Quickening has started to
do weird things to me and...
Well, if I wolf-out,
you might need to stop me.
It's not gonna come to that.
I promise.
Now come on.
Let's go steal Kanye's lizard.
[SOFT MUSIC]
♪♪
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
As you can see, it's
rather hard to get in unseen.
Not if you can bend light.
Regardless, stealing
the books isn't really
the biggest issue, is it?
If the library
discovers they're gone,
they're gonna come after you.
Yeah, but if they read my book,
they'll know exactly
where I'll be.
Yes, but what if
they read your book
and still had no idea
where you were?
What are you proposing?
When I was writing
"The Wandering Dune,"
I was also studying magic.
I... I kept blowing deadlines
until I found a spell
for automatic writing.
Now, you feed it a premise
and it constructs
an airtight storyline.
I... I gather they use it
in Hollywood all the time.
That explains Netflix.
How does this spell work?
Uh, we steal the manuscripts,
pull the endings,
cast a spell on them,
and then replace them
just before they take them away
to bind them as books.
Voilà!
Oh, you'll be very surprised
how your stories turn out,
Let me guess.
You'll show me
how to do the spell
if I help you
with the World Book?
Well, that only seems fair,
doesn't it?
Look, do you want my help
or not?
[DOOR SLAMMING]
Mom, I told you I'd have
this done by tomorrow.
So just... ah, Jesus.
Hello?
I found these in
your dead father's fridge.
They're not quite what
I'd hoped they'd be.
You finished with
the killing yet?
With the, uh... what?
You father's dead.
I thought perhaps you'd
get angry and kill things.
That's what I'd do.
It's not really what people do.
Nowadays, anyway.
You're not going
to kill anything?
Interesting.
[EXHALING DEEPLY]
Frozen peas?
Nope.
Uh, no thanks.
Let's go then.
I'm bored of this food.
Can I just have a few minutes
to finish this?
This is important to you.
Yeah, it is.
This is a very interesting game,
the loving your dead dad game.
I don't understand it.
It's not a game.
It...
There must be someone
who's important to you,
who you... who you miss.
I don't remember.
But perhaps you're right.
I could learn something
from this.
I'll let you play this game.
I will sit still
and I won't kill anything
and I'll watch you while you...
You think about
your dead father?
Is that what you're doing?
Yeah.
Kind of.
This is the weirdest thing
I've ever done.
[SOLEMN MUSIC]
♪♪
But maybe it'll be fun.
[CLINKING]
I... she wasn't lying.
This is pretty intimate.
Yeah, well,
you're not the one
who has to strip naked
and be anointed with oil.
Are you sure you want
to do this?
I don't really see
another way, do you?
Wait, um,
maybe there is another way?
Uh...
Something a little less painful?
Painful?
Not... not painful.
Um...
You know I'm not broken, right?
I'm not some flower
or a delicate piece of glass.
I'm a person and people heal.
Yeah, look, I'm ju...
I'm just not very
comfortable with the way
this is going down, you know?
Yeah, well, this isn't
really about you.
So maybe you could just
get over yourself.
I'm trying.
It's nothing you haven't
seen before.
Ta-da.
I guess I should start.
I guess you should.
Yeah.
[TEP NO'S "TOLUCA LAKE" PLAYS]
♪♪
♪ I do what I want,
don't do what I'm told ♪
♪ What I'm told
♪ Been riding on the edge
♪ With your heart in
a chokehold ♪
♪ Heart in a chokehold
♪♪
♪ Maybe I'm a lost cause
I...
What's wrong?
I, uh...
I got to, uh, go up front.
♪ Won't do what I'm told
Are you asking if you can
touch my boobs?
I am asking you
if I can touch your boobs.
You can touch my boobs.
Just don't break them.
Ha ha.
♪♪
♪ Oh
♪ You should know, you should
know, you should know ♪
♪ Oh
What?
No, it's just... it's cold.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I can warm it up.
♪ I don't know how
to give you my love, babe ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm too good
at messing it up ♪
♪♪
♪ Maybe I could change
♪ By now you should know
everything is strange ♪
It's weird for me, too,
you know.
♪ Oh
♪ Give you my love
♪ I don't know how
to give you my love ♪
You ready to wash my feet?
[CHUCKLING]
[SHOUTING IN INDONESIAN]
[CONTINUES SHOUTING
IN INDONESIAN]
Now what?
Scream!
[BOTH SCREAMING]
Now eat it!
It's not bad actually.
I told you, vulnerable is
not technically endangered.
I think I'm going to be sick.
Don't you dare throw up
that lizard heart.
We killed a vulnerable creature
to save your ass.
It better not be for nothing.
Not to mention that is not the
way I thought I'd meet Kanye.
It's actually less messed up
than the way I thought it'd be.
Oh, yeah.
You won't be judged.
[HEART BEATING LOUDLY]
You know what would be hot
right now?
If you just took me right here
in this car.
Stop the car!
What is it?
Pull the car over
right fucking now!
[BRAKES SCREECHING]
[GROANING]
[HOWLING]
[SOFT MUSIC]
♪♪
[BRANCH SNAPPING]
[SCREAMING] Son of a clit!
The ritual didn't work.
Oh, is that why you screamed
and ran out of the car?
Just let me in, okay?
Why? So you can wolf-hump me
to death?
No, I wanted to do things,
but you're safe now, okay?
It passed.
How?
I kinda of turned a tree
into a werewolf,
if you know what I'm saying.
Oh, got it.
It's not a permanent solution.
But it's enough to keep
the urges off
until we get
to where we're going.
You mind telling me
where that is, maple dick?
Brakebills.
I thought this would
be interesting.
It's not.
I'm almost done.
Just...
A little while longer
and then we can go.
Why did you do that?
Slightly more interesting.
No.
Stop it!
[CHUCKLING]
I don't understand.
Your father is dead, right?
So these belong to you now,
do they not?
Yes, they belong to me.
What is your point?
Why are you doing any of this?
Because I told my mom
I would, okay?
Jesus Christ, I can't believe
I'm having to explain this.
Why does your mother have
such strange power over you?
Because once, when I was a kid,
I broke an ashtray.
And now she still fucking
thinks that I break everything.
Because...
Basically, your parents never
change how they see you.
No matter what.
So if they can't change
how they see you,
then why does it matter?
Because sometimes
I think she's right.
Things break around me.
Alice, my dad,
all of goddamn magic.
Then break them on purpose.
They're your planes.
You can do what you want
with them.
Maybe you'll feel better.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪♪
[YELLING]
[KEYS CLACKING]
[TENSE MUSIC]
I don't meant to be rude,
but here I am helping
as promised
without an assurance
you'll do the same.
Jesus, you're relentless.
Okay, fine.
I'll help you with your spell.
Yet you seem to hate
yourself for it.
I mean, you can understand
my worry.
I don't have to be happy
about it.
A word of advice.
If you want to survive,
stop torturing yourself.
Maybe you could do will
a little more self-hatred.
And fewer Mr. Rogers vests.
You think that what you've done
and who you are
are the same thing.
When they don't match up,
you hate yourself.
Alice, they'll never match up.
You don't know anything
about me.
I know what it feels like
to be unable to change
no matter how much I want to.
Children don't care if you
contradict yourself, you know?
[SCOFFING]
Perhaps that's a bad example
coming from me,
but I'm just trying to help.
Please just stop doing...
What is it?
The end of Quentin's book.
He's going to die.
Isn't that how all books end?
His ends next week.
Uh, as requested,
the water my feet
were bathed in.
Ugh, that's pretty murky.
Okay, judgey.
What's it mean?
It's too early to say.
This is very interesting though.
I thought you said
you didn't have any power.
No. I... I don't.
I can't do magic.
Those aren't the same.
Oh, this...
This is real weird.
You weren't bullshitting me
when you said you were
a goddess, were you?
No, but how... how can I be
a goddess
if I don't have any power?
Maybe you think you don't,
but...
I have never seen anything
like this before.
So we're good now?
You're not gonna kill yourself?
No, I can't now.
I have a new deity to follow.
[SOFT MUSIC]
Oh, boy.
♪♪
I think you're overreacting.
I could've sexually assaulted
you or ate you.
I don't honestly know how
things would've turned out.
It's no reason to give up.
There's got to be a solution.
I've got, what, a couple hours
before the Quickening
takes over,
and I'm sorry if that
makes me a wimp or whatever,
but I don't want to rape
or murder anyone.
Oh, come on.
There are plenty of people
who deserve to be killed.
I can think of a half dozen
at Brakebills alone.
If you can just keep
your twat together,
I'm sure I can get at least
one of them down here.
I mean, Todd totally owes me.
He doesn't owe you his life.
Doesn't he?
I can't do it, Margo.
Well, you can't do nothing,
because you'll die in this cage.
At least I can live with that.
I mean, not live exactly,
but you get what I'm saying.
This is bullshit.
You're just throwing
your life away.
I was thinking more like
noble sacrifice.
Screw your noble sacrifice!
What is it with you boys
and your noble sacrifice?
I'm not gonna let you do it.
Well, it's not your choice.
You can't fix me, okay?
Some things are just broken,
and there's nothing
you can do about it.
Said the quitter
right before he quit.
You think I want to die?
Of course I fucking don't!
But I don't see
a way out of this,
and frankly you not giving up
is making what
I have to do harder.
You want to do something stupid?
Fine by me.
What the hell are you doing?
Something stupider.
This isn't a joke, Margo!
I'm not going to be able
to control myself.
I might kill you or... or...
Or what?
Fuck me?
Margo.
This curse isn't curable.
I don't want you
to go through this.
The Quickening is...
Why not?
Because...
I like you.
I like you too.
And I'm not gonna lose
another friend today, okay?
I can't make you kill someone,
but I can consent.
Damn.
The Quickening makes you
a really good kisser.
I know.
That was more cathartic
than I thought it would be.
It was kind of fun, wasn't it?
It feels good after you deal
with death, doesn't it?
A little.
Still hurts, but...
eventually it hurts
a little less.
I'm going to need your help
to search for more Gods.
You'll be more useful
to me if you feel better,
so you should know that
your friend Eliot is dead.
You can smash more things
if you want.
And then we'll go get
something to eat.
Sound good?
I cannot believe
you just did that.
I rocked your world.
Get over it.
Oh, no, you... that was great.
It's just you can't
have sex now with anyone
who isn't L-positive
without infecting them.
You know, so...
Since when is P-in-the-V sex
the pinnacle of what one
or two or three or five
or an animal can do together?
I mean, it's not even
on my top ten.
[CHUCKLES]
I guess I see your point there.
All the same, what are you
gonna do about the Quickening?
How are you gonna handle that?
In what, 30 years?
No way I'm gonna live that long.
And if I do,
Todd totally owes me.
You're joking, right?
You're joking.
So what is this?
This is...
This is just casual, right?
We're not... you know?
I saved your fucking life,
bitch.
[SCOFFS]
Casual that.
Thanks, Margo.
I'm sorry we couldn't
figure out a way to help,
you know...
I am too.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
I would have done
anything to save him.
♪♪
But I think he might
actually be gone.
♪♪
I felt the moment his soul died.
It only hurt for a second.
I promise he didn't suffer.
[LAUGHS]
You'll come around.
I know it.
[VAULTS' "PREMONITIONS" PLAYING]
♪ Let's take it right back
Hello?
♪ To where we used to go
♪ But we never look back
♪ No we only look forward
♪ To all the new pain
♪ And violence that we blame
♪ No we never look back
♪ No we only look forward
Hello?
♪ With all our fate
♪ Hearts
♪ Broken from the start
Is anybody there?
Margo!
♪ Only to be held tall
♪ By the writing on the wall
♪ We don't need
no premonitions no ♪
♪♪
♪ Let's take it right back
♪ To where it all began
♪ But we never look back
♪ No we only look forward
♪ To all the new shame
♪ And waste of what we gain