Previously on The Magicians...
I will save the
people of Fillory.
The people would decide to
make this dark wizard their king.
The Dark King.
So, you built a
golem out of living clay
and then you animated the
whole thing with his essence?
No, it's just a tiny grain of Q's soul
that I pulled from the Underworld.
Put back the piece of Q's essence
that you stole and let him be at rest.
Goodbye, Quentin.
Some surges come and go
and hardly anyone notices.
And sometimes
it's a catastrophe.
Is there any way
to predict them?
Look, I need help with
a metamath problem.
My dad had a friend with a really rare
discipline, predicting circumstances.
She wrote this.
Wait. I recognize these.
Put them on a letter
address it to whoever, wherever,
whenever and it gets to them.
Because I want you to be safe.
I want you to be safe.
Are you saying that
you... No, I'm just...
We've tried the whole
"saving each other" thing,
with mixed results.
Well, yeah, sure, but I...
And I've been thinking about
what works best, and I think...
No, I know that we're
best when we're a team,
and we work
together, you and me.
If nothing else, I
like the sound of it.
Quentin?
Quentin.
Oh, shit.
- Whoo! Yeah, there she is!
- Champagne for our girl.
High King Margo, a
thousand huzzahs!
Go, Bambi.
Um, why? We wanted to honor you.
So, when Julia sent us the bunny
saying that they put the clock in here,
we asked them to stock
up on celebratory beverages.
Stay on the mission.
We're going back.
Copy. Give me 30, we'll
have cookies to help brainstorm
how you're gonna
overthrow the Dark King.
Well, your subjects
are rightly grateful.
For sending that letter?
A.K.A. that thing I
totally didn't do, you did.
Why split a hair? Let
them bake cookies.
Lie cookies? It's not a lie.
You saved them through me,
your advisor, acting on your behalf.
Nice retcon.
And as a wise king once said,
"Ovary up."
Let your subjects be inspired
by a simple, uncomplicated story.
That's what the people want.
Would you excuse me?
Where you going and why are
you dressed like a goth survivalist?
Fillory. Just quick.
What you got there? Nothing.
I did a thing. This is a byproduct.
I just have to take care of it.
Alice, do you need help?
You seem a little bit distressed.
I'm fine.
I just have to do it alone.
Okay. Great. What was the spell?
I made a golem, okay?
You've done it before.
It's not a big deal.
A golem of who?
Can we not be
dramatic about this?
I used his book
from the Library.
Quentin's? But I
was out of my mind.
And I didn't think that
this would just stay here
when I buried the golem,
and not be released.
It's Essence. It's a
tiny piece of his soul.
I'm sorry. You pulled an actual
piece of Quentin's soul out of his...
That is insane. What if it's...
Keeping him from resting?
Well, is it?
Look, I just need to get to the
top of this mountain and throw it in.
The Mountain Of Ghosts, that
Rupert Chatwin was looking for
before the band of aggressive
talking squirrels kidnapped him?
I'm finally reading the books.
Margo's been on my ass about it.
Anyway, is that it?
The one with the hole
at the top that goes all...
All the way down
to the Underworld?
Yes. Well, this
is too important.
I'm helping.
I don't need your help.
Well, you're getting it.
Fine.
Head hurt from the patch?
Uh...
Beats the noise.
Burning through them, though,
so looking for
some real answers.
None of these books is for shit.
Requested some from the Library,
but not getting the sense
they're gonna be that speedy.
So, while you're waiting...
God, that...
Always a great idea, but I
really do have a headache.
No. I need a ride.
Fine.
I've been thinking.
We should tell her.
Look, can we just concentrate
one thing at a time, please?
Let's just get her back
on the throne, huh?
Yeah, well, with those
banishment brands,
good luck getting her in the
kingdom, never mind the castle.
Oh, shit.
What month is it in
Fillory? Is it spring yet?
Yellow Ferret Month, yes.
Have you ever seen the
movie The Dirty Dozen?
Not the porn one.
No, and I have a
life, so summarize.
Uh, not important.
Point is, it inspired
me to do this thing
when the Taker attacks
were just starting.
We needed better guards, so I
created an annual tournament.
First week of the month
of the Yellow Ferret,
to find the 12 greatest
fighters in the land,
to become our elite
Centurion Guard.
Pretty cool name, right? Yeah.
Anyway, we offered fame, glory,
and instant wipe-clean
of your criminal record,
including, uh-huh,
Banishment Marks.
And if they still hold the
tournament, it would be going on now,
as we speak.
We should check on that. No?
It's Living Stone, I think.
Hmm.
"Beware Takers."
"Beyond The Wall Adventure
Tours. 500 feet that way."
Fill them. Rocks, lots of dust.
That'll be heavy.
Burns Takers.
They come at night.
We'll make a circle to camp in.
Or, hey, travel light,
if you want to die.
So, Takers. What
exactly are they?
You really don't know?
Nope.
Umber's tit. Don't
tell me you're grievers.
What's wrong with that?
You're not prepared
for the mountain.
You can't run fast because you've
been sitting around eating cake and crying.
Okay, I can grieve and handle a
little cardio, thank you very much.
Yeah, we're
Magicians. We'll be fine.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
You're planning to throw
something in at the top, keep it safe.
Takers don't just take people.
They know what thing
you value, and swipe it.
Alice.
This zips. It's the
safest thing we've got.
Alice, please let me take it.
Okay.
Come on.
Well, this stopped being fun.
Well, you wanted to come.
Sure did. And it's awful.
Yeah, it's meant to be.
But maybe you don't feel that
way because it's not your pilgrimage.
What's that supposed to mean?
Nothing. Can we
please not bicker?
Sure. Let's not bicker.
What did you mean
by not my pilgrimage?
I mean I'm here putting my
boyfriend to rest, and you tagged along.
Right. Because I
barely knew him.
You know what I mean.
You're here out of some sort of
combination of thinking I'm incompetent
and your guilt that
he died saving you.
You know what?
You are way too smart
for me to ascribe what you
just said to total stupidity,
so I'm gonna go ahead
and I'm gonna file it under
"You must be fucking
joking right now."
No. I'm not.
This is hard enough without you
judging me every step of the way.
Is that how you don't bicker?
'Cause that would explain a lot
about how you and Q kept falling apart.
Beyond the obvious, of course.
The obvious? Yeah.
What, like drunk threesomes
with you and Margo?
Oh, mmm, solid point, but I
was thinking more that one time
where you betrayed all of us,
I ended up possessed and
Q died cleaning up the mess.
And time for Yan
to roll a smoke.
That was a little harsh.
And correct.
But not right. Because
he also saved my life.
Right.
Trying to fix the mess I made.
Here we are again.
Let's just finish this, okay?
Yan, let's go.
Finished with your feelings?
Yes.
Uh...
Alice, no, don't go that way.
Good luck and
enjoy the tournament.
Hello. I am Bick of the
esteemed House Pickwick.
Who is entering? Me.
Your name?
Janet. Janet.
Pluchinsky.
Weapon of choice?
Me. But also I like axes.
You are registered.
Proceed... I'm entering too.
I just want to.
My name's Fen... cicle.
Wahlburger.
Weapon of choice? Knives.
I choose to use my
Childsplay knives.
The kind of knives they
give to very young children.
Wow.
You had some kinda childhood.
Hmm.
Okay, so I found you this.
Fuck my life. Or I can
get you something else.
I just tried to do Singh's Advanced
Skin Hardening twice, and touch me.
Smooth and perfect.
And I'm getting eaten alive by
whimsical goddamn Fillorian bugs.
Huh. Um...
You know what?
You just keep practicing
that shield casting,
and I'm, uh, gonna go check
on something real quick.
Do we even have an appointment?
What do you think?
What the hell just happened?
Where are we?
Um, excuse me. Is
this P.K. Endeavors?
These two look confused.
Hi. Zoe Markus. I run the
joint. Julia Wicker. We emailed.
Hey, why does this place look
exactly like the Physical Kids' Cottage?
You went to Brakebills?
I'm a professor at Brakebills.
Really?
Brakebills. Best
years of my life.
Hence, I did a study.
Most Magicians cast 23% more
accurately when they've been drinking.
God, we're fucked.
So, what can I help you
with? Stocks, you said?
I did say that. We were hoping
to talk to your sister Daniella.
How come?
Well, to start, you know
how magic was regulated?
Until it wasn't, thank God.
Well, we stopped
that, and a lot worse.
A friend of ours did. But
there were side effects.
Like the surges. Which
are... Getting stronger.
We're concerned we're
heading towards a major event.
And you need... Daniella,
to predict when
it's going to happen.
We'll pay what we can.
Zoe, you and your sister would
be helping to save the world.
I'd love to help. Great.
But, unfortunately,
I must decline.
Please. Wait.
Stay as long as
you like. Wait. Shit.
Shit.
It's okay. We'll figure
something out. Come on.
Okay, so I got some
kinda bad news.
Fillory has two moons. And
if either is full, then wolf time.
So one of them's full soon?
Both are. Tomorrow night.
Which is why your wolf PMS
is acting so bad right now.
I'm about to be a
double werewolf?
It's okay, because there's
still cages. I checked.
So it's totally
fine. It's not fine.
You're doing great.
No. The skin-hardening
spell I keep trying to cast
so I don't get flayed alive only
stuck to the left half of my body,
and also, I want to
murder everything.
Oh! Um...
More than usual? Yes, in fact.
Well, maybe just some deep
breaths, and, you know, you got this.
So... Fuck breathing.
I'm too annoyed to breathe.
But I like you, anyway.
Thanks for the
cheerleading, wolf boy.
Uh...
Of course. That's fine.
The air's so thin up here,
I think I'm hallucinating.
We're gonna need to
rest before we go again.
I just wanna pin
the circle in place.
Eliot?
Hey, Eliot.
Okay, just...
Okay.
Eliot, Taker! Back up.
Q's vial, you set it down.
Fuck. Just stay in the circle.
Eliot, no!
Fuck.
You all right?
I'm really glad I
took the north trail.
Pretty sure I'm gladder.
Who needs a drink?
Sorry. Are you still...
Yeah, no, we're
just about done here.
Any luck?
Zoe definitely went
here in the '90s,
but her professors don't
seem to remember her.
She did a lot of field
work in Poland, I guess.
Zoe Markus?
Yeah. Do you know her?
She was my lab partner.
Oh, my God, we dropped
so much acid together.
We went to visit her work.
She's a big financial advisor.
Seriously?
Wow. I mean, she was
really not into money at all
when I knew her and her sisters.
Sisters?
More than one? Yeah.
Beth, Zoe and Dani,
who, no offense, is...
little weird.
Rumor has it that they averted
apocalypse in senior year.
Good.
Janet of House Pluchinsky.
Yeah!
Versus Faun of House
Caicos Swordmasters.
Yeah!
Whoo!
Fencicle of House Wahlburger.
What?
Whoa!
Yeah.
God damn. We've
been wasting her, right?
This is like spy movie perfect.
You're both in The Dirty Dozen,
and I'm the guy on the outside.
Victors, please
approach the dais.
Congratulations.
Fencicle, what is
your persuasion?
Uh, I mostly date humans.
Are you a female?
And you, Janet?
Duh.
There can, of course, only
be one female Centurion.
And act three twist.
For all the obvious reasons...
Um, not obvious to me.
I know, dear. That's
one of the reasons.
You spar by the light of the
glorious double full moon,
tomorrow night.
Tomorrow night? That's
no good. I've got plans.
Me too. I mean...
Oh, gravest apologies,
but the schedule...
Chucklebuddy, I have a
sexually transmitted curse.
Sun goes down
tomorrow, I go wolf.
This guy goes wolf... Hi.
Ember's balls.
And her, too, for some reason.
That what you want here?
Sure to be entertaining.
Probably be everyone
in here's last show.
Reschedule the mimes. Yes, sir.
Your match will occur in the
hour before sundown tomorrow.
Margo, Josh and I
only... Six or seven,
or less than a dozen
times, give or take,
and we would've never,
ever done it if we had known...
Excuse me.
I need to sharpen my axe.
Well...
Please say something
nice at my funeral.
So, Loria.
I was making ends
meet selling rare objects.
Of course, when I got
there I mostly drank.
I think this story is
making me sound
much less mentally
well-composed than I actually am.
We're literally camping
on the Sadderhorn.
Anyway, I was at the border
when I saw my first Taker.
That thing you did.
I tried to throw something
at one earlier, and nothing.
Well, most things don't work.
Well, the Dark King
can fend them off.
There are a few of us out
here who have figured out ways.
How? When it touched me,
it felt like a virus, a plague.
I shot something off on
instinct, uh, an antiviral...
You're a Magician from Earth?
My family is.
Do you think you can
show us what you did?
I will teach you whatever I can.
And something
else I can share...
Lucky that the
Taker didn't snatch it.
Thank you.
Is that Lorian Bumble Wine?
Ah-ha.
Cures altitude sickness, opens
the lungs, and gets you smashed.
Wait. I was gonna...
I was gonna say you
should go easy on that.
Oh, my God.
It's too late now. I'm sorry.
Well, cheers to that.
You're a danger tourist? No.
Mourning someone.
Who was it? I mean,
if you wanna say.
Well...
The love of my life.
Died ridiculously young.
But he was a Magician.
And there's nothing
more dangerous than that.
My dreams were so filled with him, I
was convinced he was haunting me.
So, I took his diary up to the
top of the mountain and threw it in.
Felt a little better,
so who knows?
But you're here again.
I come every year.
To honor him. My boyfriend died.
A little bit
on-and-off-again. It was...
Well, it was complicated.
I don't like talking about it.
I understand.
You knew him, too?
Um...
Good friend.
It's nice that you
can do this together.
Yes. Cheers to that, too.
Well, I think I should start thinking
about going to lie down, so...
My eggs are scrambled.
They sure are.
Hi. Daniella?
Awkward.
Um, we didn't mean to scare you.
We just wanted to talk to
you and your sister about...
What the hell are you doing?
I told you, we can't help you.
You can, but you won't.
Hey, look, we're not
asking you to join the fight.
We just need your help
with the... It's not "just."
You think she'll stop? If
she knows the stakes?
Tell me about
the problem. Don't.
Unless you want to explain
how obsessed you get,
how you nearly got yourself
killed, how Beth did get killed.
Look, we're sorry. I'm not.
Look, I get that you've
lost a lot. But so have we.
We need your help.
I'm just saying...
We already saved
the world. Okay?
We get to be done.
Get out. Don't come back.
There's nothing like
two grieving lunatics
drinking themselves to
death on a mountain of ghosts.
Cheers.
Hmm.
Oh, it's a good sky tonight.
Please.
Used to do this with him.
We'd go somewhere, camp out,
and use illusion magic to
change the color of the stars.
Sounds perfect.
Have you ever had love?
Love. Uh, like...
Love. It's okay. You
can say anything.
I'm a stranger and you're drunk.
The friend we're
putting to rest...
Wasn't just a friend.
Does she know?
Oh, God, no.
A torrid secret affair.
Nothing like that.
Hmm.
It seems a bit selfish then.
I'm just saying, that seems
rather important information
that he can't give her.
I mean, why punish her
like that? Why spare her?
You don't seem close.
Because she really,
really loved him.
So did you.
Yeah. So I don't
want her to think that...
Have you ever noticed
that people generally think
what the hell they want?
I'm starting to think that
you're a little bit of a shit-stirrer.
I just fundamentally
believe that
the best way to honor someone
is with the truth of them.
You could give her more
of that truth, but you won't.
I just want everybody to remember
Quentin however they want to,
and to get through
the fucking day.
I'm just pointing out,
what you've got in
that secret pocket
could help her remember
the real Quentin.
Death is so simple and
life is so complicated.
I know.
Well...
I should go to bed.
Before things get
any more complicated.
Years ago, the Dark King,
in a show of progressiveness,
allowed that there might be a
female among his Centurions,
if one proved worthy.
This year,
we have two competitors
of the weaker sex.
I know, I know.
Or you could walk away.
Can't. This is for Fillory.
You're a little wolf-crazy
right now, and mad.
You might actually kill her.
I know how to properly
lightly maim someone.
Thanks for your concern.
Janet, Fencicle, let
the battle commence!
You smell anxious.
And you smell angry,
so please let me stab you.
You are out of your
mind. Margo, please.
Actually worked.
That's no fair, 'cause
you can do magic.
You can do that twirly
knife shit. You have an axe.
Fine. No magic.
Magic.
Oops.
We have a victor!
A... A victorette!
Your new lady Centurion!
I'm so sorry, Fen.
What?
That was so well-played.
How you knew to grab my knife.
Did I know that?
Of course you did.
Childsplay knife, perfectly safe.
We make them for
children so they can practice.
Oh.
Sir, can you please bring us to the
werewolf cages? Quickly? Thanks.
I think I'll take the east view.
I'll find you later if you
wanna hike down together.
I'll just give you a moment.
No. Stay.
You cared about him, too.
Do you think it goes all the
way down to the Underworld?
I hope so. For Q.
Is there anything you
want to say to him?
Rest.
Okay. I think we can go now.
Wait. There's one more thing.
Uh...
Wait. This stamp is enchanted.
You could send this to him.
Mmm-hmm.
Before... Oh, my God. Eliot.
But you didn't send it 'cause
you were worried it could be...
So much worse if I changed it.
Uh, Alice...
Huh?
Is there a way that we
could really, truly know?
Eliot, I really don't know.
It's...
Sometimes I just wish, if you
all just went faster. If you just...
Just locked the fucking door.
No, because
Everett would still...
It's Everett, of course.
Q...
If Q hadn't stopped
Everett, then...
So many more people could die.
But I just keep thinking
if I can just crack the
code, then we can fix it.
I don't think there's a perfect
code for changing the past.
I can't send it.
But I... I can't just let it go.
It's okay.
He was your friend.
He wasn't just my friend.
I'm sorry.
He loved you.
Why would I want to take
that away from you now?
That would be so cruel.
Do you really think I didn't
know there was more?
I knew Q really well.
And if anyone was
messy, it was him.
Yeah. Yeah.
He was pretty in love with you.
I'm not sure that
I'd say that. I would.
What was I supposed to do, huh?
Demand that he only love me?
Scream at him to be a
less complicated person?
I mean, it's Quentin
we're talking about.
And I loved him.
The real him. All of him.
Well, um...
There's something he
probably didn't tell you about.
The mosaic.
Um...
There was this timeline.
We somehow
remembered pieces of it.
These, uh... These
beautiful pieces.
And it was so...
We loved each other for
a really, really long time.
And, um...
So, you know, uh, I
promptly told him to fuck off,
and then, you
know, he died for me.
Eliot.
Eliot...
I have done
a lot of bad things, and I
have hurt people, okay?
And the one thing
that I hold on to
is that I know deep down
that I was doing my best.
Were you doing the
best that you could?
Unfortunately, at the time,
yes.
I never even got to talk
to him again. He just died.
I'm sorry.
Yeah. File it under
"Things I wish I could say in this
fucking letter that I can't actually send."
But I can't let go of it either.
You want my help?
Yeah.
But we can do it together, okay?
On the count of three.
One... One...
Two... Two...
Three.
That was brave.
He was brave.
You are brave.
Eliot?
Yeah?
Thank you for telling me.
Guards! Hello!
We're human again!
Margo?
Can I say one thing?
I'm sorry I slept with Josh.
We were just lonely.
Fen, stop apologizing.
I don't own Josh's
penis and I don't want to.
But you seem...
Can I have a
complicated emotion,
without having to resolve
it so you can feel better?
I am grateful that even
in your complicated state,
you still reached for
the Childsplay knife.
You're a good person. I
thought it was a real knife.
Glad it wasn't today,
but I'm not a good person.
Okay, well,
matters of the heart
can be irrational,
and sometimes
even the best of us...
Stop trying to forgive me.
We want you to forgive us.
We promised ourselves we
wouldn't give up on you, but we did.
You never gave up on us.
Yeah, you figured out a
way. Eliot sent the letter.
I was gonna let
you die for Fillory.
But kings...
We have a job and
we put it first. Right?
So, you didn't save us,
and then you stabbed me.
Am I a fool?
No, really. Am I?
No more than me.
You're a lovesick idiot! Hey.
I went into battle for you.
Thinking that you gave a
single flea on a donkey's ass
for any of us.
Thinking that we
owed you something.
Stupid me.
I've been thinking
about what Zoe said.
It's a valid question.
When do you save
the world enough?
Look, I'm with you on anything,
but I gotta be honest.
If we survive this one,
I want a life, Julia.
Ideally with you.
Yeah, I want that, too.
I'm not sure you
do, and that's okay.
Right now we got shit
to do. But if we don't die,
we gotta figure this out.
Hello.
I solved your problem.
You were right.
Surges are increasing.
They're unpredictable, hidden
variables that defy calculation.
But if we can't predict
it... Correct. You can't.
So instead, I created
a statistical model
to predict a window within
which a surge might occur.
Wow.
Okay, this is a start.
Are you familiar with the
Harmonic Convergence?
No.
A rare and powerful
astrological occurrence.
A magnifier of magic.
There have been four.
Extinction of the dinosaurs,
Pompeii, sinking of Atlantis,
and the invention of Auto-Tune.
In two weeks,
there will be a fifth.
How bad will it be? This is
the event you're worried about.
Circumstances on the Convergence
will be exceptionally favorable.
Which, in this case,
is not a good thing,
because it falls
in a surge window.
Castings will be
exponentially magnified.
Enchantments will malfunction.
Death toll in the millions.
Maybe much higher.
How can we stop it? You can't.
Unless you stop the
surges. Change astrology.
Or tell everyone on
Earth not to do magic.
Whatever you try, if you
need help, I will help you.
And so will my sister.
I'm pretty sure
she doesn't want to.
She doesn't.
But if the moment comes,
you can count on the both of us.
Wait, Dani.
Thank you so much for
your help. My pleasure.
My sister will invoice
you for my time.
Well...
We go thataway.
Tree near Whitespire
can take us home.
I'm headed in that direction,
if you'd like some company.
We wouldn't mind. Yeah.
Make way!
Is that the Dark
King's carriage?
Are we in trouble again?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Would you like a
ride to Whitespire?
I think we'll walk.
Um...
I hope your journey gave you
everything that you needed.
Please call on me
if there's ever anything
I can do for you.
He's...
I think I almost
fucked the Dark King.