ELIOT: Previously
on The Magicians...
(GRUNTING)
Your new lady
Centurion! (YELLING)
You said you heard
voices from other worlds.
You hearing something? A signal?
(ODD SQUEALING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Professor? Did the
signal make you do that?
ELIOT: He loved you.
Why would I want to take
that away from you now?
That would be so cruel.
Do you really think I didn't
know there was more?
What was I supposed to do, huh?
Demand that he only love me?
"Dark King" is a little generic
as villain names go. Mmm.
Wouldn't you say? I have notes.
Although he is
somewhat effective.
Everyone seems terrified of him.
Eliot, Taker! Back up.
(GRUNTS)
You all right?
Death is so simple and
life is so complicated.
I know.
I think I almost
fucked the Dark King.
Are you familiar with the
Harmonic Convergence?
A rare and powerful
astrological occurrence.
A magnifier of magic.
How bad will it be?
Death toll in the millions.
Maybe much higher.
How can we stop it? You can't.
MAN: (OVER PA) I
repeat, ward break.
(GRUNTING)
KADY: Hedge witches.
They're used to crumbs
and, yes, ambient is low.
But you know what amplifies it?
JULIA: Cooperative magic.
KADY: We tell everyone,
and we all do the same
thing at the same time.
KADY: And I thought that if I took on
more power and more responsibility,
that I'd want heroin less.
When I thought I'd relapsed,
I was relieved.
So, uh, I've been
clean for a year.
Barely.
Thanks, but, uh, maybe hold that
'cause I've been jonesing
hard. (CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
Well, uh, I'm a Hedge.
You know, before we helped
save magic, we got a shit deal, right?
Well, there was a
blood worm scare,
so the Library gave a lot
of Hedges the Reed's Mark.
Get a mark, you're magically
castrated until they take it off.
And the Library's
imploding, they can't fix it,
and the marked ones
are looking at me like,
"Hey, bossy pants, you rallied us to
save magic, how about saving us?"
And I found a spell to remove
the marks in a depository,
Only, all of a
sudden, it's gone.
But I know only way to
move something that warded
is to move it through
the Etheric Realm.
Cool. I've heard it's awesome
there. What's the prob?
The prob
is there's only one
way into the Realm.
Anybody heard of "RCH"?
Nickname, "Archie"?
Yup. (CHUCKLES)
The way to save every
marked Hedge is to drop acid.
True 12-step conundrum.
I'm assuming you have the Archie
on you? (SCOFFING CHUCKLE)
Call your sponsor, kid.
It'd make sense,
in case somebody here, you know,
gave you permission to jump off the wagon.
Sorry MA is so strict.
You met the nice me.
Here's the real me.
Fuck off. (LAUGHING)
What?
Well, I take the "anonymous" part of
Magicians Anonymous very seriously.
So, you quit drinking?
Thirty-three days,
six hours, 19 minutes
of skin-peeling,
soul-searing hell ago, yes.
Well, I can relate. As can I,
in regards to the crushing
weight of leadership.
I've never seen Archie.
May I?
Why two?
In case the first trip's a bust.
Or in case it's fun.
I've been dismissive or
downright derisive about Hedges,
and I admit, I was quite wrong,
and I'd like to try
and make, um...
Hell, what's the word?
Amends. Yeah.
Are you crazy?
(GULPS) I am.
But I am not an addict.
I'm an alcoholic.
Totally different.
So, I will go hunt
down the depository.
You're not going alone.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
JULIA: So we know about
the Harmonic Convergence.
The problem is we know
just enough to be useless,
so maybe we find someone
who can see the big picture.
Find? Summon.
A god?
Whoa, you've got
to be kidding me.
Wait. Julia, before you do that,
I think the Library might have...
(GROANING)
Penny? (EXHALES) I'm fine.
Wow, that is a whole
other level. Jesus.
I thought the patch was working.
Merritt's signal just
keeps getting stronger.
I'm sorry. I can't stay. I'm just no
use until I get this under control.
Maybe do the summoning
once I get back?
Let me know if
things get too weird.
Yeah. Same.
The Library has summoned me
about 7,000 times to come work there.
And they also gave me this.
It'll get me in any time I want.
Look, I'll bring back
whatever they have
on the Harmonic
Convergence as fast as I can.
Are you sure you'll
be okay? Yeah.
Good luck. You, too.
Makes sense the
signal's hitting you harder.
I'm starting to actually
hear... A voice?
You, too? Kind of.
I can't make out actual words.
At least, not ones
I can understand.
MERRITT: Is that
for me? PENNY: No.
I think the problem with the first
patch was that it was just a deflector.
The signal is getting bounced off,
but I'm still getting hit by the reverb.
This one should absorb
the sound and kill it.
And if it does, we'll see
what we can gin up for you.
(SQUELCHING) (GROANS)
(PENNY SIGHS HEAVILY)
Okay. Mmm.
Better, I think.
Uh...
Okay.
(PENNY GRUNTING)
What was that?
Where did you go?
I don't remember.
You didn't blip out on purpose?
No, when the pain got so I was
gonna pass out, I just... I just went.
You need a doctor.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I'm impressed.
Not with this. It's
dreadful. Sorry.
With your skills as a
Magician. Who trained you?
Well, I just picked up a
little bit here and there.
Clearly not enough, since I
couldn't put a scratch on that Taker.
Don't be modest.
You have what it takes
to be quite formidable.
I could use you.
Official Court Magician in
Defense of the Kingdom.
You could teach others,
and be taught by me.
I would be honored,
Your Majesty.
Hmm.
A different lining, perhaps.
Gray, please.
When we are
alone, it can be Seb.
Well, Seb,
we have a saying
where I come from.
You kinda buried
the lede on the...
On the, well...
On you. (SNICKERS)
I didn't mean to deceive you.
Kings have to be very
careful about who to trust.
And also, it can
be a relief to not...
Feel the weight of the crown
on your head every second?
You are wise.
But I knew that already.
(DOOR OPENING)
In any case, settle in,
and we'll get down to the
particulars of your duties later.
All right?
All right, Your Majesty.
MARGO: Ugh, please. ELIOT: What?
If you say his gorgeous
eyes see into your soul,
I'm gonna puke all
over your new leggings,
which are quite sharp,
by the way. Thank you.
Legs for days.
(CHUCKLES) Thank you.
And I never said his eyes were
gorgeous or that he sees into my soul.
But weirdly, he might.
Or he's sucking the soul out of
you because he doesn't have one.
Um...
He did save my life.
He's called the Dark King.
You're called
Margo the Destroyer.
I was a woman ruling a patriarchy.
My brand had to be overkill.
Bottom line, he likes you.
Use that to find out
what he's really about.
I'll see if my fellow
Centurions like to gossip.
Then we regroup and decide.
Benevolent dictator
by necessity,
or psychopathic
despot by choice?
What if he's the latter?
Then I always got his back.
Perfect place to bury these.
(DISTANT CLATTER)
(BOOKS CLATTER)
(GASPS)
Zelda, help me, please.
What's going on? Who are they?
Goths. (POUNDING)
Like Marilyn Manson? Visigoths.
Oh, Germanic barbarians.
Who always show up at the
absolute worst points in history.
(POUNDING)
(SPEAKING GREEK)
(SPEAKING ENGLISH) Fucking hell.
Oh, sorry. Did you...
Did you want Hades?
(CHUCKLES) I could get word
to him, but, ugh, what a dick.
Are you...
I'm Clarion, Goddess of Melody.
Hey, Julia. I've, uh, had my
eye on you for quite a while.
You have? Yeah, yeah.
So, you were mortal, right?
And then you were one of us, and
now you're back to mortal. Whew.
You're one tough
cookie, Cookie. Thanks?
Yeah, but the way that you're
imagining the Harmonic Convergence
isn't quite enough.
It's so much worse.
So, when all the spells cast by
all of the Magicians go haywire,
you're gonna get earthquakes,
fire, drought, starvation, plague.
And then comes cannibalism.
Um...
Is there anything you can do?
I could stop it.
How would that be? Great.
But I'm assuming there's
something you want in return.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah. You, uh... (CLICKS TONGUE)
You have dealt
with a god or two.
Yep.
I wanna be human.
Like you.
Excuse me?
I worship you, Julia.
How did you do it, though? Because
that's the part that I couldn't quite see.
There's some kind of cloak
around the whole process.
Uh, rumor is it has
something to do with a book.
Yeah, okay, I'm gonna
need just a few more details.
I don't know.
Starting with "Why?"
Do I want to be
human? Oh, it's simple.
So, I'm the Goddess
of Melody, right?
But did you know that we
can't actually feel music?
Like, we understand it, we can
tell the good from the bad. Sort of.
So you want to be human
so you can do karaoke.
I know that it sounds
like hubris itself, but...
I think I could be a rock star.
I mean, I pretty much know the
gig, right? They all prayed to me.
Except for Amy Winehouse, okay?
Look how that one turned out. Poor thing.
Any other questions?
Oh, boy.
(CAR HORN BLARES)
(CHUCKLES)
(KADY LAUGHING)
KADY: This is amazing.
(DEAN CHUCKLES)
(HONKING) KADY: Careful.
Whoa!
Real world isn't quite gone.
(STUTTERS)
DEAN: Oh.
This is what my neck feels like.
(CHUCKLING)
Come on. The
depository. Come on.
Welcome. KADY: H... Hi.
Oh. (STAMMERS)
We're looking for a depository
that was, uh... It was over there.
Eat up.
Yeah, in a sec, but if you
know where the depository is...
Nobody knows where
anything is in the Realm.
Except for the Emperor.
Dear God. This is strange.
Tastes like, uh...
burning charcoal.
Hamburgers on a grill.
(KADY CHUCKLES)
Popsicles.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
KADY: Is that bunny
staring at us? (CHUCKLES)
Summer at the beach.
Brown bunny,
sunglasses. Beach clue.
I'm trying real
hard to give a shit,
but it just feels so
good to be high again.
DEAN: Mmm. Uh...
DEAN: I guess we
follow him. (CHUCKLES)
CAPTAIN: So we all know
the threat we're facing.
These are Fillory's second greatest
protectors against the Takers.
Who can tell me the first?
His Majesty, the Dark King.
CAPTAIN: Which is why protecting him
is the most important job in the kingdom.
His Majesty is immortal,
yes, but he is not invulnerable.
Which makes us?
Expendable.
A group of Royal Map Makers
won't make it back here till after dark.
And the first cohort is trapped
in a blizzard on Madness Plains.
You wet-nosed
whelps are all we've got.
Well, you, me
and our glorious leader.
What are we looking at here?
His Majesty wants the kingdom to witness
him saving subjects from the Takers.
These are in almost every room in
the castle, most of the taverns, and...
It's fucking Fox News.
Foxes all lie. Who'd
ever believe their news?
His Majesty, I'm afraid all we
have are the newest recruits.
Who'll learn by doing.
CAPTAIN: Yes, sir.
With me, recruits. Break.
Quick step now.
Ready, hup.
Give me a phaser
and a red shirt.
What? Yeah, just don't.
(GRUNTING)
(THUDS) (GROANS)
(BREATHING SHARPLY)
The Binder was annoyed.
But unsurprised Julia had
failed to burn him out of existence,
per their agreement.
(BONES CRACKING)
Look, I just thought maybe
we were both a little hasty,
and, I don't know, maybe I'd keep
you safe, let us both cool down.
So can you do it?
The Binder stared at Julia,
wondering if she'd learned nothing
from her interactions with deities.
I don't have a lot of
choice here, okay?
If you can't do this,
the Earth is doomed.
Mmm. "Again?" the
Binder, asked, bored.
Still, the Binder wondered,
why on Earth would
Julia trust this "Clarion"?
I don't. But the options
here are narrowing.
As a book, the Binder enjoyed
any opportunity to teach.
And here was a word Julia desperately
needed to understand. (CLEARS THROAT)
No.
(SIGHS)
So are these the same Visigoths that
raided cultural strongholds on Earth?
Burned the Library
of Alexandria.
Sacked the statuary
of Ancient Greece.
Burned Rome,
London, Paris, Chicago,
where they framed
poor Mrs. O'Leary's cow.
That's around the time
they started getting bored
and moved into the multiverse.
I'm sorry about all of this,
but I need every book you have
on the Harmonic Convergence.
We have a vast collection
on the other side of that door.
Oh, wow. Lovely timing.
(LOUD POUNDING)
How do you do?
I'm Visigoth Overlord Terence.
Apologies for the mess. But
recall, I did announce our incursion,
and asked you most politely to
drop all your defenses and surrender,
having given my word that
you would be absolutely safe.
(CHUCKLES) Right.
The word of a barbarian?
Actually, Visigoths are famous
for always keeping their word.
Yeah, that's weird.
My dear, if you'd be so kind...
Sorry. I'm just a little
confused here, but you seem...
Educated? Polite to a fault?
We seek to acquire only
the deepest knowledge,
highest art and most
illuminating philosophy.
Is it any wonder a
little might rub off?
What about all those inconvenient
commandments about theft?
Alice, it's no use debating.
Alice, is it? That's
lovely. Thank you.
We seek only those works that
transcend appetite and avarice,
that touch upon the immutable.
That's why we spend so
little time on Earth anymore.
What's left to raid?
Tent-pole franchises? Jeff
Koons? The, um, hoodie?
Visigoths never lie, but they
never tell the whole truth either.
I know what you're really after.
(DOOR SHUTS)
The books of everyone...
Is actually what they want.
Every sentient being's life,
birth to death. Can you imagine?
They could plan the pillaging of every
great work before it's painted or written.
Not to mention the stock
market. Stock market?
They have a thing about
shorting. They think it's hilarious.
Look, Zelda, I understand how important
this is to you, but what's the point?
They're gonna get in here,
and this is the only door.
(POUNDING)
Okay. How about this?
You want to teach? Teach.
(SCOFFS) You? To
turn a goddess mortal?
The Binder inquired, with
not a small amount of disdain.
Hmm.
Too tough? Fine.
Maybe I'll just hand you to her.
Ah.
The Binder realized Julia had
cornered him with his own credo.
But still, he wondered,
what was in it for him?
How's this, paper boy?
Said the Binder, "Let
the lessons commence."
(SLOW PSYCHEDELIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Whoa. (LAUGHS)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
Socks. None of them match.
So, this is where
they go. (CHUCKLES)
If you see a red and orange argyle,
cashmere, size 13, grab it, please.
(GROANS)
I don't usually say
this when I'm this high,
but we really need to focus.
Exactly. Red and orange.
Jesus. No, no.
We're looking for, uh...
Christ. I don't believe it.
There it is.
(KADY LAUGHS)
You were right.
Just needed to focus.
Mmm. (CHUCKLES)
KADY: Oh, bunny. Bunny.
(KADY CHUCKLES)
Um...
Hi. Uh...
We're looking for an Emperor.
Hey, Kady. (BURPS) Hank.
Hank. (CHUCKLES)
I don't hate that.
KADY: You know us?
What kind of an Emp
would I be if I didn't?
You roll into my town, I take
a gander at your thoughts
and if I dig you, I show
you the brown bunny.
And I dig you both.
Congratulations
on the first sock.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
How great is Archie,
by the way? Huh?
Pretty great, once
you let it settle in.
(KADY CHUCKLES)
And as long as you're here,
the high never goes away.
(LIGHTER CLINKS) Wow.
That's, uh... (CHUCKLES)
That's perfect. KADY: Yeah.
We... We really
need to find the, uh...
Oh, Jesus. The, ugh...
Depository, Kady.
Right. Right. Uh, can you
tell us where that is now?
Sure can. Won't be free, though.
Even here, where
everything's fun, there's a price.
Sit. Have some suds.
This'll take a sec.
DEAN: What will?
For me to dig deeper
into your thoughts,
see which one of
you gets to leave
and who has to stay.
Mmm. (CHUCKLES)
DARK KING: The Map
Makers are in there.
(TAKERS SNARLING)
Do you hear that?
Oh, boy.
Breathing.
Coming from there.
With respect, Majesty. There.
(SNARLING CONTINUES)
Guys? There. There.
There. We're surrounded.
You can see them?
I have really good night vision.
My grandpa married a
snow leopard is the rumor.
Sire?
Where is he going?
Oh, I've seen that before. It's
a legit royal tactic. Never fear.
MERRITT: Shouldn't we get
him to the infirmary? (CHUCKLES)
With all the newbies
practicing during surges,
it's like a meat
locker down there.
And the meat's alive.
Until it's not.
(HIGH-PITCHED SQUEAL) (YELLS)
Penny?
Get Julia. Who?
So our Dark King, did
he just shit the doublet?
(CHUCKLING)
I hope so. I really don't want to
be the only one who does it when...
(TAKER SNARLS)
(SIVART SCREAMING)
(WOMEN GASPING)
(TAKERS SNARLING)
(GRUNTS)
(SNARLING)
(TAKERS SNARLING)
ELIOT: (LAUGHING)
That's amazing. Right?
I mean, honestly, fuck
Netflix. That is peak television.
Jesus.
No kidding. You kicked some
serious ass for your kingdom.
(LAUGHING)
Pretty cool.
You're both equally awesome,
by which I mean totally fucked up.
By which I mean I get
you're on a mission.
One of you has gotta jet,
but either one of you
can hang for eternity.
You guys decide.
I'll stay. DEAN:
No, you will not.
Are you kidding?
This place is heroin heaven.
And a billion times better
than Isabella's Islay single malt.
Look it up when you
get back. I'm staying.
You've got students
counting on you.
And I've had it with the goddamn
lot of them. All 40 timelines' worth.
I never really knew how sick of
them I was until I stopped drinking.
I've earned the
right to step off
and do tai chi with the Elvi.
I want this as much as you.
As soon as he tells you
where the depository is...
(MIMICS BUZZER SOUNDING)
Sorry, Kady. But you just revealed
to the entire studio audience
that you're hanging on to a
thread of responsible intent.
Which could make you kind of
a bum hang in 100 years or so.
Hank, on the other hand,
(GRUNTS) is laid-back
mondo perfectos.
(DEAN CHUCKLES)
Hey. You don't really want this.
Kady, sweet Kady.
I'm sorry I did this to you.
I had no right.
My whole life,
all the senseless
worry, suffering and pain,
both inflicted and received...
it wasn't for nothing.
It guided me here.
And you were right.
I am home.
I'll be back, okay? I promise.
Goody. See you soon.
(POUNDING)
Use your key. Go.
I'm not going
without you. I can't.
Do you really want to
die for a bunch of books?
If I could do it all again,
I'd be a better mother,
a truer friend.
But I wasn't. I'm not.
Because I've
given my life to this.
It's all I am. It's all I have.
I can't lose everything.
You can. Believe me, I have.
I'm sorry about Quentin.
But this is
different. No, it's not.
Because whoever, whatever you
love that gets ripped away from you,
it stays alive, inside of us.
And anyone you share it with.
I can't. I can't.
I'm not strong enough. (SOBS)
CLARION: Stopping
her signal is impossible.
It's coming from a
place that I can't reach.
But I could save
him. Then do it. Now.
I'll just need you to give
me what we agreed to.
And the rest of
it? Rest of what?
The part where
you save the planet.
You have one thing to
trade, Julia, for one miracle.
So, your miracle can be to
save your boyfriend or your world.
But you could save both.
You know what? Humans have exploited
gods since you guys staggered upright.
The deals that we
make need to be strict.
So this deal, one
book, one miracle.
You're really gonna
make me choose?
The planet or him?
Yeah. I know. It's
total bullshit, right?
You see why I want to be human?
I can't feel the melodies I'm goddess of,
can't bend the rules I didn't make. Eh...
Don't put this on your kind.
This is you, choosing.
But the one who
has to choose is you.
I'd say he has
about a minute left.
I feel
better.
So why do I feel like something
really shitty went down?
Maybe because you're here.
Like all humans.
23 saw little and knew less.
What strange, sad,
angry, narrow, little lives
these humans stumbled through.
Okay, just tell me what
you did to me. I helped you.
And now, you're
going to help me.
The Binder reminded the goddess
he couldn't be forced to
do anything he didn't wish to.
Aw.
Honey, I don't force anyone.
I just get what I want.
Goodbye, Julia.
And for what it's worth, I feel
like you made the right decision.
For what it's worth,
go fuck yourself.
(CHUCKLES)
That's all of them,
sir. None harmed.
We'll secure the site. You should
go back with the Map Makers.
Kind of feels a little abrupt.
You know? I kinda felt like he was
gearing up to make a big speech,
and it's just...
Wait.
Back inside. Now.
Excuse me, sir, but wasn't
this a rescue mission?
A super-successful
one? That's over?
Inside.
So, I... I take it she's
the god you summoned?
Who is not going to
save the world for us?
Look, we'll figure
something else out.
We've got time.
There's more, isn't there?
Anyone else need a drink?
Look, the signal was killing you. I
did what needed to be done now.
But she didn't have time
to be delicate. She just...
She said that the
only way was...
Take away my psychic abilities.
Yeah, 'cause
I'm not getting
Merritt's signal anymore.
Or anybody's thoughts here
or anywhere.
So this is quiet.
It is fucking weird.
You can't travel anymore.
Technically, I can.
It'd just be like
flying a jet blind.
And since I'm not suicidal, I...
I'm sorry, Penny.
No. We just settled a really
big spiritual argument here.
There is for sure instant karma.
If there had been
more time... Come on.
You can appreciate the
balance of it, the irony.
I had to make a choice for you,
you had to make a choice for me.
It is fucking radiant.
BOTH: Um...
MERRITT: This...
So, uh, this happened...
This is because of me.
I didn't see it coming and I never
thought it was gonna get this bad.
Merritt, what could
you have done?
I should've told you the truth.
My name, my real name, is Plum.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Plum Merritt Chatwin.
Wait. What? You're a Chatwin?
Wait. What do you mean?
Like the kids' books?
I missed an episode.
I am so sorry.
I was terrified and alone,
and being here was
the first time I felt safe.
But I'm not.
The thing with being a
Chatwin is, it's like a curse.
It's like there are things coming
after you you just don't understand.
I don't know what this signal is,
but I know why it's targeting me.
And I'm gonna figure out how
to fix it. Whoa! Hang on. Hang on.
Merritt, you don't know what
that's gonna do. (CRACK)
(GROANS)
(SIGHS)
You're right.
What...
(POUNDING)
Funny thing about doing the
same thing over and over again,
you learn how to do it better.
I suppose that's the true
purpose of a library now?
Ah.
Your treasured tomes.
Each one a life.
A destiny.
I'm most curious about who
my next few wives will be.
You never know, Alice.
Let's go find our
books, shall we?
Something to add,
Madam Librarian? Yes.
If you really want
to know your future,
you'd better be
able to speed read.
No!
No! No!
No! No! No!
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Enter.
I was just checking to
make sure you were all right.
Thank you for your concern.
I'm fine.
Just a bit tired.
Hmm.
I can imagine. (GROANING)
You were incredible out there.
Maybe once.
Now it's, um...
What's the military term?
Holding action.
Nothing but holding actions.
I saw that not all the
Centurions returned.
Good night, Seb.
What exactly are
we looking for, sir?
Not what. Who.
Well, both.
(CLATTERING)
(MEN GRUNT)
Grab it. Grab it.
You two know each other?
No.
Then you won't mind taking
charge of its imprisonment.
Of course not, sir.
And all the books on
everyone are gone for good.
Maybe that means actual free will
now, and not any of that predestined shit.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Or lots of rewrites to do.
Sorry, Zelda. It's a
bad day for everybody.
At least the fires
drove them out.
We think they got about
half the collection. Mmm.
Yep, and everything
on the Convergence.
So what do we do now? We
try and trade with the Visigoths?
What do we have that they want?
I mean, the Overlord kind
of liked me. Off the table.
I read most of the books
on the Convergence.
Enough to know
it can be stopped.
It's almost impossible,
but not complicated.
Zelda, please tell.
Oh. Of course.
Well, all you have
to do is move that.
Move?
The fucking moon.
(SIGHS) Well, at least
we know where it is.