Previously on The Magicians...
Alice is fine.
Depressed, surly.
Still asking to see you again.
She's fixated on the thing
she says she saw in the castle.
She's worried about her friends.
I can't think of anyone
better protected than they.
They must stay where
they are, as they are.
They'll be fine.
Your spellwork was masterful.
There's something
you need to know
and as soon as I start
telling you about this,
bad shit is gonna
start flying at our heads.
So, how do we figure
out who we really are?
Hi. I'm Marina.
I'm here to help.
So, you're like some powerful,
benevolent white witch?
Uh-huh.
Let's take a peek underneath
and see what you really look like.
Fix it.
I don't know what
you want me to fix!
Whatever the
matter is in Fillory!
Hello?
Old.
Things get old
so fast, don't they?
Sorry, but where are we?
I told you, Greece.
Right, right.
This is the temple of the
god we are summoning.
Enyalius.
God of war.
Thought that was Ares.
Say that when you see him.
It makes him so mad.
So, okay. Go in the woods.
Get a pig.
Excuse me? A wild pig.
The younger the better.
Sorry, I don't mean to be difficult,
but couldn't you just conjure one?
Hmm, no.
It has to be caught
with human hands
and stained with human effort.
You know, that... That stuff
that comes out of your skin.
Sweat?
Hurry.
What the fuck did you do?
I didn't do anything.
That spell's a cunt with fangs.
I thought your amulet
was supposed to protect us.
It did. You're alive,
and welcome, asshole.
Great. Well, that didn't work
and we're back to square one.
Yeah? DEAN: Hello,
whoever you are.
Do not tamper with
my enchantment.
Holy shit, it's
James Earl Jones!
Shut up.
Yes, you've triggered a
read-me file voicemail.
And, no, you may not
take me off speakerphone.
You will not circumvent
or defeat this spell.
Whoever you are, walk away. Now.
Or your death is as certain
as those I've enchanted.
So, spells are
basically credit cards
with automated
fraud warning calls?
That's not super inspired.
Well, neither is Henry Fogg,
nor his favorite
students, right?
Sit in the kitchen
until I tell you it's safe.
You stay.
She scares me.
Yeah, well, she's not
the one with the Glock.
I've got a theory
about you, stud.
Stand close.
Ooh.
Oh, Henry. Such a good try.
What are you doing?
Ow.
I'm making you useful.
Wait.
Where's Janet?
Hello?
Anyone?
Mother Nature, can you hear me?
Wow, forests don't even talk.
Whole psychotic break
just lacks imagination.
Again.
Jesus. Dude.
The chips.
How am I doing this?
Yes.
This pond better be vodka.
Your Majesty?
Jesus Christ.
Forgive the suddenness
of my introduction.
I know you're not quite
yourself, King Margo.
What are you?
Where am I?
And why does everybody in this
nightmare keep calling me king?
Is that even a thing?
I'll endeavor to explain.
Hello.
You're being kind of quiet.
Look, you're nice and all.
Sort of. But I... I could use
some intel on this place,
but how do I know
you're not a snitch?
Well, because like
it or not, I'm Santa.
Which used to mean I was
once considered fairly honest.
Reasonably reliable,
but I... I don't know.
Maybe, uh,
slightly admired.
Then all of a sudden
it was like, "Hey,
"you break into houses once
a year. What's up with that?"
And, "Kids sit on your lap.
"How is that not creepy?"
Congratulations, Earth.
You ruined the name of Santa.
So, you don't want
to hear from me?
Good.
'Cause I'm sure you don't
need this thing I could get you,
called magic.
How?
I am the Lord of All
Fillorian Fresh Water.
Which is a bit pretentious,
so, please, call me Lord Fresh.
Assuming this is actually
happening, you pulled me down here.
Why?
Your birthright box.
You and my birth
box ain't happening,
so back up, Shape of Water.
No, no. Your birthright box.
There. Oh.
Right.
No, Majesty!
If you touch it,
it will harm you.
Even my protective
wards couldn't save you.
You know about that spell shit?
I'm really somebody else,
and if I try to figure out who
shit clobbers me, burns me?
Correct.
Though, as I said,
you're safe down here.
Your birthright box,
which it has been
my honor to guard,
dictated your absence
from the kingdom,
your loss of self,
and your return
this day and hour.
But I must caution.
It also predicted
that you would learn what it is
to live and rule alone.
Yeah?
Well, alone's my
jam, grenouille.
And no matter what, I rule.
Your enchantment
is most powerful.
I'm not sure that
my wards will hold.
To come back and
claim your destiny,
you must find the god who
summoned you in the dream.
Please accept my apologies.
I'm afraid I can't keep
you as safe as I had hoped.
Walk toward the mountains.
My destiny is to die
of pneumonia, isn't it?
You can tell me.
Hardly, Majesty.
Please return when
the spell is lifted.
Here's your lunch.
Ugh!
Well, if he's anything
like my Henry,
he keeps most of his secrets
in here.
Todd.
Oh, my God.
Hansel?
Hey. We gotta hustle.
Yeah, uh...
Anything I... I can do?
Yeah. Take your shirt off
and make me a sandwich.
Sorry, but I'm starved.
If it helps, I'm vegan,
so this sucks for me, too.
Todd? Jesus, are you drunk?
Marina.
Hello, Henry.
What is this? What did you do?
It's the same blue
shit you gave Hansel.
Only I knew you wouldn't
drink it at my request.
So, here's the deal.
Give yourself the antidote.
There is no antidote.
Bullshit.
Whoa, hoo, hoo, hoo!
So, it's true!
Everything she's
been telling us is true!
Us?
Who else is involved in this?
Pretty much all of your apple-shining,
ass-kissing teacher's pets.
Oh, Christ.
Whatever she's saying she's
going to do to help you, she isn't.
And how are you talking
about this without...
Being attacked by the world?
It's magic, remember?
What timeline are you from?
The one where you
owe me child support.
I'm kidding. So, the
spell takes, what,
a day to kick in?
It's almost dawn.
You say there's no antidote.
You better get to
a lab and get to it.
Because I'm not
turning you into a DJ.
No.
You won't like the new you.
Unless you have a secret
dream to live in a moving box.
You just hit the
rethink button, okay?
Let's go.
Bye.
Jesus.
Todd.
How long have you been awake?
We need to get
you some help. No.
And what you just
saw dies with you.
Do you understand?
This cannot continue.
An infinity of pardons,
Acting High King Fen.
There is an urgent matter.
An urgent poacher?
Who claims to be the High King.
So, an urgent, insane poacher.
Was my first thought. Until?
The name was uttered.
So,
you claim to be High King
Margo? No!
Ow!
There you have it. So,
every time you say...
Weird, huh?
You look nothing like her.
Look.
I'm not saying I'm who
we are not talking about.
But I had this dream
where this goat god, Amber?
Ember. Ember.
Whatevs.
Said I had to get
here quick and dirty.
The reports are true.
Ember has indeed
returned to Fillory.
Miraculously risen
from the dead.
Look, if you know
where this Ember is...
We don't, is the problem.
We don't want to
find him. We have to.
Something's happened
since his return.
Oh, I'm nodding so you hurry
and you get to something
I actually understand.
Oh.
Our air has always been graced
with what you on
Earth call opium.
But now it's saturated.
For some it's tolerable.
Some get quite giddy,
a few succumb to sleep at
the most inconvenient times,
and then there are those who...
Dance. In the nude.
It sounds lighthearted,
but it's actually resulted
in a number of deaths,
mainly in falling asleep
in the wrong place
at the wrong time.
Trampled in the middle of the
road being the most common.
However, a dance troupe did
die of exposure on a glacier,
though, by all accounts,
quite gracefully.
Magic is now rationed.
And none of it is powerful
enough to reverse this.
And since it coincides
with Ember's return...
His glorious resurrection
and divine rule!
We hope.
We've come to believe
that this is his doing.
And perhaps if he could be told
of the damage it's causing,
he could be convinced
to reverse this.
Guys.
I need to stress
how much I don't give a shit.
Oh.
But he's dodging you
and he wants me.
So, let's find the fucker.
Sassy.
Hi. Hi! Kim, sorry, I'm late.
No, this won't take long.
I think I'm flunking out.
Oh, first-year
nerves, totally normal.
No, no, no, I am
literally failing everything.
I mean, if I could
just pass one...
And somebody told you
I have a cheating spell.
Yes. Okay, I will hook
you up but right now,
I'm trying not to freak.
What's wrong? I can't tell you.
Okay. I promised.
Right. Dean Fogg
is leaving. Shit!
Why did I just say that?
Because it's too much.
Why do I have to be
the only one who knows?
Wait, he's leaving? Why?
Oh, believe me,
it is not his choice.
See, there's this
Hedge Witch, and she...
Dean Fogg, hi! Sorry, I'm late.
I will give you every
cheating spell I have
if you please don't
repeat this, okay?
Great. Thanks.
It's gonna be fine.
Oh, my God, this is horrible.
So, even after you're gone, nothing
about Marina can go in the memoir?
Write or breathe a single word and
there will be blood on your hands.
But the outstanding
business I'm attending to today
should be recorded
in minute detail.
Walter.
You're the best drinking
companion I've ever had.
Thanks. I mean, we
only drank together twice.
I'm a high-functioning
alcoholic, Walter.
We prefer to do our
serious drinking alone.
So that when we weep, we
can wallow in self-loathing
without embarrassment.
Did you get that,
Todd? Fantastic.
Excellent.
Walter, in my office bar
is an unopened bottle of
1977 Hollcroft single malt
that I was going to drink
if I ever committed suicide.
Enjoy, my dear friend.
It's not your fault I'm
always broke, Ashley.
I'm a degenerate gambler
who could use magic
to alter the outcome
of any game.
But then I couldn't relive
the secret shame I've held
since I was two years old.
What I crave most in the world
is the degradation of losing.
Thank you for every
single moment of that.
You're $56 short.
You're a cutthroat bookie.
Gold.
Magic has been a brutal
series of disappointments.
And after having
lived 40 timelines,
39 of which range from
the comically horrendous
to the apocalyptically absurd,
to find it was
all for nothing...
Well, leaving this life
actually feels liberating.
Hold this, Todd.
Thank you. Okay.
Tell Jennifer thank
you and goodbye.
I had an affair with his wife.
He behaved abominably.
Do you find all this as
cathartic as I do, Todd?
I think you really hurt him.
Well, back to my childhood.
I was raised by my grandmother,
the kindest, wisest
person I've ever known.
Of course, I could
never tell her that
because all forms
of intimacy horrify me.
"All forms of intimacy
terrify the hell out of me."
Yes?
Kim. What can I do for you?
Look, I'm pretty sure I
shouldn't tell you this.
Well, you probably shouldn't
have walked in and said that.
I don't think that
I belong here.
As I said, it would
take some time.
And, I promise, you do.
Right, and you're literally the only
one that thinks that, and you're leaving.
Todd.
Look, it's not his
fault. He's just upset.
I am, too. Anybody
that knew would be.
Please.
I probably owe
you an explanation.
My life is mostly
made up of regrets.
I'm not looking for
contradiction or pity.
It's just a fact I'm
suddenly forced to face.
But of all my many regrets
the greatest is something
I did very recently
to some of the most maddeningly
millennial students I ever had.
What...
Were they gonna hit us?
Advantage of being
the spell caster.
I'll never be able to
correct what I did to them.
But, Kim, one day you might.
Me?
You have no idea
what you're capable of.
I do.
Okay, then if you want
me to help these students,
can you tell me who they are?
Their lives were
in grave danger.
I cast a spell that erased their
identities and gave them new ones,
and now that same spell
has been cast on me.
Jesus.
I mean, isn't there
anything you can do?
Well, if I reveal that the
spell can be reversed,
then someone would reverse
the spell on my students,
ensuring their deaths.
I will not allow that to happen.
I have to do this.
I must accept this.
Hmm...
Ah, stubborn dude.
You got Plan B?
B plans are for losers.
Okay.
Uh... Well, whatever
happens, thank you for trying.
I don't really know
why you're putting
yourself out so much for us,
but it's pretty cool.
Well, it's pretty
common knowledge
that I'm a very,
very good person
who lives to help others.
Mmm.
Oh.
It's such a piece of shit.
Hey. I like the artwork.
Yep. Sure.
You have to admit,
the characters? Us?
We're pretty complex.
Oh, yeah, real complex.
Yeah, Isaac's big problem
is his dick is too big.
Hey. It can be a problem.
Seriously.
It narrows the field by a
lot more than you think.
I've been on way too many first
dates that end in urgent care, so...
Gross. HANSEL: Look.
My life is pretty cool,
so, how do I know
this other me is gonna...
Nail as many groupies?
Whoa, hey, whoa, no.
That is not what
Hansel is about, okay?
You think there's a chance the
real you didn't bang your sister?
Hey, no, isn't that...
She was my stepsister, okay?
Stepsister.
And we didn't
know till... Till later.
Mmm.
Too many stepdads.
All right, well, what about you?
What's your kink? Me?
No, see, I'm perfect.
Yeah, I catch drug
dealers, murderers,
arsonists, blackmailers, pimps.
I even stopped a girl from giving
herself a coat-hanger abortion
and got her to Planned
Parenthood. You see, I...
I'm a hero.
So, why would you give that up?
You sound awesome.
I sound fake.
Which I am.
Oh, like your thunder meat.
All right, easy. It's...
It's... It's a meat.
I don't know if it's thunder.
We just never know
where his celestial,
newly risen godliness
is going to pop up next.
From the brothel in
the Lower Meerskin,
Ember was then sighted on the schooner
of the thin white duke off Basher Island,
where there was a celebration
for three days and nights.
Okay. Well, so far, every sighting
he either gets the party started
or he dives right into one
that's already jumping off.
Ember has always
enjoyed his pleasures,
but this pace reeks
of self-destruction.
Please.
One July 4th,
I bet I could snort my
body weight in coke.
This dude's an amateur.
Next.
Landfall at Shimmering
Cliff Palace, then an orgy
at Sacred Sky Nunnery.
Okay. That's almost impressive.
So, look, he's headed east.
If he keeps going,
what's the next hotspot?
The Hare on the Ass.
Seriously?
Whimsy.
I fucking hate it.
So, you found a whole
family of them, huh?
Mmm.
What happened to the mother pig?
Kill it.
What?
Enyalius won't come
without a sacrifice, silly.
Here.
Slit its belly open, please.
Entrails on the altar.
No, I'm not, I'm not...
Look, I'm a person with a
job and a girlfriend and a life,
and I'm not your... Your
pal. Or your playmate.
And I'm not scared
of you anymore.
So, why don't you
just fucking kill me?
I would never do that.
Ah!
Hello, Etta.
Oh, I suppose this is
why you summoned me.
Thank you.
Oh, and the answer is no.
Your new suit is
not finished yet.
Oh, pity.
You are usually
not this impatient.
Henry, would you like to
see the work in progress?
Oh, yes.
Okay.
Ah.
Beautiful.
Of course.
Damn it. What in the world?
Magic ration.
My office had some
unexpected visitors today
who took a huge
portion of today's magic.
Ah. No worries.
Smell.
I'm sorry.
That's my grandmother's
huckleberry pie.
Wait, what?
What is it, Henry?
So, why a comic book?
Graphic novel, Etta.
Had a lot of characters
with detailed backstories.
And I could look at them.
So, the glamour was
much easier to cast.
Doesn't matter now.
I'm about to live
a version of it.
Though, I'm assured,
one not quite as nice.
Well, you seem awfully sanguine.
Fate's a fucker
that always wins.
Okay, I've known you for 22...
Well, 23 years now.
And I've loved you
dearly every moment.
Fully aware that you
can barely stand yourself.
And that made me sad,
but it also made you
my best customer.
How so?
Isn't it obvious?
Come on, the bespoke
suits, the hand-sewn shirts...
It's armor.
It's an armor to
keep the world away.
A disguise so that nobody
can see what a truly
loving heart you have.
You said if revealed,
the spell can be reversed.
Kim. Don't.
I'm one of them, aren't I?
You have to undo
this on all of us.
And then what?
And then we fight.
I know I can't stop you.
But please, be more careful now
than you've ever
been in your life.
Well, lives.
Finally getting to
be your teacher
has been an honor.
You're now the saddest
loser I ever buried.
Look.
Marina.
Hi, Dad.
How's it going?
Got it.
Do you feel it?
Stronger further up.
My arm wouldn't
even fit in there.
Go, little buddy. Come on.
Come on, little buddy.
Hey. Hey, come on
now. Little narration.
Fuck off.
Come on, little buddy.
Yes?
I realize that.
But these dossiers are private.
Holy shit.
Sorry, little buddy.
What happened?
What?
Did... Did anyone ever tell you
you're kind of withholding, you know?
Oh, come on. You're not trying
to kill yourself again, are you?
No.
Hey, is all of that chimney
stuff about you true?
Never met one I couldn't crack.
Leg next? No, no, no, no, no.
Okay, I'm ready.
Whatever you want, okay?
Ah.
Oh.
Time to die. Yes, it is.
Give me a little goodbye kiss.
Yes.
Explains a lot of weird shit,
but I promised I'd keep
everything about him private.
Okay.
Yeah, and I'm
trying to save him.
So, please.
How was that? Was it good?
Yeah. Can I have one?
Oh, yes. Of course.
Thank you.
Magic's supposed
to stay on till 11:00.
Spells take magic, right?
Which is rationed. Which sucks.
And a spell like this would take even
more power than a normal one, right?
I mean, think about it. It's
six, seven, eight people?
Plus whole lives?
No. If you had any
interruption in the flow...
Wait. Magic's off.
It's him.
It's the spell. He told me
that it would try and kill us.
Right, but without magic, how...
Shit.
Maybe he actually finished it.
Finished what?
This thing he
worked on for years.
A perpetual battery.
Come on.
Pray a little harder, please.
Is that suckling I smell?
Enyalius?
Well, fuck, yeah, it is.
You know what's funny?
He sacrificed the pig.
He prayed.
And he's never heard of you.
How dare you?
I want it back.
Give it to me.
Well, I have no
idea what "it" is,
but I grant you permission to
search my ball sack with your tongue.
Fine.
I'll just take it.
Okay, so,
remember, Fogg said
be really, really careful.
Because...
Oh, my God. Kim?
Kim.
No, no.
No, no, no.
Yeah, I need a medic.
Yeah, I think she's...
Sorry, prank.
Kim. Are you okay?
Fine.
No, see.
You kind of
died.
Well, maybe being
un-killable is my discipline.
Yeah, that's not a thing.
Hey.
How much juice do
you think this thing has?
Well, it's perpetual.
So,
it can be overloaded.
I have no idea.
Oh, shit!
How is this a good idea?
Oh, God.
It's not in there!
You're not Enyalius, are you?
You're his servant.
A Corybant. Aren't you?
All right, look, he's... He's
not who you want, so just...
You know, let him go.
All right?
Why did your master
send you to trick me?
He knows.
It's not even midday.
Real ragers rave in the day.
Horn guy. Is that him?
Who is that?
An imposter.
No wonder he won't see
anyone who knows him.
Hey. Ember.
I'm here.
Yeah, you are.
Congrats.
Where are your hooves?
Todd!
Quentin. You're back.
Oh.
You wanted to play.
Sorry. He's too dead.
Cool trick. Do it again.
Okay, what the what now?
What the fuck are you
doing here, Bacchus?
All right.
Have we banged?
I followed you on Instagram.
Everybody did till
they kicked you off.
Oh, I know, right? Dicks.
Well,
that explains all
the opium in the air.
Nice touch, I like it.
It's pretty sweet, right?
Mmm-hmm. All right, all
right. What are you doing here?
Why do you want everyone
thinking you're Ember?
Hey, so, you really want
to go back to Earth, right?
No, I want you to answer
my fucking question.
Thanks for popping in.
Where is our High King?
Who are you?
A god
is all you need to know.
I'm glad you're back, Quentin.
I was getting a little
tired of the Brian game.
Yeah. Me, too.
So, maybe I missed something
when we were playing,
but you had to
torture him to death.
Why, again?
Gods are so tricky.
Right.
But what about the one
that you were after today?
Oh, we'll get him.
And I'll get back
what he took from me.
And then the others.
They all took.
Took what, exactly?
See, that's what I
don't really know.
They took this part of me
that knew things.
It's not fair.
No, yeah, totally.
They owe you.
Got it.
You really understand
me, Quentin.
It's good to have
a friend like you.
You know, speaking of friends,
when you get back what
the gods took from you,
maybe...
Could I maybe have Eliot back?
The one who tried to kill me?
Hey, hey, no. No.
That was a mistake.
You were there. Do you
like him more than me?
No, I... I didn't say that.
You miss him.
You... You miss
all your friends.
The...
The ones in my castle
who tried to kill me.
Good.
Huh.
Well, upsides and downsides.
Yeah, no, I remember everything.
Kind of like a dream.
I was gonna say
acid trip myself.
Oh, my God.
Mis hermanos.
Where were you? We...
We looked everywhere.
Stay back. Why?
Because I'm not here to play.