QUENTIN: Previously
on The Magicians...
MAYAKOVSKY:
They know everything.
Who you are, what you've done.
You cannot go back.
KADY: What am I supposed to do?
What we all do. Decide.
QUENTIN: Hey, where's Kady?
Who gives a shit?
I don't think Penny even
cares that she's gone.
Believe me, he does.
We're gonna make another you.
You sleep here, your
mind goes into the golem.
(COUGHING)
DR. HIGGINS: The
test was positive.
I want an abortion.
It's a totally
mundane procedure.
Is it?
'Cause it might not be a "simple,
totally mundane" human embryo.
Stop! What are you
doing? Stop! Kady!
(SCREAMING)
DANA: So sorry about this.
That's my Haxenpaxen.
Just imagine what
it's giving off magically.
We're invisible
while we're near him.
Kady!
Your magic is no good here.
What's with Stink-master Flash?
He's coming with us.
It's my mom's contact. She
can help with the baby situation.
They may be able to help
your friend with her problem,
but listen, I would never ever do
business with them if I had a choice.
PICKWICK: Your Majesties,
the much-venerated emissaries
of our neighbors to the north.
I present Prince Ess of Loria.
You fucked with us.
Mmm-hmm. Yes, you did.
You fucked with our castle.
Amen, sister.
And now the High King and I hereby
declare war on the kingdom of Loria!
Yes!
Wait...
Really?
I cast a Niffin summoning
and you didn't come.
You're wrong. I was right there.
I killed you. My cacodemon...
Your cacodemon wasn't
powerful enough to kill me.
It tried, but when it
saw that it couldn't win...
Well, let's just say it stuffed
me in a place most convenient.
That stupid tattoo
trap on your back.
We're stuck with each other.
Oh, Quentin.
We're gonna have so much fun.
Stop ignoring me! Stop
ignoring me, you pussy.
Pay attention to me, you miserable
sad sack. What's wrong with you?
Stop it!
Are you ready to let me out
of that hairy back of yours?
'Cause I'm never gonna stop.
And sooner or later
one of these dummies
are gonna call the brain police.
And you got priors.
QUENTIN: This is not
Alice. This is not Alice.
This is not Alice. This
is not Alice. This is not...
Just keep telling yourself that.
(BOOKS SLAMMING)
You have got to stop.
Fine. Let me out of
this trap and I'm gone.
Okay. Look, Alice.
Evil thing inside of me
that used to be Alice.
I have to say the
words to open the trap.
Of my own volition, out loud.
And I'm not going to do that.
Because there is one
policy for you out here,
and it is to box
you up for eternity.
Kind of boxed up
right now. In you.
It's not the same
thing and you know it.
Block of wood isn't
trying to fix this. I am.
Save me? Is that what
you think you're doing?
You think I want that?
I think if you were really you
right now, that's all you would want.
Oh, what, and you're the world's
foremost expert in all things me?
Based on what?
Our garbage fire
of a relationship
that ended with Eliot's
dick in your mouth?
Look, you came really close to
fixing this once for your brother.
I thought I did. But
I was like you then.
Small, yet weirdly arrogant
for somebody who didn't
understand magic at all.
If you would just work with
me instead of jabbing at me,
we could figure
out what's missing.
(STAMMERING) We could make
the spell work. We could do this.
ALICE: Listen to me.
I promise, the math
will never add up, Q.
You'll never get that girl back.
Everything that's missing
burned up when I became this.
It's gone forever, Q.
This isn't good
for either of us.
No, no, this is making
me saner by the second.
I don't want to hurt you. I
actually don't want to hurt anyone.
Bullshit. You're a Niffin.
Q, I'm not bloodthirsty.
I just want to be free.
And I already told
you. I can't do that.
Fine, just let me
take over your body.
For just the tiniest little bit.
I'll be good. I'll be so good.
No! That's crazy.
So I have to be a Niffin,
yet I don't even
get to be a Niffin?
I could travel the universe, I could
see things you couldn't even imagine,
but instead, I have to be
bored and stuck with you!
I'm sorry that it is torture
to be with the one person
who's trying to help you.
So, go back to screaming
until you go insane?
Is that your choice?
No, that's your choice
or you could be quiet.
(WHISPERING) And you
could let me try and solve this.
(GROANS)
Well, this is the place.
Of course it is.
Why wouldn't it be?
I mean, Goldie
said they're legit.
Only one way to find out.
Yeah.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GROANS)
(BOTH SPEAKING KOREAN)
(SIGHS)
Problem? No problem.
We're just discussing how
to handle your situation.
It's okay. My way's best way.
But you can abort it, right?
This is exorcism.
That thing is not human.
The longer it's inside you, the more
tangled it gets with your essence
and the harder it is
for me to help you.
You understand?
(WHISPERS) Okay.
Then I exorcise
the trickster for you.
After you pay. Thank you.
One million dollars? In gold.
Paper money's for
drug dealers and idiots.
Look, Goldie will
tell you I'm good for it.
Can you just do it now
and we'll pay you later?
Bars. Two big bars.
Maybe 60 pounds. That's all.
What?
No, I'm just, uh...
I'm trying to remember the last
time not having enough money
was one of my biggest problems.
Okay, well, cash
won't cut it. So what?
Pawn shops?
Yeah, a million dollars
in chains and earrings?
I mean, that would take
so many pawn shops.
We might as well rob a bank.
Well, we are Magicians.
Why don't we just rob a bank?
So there's really no way to just
take it all back?
Your Majesty, one cannot simply
take back a declaration of war.
Good. Because I don't.
There are Lorian troops
marching to the border.
They're days away.
We believe they intend to penetrate
Fillory by way of the Grudge Gap.
And, of course, our
preparation is affected
by the continued
unsteadiness of the Wellspring.
Okay, well, we've got literally
every engineer in the kingdom
working to de-shitinate
the Wellspring.
I'm gonna invent the
guillotine in a hot second
if they don't get
their shit together.
Everyone is doing
their best, my Queen.
We expect to clear
said water shortly.
We're excessively optimistic.
Spare no expense.
PICKWICK: Which
brings me to my point.
Fixing the Wellspring
is expensive.
War is expensive.
And at this time, we do not
have the funds necessary.
We're broke?
It's magic residue.
Probably from a ward around
the bank's underground vault.
It's a regular bank.
Regular banks
have magical wards?
KADY: Ones connected to
the Federal Reserve do, yeah.
Okay, so how do we get past it?
(GROANING)
Shit, it's...
Haxenpaxen.
(GROANING)
(BANGING)
Hey, we can't
just let it out! It...
(GROANS)
(SCREAMING)
(JULIA COUGHING)
(GASPING)
(GROANS)
(FLESH TWISTING,
BONES CRUNCHING)
(GROANS)
What the fuck?
(GROANING)
Wait. What the hell? A spoon?
I think it's dead.
What the hell was it?
Besides huge and invisible?
Fuck! We have to
stop the bleeding.
(SIGHING)
(EXHALES)
We should bury it properly.
Okay. But, Jules,
we gotta move, okay?
We really need to
get somewhere safe.
Okay, like?
You're not gonna like it.
Have you seen
the Twilight movies?
Specifically the last one?
No.
Huh.
That's probably for the best.
Your problems extend
beyond your uterus.
The fetus' élan vital
is entangled with your soul.
I mean, I've read about this,
but I've never seen it in person.
You'll need to find a
Mudang. It's their area.
Yeah, we did. She was expensive.
Yeah, tell me about it. I've been
trying to get one on staff for years.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(EXHALES)
That poor girl's fucked.
And you're suggesting?
Let her stay.
I know that you expelled Kady.
And that you are not generally
keen on granting asylum,
especially to Hedges.
Yes, well,
this is a special case.
Huh. Julia and I have a past.
Handle it however you want,
but for the record, that girl
will be safer at Brakebills.
Mmm.
Well, transfer the
energy from one being
and transform it.
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey. What are
you two doing here?
What?
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
What's this bitch
doing in my room?
I know that this
was her room, right?
I guess they haven't
moved her stuff yet,
but Fogg said space
was limited. So...
I talked to Kady.
What? No respect
for the dead, Q?
You're just gonna
let her sit on my bed?
(SIGHS) Jules, I
don't know what to say.
Say what you're
thinking. That I'm cursed.
Must've been a serial
killer in a past life.
Yeah, raise your
hand if she's the reason
that you fucking
exploded in this life.
Sorry for everything
that's happened.
Yeah, speak for yourself.
For everything that
you're going through.
Mmm, now you're
just lying to her, Q.
I'm sorry. I'm just
having a hard time.
Yeah, because you blame her!
I'm not blaming you for Alice.
If I'm being honest.
No, if I make you
feel so shitty, just go.
No.
Why? I'm the reason.
If I'm the reason, and I...
'Cause that doesn't
feel right either.
I don't know what's right.
My best friend in the
world does crazy shit,
and doesn't trust me,
and doesn't listen to me.
It is not that simple
and you know it.
Well, I don't... What
am I supposed to do?
Oh, you guys are both
so goddamn maudlin.
(SHUSHING)
I promised you in Fillory
when you told me about Reynard
that I would help you, somehow.
And that is not a promise
that I intend on breaking.
(SIGHS) So, if there's
anything that I can do...
Actually, there is.
Help us rob a bank.
Oh, my God, yes.
You say yes.
It's for Professor Mayakovsky.
It was destroyed by other books.
Future Movements of Magic
was written by a Polish scientist
who happened to be a...
What?
Jew.
So the Eugenics
books came for it.
I'm really sorry.
They've been put in
the restricted section
with the other
anti-Semitic texts.
(GROANS)
Hey.
I'm...
Long story. (CHUCKLES)
Anyway. (CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
There's our little king. (SIGHS)
So, how have you
been since, um...
Uh... I'm managing.
Um, how are things
with you guys?
Glad you asked. We're at war.
Also, Fillory is seriously,
dangerously stone-cold broke.
Wait, how's that even possible?
The Nugget Beetles
of the Outer Islands,
they literally shit
precious stones.
Gone extinct, apparently.
Ember shitting in the power grid
really screwed us in
a cornucopia of ways.
And before you ask, yes, every
alchemist in history is a lying,
cheating illusionist.
They turn lead to gold, it
turns right back in a day.
So, we are boned.
How would you guys
feel about robbing a bank?
(KADY CHUCKLES)
Phew.
(SIGHS)
So,
what are you really up to?
(GROANS)
We need to rob a bank.
A bank heist.
Wow. Mmm.
I think the time we've invested
in him may actually pay off.
Mmm-hmm.
Okay, first there's
something I need to tell you.
You're not going to
like it, but hear me out.
For Julia? The psychopath?
The victim of a fucking
rape by a trickster god.
(SCOFFS)
(SIGHING) God!
Look, I gotta do
this, okay? I owe her.
So?
You're gonna ask the Traveler
you just fucked the shit out of to help?
I mean, no. I didn't really
feel like I had the right.
That's noble,
but ask.
Not gonna lie. I always
wanted to rob a bank.
To our little
thievery corporation.
P.S., we still hate you.
But it's the 21st century.
Shouldn't be
this hard for a girl
to get an evil demigod abortion.
ELIOT: And we're
emotionally advanced.
We can hold resentment and
sympathy for a person at the same time.
And Fillory's broke.
We need gold.
So, lucky you.
Thank you.
Okay, uh,
so, if this heist is happening,
any ideas as to how?
Well, we cased the bank. There's a
pretty gnarly ward around the vault.
Who here's actually
robbed a bank?
When was this?
Senior year of high school.
(INHALES)
I had some issues.
Okay, listen up,
'cause I'm only going to
go through this shit once.
Any bank worth robbing uses
one of a handful of security systems.
All the usual
bells and whistles.
But what most idiots don't know
is those companies are
all owned by Magicians.
So the people that work there...
Clueless.
Tellers, managers, security
guards, they're all Muggles.
They have no idea the
vault has a secret feature.
Serious wards.
Designed specifically
to keep out Magicians.
Now, in the case of our target,
their fingerprints control
the alarm systems.
It takes two managers scanning
their prints simultaneously to do this.
Once both the alarms
and the wards go down,
you've got 10 minutes
to get downstairs,
past the armed guards, and
enter in the correct 10-digit combo.
If you screw up the combination
or you take longer than
10 minutes, you're fucked.
Now basic bitches trip all
the standard alarm systems,
but Magicians, we also
trip the magic wards,
which means Battle Magicians.
Full-time security employees
on the D.L. with benefits.
You see one, run.
They only ask
questions post-mortem.
But our ace is you.
Once we nab prints and drop
the wards, you travel straight in.
You really don't
think a bank vault,
of all places, has
anti-Traveler protection?
MARGO: Oh, they do.
The entire floor of the vault
is one big anti-Traveling sigil.
You're locked in
till you run out of air.
Yeah, pass. I like air.
Relax, dummy. You only
get stuck if you hit the floor.
Oh, so it's like
Mission Impossible.
That movie was
stupidly unrealistic.
It's so much easier
to just levitate.
Yeah, I don't know how, and in
case you guys have all forgotten,
I can't do magic.
Oh, that's fine. This is
gonna get done to you.
It's a little thingy any Physical
Kid can make in their sleep.
MARGO: Gravity Belt. Exactly.
Once we drop the
wards, float Penny,
he zips in, he zips out, payday.
(SCREECHING)
KADY: Julia, run!
It's there. You just
don't see it. Go!
I thought it was dead.
My guess, it's got friends.
Kady, come on. No.
You go. I'll catch up.
Kady... No, I need
to kill it. I'll be fine.
Why? I need its spoon.
Spoon?
KADY: This is yours, isn't it?
You sent those things
after Julia, didn't you?
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
See? This is what
happens when you don't pay.
(SPEAKING KOREAN)
Lady. Use your words.
What the... (SPEAKING KOREAN)
This is for a dokkaebi.
How you say,
goblin? Invisible, right?
Yeah. Right.
This is very old magic.
You bring to life, using old, abandoned
things like this wooden spoon.
And menstrual blood.
Probably Moon's.
These creatures are
mercenaries. They won't stop.
You kill one, another
one grows in its place.
Very fucked up.
Why the hell would she do that?
To kill your friend.
I told Moon to relax, but
she's all, "Baby's too evil.
"It might hurt more people."
She wants to play it safe and
kill both spawn and mom together.
She's so stupid.
You won't pay if
your friend is dead.
Listen, we're trying to
get you the money, okay?
If you wanna get paid so
fucking bad, tell her to call it off.
Can't. She has 100 spoons.
Dokkaebi will not stop
until trickster baby is dead.
So, you got two options.
I can exorcise for you
or a monster rips your
friend's head off her neck.
So, hurry up with my gold.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Hey.
Is that...
You remember that one time Richard
and the Free Traders rewound time?
Déjà pizza? Yeah.
I think this is how they did it.
That was heavy
cooperative magic.
Yeah, well, there are
notes for version 2.0 here.
I mean, it's more
efficient, takes less juice.
Either one of us could run it.
Let's see.
"The Quarterback?"
It goes back 15 seconds, get it?
Quarter of a minute?
Yeah, Richard did like his
dad jokes. (CHUCKLES)
Anyway, I thought
it could be useful,
but at this rate I won't
actually get it to work for weeks.
And I guess I'd be weighed
down lugging it anyway,
it's got a pretty small
radius of influence.
Julia, you can't come.
What?
Those invisible blood-goblin
things, they won't stop coming.
Not until your problem's dead.
Meaning you are.
If you step out from
under these wards...
It'll find me and
all of you. Right.
So, I'm supposed to what?
Just wait here? Fingers crossed?
While everyone who blames
me for Alice's death risks their life?
I mean, how does
that even make sense?
Just 'cause you can't come
doesn't mean you can't be there.
You can listen in and watch.
All right. But if
anything goes wrong...
Nothing will, okay?
MARGO: Librarian, Neck
Beard, and White Privilege.
They're the managers.
We need two of their prints.
The good news is, they all go
to the same lame bar after work.
I'll take White Privilege.
Kady, you take Neck Beard.
Oh, nut up. It's just a finger.
Walk up to him, grab his hand,
and say, "Can I borrow this?"
Dip his stupid finger
in his drink to sanitize it,
and pop it in your mouth.
Walk away yet stay emblazoned
on his heart for a lifetime.
Done and done.
Fine.
Why's it got to be Kady?
It could be Penny or Eliot.
Or you.
Yeah, sounded like volunteering.
Okay, fine. I'll take the
Librarian. (LAUGHS)
Great. Quentin will go
in my place. Thanks, Q.
So, he really just stuck
that in your mouth?
KADY: Yup.
That is how the spell works.
Damn.
Unexpectedly, I am
somehow turned on right now.
Oh, really?
Look at this idiot.
(GROANS)
Took you long enough.
So show us the goods.
(QUENTIN SIGHS)
KADY: (LAUGHS) Oh, God!
(LAUGHS) Oh, that's bad.
PENNY: How'd you
get it in your mouth?
Oh, it wasn't with
your mouth, was it?
Oh.
(LAUGHS) Oh, shit.
(SNORTS) She went
digital underground?
KADY: Oh, God. PENNY: Whoo!
What else do we have to do?
With these, we're golden.
Margo and Eliot grabbed everything
else we need for the morning.
So go rest up, Coldwater.
You've earned it.
MARGO: All right. Stick to the plan,
precisely, and we should be golden.
I'll be right here
waiting. Engines running.
Of course you will.
The brains of the operation
drives the getaway.
Everyone knows that.
Of course.
Okay, bitches, let's do this.
Thanks, Jimmy. Yeah.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(GROANS)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
GUARD: All right, here we go.
Good luck.
All right. Let's set the clocks.
(BEEPS)
KADY: Okay.
Three, two, one.
(BEEPS)
(ALARM BUZZES)
Okay.
Alarms and wards are
down. It's up to Penny now.
Let's go.
(LAUGHS)
Wait.
Oh, shit. Um...
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, shit.
Shit!
(GRUNTS)
(GRUNTING)
God damn it.
Fuck!
Fucking Physical Kids.
Penny's only got one
minute. Where the hell is he?
Cutting it a little close, don't
you think? So where's the booty?
Eliot, who are you talking to?
PENNY: They can't see
me. I'm not technically here.
I'm incepting your ass.
Your head. Your dreams.
You're still asleep in
Fillory. Remember?
That is overly complicated.
You know what's not? No.
The sigil I just touched 'cause
someone messed up the buoyancy math.
(SIGHS) That is not good.
Eliot, what's going on?
How do I put this?
Penny fucked up.
No, it's your stupid
device! I'm stuck now!
Penny's incepting my...
Never mind, just trust me.
We have to get him out of that
vault. Now. (WATCH BEEPING)
Or, say, sometime in
the previous 10 minutes.
Fuck. Shit. Shit, let's go.
Tell her I'm fine.
I'm running out of air.
Well. Way to mix the message.
Hey, Margo, keep
the engine running.
I'll inform the bank manager the
bees are resisting extermination,
and everyone needs to
stay clear a little longer.
Let's go, kids.
We're going back in.
(SUZIE GIGGLING)
(JIMMY CLEARS THROAT)
JIMMY: Stop it. SUZIE: Shh!
Quiet!
You...
You are bad.
No, you're bad.
Oh, shit. What?
Guards.
What? I thought they evacuated.
I got this. I brought
the perfect weapon.
Wait, you're not gonna...
Kill them? God, no.
The wrecking ball is
a weapon of peace.
Trust me. I'm a genius.
SUZIE: Well, when you read the
book and then you watch the movie,
it's always disappointing.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
SUZIE: It's always
disappointing.
JIMMY: What if I read to you?
SUZIE: Stop it. Get back...
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
Whipped that up
trying to get anybody
to dance at our cottage soirées,
but it came on a bit strong.
Shit.
There's no way we
can pick this lock.
Maybe we can brute force it.
Hold on. I think this door's
too thick. Even for you.
Okay, just so we're
on the same page,
we've got less
than four minutes.
Fuck! Penny! We're
getting you out.
I don't even think Alice could
do this in under four minutes.
Maybe not then. But now
I could do it in 15 seconds.
Oh, well. Rest in peace, Penny.
Well, I guess I
could help for a price.
I wanna drive. For an hour a
day, I get control of your body.
Okay, okay. Maybe we break
this up. We split up the work.
I don't even know
where to start.
Well, we can't just stand here!
I wouldn't hurt anyone.
I just want to stretch
the tiniest bit. Breathe.
You set the terms.
We could even do a Word
As Bond, so that I can't break it.
(SIGHS)
Okay. Thirty minutes.
That's all you get.
After we hash out
the Word As Bond.
Great.
(WHISPERING) You
try anything crazy...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Box. Is it a deal?
Fine. It's a deal.
ELIOT: Are you
talking to yourself?
Uh, no. Yeah. Uh...
Yes. I'm just... I'm doing
long division in my head.
Move. Move!
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
(ALARM BUZZES)
I've always been good at math.
Penny, you okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Hurray. Princess rescued.
Let's collect our reward and go.
Yes!
(WATCH BEEPING)
Shit!
Q, stop!
QUENTIN: Oh.
Shit. Oh, no.
(ALARM BUZZING)
Let's go! Come on.
ELIOT: Whoa,
whoa, whoa! Hold it!
(STRAINING)
Shit.
Shit, shit, shit!
Well, why should
I go out there first?
You're the Battle Magician!
(EXHALES) What about
another Wrecking Ball?
(SIGHS) It was a one-off.
(BEEPING)
(ALARM BUZZES)
Oh, shit!
You're the Battle Magician.
Wait, did we just...
Go back in time? Yeah. Julia?
JULIA: I'm outside. I can
see you in the van's mirror.
The effect reaches far enough?
Listen, you only
have four rewinds.
Julia's outside.
She's watching with a
machine that can rewind time.
(BEEPING)
(ALARM BUZZES)
PENNY: Now! Let's go.
You're the...
Kady, three rewinds left.
She can only go back
15 seconds. Let's go.
(BEEPING)
(ALARM BUZZES)
You're the...
Two rewinds left.
(BEEPING)
(ALARM BUZZES)
Penny!
Kady. Last rewind.
Okay, look. We need a plan.
Okay.
Okay, I'll blast the bitch.
You all run left. She's
always on the right.
Is she? 'Cause last time I thought
she was more in the middle...
Fifteen seconds!
(SCREAMING)
(DOKKAEBI ROARING) (SCREAMS)
(ALARM BUZZES)
Go.
PENNY: Kady!
(GROANS)
Julia.
Julia, answer me.
Let's go.
Q, come on. Grab the bar.
But...
PENNY: Grab the bar! Let's go!
What... What about...
It's clay. Eliot's
fine. Let's go!
(GASPS)
Eliot? Eliot! Eliot!
Guards!
(DOKKAEBI SNARLING) (COUGHING)
(CHOKING)
(DOKKAEBI ROARS)
KADY: Julia, are you okay?
QUENTIN: Jules? Julia?
KADY: Talk to me.
QUENTIN: Julia, stay with us.
Are you all right?
QUENTIN: (ECHOING) It's
gonna be fine. We're gonna be okay.
KADY: It's gonna be
okay. QUENTIN: Julia?
KADY: Julia?
QUENTIN: Jules,
stay with us. Come on.
KADY: Julia.
KADY: Hey.
Don't move around too much.
Sun patched you up,
but it's gonna take a while.
Did she do it?
Did it work? Is it gone?
Yeah, she did it.
But, Julia,
there was a complication.
(SIGHS)