ALICE: Previously
on The Magicians...
I see blood on the walls. I
hear its voice. It wants out.
Have you tried letting it out?
ELIOT: Charlton?
CHARLTON: I once was
possessed by The Monster, too.
When all the scary
creatures were pulled out,
I held on tight as I could
in your Happy Place.
I found this in Q's
stuff at Brakebills.
Professor... I mean, (CLEARS
THROAT) Dean Adiyodi?
Yeah. Come in.
ALICE: What did
you do with Fogg 17?
I call that one "Psycho Fogg."
Put him in the Clean Room.
He can't cast there, so...
I can't do what I need to do
if I'm worried about
how it's gonna affect you.
I think we need to be done.
I'm interviewing for the
botany job. Hamish Bax.
If I'm right, this should adjust
Circumstances in the entire greenhouse.
Allowing us to cast.
You risked everything for us.
The least we can do
is to show you the truth.
(SPEAKING OTHER LANGUAGE)
(CHILD SCREAMING)
(CHILDREN LAUGHING
AND SCREAMING)
(GROWLING PLAYFULLY)
You can't outrun me!
(BUSH RUSTLES)
(CHILDREN CLAMORING)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
Six children
taken. It's horrific.
The Takers are
swarming. It's my fault.
They're swarming because
Seb summoned them with a spell
using the gold I gave him. I didn't
know what he was going to do with it.
FEN: The Takers.
That's how he stays in power.
He summons them, and
only he can fight them.
Jesus, I go away to my
nephew's bar mitzvah
for one week, and then
everything gets fercockt.
What are we going to do?
We got to kill the Dark King.
What? We're all thinking it.
Eli's Torah portion was
all about the sanctity of life,
and I found it very moving.
So, can't we, I don't know,
peacefully overthrow him?
No, we can't.
He's got a Centurion army, I
should know. I'm one of them.
Also 300 years of propaganda
convincing everyone
they need him.
Also, also, 300 years?
We're talking a powerful,
immortal Magician?
Doubt you can just
walk up and stab the guy.
I've been researching.
The Dark King's survived
seven assassination attempts
since he took our thrones. Must
be big magic keeping him alive.
We have to figure
out what it is.
Find out his weakness.
You're on board with this, too?
I mean, I'm here to stop
an apocalypse that happens
'cause an evil force
invades from a distant realm.
That sounds like the
Takers. Then it's settled.
We kill the Dark King,
stop the Takers from pouring
in, stop the apocalypse. Who's in?
Just a couple of Qs.
Like, how are we gonna get
close enough to the Dark King
to learn his weakness
and assassinate him?
We're a cook, a maid, a
army grunt, a Julia, and a...
Counselor/confidant.
You got to admit, El,
you're perfectly placed.
Plus, he's always dismissing his
guards when you come around.
Why does me liking somebody
always end up with them dying?
You should tell
your friends, Eliot.
That I don't want to save
Fillory because I caught feelings?
I'm saying, they should
know how you feel
before they try to make you
do something you'll regret.
No, I'll just look
selfish, Charlton.
And I'll still end
up having to do it.
Talking to somebody? Um...
Myself. I'm psyching myself up.
Fillory needs the
Dark King dead,
and I am the obvious inside man.
You sound weird.
You sound weird. Okay,
it's that Eliot.
CHARLTON: Uh...
I know I'm just a guy
who has to live inside
your tragic
remembrances and all,
but I truly don't understand
why you won't at least tell her.
Margo, look.
I'm not sure I can
go through with this.
El, you have a crush on
a boy who's bad for you.
Happens to all of us. But how do
we get crushes out of our system?
Lots of drinking, pining.
Some detailed sex fantasies.
No. We bang them
out. Okay, that's great,
except for the part where
now I have to murder the guy
I just hypothetically
slept with,
which is a thing that shouldn't really
happen to a person more than once.
El, Fillory does need this.
So if you can't
do it, tell me now.
I know he has to die,
but I don't hate
him. I don't. I can't.
I can't make
betraying Seb easier,
but let me help make it simpler.
Say you didn't have
to kill him yourself?
But I'm the one with access.
Even you just said it.
You're also my best friend.
If you can find his weakness,
I'll find a way you don't have
to be the one to do it. I promise.
How?
I have no fucking idea,
but I'll figure it
out for you, okay?
Okay.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
BAX: You took the thing.
The panel. You can't just...
This is mass floricide.
Sorry, I had to bring the
panel here, so I could study it.
Sorry, can't hear you
over my plants dying.
Is this a western-facing window?
And now we have a working
classroom because, you know,
school for Magicians,
not flowers.
I took the botany job 'cause
you fixed up the greenhouse.
Should've known you'd
just turn around and wreck it.
Here, let me explain
how that feels.
Wait, don't touch that.
Ah. Thick venation
through the leaves,
and look at the asymmetry here.
Do you recognize it?
Don't think it's terrestrial.
You'd need a
classification expert
with the right magical tools.
I know a taxonomist
who's been around,
you know, the multiverse.
Well, do you think we
can get him to come here?
Don't see why not.
I'll tell you why not.
Your pal Raylan is on the
Dean's "Do Not Admit" list.
You're Acting Dean.
Can't you just... Alice.
He's a botanist. PENNY: Yes!
Who visited a world called Anansia,
home to some highly infectious shit.
He's still alive, isn't he?
Magical phytologists do
crazy shit, but Ray's smart.
I doubt he's carrying anything.
Well, dangerous.
No offense, but I'm gonna
trust the file with the red stamp.
Look, the only place on
Earth right now with magic
stable enough for Ray
to examine it is in our lab,
thanks to me installing the
Circumstances control panel for you.
Don't you think figuring
out the deal with magic
is more important than
translating some page
you found out about a plant?
I found it in Quentin's desk.
This thing, it makes no sense.
Except it was important to Q.
So, maybe it's important
we figure out what it is.
If we test him thoroughly,
and he's clean, he can come.
Hey, Fen. Yeah?
Can I ask you something? Yeah.
Um, lately I've just
been feeling a little bit off.
If we were on Earth, I'd
know what to do, but...
Is there, like, a magic
plant or something out here
that I can pee on
to find out if I'm...
RABBIT: Pregnant.
Shit.
Sorry. God, I don't know
why I'm crying. Just... Babies.
(EXCLAIMS AND CHUCKLES)
Um, do you know
what you're gonna do?
Um,
I'm not so sure.
Do you want me to
send a bunny to Penny?
Uh,
Penny and I are just...
We're sort of in
a weird place. Oh.
Actually, until I've had
some time to process, uh...
I'd really appreciate
it if we could keep this
between you and
I, please. Of course.
I'm really good with secrets.
I've kept Eliot's fear of
butterflies a secret for years.
Until now. Shit. (EXCLAIMS)
Sorry, I won't do that
with you. Pregnant.
Made macarons, mango yuzu
and matcha, anyone? Why?
For sustenance? You'll love
them. Nice try, Hoberman.
We're on mission. So,
no distractions. Out.
Sorry for interrupting.
Can you believe that guy?
What are you talking about?
You eat matcha everything.
Those macarons were a
trap. Josh is an emotional ninja.
He comes at you with sweets,
and then you just confess things.
So you're still avoiding that conversation
you owe him about leaving him in the past.
That is not going to be a good
talk, so we're not going to have it.
We have real
things to worry about,
like how you're going to find
out the Dark King's secret.
(SIGHS) And we can't enjoy
mango yuzu macarons
while we worry about that?
Never take the food, Eliot.
(SIGHS)
Which gives me an idea.
Seb? I brought you
something. (GLASS BREAKS)
DARK KING: Oh, boy.
Oh, my God.
Um, are you okay?
Six children.
Six children taken.
It's my fault.
If I had been there, I
could've stopped them.
Being a king,
nobody knows
what it's really like.
(SIGHS)
Seb,
do you think you
could ever step down?
I have to be King. You
don't have to be anything.
I could help you.
Eliot. I appreciate your concern
more than I can say.
This is my burden.
I can't leave. Is it
something we can fix?
A spell, or a curse
of some kind?
A choice I made a long time ago.
Tied to a conduit.
I thought it was the only
way I could save Fillory.
A conduit? What do you mean?
(EXHALES) It was a lifetime ago.
So many lifetimes ago.
We could just get out of here.
We could just go
camping, or, um...
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I'm sorry.
I forgot myself.
Look, Seb, we
can make this okay.
Perhaps we shouldn't
see each other again.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Sorry, Ray. Got to test you
for spine-burrowing spiders.
You know the drill.
Chew, don't swallow.
Your Primula scotica
isobelae is flourishing, Baxie.
BAX: Spit.
Everyone's panties untwisted?
Because it turned purple?
Purple is good, uncontrollably
shitting spiders is bad.
Ray, what do you make of...
(CLEARS THROAT) All right, Glasses.
I'm going to say a word that
you don't know. Phyllotaxis.
The arrangement of
leaves around a central stalk.
Oh-ho-ho, you're one of those.
Hmm, says the arrogant, dime-a-dozen
academic with a plant fetish.
But later, when you
recount how you told me off,
I'm sure you'll punch it up
to be more of a dick chop.
It looks chaotic, but it's not.
It follows a
mathematical sequence.
The leaves of this plant suggest
that its origin is exceptionally exotic.
Or it is just a made-up drawing.
To an amateur,
I could see that being the
easiest explanation, yes.
But, no, no. This has something.
Plants, they have a certain integrity
to them. Mmm, it's hard to fake that.
Do you think you
can identify it?
Only guy who can. Mmm, joy.
Would you be a
sweetie and get me
a spectral-reactive phytometer,
a Bertric lens
and a pamplemousse
LaCroix. (SCOFFS)
Happy to. No. If I
stay, I might kill him.
JOSH: The Dark King is
immortal because of a conduit?
Like a vitality conduit?
Do we know what that is?
I guess not.
It's an old naturalist ritual.
Draw life force from a stalk
of corn to fight a summer cold.
That sort of thing. Seb's
immortality comes from corn?
What about a tree? He
had a tattoo of one with...
Looked like maple
leaves, only more jagged.
Oh!
You can just talk.
That's a blackwood tree.
Okay, so, what if we locate the tree
from Seb's tattoo and chop it down?
Would that sever this
conduit? In theory, yes.
He would be mortal,
and 100% stab-able.
So, how do we find this tree?
Who has two thumbs and
aced their elective in dowsing?
Probably safer to
send two of us, though.
Just in case
something goes wrong.
Well, I'm a former tree goddess.
I'll go. No.
You can't go on a long hike
because you have the toe worms.
Oh, right. My toe worms.
I thought that was
just a wooden toe thing.
You thought wrong. There's a lot
of misinformation about toe worms.
I have them. Are you
gonna make me take a hike?
No. No worm-shame here.
Okay, uh, how about you, Margo?
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Could use your Centurion skills
with all the Takers out there.
If you do that, it'll just leave
me. And I kind of have a problem.
After our last talk, Seb told
me to stay away from him.
So I don't really think I'm in a
position to, you know, stab him.
Yeah, but what if he needs you?
You're his Magician advisor.
Fen and I will come up with a
problem that takes two Magicians to fix,
assuming our toes can handle it.
It'll be touch and go.
Okay, but what if the
Dark King can feel it
when we chop down the tree,
and we have to act quickly?
I just don't know how quick
I can be, given everything.
Don't worry. We'll make it work.
The fuck, Margo? You promised.
And I meant it. You won't
be the one to kill Seb, exactly.
Why are you being so
weird and tricky about this?
I thought I was clear.
Wait.
Mmm.
That is the worst mojito
I've ever had in my entire life.
That's because, not
a mojito. It's a potion.
I was going to explain before you
got all grabby. But I guess here we go.
Oh.
Seb needs to die. You
can't do it, but I can.
So, get ready to...
Ovary up, bitch.
(SOFTLY GASPING)
Margo, did we
just Freaky Friday?
Bax.
(GROANS)
What did you do to
him? He's fine. He's fine.
Give me my page back.
Look, I will buy it from
you. Name your price.
Put it down, now.
(GRUNTING)
(THUDDING)
(GASPING)
BAX: Holy shit.
I just pushed him. It
shouldn't have done that.
What the hell was that?
We need to seal this room.
Jesus, Bambi. That was
kind of non-consensual.
You drank before
I could explain.
I've been trying to figure
out how to help you.
This is the only
way I could think of
to keep your hands
clean of Seb's murder.
Except they literally won't
be. Those are my hands.
Look, you're the one
who can get close.
I'm the one with
the will to stab.
(SIGHS)
El, I love you, but we
have to do this thing.
Even you agree with that.
This is the best compromise
I could come up with.
So, listen up. This
spell's got a little quirk
you should probably know about.
Tell anyone we've swapped and
we won't be able to swap back.
Permanently. That
is good to know.
Strange. It's like you're
Eliot. But not Eliot.
Oh, my God, you're
seeing Charlton.
What kind of a name is Charlton?
Family name. I never liked it.
He lives in my
head... Your head.
And why is there a
man living in your head?
Charlton and I were
Monster victims together.
He stayed in my head when
you pulled The Monster out.
I held on real tight.
So if he's in your head,
why didn't he swap with you?
I have no idea. Honestly,
this is all very new.
I'd have given you a
heads-up if I'd known your plan.
Listen, Charlie, stay
the fuck out of my way.
Hey, Bambi, before you go
all Bambi and scare him off,
why don't you maybe
let him help you?
I've managed just fine without a
Tyler Durden on my cooch. Thanks.
I'm just saying, this Seb
situation is pretty complicated.
You're not exactly a
subtle relationship person.
From what I've seen, he's right.
You've got to ride a really
fine line with the Dark King.
He lost his love,
but he likes me.
So, that feels like a betrayal.
That is a lot of drama to track.
What about you and Josh?
Since I'll be going on a long
walk to cut down a tree with him,
is there anything I should know?
Yeah. If Josh tries to pull
you into any kind of talk,
just don't.
(SIGHS)
(MEN SNORING)
I was a little surprised to get
your message after our last convo.
I know things got complicated.
But circumstances have changed.
The castle has been struck
with a strange sleeping curse.
Is that what happened to...
Wow.
We've kept it quiet.
Obviously it requires
a magical solution,
but I'm afraid it's beyond me.
I think I know this curse.
Good news, there's a cure.
Only prob, it takes a bit
of cooperative spell work.
You need four
hands to do it. I see.
So, you want to solve this,
we're gonna have
to work together,
even if it makes you
uncomf or whatevs.
You sound strange.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I haven't been feeling
myself since our last talk.
Yes.
Let us work together to
solve this curious malady
for the good of Fillory.
That could have gone smoother.
(DOOR OPENS)
Sleeping pollen worked like
a charm. Or a curse, I guess.
Oh, Umber's balls!
Margo just keeps leaving
her uniform lying around.
Makes me feel
like a maid. Right.
Julia, let me take over.
Rest is good for the baby.
Not a baby. Still baking.
But it'll become a baby. You
do know how this works, right?
(SIGHS) Look, Fen. I
just want to live my life
without this defining
every aspect of it.
You get me? Okay,
well, if that's the truth,
then why haven't you
done something about it?
It's not a hard
procedure, even in Fillory.
You think I should abort it? I'm
saying you should make a choice.
You're letting something into
your life that you can't control,
and in lots of ways
will control you.
It'll make you happy
or devastate you.
Hey.
Look, I've been pregnant
before, and it was really bad.
And I knew this time if
I told everyone about it,
they'd get worried and
overprotective, and I...
I just wanted to take one
of the next nine months
to feel like maybe this time,
it wouldn't be so
terrible, you know?
Nine months? What...
What are you talking about?
It's Red Monkey Month.
Red Monkey what?
Everything goes faster
in Red Monkey Month.
Healing, crop growth.
Weirdly, not monkeys.
I'm sorry, are you saying that
my pregnancy is
going to be sped up?
Julia, it already is, as
long as you stay in Fillory.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
(JOSH BREATHING HEAVILY)
Get the fuck away
from me! What's wrong?
I thought I saw a butterfly.
You never know where
they're gonna go next.
Lavender rose macaron? I
know they're your favorite.
I'd better not. Margo,
it's a snack, not a trap.
You're a really good baker.
Also, taller from this POV.
I learned to dial in that recipe
while I was stuck in the past.
Fen had her
knives. I had baking.
Oh, yeah. That must have
been tough for you both.
It was, I mean...
Sorry, I didn't
mean to bring it up.
We don't have to talk about it.
Okay. How much further
you think... It's just, we thought
we lost you guys, and
it was a scary time, so...
So we must be getting
near Seb's tree, huh?
Are we really not gonna do this?
Look, I'd be lying if I
said that it didn't hurt
when you wanted to
abandon me in the past,
but I know it wasn't about me.
Still, Margo, I have to ask,
do you want to break up?
I mean, are we even a
thing that can be broken up?
I, uh...
What do you think?
Sometimes I feel like
that's what you want.
Look, when we got together,
I said I wasn't into games.
And do you remember
what you said?
Uh...
You said, "Fuck games."
(CHUCKLES) That does sound like me.
I can accept it's over if
you just say the words.
Josh, I want to talk, I
really do. But I can't,
except to say that maybe I need
a little more time to forgive myself.
Oh. Uh...
Really? Yes.
Because I've realized that deciding
to leave you in the past was a mistake.
A big one. And now I need
to earn your forgiveness,
which may take a while.
So we can kind of keep things
status quo in the meantime.
I... Sure, sure. Great.
Now, which way to the tree?
Uh...
(SIGHS SOFTLY)
BAX: I think Ray was
hosting a symbiote.
He was possessed? Not possessed.
It's rare, but a few fungus
species have been known
to join consciousness
with other creatures.
You're still you. You just
share brain power, thoughts.
And then you explode?
Well, I'm not a mushroom guy,
but I think that's because Ray merged
with the fungus a long, long time ago.
Is he... It... Shit, are
they dead? Ray is.
But those particles that came
out of him were fungal spores.
They'll want a new host body.
I sealed them inside the lab,
but it might be a good
idea to close the air vents.
Yeah, hi, new to this job.
I have no idea how to
control the school vents.
We need to evacuate. I knew I
should've trusted my instincts.
Hey. Hey, there's, um...
Eukaryotic phytosymbiont. Yeah,
there's a monster on the loose.
Head to the Physical Kids'
cottage to be quarantined, now.
Alice, give us the plant
page. And we'll stop spreading.
Whoa, whoa.
Okay.
New theory. The fungus
can spread to multiple hosts.
This might be a
zombie plague situation.
What? What?
(ALL YELP)
I say this as the man
who blew up my Brakebills.
You're the worst goddamn
dean we've ever had.
Yeah, I'm not here for a
lecture from my prisoner.
Just hiding from spores.
Oh, so you remembered that
this room is hermetically sealed,
but not to consult
the "Do Not Admit" list.
I did everything a
dean is supposed to do.
A dean is supposed
to have strong instincts.
Like knowing anyone who'd
visit Anansia is also insane enough
to visit other worlds with
infections for which we cannot test.
Do you want to help, or what?
Yes, I can provide a solution
in exchange for my release.
How do we know
you really have one?
I developed a potion
with a Dr. Maria Pilkin.
You can check with her,
but she died in this timeline.
No deal. We'll find our own way.
You cannot save your
students without my help.
See, in our timeline,
Pilkin's work was published
after her death.
So, it's in our library.
(PENNY INHALES SHARPLY)
Gave away your leverage.
Thought a dean was supposed
to have strong instincts.
I will get out of here,
and then, I'll turn you
into lobsters and eat you.
Okay.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(WHISPERING) Okay, the
book we need is right there.
See any twitching? Just
assume they're all infected.
And assume they're
all looking for us.
It's too risky for us
to go in together.
I know where it is. I'll go.
Hey. Remember, magic is
unpredictable outside the lab.
So, no phosphoromancy.
Good thing I have experience
being invisible from high school.
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
You got us the book and
a guinea pig. Nice work.
PENNY: It said the
potion should work fast.
(COUGHS)
ALICE: Penny. BAX: Oh, shit.
Penny.
Just give up the page, Alice.
Come on.
(MEN SNORING)
Almost ready. Great.
(SCOFFS)
Margo, you have to
draw this out, you know.
The second they wake,
Seb will dismiss you.
No shit, Sherlock. This is all
part of my plan to win him over.
How is finishing the ritual early,
and in silence, part of your plan?
Because I taught
it to him wrong.
So, to fix it, I'm gonna have
to get real close and personal.
(SCOFFS) Eliot?
Something in the middle
section doesn't feel right.
The energies aren't
moving as they should.
Mmm.
I can walk you through it.
Wait.
That's not right.
Here.
We should keep our distance.
It will make things easier.
Right. Of course.
If you need my help, just ask.
Jesus' clit! I know how
to work a guy, Charlton.
Yes, you do. Margo. But as
Eliot, you're coming on too strong.
Seb likes Eliot's
vulnerability. Don't be pushy.
Just open up.
He and Eliot are close
because of the losses they share.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I can show you the
rest if you're ready,
but first, I think I owe you an
apology. Eliot, that's not necessary.
It's just, I haven't felt this
way in a really long time.
I think the fact that we both...
It just felt safe with
you, you know?
On that mountain,
we both felt it.
There's nothing wrong
with wanting more.
I wish I could give you
more, but I just can't.
I must put Fillory first,
even if it means I suffer.
I do hope you understand that.
I get it. It's hard to be King.
People don't know
what you go through.
Now, let me show you
how to do that spell correctly.
Are we close to the tree?
I don't mean to rush.
You're the expert.
Okay, that's it.
I'm not buying it.
Not buying what? Any of this.
Emotional, agreeable,
patient? You're not Margo.
Who else would I be?
This is Fillory. I don't know.
You could be a hallucination,
or a shapeshifter, or an
agent of the Dark King.
But I'm not. Josh, I'm...
Shit. I wish I could explain.
Oh, well, until you do, I'm not
taking you to the tree. Got it?
The antifungal kind of worked.
We got the spores out of him.
Yeah, and into Penny.
It must be the fungus's
networking ability.
Long as it's alive
in other hosts,
it can still direct its spores
into whoever it wants.
So why not into us?
We were right there.
Uh, Penny was closer? I
thought you were an expert.
I told you this isn't my area.
At this point, my best advice?
Give the fungus
what it wants. No.
Ever since I found this
page, I knew it was important.
If the fungus wants it, I was
right. I have to know what it means.
Is it worth dying over?
Is that what Quentin would
want? For you to die too?
Back the fuck up, botanist.
Sorry. Maybe I
overstepped. It's just...
Remember that plant I put
on the window sill in the lab?
Yeah, you only
screamed at me about it.
Scottish Primrose.
It's this fragile little flower.
Even grass can kill it.
So it has to survive on cliff
walls where nothing else can.
It was my wife
Isobel's favorite.
Primula scotica isobelae.
You named it after her?
You remembered the name.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
She loved that stupid flower.
Kept it alive without
any spell work.
Huge point of pride that I
thought was just kind of silly.
Then she died. So
now I keep it alive.
If it's anything like that,
I get why you'd want
to keep that page.
How long ago?
Five years. You? A lot less.
So, how long until, you know, it
feels less like it's eating all of you?
I'm kind of still waiting.
I just feel like I'm going to be
this walking
whatever I am forever.
I did, too.
It starts like this tight
ball in your chest,
but over time, it gets lighter
because it just kind of
spreads into the rest of you.
It's like your own
personal symbiote.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah, kind
of. Except not murderous
and weirdly paper-focused.
Just, uh, sad.
Yeah.
Make it to a year.
It'll still suck, but
it gets quieter.
I promise.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Shit. I know what to do.
Damn.
I actually felt bad for him.
For what he's been through.
He's a nice man,
but an evil king.
It doesn't make
sense. He seems kind.
He seems sad.
Why the fuck would he summon
those monsters into Fillory?
Eliot, I think we're
finished. It worked.
Before you go,
perhaps we should talk.
I don't know why
he summoned them,
but I don't think we're going
to get another chance at this.
Not as easy as it
looks, is it? Josh, please.
Eliot's waiting for the signal.
If we don't chop down the tree,
he's screwed. We're screwed.
You said you wish you could explain.
That means there's something
to explain. So explain.
So you've been wanting to talk to me for
weeks about what happened between us.
But when I finally apologize,
you accuse me of
being possessed.
Right. Apologize. Does
that sound like Margo to you?
Fine! Maybe I was saying what you
wanted to hear 'cause you never let up.
You keep trying to get
me to talk about something
I don't want to talk about.
Okay, fine. I get that. You
want to know the truth?
You picked someone
who will never put you first.
There's no fixing
Margo. I mean, me.
Because chances are if I had to
relive it, I'd make the same decision.
So, stop asking me to apologize
for something I don't feel sorry about.
Now you sound like you.
Not that I won't feel
differently tomorrow.
No. You won't.
You're very clear.
The conduit tree's
that one over there.
Cut it down. I'll give
Eliot the green light.
Oh, God.
I'm fine here. Go help
the others search the castle
for any remaining victims
of the sleeping curse.
(DOOR CLOSES)
What you said last night,
did you mean it?
Um...
Oh, right. Eliot asked Seb if
he'd consider giving up the throne.
He even offered to help
him, but Seb said no.
Eliot? Are you all right?
Yes, sorry. Of
course I meant it.
Because I've been thinking...
Margo, the candles.
That's the signal.
They cut down Seb's tree.
DARK KING: Eliot?
CHARLTON: It's now or never.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Eliot should be done by now.
Well, they're in a hurry.
Oh, gods, we're in trouble.
Here, take my extra knife.
All the knives in the world
won't get us past the Centurions.
Do you have a better plan?
Are you under a hex? A
witch's spell? What's going on?
I can explain. Just...
There will be serious
consequences if I do.
No, you can't tell him,
Margo. You'll be stuck in there.
There will be serious
consequences if you don't explain.
(GROANS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
PENNY: You asked, and I'm here.
So, you gonna give up the page,
or make us spore you, too?
I'll give it to you
if you tell me why you want it.
It's an instruction
manual. For what?
The World Seed. It's a
magical botanical organism.
Legend is, the seed
is pure potential.
With the right nurturing, it
can grow into almost anything.
Even an entire world.
Well, if you want the page, does
that mean you already have the seed?
We're done talking.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
Alice, what are you doing to us?
Me? I'm just
keeping you talking.
All that shared brainpower,
and you never thought to
yourselves, "Where's Bax?"
(GRUNTS)
I mean, you had us
stumped for a while.
It seemed like if we
got you out of one host,
you'd just keep spreading
yourself to other ones.
But you didn't.
For some reason, you
were limiting yourself.
Some of your spores
didn't try to spread.
Bax wasn't sure why, because
fungi can typically grow and grow.
But you're also a
consciousness, like us.
And we have limits. Try to juggle
too much at once, and we're useless.
It's a professor thing.
WOMAN: What?
Just go with it.
ALICE: So I have Bax spreading
you too thin to affect your hosts
mentally or physically.
You won't be able to
control them anymore.
You're killing me.
No, don't worry.
You'll be a part of
your host forever.
You're just getting quieter.
(GASPS)
(CLEARS THROAT)
(GASPING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
This is the worst
fucking job ever.
Penny? Are you okay?
Found your page. Do you
know why you wanted it?
It's fading, but to sell.
There was this huge debt to pay.
I don't know what for, but
when the Couple came to collect,
we didn't... They didn't
ask any questions.
A couple of... No, the Couple.
Weird name, but I remember
feeling scared shitless.
The Couple has
power, it has resources.
It's been looking for the
World Seed page a long time,
and they are not good people.
And they know I
have what they want.
I don't think that's gonna be the
last person or thing to come after it.
What the hell was Coldwater
doing with instructions
to something so powerful?
Yeah.
I have no idea.
Jesus Christ, El,
you had one job,
don't blow up my relationship
with Josh. And what did you do?
I'm sorry, there was no way
to avoid that conversation.
He's just so goddamn persistent.
Tell me about it. By the by,
Charlton's gonna go hang out
in your beach
memories for a while.
Think the whole Seb
thing was hard on him.
So, um, what did you and Seb
talk about, you know, before?
Don't do this to yourself.
I ended your relationship.
Seems like I deserve
whatever pain's coming my way.
That wasn't your fault.
You were just dealing with some
shit I set up way before you took over.
So, in summation,
we're both equally skilled
at destroying our own happiness.
Yeah, well, at least we
used our powers for good.
How fucked up is
it that I miss him?
El, there's nothing
wrong with you.
He was hot and complicated.
Those are the
ones worth banging.
You've just had some shitty luck
with boys so far, that's all.
It doesn't mean you
don't deserve love,
or that you won't ever find it.
Well, at least I have
better luck with friends.
(GASPING)