Previously on
The Magicians...
So this book is used to help
me locate different worlds
via a cooperative spell?
Well, it is called
The World Book.
Okay, there's a spell in here that will
tell me where I'm supposed to go,
and I will stay there for good, okay?
Just let me help you.
This is just casual, right?
We're not...
I saved your life, bitch.
Casual that.
A talking lizard
of the Dunes.
Well, what's my birthright,
you scaly shit?
It's the talking animals.
They've all been struck dumb.
All those organs,
they're building blocks,
trying to piece together
a body.
Is it yours?
Eliot's alive. He's alive.
- So you're Team Monster now?
- I'm Team Eliot.
Your Penny's dead or not alive
in some confusing way.
- You're Kady?
- What's going on?
I'm not your Penny.
Marina.
I've been looking for you.
- Penny, right?
- I know you?
Ahh!
Well, it's about time
you woke up.
The hell?
I assume you remember
getting jumped.
Well, what happened next is you were sold
for 500 bucks and an Alpha Black Lotus...
Mint condish.
It's Magic: The Gathering?
Are you telling me that Magic cards
are actually magic?
No, just really expensive.
Excuse me.
Okay, you know this kid?
Not personally.
He's kind of a legend, though.
He's a horomancer.
You know, time magic,
fourth dimension shit.
Yeah, cool story.
Why am I in a cage?
Hey, Stoppard.
What is it you want, huh?
You want a spell? Deweys?
- Lose your virginity?
- You're not really my type.
Oh. Well, if he is,
you can totally have him.
That's... No, I don't
want sex or to hurt you.
I don't want any of that.
I just want you guys
to go back to your timeline,
where you belong.
Look, it's nothing personal.
Mmm. People in cages
is never not personal, sweetie.
You guys are creating
a frequency dissonance.
It's your quarks, subtle.
Most people wouldn't notice,
but what I do...
What are you doing?
You guys are
fucking up every spell.
Here's an idea,
adjust to our quarks.
They're subatomic.
How hard can it be?
Yeah, I tried that.
Didn't work.
So...
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
No, no, no.
- Welcome home, guys.
- Father fuck me.
That's weird.
It was just working
a minute ago.
Yeah, it's 'cause there was
magic in that timeline.
There ain't in timeline 23.
You gonna let me out?
Why would I?
You're a psychopath.
One, rude.
And, two, I know how to use that thing,
and you don't.
You're also
a compulsive liar, so...
Okay, well, you're
going to send yourself
to some cracked-out in-between space,
but whatever.
Don't screw this up.
Calm your man tits.
I got this.
Okay...
I thought you said
you knew how to use this thing.
Well, you should learn
to trust your instincts
about people.
Just relax, there's enough juice
in the Dewey for one more jump.
Let's just not use it
until we know how to, okay?
Sure, sure, cool, cool.
The vibe I'm getting
from this timeline is very 1984.
Worse. It's The Crucible.
I don't know, Q.
If we help him collect
his stone organ prizes,
we can get him out of Eliot.
It's a good plan.
Unless we help him build
a completely indestructible
titan god body.
Well, he's already pretty murder-y.
It can't get much worse.
You say that like we
can just risk people's lives.
We've taken down gods before.
And we end up
losing every time.
It's Eliot.
Right now we can't
fix everything, but
I think that we can do this.
Okay, for now, we help The Monster,
but at the same time,
we also figure out
what our next move's going to be.
Thank you.
I don't know.
I guess I'm just worried.
- I can't help you if you...
- You're helping a lot.
I was a goddess,
and now I'm just
your friendly neighborhood
bulletproof vest.
I mean, you would be
a very high level X-Man.
Mmm?
Like Emma Frost's
diamond form.
- Mutant.
- A mutant.
Like The Indestructress.
The page you gave The Monster,
you remember what it says?
We didn't have time
to decipher it all.
I mean, there were
a lot of hieroglyphs.
Okay, do you remember
what hieroglyphs?
So I'm thinking,
like, so...
We've got two stone things
covered in hieroglyphs,
neither of which came
from an Egyptian god, so...
- Who did the writing?
- And why?
Um...
There were a lot
of these ones.
- What is that?
- A lot.
A yellow fruit?
- Is there a yellow fruit god?
- I don't know.
I don't remember anything
from any class at Brakebills.
Ooh! "Recently uncovered
tomb changes much
"of what archeologists thought they knew
about ancient Egypt."
Maybe stuff Brakebills
didn't know about.
Worth a shot.
Why Modesto, Alice?
Still trying
to figure that out.
My life, that is.
Oh.
I like your bunnies.
They were my mom's.
Well, she had lovely taste
in glass animals.
No drugs, no booze,
no bullshit.
You want to smoke,
you do it outside,
and the rent is due
on the 5th.
- I understand.
- Okay.
I'll show you
to your room.
Oh. Um, just
one more question...
What is there to do
in, uh, Modesto?
Shit-all, really.
So then why is it here
if it's native to Loria?
We're unsure, but since
the return of magic,
the Atros flower has been found blooming
all over Fillory.
Its pollen is why
the talking animals can't speak.
Allergies are why
my birthright lizard ain't saying shit?
Wait, if the bunnies
can't talk,
that means that we're cut of
from everyone else back on Earth.
How am I going to remind them
to water my rosemary plants?
Or ask 23 to blip
our asses back.
- That, too.
- There is good news.
- We found a remedy.
- The juice from a beet
that grows on one of
the smaller fingerling isles,
Codswall.
Best known for their
inordinately polite alpacas.
- Alpacas can be supreme dicks.
- Great.
Get a ship to Cockswallow.
- Codswall.
Juice the beets,
distribute, done.
There's one small,
minute, trivial,
infinitesimally minuscule,
itty-bitty problem.
Lady Pike, who rules Codswall,
has been known to be, uh...
Difficult.
Are you saying she's a bitch?
Good thing I'm not
one at all, then.
Stop laughing.
That it?
Do you have any suggestions
on things to do
in or around Modesto?
Don't die of boredom?
I like your tattoos.
Mmm-hmm.
Hard getting by with
all those shortages, huh?
Yeah, maybe for
the classically trained.
Cockroaches like me,
we do what we got to.
Always have.
- Get over there!
- I didn't do anything.
They're just tattoos.
They don't mean anything.
Keep moving.
They are not
fucking around here.
Yeah, honestly,
I'm more concerned
about what my girlfriend
will do if I don't make it back
in time for her birthday.
You have a girlfriend?
As in a human
you give a shit about?
Yeah, and I'd rather not
lose her this time.
We were a thing back in timeline 23,
and I fucked it up.
You're telling me that you found
another one of her in timeline 40?
Yes.
And now that I know what she will
and won't put up with,
it's going so much
better this time.
- That's sociopathic.
- Dude, we're refugees.
We deserve any and all
advantages that come our way.
Yeah, like penthouse
apartments?
'Cause I don't know
any refugees that live like that.
You want that thing? You can have it.
It's way more trouble than it's worth.
Hey, crazy pitch...
What if we asked
Stoppard for help here?
Like the Stoppard
in this timeline?
Probably got burned
at the stake.
Okay, but if he didn't,
he has no beef with us.
We take the thing to him.
If anyone can fix it, he can.
There's so much terrible
about that idea.
Okay, do you know
another horomancer? No?
Then let's go.
Brothers and sisters,
when things are lost,
they want to be found.
Ms. Ross' engagement ring,
little Joey Mireles' dog...
That we will find the money
to pay for Kiersten Bron's
leukemia treatment.
- Tea?
- Uh, no, thank you.
Um, do you know
Reverend Ted Grayson?
Yeah, he's my minister.
He's a little theatrical at
times, but he's a good man.
Why, are you religious?
Not really. You?
No.
My mom was.
I was on probation
when she passed,
and the congregation
was there for me, so I still go.
Ah.
Look, I'm not good at
the whole back-and-forth thing,
so I'm just going to say it.
I saw you. I saw you
find the lock box.
You followed me?
How did you know where to dig?
No idea what
you're talking about.
How the hell
did you just do that?
Same way you found the box.
I'm a magician. Like you.
You had no idea,
did you?
That it was real
till you could do it.
You can talk to me.
To me, this doesn't even
count as weird.
It just started a couple
of months ago.
I lost my keys, and then all of a sudden,
I could just feel it in my head.
You're a quaeromancer.
It's really rare, actually.
I've never met one,
and I went to a school
full of people like us.
- Are you shitting me?
- Nope.
They can do
all kinds of things.
Most people don't figure out
their thing until their 20s,
but every now and then, somebody...
It takes them longer.
Have you told anyone?
They would
think I was nuts.
Honestly,
it's the best thing
that ever happened to me.
Do you know what I mean?
Well,
yes and no.
Sheila, I think you
might be why I'm here.
- Librarians.
- Librarians?
They can't know I'm here.
Please don't tell them.
Thanks, but I'm
not interested.
Sheila Cozener?
I'm Paul, this is Laurel,
and we'd like to talk to you
about an opportunity.
One involving
your newfound talents.
Sheila, I am telling you,
you can't trust the Library.
Okay, I know that they told you
they'd give you more magic
if you signed up for a Library card,
but they won't, okay?
The Library card is just a way
for them to keep tabs on you.
Alice, I get it.
You know, whatever run-in
you had with them
clearly traumatized you.
I don't know enough about any of
this to be signing up for anything.
You said that you were
in Modesto because of me.
Right?
What if it's because you're supposed
to teach me everything?
No. Knowing more isn't better.
How could it not?
Because it's powerful
and it can be really, really bad.
Okay, look, I'm a grown woman,
you're a grown woman, we make choices.
Is there something
I'm missing here?
Okay, listen,
I did a lot of stupid shit
when I was your age.
Yeah, so did I,
and magic made it
so much bigger and so much worse.
And if you regret it,
if you think about
those people that you hurt
and all that time
that you wasted every single day,
then I know how you feel.
Look, I hear you.
I get it.
But it's what we
make of it, right?
And for me, it's...
It's like the first time that I can,
you know, turn things around,
maybe do something good.
But I need you
to help me do that.
Please!
All right, we are going to
need to take this outside.
If you own the house,
why do you smoke outside?
I don't know, it's my
mother's rules, I guess.
Always seemed kind of wrong
just breaking them
'cause she was gone.
Come on.
Okay.
Let's start with Popper 1.
I'll make this simple.
We need your beets.
At a fair price,
of course.
I doubt the
island of Clitswell...
- Codswall.
- Anyway, I...
- Do you even know where Codswall is?
Of course.
It's one of the bigger...
Smaller fingering islands.
- Fingerling.
- Exactly. Fingerling.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
- For?
- Confirming my suspicion
that you've never had
consideration for us.
This makes my decision to sell
our beets to West Loria that much easier.
- Where the fuck is West Loria?
- West of Loria, Your Majesty.
- But since when?
- While you were Janet,
King Idri and his sister Ru,
had a squabble/slight war.
- Like a civil war?
- And as acting High King,
I asked myself, "What would
Margo or Eliot do?"
- Support our ally, Idri.
- Unfortunately, he lost.
Now Queen Ru rules
over West Loria.
And 'cause she's pissed we helped Idri,
she wants all Lady Pike's fresh beets?
Damn. That's cold.
Verily, they don't even have
talking animals in West Loria.
One problem at a time.
- The Cumdumpsterson twat...
- Codswall.
Oh, I know what I said.
I'm going to firebomb
the shit
out of her floating patch of dirt
and take her beets.
Bada-bing, bada-fuck her.
Could we be a tad
less incendiary?
Agreed.
What would Eliot do?
Eliot's not here, sweetie.
I am.
So, just to ask this,
can we really risk
war with West Loria?
Diplomacy was
Eliot's thing, Josh.
Diplomacy is what
got you elected.
I got elected because
I listened to a drunk bear
talk about his fee-fees.
- That's all diplomacy is!
- It was an accident.
I don't know how to intentionally care
about other people's shit.
Lucky for you,
that's all I do.
Fine.
One shot, Hoberman.
Hi, we're looking
for Stoppard.
Daniel, honey.
Come in before
someone sees you.
Amazing.
I haven't seen anything like this since
before the exclusion laws.
I have one of these!
And it's missing
a spoke like mine.
What are the odds?
Anyway, this one, it didn't
come with a manual.
Do you have any ideas?
Well, it's hard
to explain, but I think...
Daniel, something's not...
Mom? Mom, what's wrong?
Something's wrong
with the spells.
Hold on,
I'll figure this out.
Quickly, while he's busy.
Found an outdated copy
of Taussig's Primer and a VCR manual.
This place has shit
for helpful books.
Well, at least it's standing.
I cannot believe a bunch
of militant muggles
beat me to burning down
Brakebills.
- What's that?
- Oh. It was Sonia's.
- You mean Stoppard's mother?
- I mean Sonia Kikuno,
the genius who basically
pioneered horomancy.
This is easily one of the most
accidentally valuable things
I've ever stolen.
Here, look.
Wasn't that in
Stoppard's workshop?
Yeah. That screen
opens a window in time.
You can FaceTime
with the past as far back as 50 years.
It's genuinely genius.
Like, wow.
A lot of these spells
use cinnabar.
Hasn't that stuff
been banned for years?
Yeah, it causes severe
neuro-degeneration,
which is probably
what's happening with Sonia.
She's been
hitting the cinnabar
pretty hard for decades,
I imagine.
So,
she has
clockwork Alzheimer's?
Hmm, kind of,
but so much worse.
Your brain gets
unstuck in time.
You don't know
where you are or when you are,
and you can't
control it.
It is good, good times,
and then you die.
Yeah, but it seemed like
they had a treatment.
I mean, those weird watches
she had on?
Mmm, yeah, until
they got messed up
by us.
Must be
what started all this.
I mean,
back in timeline 40...
It's why Stoppard
hunted us down.
He's trying to save his mom.
Oh.
Now I almost
feel bad for him.
No, feel bad for us.
Even if we get back
to timeline 40,
Stoppard is going to do
anything he can to kick us out.
Unless we kill him.
For trying to save his mom?
Moms die every day.
Circle of life.
Wow. No!
We help him save her.
Am I just absorbing
a fuck-ton of cinnabar right now?
Yeah, and breathing it.
Great.
Let's finish this
and get the hell out of here.
- Sonia?
- Who are you?
Friends of Daniel,
who's grown now.
Listen, we need
to talk to you
about that cinnabar
that you're using. It's...
Frying my brain into
cheesecloth, I know.
Daniel used my designs to build
the device you're using.
We talked
a couple months ago.
If you were his friends,
you'd know that.
He asked you to stop?
Of course.
He also told me I'm about
to have a breakthrough
that creates
a whole new discipline.
I can't stop now.
My work's too important.
Fair point.
So you're just going to pick
your clock shit
over your own kid?
No, idiot. I choose both.
I designed devices
to counter the cinnabar,
tether my mind right here
with my work and my kid.
As long as I have these working for me,
I'll be fine.
I intend to die
a very old lady...
Sharp as a tack.
Fuck her.
It's not our fault.
She knew the consequences,
and she still licked her paintbrushes.
We go back to 40,
we're taking the kid's mom away.
- I'm not doing that.
- Well, I'm not losing
my life because some horo-bitch
is a shitty mom.
She's shitty
so he should suffer?
We're the ones
who don't belong.
You know what?
You do you.
I'm going back to 40
and my future wife.
Don't touch me!
Shit.
Okay.
Quick.
- Anything?
- Nothing yet.
Keep looking.
Quentin.
Whoopsies.
Are you drunk?
This body hearts tequila
when I'm happy,
when I'm sad,
when I'm bored
because everything is taking too long,
meaning you.
Relevant story.
I was in a road,
and I almost got hit by,
what do you call it, a big fat truck.
But I wouldn't have
felt anything at all
because tequila
is my friend.
Um, you know, great news,
we've made good progress
finding that part of yours.
Um...
You wouldn't still happen
to have the paper I gave you?
Oh... I misplaced it.
Do you know anything about
an Egyptian god
of yellow fruit?
I'm not at all helpful
like this, am I?
What do you think?
You seem stressed by your vast
and obvious limitations.
Why don't we just ask
someone who was there?
You know, for having
such desiccated hands,
his Hieratic script's amazing.
What did he say?
Cut our poor mummy friend
some slack, Hoo-lia.
He took a hook
to the brain.
Of course, he's got a bit
of a speech impediment.
Oh,
uh, the yellow fruit.
It's a mandrake root,
and we are looking for Heka,
the god of magic
and medicine.
It looks like he's got
one of your stones.
Let's go kill him.
He's already dead.
Looks like he was buried
in the Temple of...
Uh...
Esna?
Uh, which was
looted shortly after.
And where is it now?
My loot?
Yes, this is
very disappointing.
Figure this out
before I get mad.
This body craves
a cinnamon churro.
Um...
Bye.
- We can take a break.
- No, no, it's okay.
I want to keep going.
It bothers you, doesn't it?
That I'm so into this?
It just worries me.
For you, magic, you think
it just can fix everything,
but it kind of has a way
of breaking things.
Sometimes I feel like
everything that's gone wrong
in my life is 'cause of it.
Yeah, I used to say the same about alcohol,
about drugs, about money,
but none of that's
really good or bad.
It just is. It's how
you handle it, really.
Don't drink that.
The tap's got lead in it.
You got to drink the bottled water
out of the fridge.
- Why is there lead in the tap?
- City's pipes.
They're old and corroded.
Why don't they
just fix it?
That's cute,
that you think they would.
Asekian's Purification.
I can show you.
It's simple.
Can you do that
for the rest of the water supply?
No, or better yet, is there a spell
that would restore
- all the old pipes in Modesto?
- There is, but...
Okay, well, then do that.
Do it, please,
because you have no idea
how many people, how many kids are...
No, it's too big.
We can't do it.
There's not enough
ambient magic.
The Library,
it doles out the rest?
Wait.
You said that
they control the levels
of ambient magic that
flow through the pipes, right?
Yeah?
I can feel one.
They're everywhere.
No, no, no.
I think this one's different.
This one has a leak.
This isn't just food, Margo.
This is your secret weapon.
You can tell a lot about people
based on what they eat.
- Everything looks lovely.
- Thank you.
- Our chef is very...
- Talented.
Extra.
I'll take that
as a compliment.
Like I was saying,
is she reserved, adventurous?
Maybe she's sexy and decadent
like a truffle lobster
mac and cheese.
Oh, interesting.
Mongoose cream egg
with caviar. She's bold.
Proud of her accomplishments,
but being so driven
has led her to be
lonely, misunderstood.
- Mmm.
- Tick said something about Codswall's polite alpacas.
Maybe she's proud
of that. Ask.
I hear Codswall
has upstanding alpacas.
It is a misconception
that alpacas have behavioral issues.
The truth is, they have a lack of
self-esteem from years of shearing.
Imagine being stripped naked twice,
even three times a year.
There it is.
She's real into her 'pacas.
- Empathize with her.
- The indignity is real.
Like humans,
alpacas need affection
- and love.
- Preach.
You may not know this,
but I ran on a platform
of animal equality.
My administration
is the first
to give talking animals
their rightful voice.
I mean, that is why
we're here tonight, right?
The animals.
I just care so damn much.
I like to drink my tea
with a splash of alpaca milk.
Would you like some?
Uh, you can't
refuse this, Margo.
It's straight from
my dearest Delilah's teat.
Uh-huh.
Do it, Margo.
Now!
Yeah, good.
You are a champion.
You can really
taste the love.
What a beautiful way
to say it.
I'm afraid I may have judged
Your Majesty too quickly.
Same.
Which is why I would love it
if we could start fresh.
Your beets...
Unfortunately, I have
already agreed
to sell my beets
to West Loria,
and being a woman of my word,
I can't go back.
You understand, right?
I'm going to
check on dessert.
I'm about to
skin a bitch.
I want you to double down
on the charm offense.
You got her eating out of
your extra-diplomatic hands right now.
I guess I could lube her up
some more about her alpacas.
Yes, exactly. You, High King
Margo fucking Hanson,
you got this.
I know you didn't think
you could do this,
but, honestly,
I think you're out-Elioting Eliot.
Oh! Strawberry ricotta soufflé
is done. I'm gonna get that.
You get back to winning
at High King-in'.
- Margo, what are you doing?
- Being the real me.
Let me tell you how this
is going to play out, lady.
You're going to give me
those beets,
and I'm not going
to skin and eat
any of your tasty alpaca
children, capisce?
That's what I thought.
What in the hell?
Hi.
I can't begin to imagine
how you fucked yourself
hard enough to get here, but...
...let's take advantage.
Interesting choice
on the hair.
Says the guy dressed
like an ambulance chaser.
- So you're dead me.
- Technically.
Does this mean
I'm dead, too?
No, no, this is a, uh,
kind of between space?
I saw you zapped yourself
here like an idiot,
and I took
a coffee break.
I mean, I've been
wanting to talk to you.
So then I assume you know
that I took your...
You took my spot
in my timeline? Yeah.
Didn't expect that twist
with Julia, though.
Yeah, I could say
the same about Kady.
For what it's worth,
it never felt right taking your place.
- But, you know...
- Everything feels wrong,
so you just pick something?
Yeah, of course I do.
Real talk...
You gotta go back.
To 23, I know,
I'm working on it.
Uh, no. My timeline.
It's where you belong.
Okay, do you want
to cut the vague,
omniscient Librarian shit
and just tell me why?
It's complicated but crucial.
You do know
me existing there
is making some very important
horomancer lady very sick?
It's doing a lot more
than that.
Look, I know you lost
everyone you love in timeline 23...
Really?
But they're still alive
in timeline 40,
and if I were you,
which I am,
I'd do whatever
to not lose them again.
Okay, you might be me,
but you don't know me, okay?
Those shits are not my people.
Fair, but I know a little
about your future.
Perks of the gig.
So is being an abstruse dick
about it, apparently.
Sonia can't be saved.
Even if you go back to 23,
she's dead within a month.
It's terminal. Period.
Sounds like something I'd say to
make myself feel like less of an ass.
Bigger things at play
than your guilt, buddy.
You got to go back. Sorry.
That's as specific
as I can be.
Sorry? Are you?
Dude, I just jumped you clear
over 1,000 miles of bullshit.
So I'm sorry if it feels bad
in your soft little heart,
but, more importantly,
you're welcome.
But Kady wants you.
They all want you.
It's not
my timeline anymore.
It's yours.
So, you remember
that when the moment comes,
I said, "Do it."
Do what
he says, okay?
No, not okay.
Vague as shit.
To go back to 40,
you're gonna want to
turn this dial
three clicks to the right.
Tell Kady I love her,
and I'm sorry.
Well, thank Christ.
I thought you pissed off without me.
- Where'd you go?
- It was, uh...
I honestly don't know
how to explain it.
But I know what
we got to do now.
It's here.
Oh, God.
You were right,
there's a crack.
I think it could split the pipe open
and let more ambient out.
Here.
Once you pour it
down the drain,
- it should clean the water...
- Okay.
...and clear the corrosion
from the pipes.
Did I do something wrong?
Huh?
No, I just...
I can't remember the last time
that magic wasn't the problem.
This calls for
a drink.
Thank you.
Look, we'll find the stone. It'll be...
What are you doing?
Stop.
Jesus.
Those pills
can kill you.
I'll take a new body.
I'm bored.
You kill Eliot, and you can forget
about us helping you.
Eliot, Eliot, Eliot.
Why do you care
about him so much?
Because I do.
You kill him,
and we are done.
I swear to God,
I am serious.
I will abandon you,
and I will die trying
to burn you to the ground.
That's cute.
But I'm strong...
And you're weak.
Break my bones,
and strangle me.
Too tired to care anymore.
Q.
You hurt him,
you take one more pill,
and you can build your body
on your own.
Fine.
I'll take better care
of the meat suit.
But you don't have to be
such a baby about it.
Hey, what happened
with the game plan?
Margo, are you okay?
You stupid, stupid prick.
How dare you say
I out-Elioted Eliot?
Tell me. Hmm?
Why would I ever want to do
anything without him?
Hey, I'm sorry.
I should have known
how you were feeling.
Why? Because I like fettuccine
and I hate rosé,
you think you know me?
You don't, Hoberman.
Because if you did,
you would know
I don't need a new
partner-in-crime.
That's not...
I was just trying to help you.
Bullshit.
Now, I may be a cunt,
but I am real.
You? You're just
a brown-nose sweater boy
desperate to matter at all
to anyone.
Wow.
And here I thought
I was being
a friend who wants
to be your boyfriend.
I really, really
got to work on the signals.
- Josh, I didn't...
- You didn't mean to hurt me?
Yes, you did.
Believe it or not, I know
exactly who you are, Margo.
Took you long enough.
I nearly gave up on you
making it back.
Yeah, well, magic was
a little scarce in your timeline,
so it took a minute
to rebuild.
- Where's Marina?
- With her girlfriend.
Listen, kid, we know you're trying
to look out for your mom.
We get it.
You saying you'll leave?
Bigger things at play here.
Sorry, man.
I'm not going anywhere.
- Is that...
- Yeah.
- It's from another timeline.
- Please. Don't blow on it.
If you blow on it...
It'll spread seeds everywhere,
root itself in this timeline,
making it impossible for you to clean?
I know,
which is why I scattered
about 10 of them an hour ago.
I'm sorry.
Hey!
What are you waiting for?
It's clean! It got fixed!
I'm serious!
Come on,
don't waste it!
Whoo!
You can go on ahead
if you want to.
I'll meet you
back at the house.
You sure?
Yeah, I'm gonna
stick around a little while.
All right,
I'll see you later.
- Thanks for calling me.
- I knew you'd want to know.
- I owe you.
- Nah.
This is for all of us.
Sheila Cozener?
You've been a busy girl.