Previously on
The Magicians...
I need your help.
Those who go into the Mirror World
rarely find their way out.
- Who's in the Mirror World?
- My daughter.
What you need to do
is pull her out.
I might have something.
It turns an ordinary object
into, sort of, a beacon.
Thank you, Alice. Truly.
There was some fallout
from your tracker coins.
Several hedges died.
Today we learned
the true danger we're in.
What about Penny?
He still, uh, sweating you?
He's not sweating me.
I was a goddess,
and now, I'm just
your friendly neighborhood
bulletproof vest.
It would be
best for you
that you make this state
you find yourself in, temporary.
Have any advice
on how I do that?
You must seek the Binder.
A monster possessed you
- and is inhabiting your body.
- What?
There's a door hidden deep
in a forgotten remembrance.
Q, it's me. It's Eliot.
I'm alive in here.
Tell me my destiny.
A moment will come to protect
the future of Fillory.
A moment to stand beside
the High King
and then dethrone her.
Take her crown, Fen.
Even if that means
drenching it in her blood.
Hedge witches of the world,
this is your wake up call.
The Library
has turned the flow
of ambient magic
down to a trickle.
We fight for scraps.
It's time to cull the herd.
Defend yourself. Go on.
Throw something at me.
Cast anything...
This is what the worm does.
Try to remove it, same effect.
We will find you.
We will infect you.
You've been warned.
Stop doing magic.
It's not for you.
Fuckers call
themselves "Serpent".
Branding's a 'B' minus,
but they are
very much for real.
Wards are no help.
Last guy was attacked
in broad daylight
in his own kitchen.
Kady, it's Alice.
Can you let me in?
I'm just here to talk.
Oh, good. So, you don't
need the crowbar.
Hi. Go to hell. Bye.
Wait, no, I'm coming in.
So, hit me, or hear me out.
You're trying to
fight the Library.
Yeah, no, I'm not.
They're calling you the new Marina.
Actually, they are
calling you that.
Mostly even in good terms.
Hi. Listen,
we're not trying to step
on the foot of big government.
We're just trying to,
you know,
not die.
But you are doing something.
And I was inside
the Library, okay?
I can help.
Look, I've been
on an apology tour.
Would you like to
hear my speech?
No.
Why do you want to help?
None of us
went on that quest
so good people would
have to be slaves
for the Library
just to get a little magic.
I wanna fix it.
At least help.
I feel better.
So, we're having a crisis.
You can help, you can stay.
Damn.
Hi, my name's Pete,
by the way.
I had no idea hedges
were taking it this far.
So, the Library
turned down the ambient.
- Is that how this started?
- They did more than that.
Mandatory cards, bans,
meters in houses...
And, I've seen those.
What's your plan?
We know this will
keep happening
if everyone's starving.
I helped open
a pipe in Modesto,
but we can't get
anywhere near that right now.
That was you?
Do you have any...
What I... We didn't
blow anything up,
and we definitely didn't know
anybody else would.
You're right.
You can't just open one.
You have to open 50, 100.
Everywhere. You'd need a...
You need a map
of the entire system.
We're listening.
Junction boxes.
Drop a tracer.
Follow the pipe.
Map the system.
Look for weak spots.
Spots with the most magic.
Great, how do we
find a box?
Oh, the one person I knew
who could help us,
the Library took her.
Okay, so, we need another way
to get at a box.
We need a mole.
Recruit a mole
inside the most powerful
institution in the multiverse?
Sure, why not?
Stop doing magic.
It's not for you.
Is this even
a Library matter?
Hedges murdering each other
in the streets is a security concern.
Can we use
the tracker Deweys?
They stopped using those.
They're not idiots.
Just psychopaths, then.
So, we continue to
do nothing till what?
They start putting blood worms
in card-carrying magicians?
We need a
middle-ground solution.
Temporary cure.
Reed's Mark.
I fail to see how hedges
will interpret
such as empathetic.
Agreed.
They might feel we're
taking away their defenses.
Well, get a blood worm
and cast, you boil alive.
So, there's that.
Reed's Mark
would prevent them
from triggering the parasite,
even accidentally.
I'm barely aware half the time
I cast little things.
Still, they'd never
submit to it.
It would be voluntary.
For those already infected,
and those living in fear.
No paperwork,
no questions asked.
Then once this Serpent group
have been dealt with,
the mark is removed
free of charge.
Sound. I second.
Those opposed?
Motion passed.
Reed's Mark it is.
Anyone can be turned
with the right leverage.
It'll have to be
someone high up in the Library.
Everyone's got
a weak spot.
Mom, what's wrong?
What do you mean, inside?
Text me a picture.
Guys?
- What the fuck is going on?
- What is she saying?
What?
What do you mean,
you're in pieces?
- Guys, I think we have our leverage.
- Okay.
How is it possible?
- Is it shards?
- No. It'll add up to the real her.
The beacon summoned
the true Harriet.
It's just she's been
in the Mirror World so long.
It's a crazy place.
Something must have
happened to her
and shattered her
into three pieces.
And you,
your mother, and I,
we were the ones
that made the beacon,
so, a part of her
came to each of us.
So, what do you want?
The nearest
pipe junction box.
Why would I ever...
After Modesto...
Because you
want your daughter.
Look, we are trying to stop
what's happening out here.
More magic will lower
the body count,
or this situation you created
blows up into a full-on war.
You put more out
there for anyone...
Hedges have
always self-policed.
I consider it my
full-time responsibility.
You have my word.
Your proposal is very risky.
So is putting
Harriet back together.
But I can do it.
Can you?
I can fix her.
If you give Kady the box.
Fine, we have a deal.
A moment?
It's urgent. Sorry.
We'll give you a moment.
Alice, walk with me.
A few details.
An entire safe house?
In 10 minutes,
everybody was infected.
Half of them are dead.
We have to find that guy
in that stupid mask.
Now. Okay,
start some locators.
Casting spells in the current
socio-political climate is...
I much prefer
option 'B', which is,
this guy gets Reed's Mark
and waits until
this mushroom cloud dissipates.
You can't be serious.
I can't believe you're not.
I got your back,
but I would prefer to do that
in one solid non-crispy piece.
Give me a day.
That's hot,
that's hot, that's hot.
So, we're looking
for what, exactly?
Any reference
to the annoyingly vague
message the dragon sent me.
"Seek the Binder."
I hate riddles.
But if it could
jumper cable her, then...
In "D&D", a Binder's, like,
a low class level of...
- Announcement.
- Damn it.
The stone from your dragon
person is 100% god piece.
That is good news.
No.
The good news is
I can feel how many
pieces are still missing.
Any guesses?
The answer is one.
Only Enyalius stands between
me and anatomical perfection.
Find him and bring me
the final piece.
Cheesy puffs?
Um...
I guess we switch tracks
to find Enyalius.
It's not gonna be easy.
He knows we're looking.
A lot of gods kind
of have signatures. Um...
Ways to look for them,
whether they mean to or not.
So, we research and,
while we're there,
we solve this Binder shit.
Are we taking
our snacky friend?
Since I have no other way
to motivate you
than this meat sack,
know if you take too long,
I'm going ice cave climbing
with no clothes,
until this body
freezes forever.
Stop changing
the subject. The Napster?
It's odd.
Not only is the Great Snow
100 years early, when it sings,
it's in soprano.
Fascinating.
Can you tell me
what the cat lady
said about
my destiny lizard?
Well, the message
was very unclear.
You were mind melding
for 12 hours.
Uh, she's very mercurial.
Josh, hello!
Hi.
Glad you're back.
Talking points up the waz.
Here's number one.
Eliot! Alive.
- What?
- Yeah.
Q sent a troop
of these cuties to exposit.
Eliot's alive,
albeit in mind-prison,
while The Monster
controls the joystick.
Talking point dos.
Thank you.
A wild Fillorian clock tree
has sprouted up,
leaving a village
stuck in time.
It's been a total
clockster fuck.
No? Nothing?
Okay, anyway,
with the ambient being so low,
that's the latest on
the magical weirdness list,
which is getting long.
- We should call the Council.
- Step ahead of you, sister.
In my official capacity
as pinch-hitter
and fill-in crown-wearer,
I planned a state dinner.
Nothing brings
peeps closer together
to solve a global
catastrophe like good eats.
Margo, you're gonna wanna
see the guest list.
Q is positive he's
alive in there?
Yeah.
Aww.
Oh. Oh!
I'll just
go now.
That was the most...
Thorough sex
I've ever had.
So, I'll see you
when I get back.
Uh, uh. But the royals
are arriving.
- And I have to go save Eliot.
- How?
Or, is the idea to
be a friend by dying?
Uh-huh. Don't make
a sorry dumb gesture.
Will you just stay
for the feast?
I invited the Foremost.
Foremost what?
He leads
a nomadic tribe that,
according to my apricot guy
who's tight with
their agave trader,
was once ravaged
by body-possessing
demonic spirits.
And?
And in act three of the movie,
the Foremost saved them
with special weapons
that expel possession.
You're shitting me.
Nope, that's the one thing
we didn't just do.
They call them ice axes,
and I'm assuming
that's poetic license.
So, we might have
a chance to save Eliot.
Yeah.
Keep it up, Josh.
I'm gonna go get dressed
for the banquet.
"Keep it up, Josh."
Phew.
Okay, fine. I'll bite.
- What's the paper?
- Perhaps, you've heard.
There's a wave of
hedge witch terrorism.
- Is it a wave?
- Depends on who you ask.
Certainly, The Librarian
who requested
a list of rejected students
had an opinion.
What? They asked
for a watch list?
Of potential hedges, yes.
Everyone has a line, Alice.
Apparently, mine is
turning over a list
to what's starting to feel
like a goddamn
totalitarian regime.
Who knew?
I have to resign.
Well, since you've grown
morals apparently,
I have an alternative.
Set myself on fire?
Tempting.
Sack up and stay here,
where you can do an ounce of
good and protect the list.
I'm old. I'm tired.
- I have no way to protect it.
- Had no way.
Zelda is outside,
and she needs your lab
and a whole lot of magic.
And most importantly,
your secrecy.
Why should that come cheap?
Go talk to her,
while I research.
Binders
of various types.
The word "Binder" is
in a ton of actual titles? Huh?
Google "The Binder,"
120 million hits.
You think that dragon's
trolling me?
Anything new on Enyalius?
'Cause I got a
fresh take on that.
Let's find him,
get his rock,
destroy it before
the Monster comes back.
Oh, I love it.
Ah.
Except for the part
where it doesn't save Eliot.
We'll figure something out.
We always do.
No, bro.
Take it from someone
from a timeline
where you did not
figure it out.
We'll find Enyalius first.
I'm not talking
about this now.
But no one
made it out of that expedition alive.
Have you ever
wondered about your past lives?
If you have long-lost loves
or suppressed memories...
Memories.
...search no further.
Thank God for
priority overnight.
I'll send your mom
some chocolates.
She'll like that,
if they're made of wine.
Traveler's blood?
Once it starts,
I'll have to seal the lab
and you'll both
have to wait outside.
Bjorn's Electromagnetic
is unstable.
Good thing
I'm a phosphoromancer.
- Okay, we're about ready.
- One thing.
The Harriet that came
to me was exaggerated.
It seems
when she fragmented,
so did her personality.
Just be aware.
Thanks.
But I'm more concerned
with getting them out quickly
to the same place, so we can
reunite them at all, so...
Now out, both of you.
Just don't fuck yourself up
too much, okay?
You punched me in the face.
Don't die.
Shit, it overloaded!
I have to fix the prism.
What are you doing?
No, we don't have any time.
We're running out of ambient.
I don't understand you.
Look, I have to do this now.
Oops. You fucked that one up.
Interesting application.
But I can improve on this.
Okay, but we have
to fix this now!
- No, we have time.
- No, we don't.
Don't be
such a scaredy bitch.
- I'm not.
- Ah.
That's what you are.
You're the mouse inside me.
I get you promised to fix her,
but honestly, I don't see the point
in putting us back together.
You're absolutely worthless.
You can go now.
Give that back
to me right now!
No. I wanna play with it.
- Give it back. Give it back, you arrogant bitch!
- Mmm-mmm.
Oh, my God, your stupid face.
You're gonna destroy
everything again!
She's dangerous. I had to.
I need to. Just wait.
Move!
That bitch.
Hello? Hello!
God damn it.
Margo will want
those by the throne.
And you go
to the wine cellar.
- Oh, hi. You must be looking for the...
- Fen.
My name is Ru.
Queen of West Loria.
I'd like a private word.
Leave us.
What was your creature?
There's no sense
in denying it.
The thing told me
its sister visited you.
My prophecy was concise.
For the health of my land,
I must aid you
in dethroning the High King,
violently if necessary.
I see yours lines right up.
Look, Margo has
a reputation, but...
Gods, don't tell me
you're friends.
No, no.
But I've thought about this
and realized my,
our job here, is indeed to do
what's best for our lands,
and that's just not
necessarily...
You're about to speechify
on fighting one's destiny?
No, no, no, no. Um...
On listening to one's guts.
I'm willing to forge
a peace with Fillory
once you take the throne.
Then and only then.
Wow. Okay.
I'm just saying,
there are so many paths...
During the feast,
you will order the castle doors open
whereupon my men will enter
- and chop off her head.
- Enjoy the dessert course.
Did you really think
I was gonna say that?
Hoped.
A ruler never walks away
of their own accord.
They must be crushed.
Now, I don't relish this,
but we are responsible
for our own kingdoms.
There is but one alternative.
Everlasting banishment.
But that's a form of death.
You have until dinner
to decide.
Or I'll be forced
to see to it
that your head joins hers
in the basket.
Quentin. Hoolia.
Whatever your name is.
I have the most perfect idea.
Um, who is that?
Is this a game, or...
Are you aware that
there's big money for psychics
who are in actuality
big, giant fakers?
I had to try 19
before I found a real one.
Allan,
you're going to
help me so much.
Help you with what, exactly?
Remembering my past life.
Could you guys
make me a snack?
We'd like some privacy.
Is that gonna be okay?
This guy's mind
better be strong as hell,
'cause if it gets
too hot in there...
Oh, boy.
Attention, customers.
Clean up in the baby food aisle.
You forgot the chips.
There's no pulse.
Relax. It's fine.
I'll get another one.
No, it won't work.
You're too strong.
Fine, I'll get
a strong one.
You're upset.
I'll get this gross corpse
out of your sight.
See you when I find
a new psychic friend.
Wait. I can help.
I know a psychic with
a real strong mind.
Penny, don't.
Who?
Me.
No.
Just... You say no,
and then no?
Cute, you wanna make this
about me being bossy,
but we both just saw
that guy die.
I'm not that guy.
I studied this.
I had The Beast in my head.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm glad that you care.
Ha-ha. But I actually do.
Ha-ha.
But I actually get that.
And I'm being serious.
So, how about this?
If I don't die,
I can take you out for a drink.
What, are you kidding?
That's something that
regular people do.
Yeah, fuck it.
Okay, try this.
Live,
and you can buy me dinner.
That was fun.
It took a lot of rocks
to sink the body.
Ready to get started, Percy?
Okay.
So, why are we here?
It's important.
Not sure why.
That's okay.
This field,
was there a house,
or anything else here?
No. Nothing.
Wait. An altar.
And some bowls.
Good. Think about the bowls.
Anything inside them?
Stones. The stones.
The ones they put
part of me into.
But not yet.
They're still empty.
And rope.
- Lots of rope.
- Nothing here can hurt you.
- They said they were scared of me.
- Who?
Bacchus. Iris. Heka.
But they needed Enyalius.
They couldn't do
it without him.
I know what they did
for Enyalius to make him come.
There is a girl
near death.
She was their sacrifice.
Stop him.
- Stop him.
- I can't.
Everything that is happening
has already happened.
He called me monster,
but look at him.
He loved it.
The scent of a dying girl.
Some god of war.
He only liked them
when they were too weak to fight.
You're not strong,
Enyalius.
You're a sad,
perverse little...
Why is this
making me so upset?
Maybe there's more here.
Keep watching.
He's bleeding. Should we...
No. He said to wait
as long as possible.
One more minute.
Hi. Thank God
you saw the door.
No. It's me, it's me.
It's the real me. It's Eliot, okay?
This is a mind palace situation
and we don't have a lot of time,
and I have some extremely
major shit to tell you.
Maybe there's more.
What is it? What is it?
Traveler.
But it is only
a matter of time
before he remembers it,
too, okay?
- So, you have to...
- Percy 23?
- Shit.
- Go, go, go, go.
Percy 23. Percy 23.
- Percy 23.
- Right here.
Where were you?
- I was just exploring.
- What did you see?
Nothing. There's nothing
else here.
If you are lying to me,
I will have you flayed.
Shit.
Penny!
That was helpful.
Tell him I said thanks.
I know just who to find
exactly to Enyalius' tastes.
We're going to find him,
and I'm going
to be whole again.
This is a great day.
Penny.
Would you care for a pipe?
We're a lot alike,
you and I.
My mother was
a hedge witch, too. She died.
I was 10.
- I didn't know you were a hedge.
- Oh, yes.
My mentor, Everett,
found me,
sounds dramatic,
in an alley.
Gave me shelter, education,
believed in me.
I will never need
to do those things again, but...
My choices now seem
worse.
That's why
I agreed to give you
the location of
the pipe junction.
'Cause someone
gets hurt regardless.
Because I know
you'll work to
keep things fair.
Safe.
And you know this how?
Because we both
had shitty moms?
Because you have the capacity
to sit with the woman who caused
the death of the man you love.
To try and understand her.
So, I have faith
you'll make choices
that hurt the fewest people.
Okay, look, you can fix
a prism with Strand's Vitrum.
Right, but do we need
to adjust the refraction angle
for a break, or...
I don't understand
sign language!
Okay.
You have to adjust,
of course.
We need to cut a new prism.
I don't know
what you're saying!
No! You don't know!
She destroyed my life with her crazy ideas
and her insane confidence.
God damn it.
Hi again, bitch.
What do I do? What do I do?
- I do Strand's Vitrum.
- Cut a new prism.
- Combine Gentileschi...
- Doesn't matter, though, because you're...
- I'm not.
- You're frozen.
You move one hand to fix it,
and you freeze.
You need to let me
out of here.
- But what you wanna do...
- What you actually deserve.
Maybe I do. Maybe I'm just
too much to live.
But the fact
of the matter is,
if you throw one tiny piece
of magic in here,
it bounces,
and we both vaporize.
Yeah, well, don't be so sure.
I hate that idea.
You can't. See?
You need me.
You, you're an egomaniac.
- You only care about yourself.
- Someone had to.
No one else gave a shit.
Because you alienated
them all.
Our IQ did that.
Your arrogance. Oh.
"I'm so smart. Look at me."
"Love me, love me.
I won't exist unless you love me."
"I'm so sorry I'm smart.
It's not you, it's me.
"I'm so sorry."
Right.
That's exactly why
you destroyed the keys,
because you're such a
goddamn genius.
I didn't do that. You did.
- That's bullshit!
- No.
My arrogance didn't destroy
the stupid keys.
Fear did. You did.
You ruined my life.
We did that together.
You're right.
I can't fix the prism.
Because it's a big swing
and it might blow up,
and that's my thing?
Do you wanna know what
the biggest swing there is?
Us agreeing.
Self destruction would be
a sad waste of both of us.
'Cause we still have no idea
what we're actually capable of.
That scares me, too.
Does it scare you so much
you'd just rather never know?
Just leave me in here to die?
And you go live
your ordinary waste of a life?
Well, that's not weird at all.
Does that say "Binder"?
- Isn't Julia looking for...
- But we shouldn't.
Clearly, it wants us to.
Let's not get
precious about it.
All right, let's fix
this fucker.
Okay, are you ready
to pull yourself together?
Red alert.
So, there is a
palace coup underway.
Fen is planning
to defenestrate you.
It's a destiny thing.
That balsa-toed bitch.
I'd like to see her try.
Quick. Where's the Foremost?
Not here yet, I guess.
Hold off the traitor
till I talk to him.
- Then let her come.
- Okay. Great.
Stand here, so,
Fen can't see me.
She's trying to overthrow me.
It's a long story
and I'm handling it.
Where is the Foremost?
Leader of the Southern Nomads?
Wandering in the south,
I imagine.
He and his axes are supposed
to be here, Tick.
But he'd never come to this.
Oceans of apology, Majesty,
but the Foremost
is a sworn enemy of Fillory
and will not interact
with her citizens.
Much less High King.
You're joking.
But this whole...
I need him, Tick.
For Eliot.
Oh, I see.
How can I assist?
Would you like me
to travel to the South
and use false Lorian papers
to seek an audience?
The Pickwicks are
a notoriously thirsty people,
making them ill-suited
for the desert,
and I have a violent
allergy to the sand.
And of course,
I'm not a magician.
But if it helps,
it would be an honor...
I get it. It's a job
for a tough bitch.
So, it has to be me.
Oh, thank you.
I would have died.
Oh, please.
You by any chance seen Margo?
Oh, my semi-girlfriend who saved
my life and is also a great King?
No. Why?
No reason. Just, uh...
Oh.
Actually, uh,
I have to go sneeze.
- Can we talk?
- Do it.
- Excuse me?
- Fen.
Do it.
I don't understand.
Overthrow me right
the fuck now, Fen.
- I never should have...
- Or I will never forgive you.
And neither will Eliot,
if you keep me from getting
the one thing that can save him.
Um...
Excuse me.
I need a word with the guard.
By order of High King Fen,
Margo of tribe Hansen
is forever banished,
never again to step upon
the soil of Fillory,
never again
to breathe its air,
or feel its magic.
Oh, get on with it.
Son of a pig fucker.
Perfect words to
remember you by.
Wait!
I curse Fen's name.
But if I were you,
I'd listen to her!
And wait!
Be nice to her!
Your grandkids'
grandkids will fear me!
Margo, wait!
Five seconds. Please.
Look, I should go with you.
Josh, I can handle my shit.
What I can't handle is Fillory blowing up,
so, please just help Fen. Okay?
Okay.
For your journey.
Just a few simple fig apricot saffron
cardamom vanilla plum danishes.
They'll keep.
So, and a new map.
Very helpful.
Also, fully charged.
When the going gets tough,
tough listens
to pop anthems from the '80s.
- Josh...
- Just a thought. Never mind.
You're a good man.
Oh.
Okay, I'm gonna try
and live through this
'cause it's feeling like
we got some more banging to do.
It does, right?
But don't wait for me, Hoberman.
Let's be realistic.
Totally. Totally.
I'm probably going to wait for you, though.
So, sorry.
Don't be a fool, Josh.
Now, there's
no looking forward
Now, there's no turning back
When you say
We belong to the light
We belong to the thunder
We belong to the sound of
the words
We've both fallen under
Whatever we deny or embrace
for worse or for better
We belong we belong
we belong together
It's been far too long.
I think we should go in.
Alice, you okay?
All in one piece,
but a little shaky.
Let's get you
several snacks, huh?
Thank you.
Consider the list
misplaced indefinitely.
There's nothing we can
do while he just goes out there
and looks for someone to kill.
- We have to do something.
- Yeah, I know. But what?
Whoa, hey, hey,
hey, hey.
- Dude, sit down.
- No.
- You just had a seizure.
- Where's the Monster?
He's looking for a girl
for Enyalius.
Okay. I saw Eliot in there.
- Is he...
- Alive. And poking around like a pro.
The Monster, everything he can't remember,
it's in there. All of it.
Wait, Eliot saw this?
He saw something in the
Monster's memories, buried.
We've been wrong
about everything.
He's not trying
to rebuild his body.
That's not what
the stones are.
That's not what they're for.
It's so much worse than that.