Previously on
"The Magicians."
I need your help.
Those who go into the Mirror World
rarely find their way out.
- Who's in the Mirror World?
- My daughter.
What you need to do
is pull her out.
I might have something.
It turns an ordinary object
into sort of a beacon.
Thank you, Alice.
Truly.
There was some fallout
from your tracker coins.
Several hedges died.
Today we learned
the true danger we're in.
What about Penny?
He still, uh, sweating you?
He's not sweating me.
I was a goddess and now I'm just your
friendly neighborhood bulletproof vest.
It would be best for you
that you make this state
you find yourself in temporary.
- Have any advice on how I do that?
- You must seek the Binder.
A monster possessed you
and is inhabiting your body.
What?
There's a door hidden deep
in a forgotten remembrance.
Q, it's me. It's Eliot.
I'm alive in here.
Tell me my destiny.
A moment will come to protect
the future of Fillory.
A moment to stand beside
the High King
and then dethrone her.
Take her crown then.
Even if that means
drenching it in her blood.
Hedge witches of the world,
this is your wake up call.
The Library has turned the flow
of ambient magic down to a trickle.
We fight for scraps.
It's time to cull the herd.
[MUFFLED SHOUTING]
[SQUISHING]
Defend yourself. Go on.
Throw something at me.
[GRUNTING]
[MUFFLED SHOUTING]
Cast anything, this is what the worm does.
Try to remove it, same effect.
We will find you. We will infect you.
You've been warned.
Stop doing magic.
It's not for you.
Fuckers call themselves Serpent.
Branding's a B minus but
they are very much for real.
Wards are no help.
Last guy was attacked in broad
daylight in his own kitchen.
[KNOCKING]
♪ ♪
Kady, it's Alice.
Can you let me in?
I'm just here to talk.
Oh, good.
So, you don't need the...
Crowbar.
- Hi. Go to hell. Bye.
- Wait, no, I'm coming in.
So hit me or hear me out.
- You're trying to fight the Library.
- Yeah, no, I'm not.
Well, they're calling you
the new Marina.
Actually,
they are calling you that.
Mostly even in good terms.
Hi.
Listen.
We're not trying to step
on the foot of big government.
We're just trying to,
you know, not die.
But you are doing something.
And I was inside the Library, okay?
I can help.
Look, I've been on an apology tour.
Would you like to hear my speech?
No.
Why do you want to help?
None of us went on that quest
so good people would have
to be slaves for the Library
just to get a little magic.
I wanna fix it.
At least help.
[GRUNTS]
- [GRUNTS]
- I feel better.
So, we're having a crisis.
You can help, you can stay.
Damn.
Hi, my name's Pete, by the way.
I had no idea hedges
were taking it this far.
So the Library turned
down the ambient.
- Is that how this started?
- They did more than that.
- Mandatory cards, bans, meters in houses
- I've seen those.
What's your plan?
Well, we know this will keep
happening if everyone's starving.
Well, I helped open
a pipe in Modesto,
but we can't get anywhere
near that right now.
That was you?
Do you have any i...
What... I... we didn't
blow anything up,
and we definitely didn't
know anybody else would.
But you're right.
You can't just open one.
You have to open 50, 100.
Everywhere. You need a...
You need a map
of the entire system.
- We're listening.
- Junction boxes.
Drop a tracer.
Follow the pipe.
Map the system. Look for weak spots.
Spots with the most magic.
Great, how do we find a box?
Well, the one person I knew
who could help us,
the Library took her.
Okay, so we need another way
to get at a box.
We need a mole.
Recruit a mole inside the most
powerful institution in the multiverse?
Sure, why not?
Stop doing magic.
It's not for you.
[SNAPS]
Is this even a Library matter?
Hedges murdering each other in
the streets is a security concern.
Can we use the tracker deweys?
They stopped using those.
They're not idiots.
Just psychopaths, then.
So we continue to do
nothing till what?
They start putting blood worms
in card-carrying magicians?
We need a middle
ground solution.
Temporary cure.
[AMBIENT MUSIC]
Reed's Mark.
♪ ♪
I fail to see how hedges will
interpret such as empathetic.
Agreed.
They might feel we're taking
away their defenses.
Well, get a blood worm and cast,
you boil alive. So there's that.
Reed's Mark would prevent them
from triggering the parasite,
even accidentally.
I'm barely aware half the time
I cast little things.
Still, they'd never submit to it.
It would be voluntary.
For those already infected,
and those living in fear.
♪ ♪
No paperwork,
no questions asked.
♪ ♪
Then once this Serpent group
have been dealt with,
the mark is removed
free of charge.
♪ ♪
Sound.
I second.
Those opposed?
♪ ♪
Motion passed.
Reed's Mark it is.
♪ ♪
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
Anyone can be turned with the
right leverage. [THUMPING]
Well, it'll have to be
someone high up in the Library.
Everyone's got a weak spot.
♪ ♪
[THUDDING]
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
Mom, what's wrong?
What do you mean, inside?
Text me a picture.
♪ ♪
Guys?
What the fuck is going on?
What is she saying?
♪ ♪
What?
What do you mean,
you're in pieces?
[CELL PHONE DINGS]
♪ ♪
Guys, I think
we have our leverage.
Okay.
♪ ♪
[EERIE MUSIC]
Synced & corrected by MaxPayne
== https://subscene.com ==
How is it possible?
- Is it shards?
- No.
It'll add up to the real her.
The beacon summoned
the true Harriet.
It's just she's been in the mirror
world so long. It's a crazy place.
Something must have happened to her
and shattered her into three pieces.
And you, your mother, and I,
we were the ones
that made the beacon,
so a part of her came to each of us.
So, what do you want?
The nearest pipe junction box.
Why would I ever...
After Modesto...
Because you want your daughter.
Look, we are trying to stop
what's happening out here.
More magic will lower
the body count,
or this situation you created
blows up into a full-on war.
You put more out there
for anyone...
Hedges have always self-policed.
I consider it
my full-time responsibility.
You have my word.
- Your proposal is very risky.
- So is putting Harriet back together.
But I can do it.
Can you?
I can fix her.
[CELL PHONE CHIMES]
If you give Kady the box.
Fine, we have a deal.
A moment?
It's urgent.
Sorry.
We'll give you a moment.
Alice, walk with me. A few details.
An entire safe house?
In ten minutes, everybody was
infected. Half of them are dead.
We have to find that guy
in that stupid mask. Now.
- Okay, start some locators.
- Uh, casting spells in the current
socio-political climate is, uh...
I much prefer option B which
is this guy gets Reed's Mark
and waits until this mushroom
cloud dissipates.
- You can't be serious.
- I can't believe you're not.
Look, I got your back,
but I would prefer to do that
in one solid non-crispy piece.
♪ ♪
Give me a day.
[CLATTERING]
That's hot, that's
hot, that's hot. Ow.
So, we're looking for what, exactly?
Any reference to the annoyingly
vague message the dragon sent me.
- "Seek the Binder."
- I hate riddles.
But if it could jumper cable her, then...
Well, in "D&D", a Binder's,
like, a low class level of...
- Announcement.
- Damn it.
The stone from your dragon
person is 100% god piece.
- That is good news.
- No.
The good news is I can feel how
many pieces are still missing.
Any guesses?
The answer is one.
Only Enyalius stands between me
and anatomical perfection.
Find him and bring me
the final piece.
Cheesy puffs?
I, uh, I guess we switch
tracks to find Enyalius.
It's not gonna be easy.
He knows we're looking.
A lot of gods kind
of have signatures.
Um, ways to look for them,
whether they mean to or not.
So we research and, while we're
there, we solve this Binder shit.
Are we taking our snacky friend?
Since I have no other way
to motivate you
than this meat sack,
know if you take too long,
I'm going ice cave climbing with no
clothes until this body freezes forever.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪ ♪
Stop changing the subject.
The Napster?
It's odd. Not only is the
Great Snow 100 years early,
- but when it sings, it's in soprano.
- Fascinating.
Can you tell me what the cat lady
said about my destiny lizard?
- Well, the message was very unclear.
- You were mind melding for 12 hours.
Oh, she's very mercurial.
Josh, hello!
Hi. Glad you're back. Talking points
up the waz. Here's number one.
- Eliot! Alive.
- What?
Yeah, Q sent a troop
of these cuties to exposit.
Eliot's alive, albeit in mind-prison
while the Monster controls the joystick.
Talking point dos.
Thank you.
A wild Fillorian clock tree has sprouted
up, leaving a village stuck in time.
It's been a total clockster fuck.
[LAUGHS]
No? Nothing? Okay, anyway,
with the ambient being so low,
that's the latest on
the magical weirdness list,
- which is getting long.
- We should call the council.
Step ahead of you, sister.
In my official capacity as pinch-hitter
and fill-in crown-wearer,
I planned a state dinner.
Nothing brings peeps closer together to
solve a global catastrophe like good eats.
Margo, you're gonna wanna
see the guest list.
- Q is positive he's alive in there?
- Yeah.
[BOTH MOANING]
Aww.
[KISSING]
Oh. Oh! I'll just... go now.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
- Oh, that was the most...
- Thorough sex I've ever had.
- So, I'll see you when I get back.
- Uh, but the royals are arriving.
- And I have to go save Eliot.
- How?
Or, is the idea to be
a friend by dying?
Uh-huh, don't make a sorry dumb gesture.
Will you just stay for the feast?
- I invited the Foremost.
- Foremost what?
He leads a nomadic tribe that according
to my apricot guy who's tight with
their agave trader was once ravaged
by body-possessing demonic spirits.
And?
And in act three of the movie,
the Foremost saved them
with special weapons
- that expel possession.
- You're shitting me.
Nope, that's the one thing
we didn't just do.
They call them ice axes, and I'm
assuming that's poetic license.
So we might have a chance
to save Eliot.
Yeah.
Keep it up, Josh.
I'm gonna go get dressed
for the banquet.
"Keep it up, Josh."
[LAUGHS]
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
[MYSTERIOUS MUSIC]
Okay, fine.
I'll bite.
What's the paper?
Perhaps you've heard.
There's a wave of
hedge witch terrorism.
Is it a wave?
Depends on who you ask.
[CHUCKLES]
Certainly the librarian
who requested a list
of rejected students
had an opinion.
They asked for a watch list?
Of potential hedges, yes.
Everyone has a line, Alice.
Apparently, mine is turning
over a list to what's starting
to feel like a goddamn
totalitarian regime.
Who knew?
Huh.
I have to resign.
Well, since you've grown
morals apparently,
I have an alternative.
Set myself on fire?
[CHUCKLES]
Tempting.
♪ ♪
Sack up and stay here where
you can do an ounce of good
- and protect the list.
- I'm old.
I'm tired.
[DRINK POURING]
- I have no way to protect it.
- Had no way.
Zelda is outside and she needs
your lab and a whole lot of magic.
And most importantly,
your secrecy.
Why should that come cheap?
Go talk to her while I research.
Binders of various types.
The word Binder's in a ton
of actual titles, huh?
I mean, Google "The Binder."
120 million hits.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
You think that dragon's
trolling me?
Anything new on Enyalius?
'Cause I got
a fresh take on that.
Let's find him, get his rock, destroy
it before the Monster comes back.
Wow, I love it.
[SIGHS]
Except for the part where
it doesn't save Eliot.
♪ ♪
We'll figure something out.
We always do.
No, bro.
Take it from someone from a timeline
where you did not figure it out.
We'll find Enyalius first.
I'm not talking about this now.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪ ♪
But no one made it out
of that expedition alive.
Have you ever wondered
about your past lives?
If you have long lost loves
or suppressed memories?
- Memories.
- Search no further.
Thank God
for priority overnight.
I'll send your mom
some chocolates.
♪ ♪
She'll like that...
If they're made of wine.
Traveler's blood?
♪ ♪
Once it starts, I'll have to seal the lab
and you'll both have to wait outside.
♪ ♪
- Bjorn's Electromagnetic is unstable.
- Good thing I'm a phosphoromancer.
♪ ♪
Okay, we're about ready.
Oh, one thing.
The Harriet that came
to me was exaggerated.
It seems when she fragmented,
so did her personality.
- Just be aware.
- Thanks.
But I'm more concerned with
getting them out quickly
to the same place so we can
reunite them at all, so...
Now out, both of you.
Just don't fuck yourself up
too much, okay?
- You punched me in the face.
- Don't die.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪ ♪
[WHISTLING]
[BOOMING]
Shit, it overloaded!
[SPARKING]
Wh... I have to fix the prism.
What are you doing?
No, we don't have any time.
We're running out of ambient.
[SPARKING]
I don't understand you. Look, I
have to do this now. [RUMBLING]
Oops. You fucked that one up.
Interesting application.
But I can improve on this.
Okay, but we have to fix this now!
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
- No, we have time. - No, we don't.
- Don't be such a scaredy bitch.
- I'm not.
- Ah. That's what you are.
You're the mouse inside me.
I get you promised to fix her,
but honestly I don't see
the point in putting
us back together.
You're absolutely worthless.
You can go now.
♪ ♪
Give that back to me right now!
No.
I wanna play with it.
- Give it back.
- Uh-uh.
Give it back,
you arrogant bitch!
- Oh, my God, your stupid face.
- You're gonna destroy everything again!
[BOTH GRUNTING]
♪ ♪
She's dangerous.
I had to.
I need to.
Just wait.
♪ ♪
Move!
That bitch.
Hello? Hello!
Goddamn it.
[WIND BLOWING]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
Margo will want those by the throne.
And you go to the wine cellar.
Oh, hi.
- You must be looking for the...
- Fen.
My name is Ru. Queen of West Loria.
I'd like a private word.
Leave us.
What was your Creature?
There's no sense in denying it. The
thing told me its sister visited you.
My prophecy was concise.
For the health of my land,
I must aid you in dethroning
the High King,
violently if necessary.
I see yours lines right up.
Look, Margo has
a reputation, but...
Gods, don't tell me
you're friends.
No, no.
But I've thought about this
and realized my...
Our job here is indeed to do
what's best for our lands,
and that's just
not necessarily...
You're about to speechify
on fighting one's destiny?
No, no, no, no.
Um, on listening to one's guts.
I'm willing to forge
a peace with Fillory...
Once you take the throne.
Then and only then.
Wow, okay.
I'm just saying there
are so many paths...
During the feast, you will order
the castle doors open
whereupon my men will enter
- and chop off her head.
- Enjoy the desert course.
Did you really think
I was gonna say that?
Hoped.
A ruler never walks away
of their own accord.
They must be crushed.
Now I don't relish this,
but we are responsible
for our own kingdoms.
There is but one alternative.
Everlasting banishment.
But that's a form of death.
You have until dinner to decide.
Or I'll be forced to see to it that
your head joins hers in the basket.
♪ ♪
Quentin.
Hoolia.
Whatever your name is.
I have the most perfect idea.
Um, who is that?
Is this a... a game, or...
Are you aware that there's
big money for psychics
who are in actuality
big, giant fakers?
I had to try 19 before
I found a real one.
Allan, you're going
to help me so much.
Help you with what, exactly?
Remembering my past life.
Could you guys make me a snack?
We'd like some privacy.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
Is that gonna be okay?
This guy's mind better be
strong as hell,
'cause... 'cause if it gets
too hot in there...
- [GAGGING]
- Oh, boy.
[HUMMING] Attention, customers.
Clean up in the baby food aisle.
[SIGHS]
- You forgot the chips.
- There's no pulse.
Relax.
It's fine.
- I'll get another one.
- No, it won't work.
- You're too strong.
- Fine, I'll get a strong one.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
You're upset.
I'll get this gross corpse
out of your sight.
See you when I find
a new psychic friend.
Wait.
I can help.
I know a psychic with
a real strong mind.
- Penny, don't.
- Who?
Me.
No.
Just... you say no, and then no?
Cute you wanna make this
about me being bossy,
but we both just saw
that guy die.
I'm not that guy.
I studied this.
I had the Beast in my head.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm glad that you care.
Ha, ha, but I actually do.
Ha, ha, but I actually get that.
And I'm being serious.
So, how about this?
If I don't die,
I can take you out for a drink.
What, are you kidding?
That's something that
regular people do.
Yeah, fuck it.
Okay, try this.
Live, and you can buy me dinner.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪ ♪
[LAUGHING]
That was fun. It took a lot of rocks
to sink the body.
Ready to get started, Percy?
♪ ♪
Okay. So, why are we here?
It's important.
Not sure why.
♪ ♪
That's okay.
This field, was there a house
or anything else here?
No.
Nothing.
Wait.
An altar.
And some bowls.
♪ ♪
Good.
Think about the bowls.
Anything inside them?
Stones.
The stones.
The ones they put part
of me into.
But not yet.
They're still empty.
- Uh...
- And rope.
♪ ♪
Lots of rope.
Nothing here can hurt you.
They said they were
scared of me.
Who?
Bacchus. Irus. Heka.
♪ ♪
But they needed Enyalius.
They couldn't do it without him.
♪ ♪
[GASPS]
I know what they did
for Enyalius to make him come.
There is a girl.
Near death.
She was a sacrifice.
Stop him.
♪ ♪
- Stop him.
- I can't.
Everything that is happening
has already happened.
He called me monster, but look at him.
He loved it.
The scent of a dying girl.
[CRYING]
Some god of war.
He only liked them when they
were too weak to fight.
♪ ♪
You're not strong, Enyalius.
You're a sad, perverse little...
Why is this making me so upset?
Ma... Maybe there's more here.
Keep watching.
♪ ♪
[WHIMPERING]
- He's bleeding. Should we...
- No.
He said to wait as long as possible.
One more minute.
Hi. Thank God you saw the door.
- No.
- It's me, it's me.
It's the real me.
It's Eliot, okay?
This is a mind palace situation
and we don't have
a lot of time, and I have some
extremely major shit to tell you.
Maybe there's more.
Maybe there's more. What is it?
What is it? [CRYING]
Traveler.
But it is only a matter of
time before he remembers it,
too, okay?
So you have to...
Percy?
Percy 23?
- Shit.
- Go, go, go, go.
Percy 23.
Right... Right here.
Where were you?
- I was just exploring.
- What did you see?
Nothing.
There's nothing else here.
If you are lying to me,
I will have you flayed.
♪ ♪
[THUDS]
Oh, shit.
♪ ♪
Penny!
That was helpful.
♪ ♪
Hmm.
Tell him I said thanks.
I know just who to find exactly
to Enyalius' tastes.
We're going to find him and
I'm going to be whole again.
♪ ♪
This is a great day.
Penny.
Would you care for a pipe?
We're a lot alike, you and I.
My mother was
a hedge witch, too.
She died.
I was ten.
- I didn't know you were a hedge.
- Oh, yes.
My mentor, Everett, found me...
Sounds dramatic... in an alley.
Gave me shelter, education,
believed in me.
I will never need to do
those things again, but...
My choices now seem worse.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
That's why I agreed to give you
the location of the pipe junction.
'Cause someone gets
hurt regardless.
♪ ♪
Because I know you'll work
to keep things fair.
Safe.
And you know this how?
♪ ♪
Because we both had shitty moms?
Because you have the capacity
to sit with the woman
who caused the death
of the man you love.
♪ ♪
To try and understand her.
So, I have faith you'll make
choices that hurt the fewest people.
♪ ♪
Okay, look, you can fix
a prism with Strand's Vitrum.
Right, but do we need to
dress the refraction angle
for a break, or...
I don't understand
sign language!
Okay.
You have to adjust, of course.
- We need to cut a new prism.
- [GROANS]
I don't know what you're saying!
No!
You don't know!
She destroyed my life with her crazy
ideas and her insane confidence.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Goddamn it.
Hi again, bitch.
Oh, what do I do?
What do I do?
- I... I do Strand's Vitrum.
- Cut a new prism.
Combine Gentileschi.
Doesn't matter, though,
because you're...
- I'm not.
- You're frozen.
You move one hand to fix it,
and you freeze.
You need to let me out of here.
- But what you wanna do...
- What you actually deserve.
Maybe I do.
Maybe I'm just too much to live.
But the fact of the matter is
if you throw one tiny piece
of magic in here, it bounces,
and we both vaporize.
Yeah, well, don't be
so sure I hate that idea.
You can't. See?
You need me.
You...
You're an egomaniac.
- You only care about yourself.
- Well, someone had to.
- No one else gave a shit.
- Because you alienated them all.
- Our IQ did that.
- Your arrogance.
- Oh, I'm so smart. Look at me.
- Oh, love me, love me.
I won't exist
unless you love me.
I'm so sorry I'm smart.
It's not you, it's me. I'm so sorry.
Right. That's exactly why
you destroyed the keys,
- because you're such a goddamn genius.
- [LAUGHS]
I didn't do that.
You did.
- That's bullshit!
- Mm.
My arrogance didn't destroy
the stupid keys.
Fear did.
You did.
♪ ♪
- You ruined my life.
- We did that together.
♪ ♪
You're right.
I can't fix the prism.
Because it's a big swing and it
might blow up, and that's my thing?
Do you wanna know what
the biggest swing there is?
Us agreeing.
Self destruction would be
a sad waste of both of us.
'Cause we still have no idea
what we're actually capable of.
♪ ♪
That scares me, too.
Does it scare you so much
you'd just rather never know?
Just leave me in here to die? And you
go live your ordinary waste of a life?
♪ ♪
[CREAKING]
[THUDS]
Well, that's not weird at all.
♪ ♪
Does that say "Binder"?
- Isn't Julia looking for...
- But we shouldn't.
Clearly it wants us to.
Let's not get precious about it.
♪ ♪
All right,
let's fix this fucker.
♪ ♪
Okay, are you ready
to pull yourself together?
♪ ♪
[CLASSICAL MUSIC]
Red alert. So there is
a palace coup underway.
Fen is planning to defenestrate you.
It's a destiny thing.
That balsa-toed bitch. I'd like to see
her try. Quick. Where's the Foremost?
- Not here yet, I guess.
- Hold off the traitor till I talk to him.
- Then let her come.
- Okay.
Great.
♪ ♪
Stand here so Fen can't see me.
She's trying to overthrow me.
It's a long story and I'm handling it.
- Where is the Foremost?
- Leader of the Southern Nomads?
Wandering in the south,
I imagine.
He and his axes are supposed
to be here, Tick.
But he'd never come to this.
[LAUGHS]
[GAGS]
♪ ♪
Oceans of apology, Majesty,
but the Foremost is
a sworn enemy of Fillory
and will not interact
with her citizens.
- Much less High King.
- You're joking.
But this whole...
♪ ♪
I need him, Tick.
For Eliot.
Oh, I see.
How can I assist?
Would you like me to travel
to the South and use
false Lorian papers
to seek an audience?
The Pickwicks are
a notoriously thirsty people,
making them ill-suited for the desert,
and I have a violent allergy to the sand.
And of course, I'm not a magician.
But if it helps, it would be an honor...
I get it. It's a job for a tough bitch.
So it has to be me.
Oh, thank you.
I would have died.
Oh, please.
You by any chance seen Margo?
Oh, my semi-girlfriend who saved my
life and is also a great King? No.
Why?
No reason.
Just, uh...
♪ ♪
Oh, actually, uh,
I have to go sneeze.
- Um, can we talk?
- Do it.
- [STAMMERS] Excuse me?
- Fen. Do it. I don't understand.
Overthrow me right
the fuck now, Fen.
- I never should have...
- Or I will never forgive you.
And neither will Eliot if you keep me from
getting the one thing that can save him.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
Um...
♪ ♪
Excuse me.
I need a word with the guard.
♪ ♪
By order of High King Fen,
Margo of tribe Hansen
is forever banished,
never again to step upon
the soil of Fillory,
never again to breathe
- its air or feel its magic.
- Oh, get on with it.
♪ ♪
[HISSING]
- Son of a pig fucker.
- Perfect words to remember you by.
♪ ♪
Wait! I curse Fen's name.
But if I were you, I'd listen to her!
And wait!
Be nice to her!
Your grandkids' grandkids
will fear me!
Margo, wait!
Five seconds.
Please.
- Look, I should go with you.
- Josh, I can handle my shit.
What I can't handle is Fillory blowing up,
so please just help Fen. Okay.
Okay.
For your journey.
Just a few simple fig apricot saffron
cardamom vanilla plum danishes.
They'll keep.
So... oh, and a new map. Very helpful.
Oh, also, fully charged.
When the going gets tough,
tough listens to pop anthems
- from the '80s.
- Josh...
Just a thought.
Never mind.
- You're a good man.
- Oh.
Okay, I'm gonna try
and live through this
'cause it's feeling like we got
some more banging to do.
It does, right?
But don't wait for me, Hoberman.
Let's be realistic.
Totally.
I'm probably going to wait
for you, though, so sorry.
Don't be a fool, Josh.
♪ Now there's no
looking forward ♪
turning back ♪
♪ When you say we belong
to the light ♪
♪ We belong to the thunder ♪
[PAT BENATAR'S "WE BELONG"]
♪ We belong to the sound
of the words ♪
♪ We've both fallen under ♪
♪ Whatever we deny or embrace
for worse or for better ♪
♪ We belong, we belong
we belong together ♪
♪ ♪
It's been far too long.
I think we should go in.
[DOOR OPENS]
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪ ♪
Oh.
- Alice, you okay?
- All in one piece, but a little shaky.
Let's, uh, get you
several snacks, huh?
♪ ♪
Thank you. Consider the
list misplaced indefinitely.
♪ ♪
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[GROANS]
[GRUNTS]
There's nothing we can do
while he just goes out there
and looks for someone to kill.
Oh, we have to do something.
Yeah, I know.
But what?
Whoa, hey, hey, hey, hey.
- Whoa, dude, sit down.
- Oh.
- You just had a seizure.
- Where's the Monster?
He's looking for a girl
for Enyalius.
Okay.
I saw Eliot in there.
- Is he...
- Alive. And poking around like a pro.
The Monster, everything he can't
remember, it's in there. All of it.
- Wait, Eliot saw this?
- He saw something.
In the Monster's memories, buried.
We've been wrong about everything.
He's not trying
to rebuild his body.
That's not what the stones are.
That's not what they're for.
It's so much worse than that.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
♪ ♪