PENNY: Previously
on The Magicians...
ELIZA: I knew the
Beast would come.
Get strong, learn fast,
any means necessary.
So that's it? That's all
you're gonna say to me?
I got into the school,
and you didn't.
I don't know what else to say.
Marina is a psycho!
You think Brakebills
cut you off from magic?
You don't know "cut
off". (SCREAMS)
I want the spells I'm
missing, so I can keep going.
I want the new ones she stole.
QUENTIN: They're
locked in her filing cabinet.
DEAN: You are a Traveler.
WOMAN: You can
move between worlds.
Had the lecture yet on
sticking with astral projection?
It works by binding
your body to Earth.
Won't make the voices go away,
but it might keep you
alive. (SHUDDERING)
(GASPING)
All I can say is, it was
some kind of dungeon.
KADY: This was on the walls.
QUENTIN: Penny, I
think you were in Fillory.
You were in Fillory.
Stop! Okay, Fillory is just a...
Did you see any animals?
Did they talk to you?
I was at some dungeon,
you Hobbit-loving freak.
What's wrong with you?
There are no Hobbits in
Fillory. It doesn't matter.
Ah, the drawing,
the crest, it means
that you were in a
certain Fillorian castle.
Oh, kill me. It was
built by dwarves.
Ah, okay, let's not get
caught up in the details.
The point is
that it's full of, uh,
a ton of incredibly
magical shit.
Oh, yeah, the Beast is
really fucking magical.
Let me pop back over there and
see if he does birthday parties.
Let's go. It's a waste of time.
I think you should
listen to Quentin
because I'm assuming
you didn't travel
to Fillory on some
planned vacation,
so you don't know
how to control it yet.
Then educate yourself.
Nobody knows more
about Fillory than Quentin.
What if you end up
back there again?
She makes a point.
Okay, fanboy.
Tell me what it says
in the books about
not getting my face
eaten by the Beast.
(STAMMERING)
The Beast isn't in the books.
How's that, if I was right
there staring him in the face?
The Chatwins, they
mostly get chased around
by this time witch,
the Watcher Woman.
She plants clocks in trees.
Ah, it's sort of surrealist.
Okay, all right, I take it back.
This is a waste of your time.
The books were written for kids,
so maybe they skipped the
monster that rips out people's eyes.
I don't know! PENNY: Okay.
We're done here.
You love Fillory so much, I
hope you get to go. I really do.
I guess I've been
trying to convince myself
that Penny's somehow
wrong about Fillory
despite having
actually been there.
That's a pretty
acrobatic form of denial.
I really am sorry.
I'm sure Fillory got you
through a lot as a kid.
Yeah.
As a kid. (CHUCKLES)
Sorry, the manager
isn't in right now.
Would you like
to place an order?
I know you know who I am.
Look, I'm sorry I insulted you guys.
But just who talked
to you? Marina? Pete?
I'm going to call the cops.
God, Rick, grow a pair!
Wait, wait, wait. I'm sorry.
Please. I don't
know anyone else.
(CLATTERS)
I'm not done with you.
Consider it a warning.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
Julia.
Julia, wait. Okay, just wait.
Marina, okay? No
one wants a war.
Here.
It's about an hour by train.
Went there couple of years back.
They're real. They're good.
Just give them a try, but please
don't come back here again.
(MACHINE BUZZING)
How'd you learn all this anyway?
Me and a friend got deep
into ink spells in high school.
Ah...
It's not the Mona Lisa, but I
do have 20/20 vision in the dark.
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
And where was all this exactly?
I told you, I'm basically
from the 'burbs.
Actually, you never say a
damn thing about your life.
'Cause it's boring.
What flavor of boring?
My mom died young,
and my dad is kind
of embarrassing.
He wears Birkenstocks
and he sells weed, and...
But he loves me no matter
what kind of trouble I get in.
That sounds nice.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah.
So, this symbol,
will it do anything for
the whole mind-slut shit?
Yeah, you know,
Brakebills is good.
Everyone knows how to pull
their blinds down, you know?
Yeah.
I still hear her, though.
That girl from the dungeon.
Can't shut her out.
I just file that under
"Wish there was jack
shit I could do about it."
Yeah.
Or were you talking
about the Beast?
If I was you, I'd be curious.
He's full-on AWOL, not a peep.
So I get this, and I
don't poke the bear.
Let's just hope the
bear has better shit to do.
(CLATTERING)
Shit, shit, shit.
Hey! (GASPING)
Why are you following me, lady?
Easy. I just want to show you
I'm just like you.
(FLOOR CREAKING)
Hello?
Is someone being
creepy on purpose?
(CLATTERING)
Secure the sacrifice!
No! God damn it. No!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(SHUDDERING)
O Manon,
we offer up this virgin,
flesh and blood!
Jesus, I'm not a virgin.
Huh.
Life is full of surprises.
What the hell, Margo?
Follow, follow. Hurry, hurry.
Ow.
Guys, the pine needles
are hurting my feet.
Shh.
Right there. QUENTIN: Ow, ow.
Hello, first years.
At this appointed hour,
as tradition dictates,
it falls upon the upper class
to administer what
is known simply as
the Trials.
The Trials test your ability
to think and act
like a Magician.
Pass, your journey begins.
Fail, you flunk out.
This is a test engineered
to thin out the herd.
Only those who
should will survive.
Oh, nut up! This isn't Harvard.
It requires actual effort.
And don't bother to go
complaining to the faculty.
They're off on a
luxurious retreat,
observing from a distance.
You are ours, miscreants.
Onward to glory!
Come on! Go! Go!
(ALL CLAMORING)
MARGO: Name, please?
Alice Quinn.
Hmm. Let me see.
Wow, you're really
enjoying this, aren't you?
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
The Trials themselves
have the power, Alice.
They will pass or fail you
as the Dean created them to.
I merely keep a little eye on
each and every one of you.
Ah, there you are.
Report to the table
on your placard.
Good luck.
Next!
Say one word about
Fillory, and I'll kill you.
Get me kicked out... Well,
then we'd finally be even.
Now I get it.
Get what?
Why our team name
is Horny Chupacabras.
I'm not a... (STUTTERING)
I don't even know
what a chupacabra is.
It's a spine-covered goat-sucking
primate indigenous to Mexico.
I can already see
we are immensely
handicapped by your presence.
(LAUGHS)
In 18th century England,
a secret society known as the
Brethren encrypted hundreds of spells
to hide them from the church.
You may open your blue books.
Each team must decode and
cast their spell by 9:00 a.m.
Screw up, and it's
back to page one.
FYI, this test is pretty
much impossible. Begin.
HANNAH: Back in the
day, we'd travel the world.
We'd pay for spells.
Trade for them.
And they weren't all the most
ambitious Hedges you ever saw,
but we looked out for each
other. It was like family.
First family I really felt
I belonged in, actually.
Okay, so what do
you want exactly?
Well, you know, our story
with Marina, it's not rare.
I have seen her chew
people up and spit them out.
Then what? You swoop in, you
buy us a milkshake? Come on.
(SCOFFS) Not till today.
You are the first I believe
can really do things
if given the
opportunity to learn.
I mean, I can feel
it coming off of you.
You're not an amateur.
You're the real thing.
Yeah, well, some
think so. Some do not.
Well, I think we
can help each other.
How?
(SNIFFS, CLEARS THROAT)
It's not much, but, you know,
they'll be new to you, I think.
Wait a minute. How did you...
All over. Where did you...
You don't want to know.
But you're welcome to them.
In exchange for what?
Just do some with me.
I miss the feeling, you know?
(FINGERS SNAPPING)
Welcome, à la Safe House Julia.
Can you make it colder?
Girl, you're strong!
Shit.
Was this the last of them?
Afraid so.
(EXHALES)
Well, hey, we'll hit the
road, right? Find new stuff.
Try, at least.
But you know who has a
ton of new stuff? Marina.
'Cause she got
her memories back.
I helped her do it.
She has...
Brakebills.
So she has everything.
We're screwed. How
much time do we have left?
I don't know. Who knows
how to read an hourglass?
This is impossible. Even
Eliot said it was impossible.
Wait, it's impossible.
Actually, he said, it was
practically impossible,
but maybe some
genius can do this.
So, what, only geniuses
can be Magicians? Really?
We have to cheat.
They want us to. We've
been Kobayashi Maru-ed.
Whatever that means, yes.
No. No way.
You're an idiot. We're cheating.
Why would... Why would
they want us to cheat?
'Cause we're Magicians.
No. No, they just want
to see how far we can get.
QUENTIN: There's no
such a thing as half a spell.
You guys are insane.
Supply closet. Five
minutes. I've got a plan.
HANNAH: Oh, man! They really
upped the security since my day.
How much do you
know about those wards?
Enough to know they're strong,
but not enough to
break them, so...
What do you think
would happen if we just
ran in there and
grabbed the filing cabinet?
(LAUGHS) Oh, yeah, sure.
You ever see the movie Scanners?
Oh.
There's a way.
There's always a way.
You have a pen?
Here.
What we need...
Think of it like a fishhook.
We grab the cabinets from
the room without tripping wards.
There's wards all over the room.
Yeah, in this dimension, sure.
The one thing I can't figure
out is how to get the hook in.
You know, we need
someone inside for that.
And I sort of burned
all my bridges with that.
You think we can
pay someone off?
No.
I know someone.
(ENGINE STARTING)
Took you long enough.
Okay, here's the question.
Do you believe
what you said earlier,
that a genius could
solve this by dawn?
Well, yeah, I
mean, if they were...
Alice Quinn?
If anyone, she could.
Can you read her mind?
No. Unlike you, she's airtight.
But I can do one better.
Just light the fucking thing.
Nicely done.
Perfect execution.
Too bad I know you cheated.
Congratulations, you two,
and on to the second Trial.
Well, what about...
Thinning the herd.
So are you gonna tell
me who we're meeting?
Yeah, she's not a
hedge witch exactly,
but, well, her and I
have some history.
So I think it's best... What
do you mean by "history"?
Hey, chickadee!
Mom, you shouldn't be here.
(CHUCKLES) This
is your daughter.
What's she doing here?
She's a friend.
Okay, come on,
babe. Please, sit.
How are you? How have you been?
(SCOFFS) Just tell me
what you want, Mom.
I want to give you something.
Oh, that's so sweet!
Yeah, my birthday
was seven months ago.
Kady, look, I was
not in a good place
the last time you saw me,
but my shit's together now.
Oh, is it? Is that why
you're hanging out
with the angriest bitch
from the safe house?
Oh, if you want to insult
me, you should try again.
Just...
Listen.
I called because Julia and
I have a line on something.
Oh, my God, here we go again.
We're gonna start our own house.
Nothing crazy, but it'll
be safe from Marina,
so come with us.
My God, you're insane.
You actually think
that you can beat her.
Hey, Marina's
strong, but so are we.
Nothing like that
at school, huh?
Protection charm.
It'll render our house
literally invisible.
You know, the amazing thing is
you actually believe
that this plan could work.
Marina will never let me go.
Ever.
Oh, did Hannah give
you the whole sob story?
HANNAH: Kady... No, no.
Marina didn't betray my mom.
She cleaned up her mess.
Yeah, Hannah, well, she wanted
to steal something. Big heist, right?
Except she can't handle her shit
under pressure,
and two people died.
Cut to now, Marina
gets to demand
that I steal shit
10 times a week.
Yeah, no big.
Don't call me again.
You can't take
that! Let her have it.
No, we need it. So does she.
If I had more,
I'd give you more.
Yeah.
But you don't.
You sold your
daughter to Marina?
No, Marina stole her.
Yeah, because of a really bad
judgment call that you made.
She said she had my back.
This is not black and white.
Yeah, well, Kady sure
seems to think that it is.
If this goes how we
want, I can fix that, too.
"If this..." Do you
hear yourself?
"If this works out"? I'm out.
Oh, no, you don't.
You do not cut me off.
My daughter just
got brought into this.
And I will share with
you everything I can,
but it is better that I
see this through alone.
This looks like a home
brew. Where did you get it?
Found it inside an old textbook.
(INHALES)
It looks underwhelming.
So how's Professor
March's research going?
Look, I tried, but he won't
take on first year assistants.
Well, you're just his type,
so I'm sure you'll figure it out.
"But where's the door, Martin?
"There's always a door to
Fillory when we really need it.
"In the clock, or the
closet, or my panties?"
Come on, celebrate! You
passed, you dirty cheater.
What's the problem? Speak.
No offense, you're
just not exactly...
Warm and cuddly? I know.
You ever want something so badly
and then realize that it's
nothing like what you thought,
and maybe that you are stupid
for ever actually
even wanting it?
Every guy I've ever slept with.
Fillory is real.
Oh, come the fuck on. It is.
Penny is a Traveler,
and he went
there, and it's real.
Look like your head's
about to pop off.
I loved those books.
You did?
Why so surprised?
I'd pretend I was ambassador
to the Fillorian Outer Islands.
But the real thing,
it's not like the story.
So, what, it's actually
totally shitty over there?
I don't know. Maybe. Yes.
At least a little.
The thing that attacked us,
that ripped the Dean's eyes out,
seems like it might
be from Fillory.
Jesus.
That is not tonally
consistent with the books.
No, it's not. And
that... I just...
I find that devastating.
Were you planning a trip there?
No, really.
Because, otherwise,
you're literally
torturing yourself
over a fairy tale.
Quentin, you
passed the first Trial.
You live to fight another day.
Drink up. Go to the party.
Find someone to bang.
Celebrate the world
you're in, dummy.
Come on!
(SIGHS) (CHUCKLES)
Okay.
Well, I'm a little...
I am very...
Wow, I'm really, uh...
Margo, did you roofie me?
(THUDS)
Can we skip down to where you
realize you no makey magic here?
(ELIOT LAUGHS MALICIOUSLY)
Oh. Cucumber. Daddy's favorite.
And too much dill. (SPITS)
There they all are, all
those little fishies, just like us,
eating, shitting, breeding.
I require one.
It's over there.
(CLAPS) Chop chop.
I am literally losing
the will to live.
So this is my next test?
I'm supposed to spear a fish?
Do your lips move when you read?
Seriously? One arrow?
Eliot!
(NEIGHING)
Bring him to me.
Why?
I want to get my
Catherine the Great on.
Google it. Totally hilarious.
Oh, and to help you out.
No. Just no, okay?
Okay.
Wait.
I'm seeing your future now.
Gay porn?
(GASPS)
(CHUCKLES)
Mi favorito.
Liver.
HANNAH: Julia, stop!
You're gonna blow
yourself up! I was getting it.
You really weren't, hon.
How did you get in?
I unpicked your ward.
I would go with
Koyosegi next time.
Thank you for the advice.
Now, can you please leave?
We already agreed that
we're not partners, okay?
Well, it didn't work because
you need 10 extra digits.
Actually, I don't.
It's interesting how
you can't look at me.
Know why?
'Cause I'm too familiar.
I mean, we both made mistakes.
We live with them. We go on.
Alone, if we have to.
But you do this alone,
and you will get hurt.
Come on. We can
help each other out.
Please.
I want my daughter back.
Kady?
Kady. Hey, Kady!
Kady. Kady! Stop
it! Stop it! Stop it!
Let go! Let go! No.
I have to catch
the bird. No! Hey!
This shit is dumb. The
school is not worth it.
No, I can't! You don't get
it. I can't get kicked out!
Ow! Fuck! Oh, my God.
Jesus. Oh, my God. Is it broken?
I don't know. Ah.
Let me see. Let me
see. Let me look at it.
It's not broken. Look, talk
to me. What's going on?
Look, it's just...
(GASPS) This is all I have.
Me, too.
(SOBBING) No, it's different.
I'm different. I
need Brakebills.
It's life or death.
I have to be here.
Hey.
(SOBBING)
(GASPING)
What are you supposed
to get with that?
(LAUGHS)
A fucking pheasant.
You? A horse.
These people are crazy.
Let's go find the others.
Come on.
PENNY: Yo!
Seriously, dude,
I almost had him.
We'll get him, son.
It's not about magic 'cause
it's about talking to each other.
All right, you got that.
But I grew up in Florida,
so I actually know how
to use it to get your fish.
But I'm after a horse.
Seriously? What?
Junior Cowboy Camp.
Pheasant.
Tree.
(GRUNTING)
(HORSE WHINNYING)
You're bleeding.
I hated Junior Cowboy Camp.
Timber!
(RUMBLING)
MARGO: Bravo!
Brava. Brava.
That's it? We passed?
After you chop the
tree into firewood,
whip us up a little
grilled salmon.
MARGO: Some honeyed pheasant.
And take turns
blowing the horse.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(BOTH SIGHING HAPPILY)
Did you see the look
on Quentin's face? Yes.
Like, "Fine, but I
am not going first."
(LAUGHS)
I'm sure by now, you've realized
Brakebills teaches us to be
arch and ironic about magic.
But this one plays it serious.
You must bare yourself
in the presence of
another magical adept
and expose your highest
governing internal circumstance,
which is to say
your utmost truth.
You have till midnight.
Ready?
(CHANTING)
(BOTH CHANTING)
(RUMBLING)
(ELECTRICITY
CRACKLING) Oh, shit!
Shit!
No!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(ALL NOISES STOP)
(EXHALES)
Okay, it's a two-person spell.
Both must succeed to unlock it.
You bind your
hands with this rope.
How am I gonna survive?
It'll fall off once you've
reached transcendence.
Okay, it's got to be some
kind of scheme, right?
To record us playing
naked truth-or-dare,
so they can blackmail
us or something.
Unfortunately,
Margo wasn't lying.
It's arcane and
a bit unorthodox,
but Secrets Magic
is a real thing.
Basically, there's no
trick or cheat to this.
It's kind of the exact opposite.
(CHUCKLES)
Focus. I'm trying.
All clear. Good to go.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God, no.
Run.
Hannah! Hannah!
You said it was all clear.
You said it was gonna be okay.
Go! Run! Marina is coming.
We need to get you help.
OPERATOR: 911.
What's your emergency?
(HANNAH GASPING)
You know, it's not
part of the spell,
but I think it could
make things easier.
You know, I always thought
when I partook in
a nude magic ritual
that I'd be sort of
in a mystical trance.
(SIGHS)
Tell that to the girl who lost her
virginity with all her clothes on.
(BLACK OUT DAYS BY
PHANTOGRAM PLAYING)
Hide the sun
I will leave your
face out of my mind
You should save your eyes
A thousand voices
howling in my head
Okay. Okay.
Uh...
I've been institutionalized
more than once.
Maybe we shouldn't drink.
Or we should drink more.
Yeah. (CHUCKLES)
William. Really?
Ask me something harder if
you want us to get somewhere.
(BLACK OUT DAYS BY
PHANTOGRAM CONTINUES)
Away, away
Ask me why I'm nice to you.
I had noticed you're a tad
brusque with everyone else.
And why is that?
Penny, you don't have to.
Look, I'm not scared to tell
you this because it's true.
Shit.
Okay.
Truth.
I am scared to tell you
this because it's true.
I'm falling in love with you.
All the stars are
shining bloody red
I can't do this.
Kady, I'm not
gonna chase after...
You won't have to.
What does that mean?
Look, I'm a liar, okay?
I flirted with
you that first day
because you looked
useful, and you were.
Look, we stole a lot
of shit, so there it is.
I've been using
you this entire time.
It's all a lie.
(SONG PLAYING) Black out days
I don't recognize you anymore
Penny.
QUENTIN AND ALICE: Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
(BELL TOLLING)
One.
I need to sit.
I really didn't see this coming.
How could you? You're the best.
You know what?
I try so hard not to be.
Why?
I'm already pretty
damn unpopular.
Can you imagine
what they would think
if they knew how
good I really am?
"Spinster Magician
dies alone eaten by cats."
I always hold back, Quentin.
Every single day. I mean,
I have no idea what
I'm even capable of,
and I'm just trying so hard
to be anything close to normal.
My friend Julia said that I
couldn't run away hard enough.
She's right.
I run, and I...
I find secret doors.
Whether I'm alone or in
a group doesn't matter.
Like, I'm here. I'm
in this amazing place.
I have literal magic in my
life, and I'm still running.
I'm still this person
that I fucking hate.
Sorry. (CLEARS THROAT)
I'm really drunk right now.
It's okay, Quentin. I get it.
Your ropes are gone.
Yeah, so are yours.
(GASPING)
(GRUNTS)
Alice, I... (GASPS)
(GASPING)
(HONKING)
(GEESE HONKING IN DISTANCE)