PENNY: Previously on
The Magicians...
ELIZA: I knew
the Beast would come.
Get strong, learn fast,
any means necessary.
So that's it?
That's all you're
gonna say to me?
I got into the school,
and you didn't.
I don't know what
else to say.
Marina is a psycho!
You think Brakebills
cut you off from magic?
You don't know "cut off".
(SCREAMS)
I want the spells
I'm missing,
so I can keep going.
l want the new ones
she stole.
QUENTIN:
They're locked in
her filing cabinet.
DEAN: You are a Traveler.
WOMAN: You can
move between worlds.
Had the lecture yet
on sticking with
astral projection?
It works by binding
your body to Earth.
Won't make the voices go away,
but it might keep you alive.
(SHUDDERING)
(GASPING)
All I can say is,
it was some kind
of dungeon.
KADY: This was on the walls.
QUENTIN: Penny, I think
you were in Fillory.
You were in Fillory.
Stop!
Okay, Fillory is just a...
Did you see any animals?
Did they talk to you?
I was at some dungeon,
you Hobbit-loving freak.
What's wrong with you?
There are no
Hobbits in Fillory.
It doesn't matter.
Ah, the drawing,
the crest, it means
that you were in a certain
Fillorian castle.
Ch, kill me.
It was built by dwarves.
Ah, okay, let's not get
caught up in the details.
The point is that
it's full of, uh,
a ton of incredibly
magical shit.
Oh, yeah, the Beast is
really fucking magical.
Let me pop back over
there and see if he
does birthday parties.
Let's go.
It's a waste of time.
I think you should
listen to Quentin
because I'm assuming
you didn't travel
to Fillory on some
planned vacation,
so you don't know
how to control it yet.
Then educate yourself.
Nobody knows
more about Fillory
than Quentin.
What if you end up
back there again?
She makes a point.
Okay, fanboy.
Tell me what it says
in the books about
not getting my face
eaten by the Beast.
(STAMMERING)
The Beast isn't
in the books.
How's that, if I was
right there staring
him in the face?
The Chatwins,
they mostly get
chased around
by this time witch,
the Watcher Woman.
She plants clocks
in trees.
Ah, it's sort of
surrealist.
Okay, all right,
I take it back. This
is a waste of your time.
The books were
written for kids,
so maybe they skipped
the monster that rips
out people's eyes.
I don't know!
PENNY: Okay.
We're done here.
You love Fillory so much,
I hope you get to go.
I really do.
I guess I've been
trying to convince myself
that Penny's somehow
wrong about Fillory
despite having
actually been there.
That's a pretty acrobatic
form of denial.
I really am sorry.
I'm sure Fillory got you
through a lot as a kid.
Yeah.
As a kid. (CHUCKLES)
Sorry, the manager
isn't in right now.
Would you like
to place an order?
I know you know who
lam. Look, I'm sorry
I insulted you guys.
But just who talked
to you? Marina? Pete?
I'm going to call
the cops.
God, Rick, grow a pair!
Wait, wait, wait.
I'm sorry.
Please. I don't know
anyone else.
(CLATTERS)
I'm not done with you.
Consider it a warning.
(DOOR OPENS, CLOSES)
Julia.
Julia, wait.
Okay, just wait.
Marina, okay?
No one wants a war.
Here.
It's about an hour
by train. Went there
couple of years back.
They're real.
They're good.
Just give them a try,
but please don't
come back here again.
(MACHINE BUZZING)
How'd you learn
all this anyway?
Me and a friend got
deep into ink spells
in high school.
Ah...
It's not the Mona Lisa,
but I do have 20/20
vision in the dark.
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
And where was
all this exactly?
I told you, I'm basically
from the 'burbs.
Actually, you never say
a damn thing about your life.
'Cause it's boring.
What flavor of boring?
My mom died young,
and my dad is
kind of embarrassing.
He wears Birkenstocks
and he sells weed, and...
But he loves me
no matter what kind
of trouble I get in.
That sounds nice.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah.
So, this symbol,
will it do anything for
the whole mind-slut shit?
Yeah, you know,
Brakebills is good.
Everyone knows how to pull
their blinds down, you know?
Yeah.
I still hear her, though.
That girl from the dungeon.
Can't shut her out.
I just file that under
"Wish there was jack shit
I could do about it."
Yeah.
Or were you talking
about the Beast?
If I was you,
I'd be curious.
He's full-on AWOL,
not a peep.
So I get this,
and I don't poke the bear.
Let's just hope the bear
has better shit to do.
(CLATTERING)
Shit, shit, shit.
(GASPING)
Hey!
Why are you
following me, lady?
Easy. I just want
to show you
I'm just like you.
(FLOOR CREAKING)
Hello?
ls someone being
creepy on purpose?
(CLATTERING)
Secure the sacrifice!
No! God damn it. No!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(SHUDDERING)
O Manon,
we offer up this virgin,
flesh and blood!
Jesus, I'm not a virgin.
Huh.
Life is full
of surprises.
What the hell, Margo?
Follow, follow.
Hurry, hurry.
Ow.
Guys, the pine
needles are hurting
my feet.
Shh.
Right there.
QUENTIN: Ow, ow.
Hello, first years.
At this appointed hour,
as tradition dictates,
it falls upon the upper class
to administer what is
known simply as
the Trials.
The Trials test
your ability
to think and act
like a Magician.
Pass, your journey begins.
Fail, you flunk out.
This is a test engineered
to thin out the herd.
Only those who should
will survive.
Oh, nut up!
This isn't Harvard.
It requires actual effort.
And don't bother
to go complaining
to the faculty.
They're off on
a luxurious retreat,
observing from a distance.
You are ours, miscreants.
Onward to glory!
Come on! Go! Go!
(ALL CLAMORING)
MARGO: Name, please?
Alice Quinn.
Hmm. Let me see.
Wow, you're really
enjoying this, aren't you?
I have no idea what
you're talking about.
The Trials themselves
have the power, Alice.
They will pass or fail you
as the Dean created them to.
I merely keep a little
eye on each and
every one of you.
Ah, there you are.
Report to the table
on your placard.
Good luck.
Next!
Say one word
about Fillory,
and I'll kill you.
Get me kicked out...
Well, then we'd
finally be even.
Now I get it.
Get what?
Why our team name
is Horny Chupacabras.
I'm not a... (STUTTERING)
I don't even know
what a chupacabra is.
It's a spine-covered
goat-sucking primate
indigenous to Mexico.
I can already see
we are immensely
handicapped by
your presence.
(LAUGHS)
In 18th century England,
a secret society
known as the Brethren
encrypted hundreds of spells
to hide them from the church.
You may open your blue books.
Each team must decode
and cast their spell
by 9:00 a.m.
Screw up, and it's
back to page one.
FYI, this test is pretty
much impossible. Begin.
HANNAH: Back in the day,
we'd travel the world.
We'd pay for spells.
Trade for them.
And they weren't
all the most ambitious
Hedges you ever saw,
but we looked
out for each other.
It was like family.
First family I really
felt I belonged in,
actually.
Okay, so what do
you want exactly?
Well, you know,
our story with Marina,
it's not rare.
I have seen her
chew people up
and spit them out.
Then what? You swoop in,
you buy us a milkshake?
Come on.
(SCOFFS)
Not till today.
You are the first
I believe can
really do things
if given the opportunity
to learn.
I mean, I can feel
it coming off of you.
You're not an amateur.
You're the real thing.
Yeah, well, some think so.
Some do not.
Well, I think we can
help each other.
H ow?
(SNIFFS, CLEARS THROAT)
It's not much, but,
you know, they'll
be new to you, I think.
Waita minute.
How did you...
All over.
Where did you...
You don't want to know.
But you're
welcome to them.
In exchange for what?
Just do some with me.
I miss the feeling,
you know?
(FINGERS SNAPPING)
Welcome, é Ia
Safe House Julia.
Can you make it colder?
Girl, you're strong!
Shit.
Was this the last of them?
Afraid so.
(EXHALES)
Well, hey, we'll
hit the road, right?
Find new stuff.
Try, at least.
But you know who has
a ton of new stuff?
Marina.
'Cause she got
her memories back.
I helped her do it.
She has...
Brakebills.
So she has everything.
We're screwed.
How much time
do we have left?
I don't know.
Who knows how to
read an hourglass?
This is impossible.
Even Eliot said
it was impossible.
Wait, it's impossible.
Actually, he said,
it was practically
impossible,
but maybe some
genius can do this.
So, what, only
geniuses can be
Magicians? Really?
We have to cheat.
They want us to. We've
been Kobayashi Maru-ed.
Whatever that means, yes.
No. No way.
You're an idiot.
We're cheating.
Why would...
Why would they
want us to cheat?
'Cause we're Magicians.
No. No, they just
want to see how
far we can get.
QUENTIN: There's no such
a thing as half a spell.
You guys are insane.
Supply closet.
Five minutes.
I've got a plan.
HANNAH: Oh, man!
They really upped
the security since my day.
How much do you
know about those wards?
Enough to know
they're strong,
but not enough to
break them, so...
What do you think
would happen if we just
ran in there and grabbed
the filing cabinet?
(LAUGHS) Oh, yeah, sure.
You ever see
the movie Scanners?
Oh.
There's a way.
There's always a way.
You have a pen?
Here.
What we need...
Think of it like
a fishhook.
We grab the cabinets
from the room without
tripping wards.
There's wards
all over the room.
Yeah, in this
dimension, sure.
The one thing I can't
figure out is how
to get the hook in.
You know, we need
someone inside for that.
And I sort of burned
all my bridges with that.
You think we can
pay someone off?
No.
I know someone.
(ENGINE STARTING)
Took you long enough.
Okay, here's the question.
Do you believe
what you said earlier,
that a genius could
solve this by dawn?
Well, yeah, I mean,
if they were...
Alice Quinn?
If anyone, she could.
Can you read her mind?
No. Unlike you,
she's airtight.
But I can do one better.
Just light
the fucking thing.
Nicely done.
Perfect execution.
Too bad I know
you cheated.
Congratulations,
you two, and on to
the second Trial.
Well, what about...
Thinning the herd.
So are you gonna tell
me who we're meeting?
Yeah, she's not
a hedge witch exactly,
but, well, her and
I have some history.
So I think it's best...
What do you mean by "history"?
Hey, chickadee!
Mom, you shouldn't
be here.
(CHUCKLES)
This is your daughter.
What's she doing here?
She's a friend.
Okay, come on, babe.
Please, sit.
How are you?
How have you been?
(SCOFFS) Just tell me
what you want, Mom.
I want to give
you something.
Oh, that's so sweet!
Yeah, my birthday
was seven months ago.
Kady, look, I was not
in a good place
the last time
you saw me,
but my shit's
together now.
Oh, is it? ls that why
you're hanging out
with the angriest
bitch from the safe house?
Oh, if you want
to insult me, you
should try again.
Just“
Listen.
I called because
Julia and I have
a line on something.
Oh, my God,
here we go again.
We're gonna
start our own house.
Nothing crazy, but
it'll be safe from Marina,
so come with us.
My God, you're insane.
You actually think
that you can beat her.
Hey, Marina's strong,
but so are we.
Nothing like
that at school, huh?
Protection charm.
It'll render our
house literally invisible.
You know,
the amazing thing is
you actually believe that
this plan could work.
Marina will never
let me go.
Even
Oh, did Hannah give you
the whole sob story?
HANNAH: Kady...
No, no.
Marina didn't
betray my mom.
She cleaned up
her mess.
Yeah, Hannah, well,
she wanted to steal
something. Big heist, right?
Except she can't
handle her shit
under pressure,
and two people died.
Cut to now, Marina
gets to demand
that I steal shit
10 times a week.
Yeah, no big.
Don't call me again.
You can't take that!
Letherhaveit
No, we need it.
So does she.
If I had more,
I'd give you more.
Yeah.
But you don't.
You sold your
daughter to Marina?
No, Marina stole her.
Yeah, because of
a really bad judgment
call that you made.
She said she had
my back. This is not
black and white.
Yeah, well, Kady sure
seems to think that it is.
If this goes how we want,
I can fix that, too.
"If this..."
Do you hear yourself?
"If this works out"?
I'm out.
Oh, no, you don't.
You do not cut me off.
My daughterjust
got brought into this.
And I will share with
you everything I can,
but it is better that I
see this through alone.
This looks like a home brew.
Where did you get it?
Found it inside
an old textbook.
(INHALES)
It looks underwhelming.
So how's Professor
March's research going?
Look, I tried,
but he won't take on
first year assistants.
Well, you'rejust
his type, so I'm sure
you'll figure it out.
"But where's
the door, Martin?
"There's always
a door to Fillory
when we really need it.
"In the clock,
or the closet,
or my panties?"
Come on, celebrate!
You passed, you dirty cheater.
What's the problem?
Speak.
No offense,
you're just not exactly...
Warm and cuddly?
I know.
You ever want
something so badly
and then realize
that it's nothing
like what you thought,
and maybe that
you are stupid
for ever actually
even wanting it?
Every guy I've
ever slept with.
Fillory is real.
Oh, come the fuck on.
It is.
Penny is a Traveler,
and he went there,
and it's real.
Look like your head's
about to pop off.
I loved those books.
You did?
Why so surprised?
I'd pretend I was
ambassador to
the Fillorian Outer Islands.
But the real thing,
it's not like the story.
So, what, it's actually
totally shitty over there?
I don't know.
Maybe. Yes.
At least a little.
The thing that attacked
us, that ripped
the Dean's eyes out,
seems like it might
be from Fillory.
Jesus.
That is not tonally
consistent with the books.
No, it's not.
And that... I just...
I find that devastating.
Were you planning
a trip there?
No, really.
Because, otherwise,
you're literally
torturing yourself
over a fairy tale.
Quentin, you passed
the first Trial.
You live to fight
another day.
Drink up. Go to the party.
Find someone to bang.
Celebrate the world
you're in, dummy.
Come on!
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
Okay-
Well, I'm a little...
I am very...
Wow, I'm really, uh...
Margo, did you
roofie me?
(THUD5)
Can we skip down
to where you realize
you no makey magic here?
(ELIOT LAUGHS MALICIOUSLY)
Oh. Cucumber.
Daddy's favorite.
And too much dill.
(SPITS)
There they all are,
all those little fishies,
just like us,
eaﬁng,shHﬂng,
breeding.
I require one.
It's over there.
(CLAPS) Chop chop.
lam literally
losing the will to live.
So this is
my next test?
I'm supposed to
spear a fish?
Do your lips move
when you read?
Seriously? One arrow?
Eliot!
(NEIGHING)
Bring him to me.
Why?
I want to get my
Catherine the Great on.
Google it.
Totally hilarious.
Oh, and to help you out.
No. Just no, okay?
Okay-
Wait.
I'm seeing
your future now.
Gay porn?
(GASPS)
(CHUCKLES)
Mi favorito.
Liver.
HANNAH: Julia, stop!
You're gonna blow
yourself up!
I was getting it.
You really weren't, hon.
How did you get in?
I unpicked your ward.
I would go with
Koyosegi next time.
Thank you for the advice.
Now, can you please leave?
We already agreed
that we're not
partners, okay?
Well, it didn't work
because you need
10 extra digits.
Actually, I don't.
It's interesting
how you can't
look at me.
Know why?
'Cause I'm too familiar.
I mean, we both
made mistakes.
We live with
them. We go on.
Alone,
if we have to.
But you do
this alone,
and you will get hurt.
Come on.
We can help
each other out.
Please.
I want my
daughter back.
Kady?
Kady. Hey, Kadv!
Kady.Kady!
Stop it! Stop m Stop it!
Let go! Let go!
No.
I have to catch the bird.
No! Hey!
This shit is dumb.
The school is not worth it.
No, I can't! You don't get it.
I can't get kicked out!
Ow! Fuck!
Oh, my God.
Jesus.
Oh, my God. ls it broken?
I don't know. Ah.
Let me see. Let me see.
Let me look at it.
It's not broken.
Look, talk to me.
What's going on?
Look, it's just... (GASPS)
This is all I have.
Me, too.
(SOBBING)
No, it's different.
I'm different.
I need Brakebills.
It's life or death.
I have to be here.
Hey-
(SOBBING)
(GASPING)
What are you
supposedto
get with that?
(LAUGHS)
A fucking pheasant.
You?
A horse.
These people are crazy.
Let's go find
the others.
Come on.
PENNY: Yo!
Seriously, dude,
I almost had him.
We'll get him, son.
It's not about magic
'cause it's about
talking to each other.
All right, you got that.
But I grew up in Florida,
so I actually
know how to use it
to get your fish.
But I'm after a horse.
Seriously?
What?
Junior Cowboy Camp.
Pheasant
Tree.
(GRUNTING)
(HORSE WHINNYING)
You're bleeding.
I hated
Junior Cowboy Camp.
Timber!
(RUMBLING)
MARGO: Bravo!
Brava. Brava.
That's it?
We passed?
After you chop
the tree into firewood,
whip us up
a little grilled salmon.
MARGO: Some honeyed pheasant.
And take turns
blowing the horse.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(BOTH SIGHING HAPPILY)
Did you see the look
on Quentin's face?
Yes.
Like, "Fine, but
lam not going first."
(LAUGHS)
I'm sure by now,
you've realized
Brakebills teaches
us to be arch and
ironic about magic.
But this one plays it serious.
You must bare yourself
in the presence of
another magical adept
and expose your highest
governing internal
circumstance,
which is to say
your utmost truth.
You have till midnight.
Ready?
(CHANTING)
(BOTH CHANTING)
(RUMBLING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Oh, shit!
Shit!
No!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(ALL NOISES STOP)
(EXHALES)
Okay, it's
a two-person spell.
Both must succeed
to unlock it.
You bind your
hands with this rope.
How am I gonna survive?
It'll fall off once
you've reached
transcendence.
Okay, it's got
to be some kind
of scheme, right?
To record us playing
naked truth-or-dare,
so they can blackmail
us or something.
Unfortunately,
Margo wasn't lying.
It's arcane and
a bit unorthodox,
but Secrets Magic
is a real thing.
Basically, there's no
trick or cheat to this.
It's kind of
the exact opposite.
(CHUCKLES)
Focus.
I'm trying.
All clear. Good to go.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God, no.
Run.
Hannah!Hannah!
You said it was all clear.
You said it was gonna be okay.
Go! Run!
Marina is coming.
We need to get
you help.
OPERATOR: 911.
What's your emergency?
(HANNAH GASPING)
You know, it's not
part of the spell,
but I think it could
make things easier.
You know,
I always thought
when I partook in
a nude magic ritual
that I'd be sort of
in a mystical trance.
(SIGHS)
Tell that to the girl
who lost her virginity
with all her clothes on.
(BLACK OUT DAYS
BY PHANTOGRAM PLAYING)
Hide the sun
l will leave your
face out of my mind
You should save your eyes
A thousand voices
howling in my head
Okay-
Uh...
I've been institutionalized
more than once.
Maybe we
shouldn't drink.
Or we should
drink more.
Yeah.
(CHUCKLES)
William. Really?
Ask me something
harder if you want
us to get somewhere.
(BLACK OUT DAYS
BY PHANTOGRAM CONTINUES)
Away, away
Ask me why
I'm nice to you.
I had noticed
you're a tad brusque
with everyone else.
And why is that?
Penny,
you don't have to.
Look, I'm not scared
to tell you this
because it's true.
Shit.
Okay-
Truth.
lam scared to tell you
this because it's true.
I'm falling in love with you.
AH the stars
are shining bloody red
I can't do this.
Kady, I'm not gonna
chase after...
You won't have to.
What does that mean?
Look, I'm a liar,
okay?
I flirted with
you that first day
because you looked
useful, and you were.
Look, we stole a lot
of shit, so there it is.
I've been using
you this entire time.
It's all a lie.
(SONG PLAYING)
Black out days
I don't recognize you anymore
Penny.
QUENTIN AND ALICE: Five.
Four
Three.
Two.
(BELL TOLLING)
One.
I need to sit.
I really didn't
see this coming.
How could you?
You're the best.
You know what?
I try so hard
not to be.
Why?
I'm already pretty
damn unpopular.
Can you imagine
what they would think
if they knew how
good I really am?
"Spinster Magician
dies alone eaten by cats."
I always hold
back, Quentin.
Every single day.
I mean,
I have no idea what
I'm even capable of,
and I'm just
trying so hard
to be anything
close to normal.
My friend Julia
said that I couldn't
run away hard enough.
She's right.
lrun,andl“.
I find secret doors.
Whether I'm alone
or in a group
doesn't matter.
Like, I'm here.
I'm in this amazing place.
I have literal
magic in my life,
and I'm still running.
I'm still this person
that I fucking hate.
Sorry. (CLEARS THROAT)
I'm really drunk right now.
It's okay, Quentin.
I get it.
Your ropes are gone.
Yeah, so are yours.
(GASPING)
(GRUNTS)
Alice,
... (GASPS)
(GASPING)
(HONKING)
(GEESE HONKING IN DISTANCE)