EMBER: Hello, glorious audience,
it is I, Ember, God of Fillory.
Feel free to bow
and grovel. I'll wait.
Oh, but I've got
so much to tell you.
I, with minor help from
my brother, Umber, RIP,
created a world
intricate as filigree.
And that is what I called it. Except
I was a bit drunk so... "Fillory."
Chock-stuffed with magic,
chatty animals, sexy creatures.
Really, what a planet.
I calibrated everything for
maximum entertainment.
I decreed it be ruled
by Children of Earth,
a glum little planet known
for its plucky Magicians.
These brave souls would come, and
when they got boring, off they went.
Case in point, Martin
Chatwin. Brave, clever boy.
Born hero.
Yet, honestly, very uncomfortable
to watch once he'd been molested.
So I made the difficult
decision to kick him out
and replace him with
someone more punchy and fun.
But Martin was more tenacious
than I gave him credit for.
He drank from the
Wellspring to get strong,
screwing Fillory in the process,
and set booby traps
for my brother and me.
And before you
know it, Umber's dead,
and I'm hiding in stupid Loria.
I'm so fucking bored,
Children of Earth.
EMBER: Cut to...
Martin's mutated into a
terrible beast in a dapper suit.
Enter Quentin
Coldwater and his friends,
the Addict, the Victim, the
Bitch, the Scowl and the Martyr.
I bestowed my blessing and
they set out to kill The Beast.
Of course they failed.
Twist!
They have to start from
scratch with The Beast. Thrilling!
The danger of sublimated trauma
is a major theme in our story,
evidenced by Julia and Martin
teaming up to kill the
Earth god who violated her.
All very ambiguous and poignant,
I know!
Julia's partnership also threw a
massive wrench into Quentin's works.
Gut-wrenching!
I was forced to
intervene. Cameo!
I have befouled the Wellspring.
Wasn't it tragic
when Alice died?
Wasn't it scary when
she became a Niffin?
The personal nature of her story
subverted Quentin's hero's journey nicely.
Character is destiny,
and, ultimately,
Quentin is a
Magician of intellect,
who nevertheless, and to his
detriment, acts from his heart.
But I did other things too, like
lead Quentin to that candy witch.
Don't worry, that'll pay off.
I hid the Wellspring
bowl in plain sight.
Made the Rainbow Bridge bloom.
Stole from the River Watcher so he'd be
good and angry when Penny stiffed him.
Oh, I know, good one.
It was I who caused
the High King's bride
to ovulate on the
right day, leading to...
(IN FALSETTO) Pregnant!
(IN NORMAL VOICE)
Ultimately leading to...
(IN FALSETTO) The Fairies
can bring back the Wellspring?
They can.
And in return?
A royal child of Whitespire.
Take her to the dungeon.
It will transport you
to the Fairy Realm.
(IN NORMAL VOICE) I repeatedly
broke the filtration system,
so the Wellspring would
be unpredictable and fun.
All those pesky
"brown outs." Moi!
To be sure, The
Order is on to me.
They're in a panic about
the Great Blank Spot,
surmising a fatal
hit to the Wellspring.
True, I am nearly
finished with Fillory.
Every chapter must end, and on
the eve of my benevolent destruction,
I'm getting it all
out of my system.
Like, causing sudden climate change that
kills entire tedious species of wildlife.
Turning people
into delicious rats.
All the babies this week
woke up with no mouths.
Oh, horrifying. (SCREAMS)
I bet you're wondering
what happens next.
And that is how I know
I've done my job well.
Sit back, have a nice pipe of
marijuana and enjoy my grand opus.
I call it Fillory's last gasp.
(WIND HOWLING)
(SIGHS)
I just miss the fire, okay?
Drink this.
What is it?
Renders you unable
to harm your own body.
(WHISPERING)
This is all pointless, Q.
You can't medicate me away...
Just fucking drink it.
All of it.
(BURPS) Ugh!
Why did you bring me back?
Why do you keep asking me that?
(SCOFFS)
I watched you almost die
trying to bring your brother back.
You loved him. I love you.
(SCOFFS)
I'd like to be alone now.
(COUGHING)
I take that to
mean I'm improving.
Well, your skin's healing.
Obviously your lungs
are, to use a technical term,
fucked,
but more importantly...
Just say it.
You have lesions on your spine.
And they're growing
aggressively.
Cancer.
Call it cancer-plus.
Whatever you were exposed
to has spell residue all over it.
So a Magician did this?
Well, if so, it may be
a code we can crack.
How long?
Well, it's hard to say,
but I have my entire
department working on it. I...
I mean, how long till I
die. If you don't crack it.
Two or three weeks.
But I promise you, we are
doing everything we can to just...
(GRUNTS) Okay...
Yeah, I'm not waiting
to die in a hospital bed.
Okay. I don't... I'm not!
(GRUNTS)
(WHISPERING) Can
we talk, please? Yes.
(SCOFFS)
(GRUNTS)
KADY: Hey there, hot stuff.
No offense, you might
look as bad as I do.
I doubt that.
You're dying.
All I am is a little strung out.
Kady.
What? It's not about me.
What happened? Just tell me.
Reynard's gone.
I should be happy,
but it wasn't how I wanted it.
It's not enough.
God, I feel like bashing
my head into a wall.
(SNIFFLES AND SIGHS)
Why can't anything
just be fixed?
Life. I guess. (SCOFFS)
(SNIFFLES)
(VOICE BREAKING)
I don't want you to die.
'Course not. I'm the
best lay of your life.
(LAUGHING) Shut up.
What are we gonna do?
Wrap our minds around it.
Kady, let's not waste
time being mad, okay?
I'm just gonna find
Quentin and Eliot.
Just gonna make a
couple pit stops first.
(HORNS HONKING
DISTANTLY) (SIRENS WAILING)
(SNIFFS)
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
(EXHALES SHAKILY)
It's, um, a nice
sconce. Did you, um...
Spit it out.
You want something.
Yeah. First...
(EXHALES)
Are you okay?
I'm whole again.
Which is a good thing?
If by good you mean crying jags
and mountains of
guilt and panic attacks,
then, yeah, I'm
doing fucking great.
And since I better be getting
back to one of those soon,
whether I like it or not,
how can I help you?
Q says you have an amulet that
would make me invisible to a god.
(GROANS)
(SIGHS)
(SOBS)
Um, I don't pretend to understand
what you've been through,
but I can tell you the way you're relating
to that couch is not unknown to me.
Then you know I
want to be alone.
And, um, also that you
probably shouldn't be right now.
Why do you care?
I just do.
Come with me
and help me try to convince
Ember to let us keep Fillory.
Why?
Because I have never met anyone
less willing to take no for an answer.
But I betrayed you, remember?
(INHALES DEEPLY)
That was a long time ago.
(CLEARS THROAT) I
need help, and you do, too.
Let's kill a few birds.
What do you say?
Wanna put some pants on
and help me save all of magic?
I'll go talk to
Eliot and Quentin.
Uh, Kady...
Just tell Penny that I went to
find a quiet place to do some dope.
I'm ready to leave when he is.
Look, here's the deal.
I just read your
book in the Library.
Both volumes.
My book? Why?
Because it ends the way
they all do in a couple days.
With 20 blank pages.
Something's about to happen.
Something magical,
and really fucking bad.
And I think it's... It's Ember.
He's been doing all sorts
of fucked up shit in Fillory.
"Bucket list" shit.
What's in my book?
You do your recon,
find out Prince Ess of
Loria has taken Whitespire.
Shit.
Then kidnap Idri,
who I guess is a rat?
Turn him back, then camp here
trying to find the perfect spell
to force Ember to keep
his mitts off of Fillory.
But if my book ends
then... Then... Exactly.
We know that doesn't work.
So you need to do anything else.
Anything. Pick a plan and commit.
If it's written,
isn't it written?
Yes. But I think
you can change it.
Okay, so we can save Fillory
if we subscribe to a free-will
view of the universe, which is fair.
So what am I supposed to do?
Go. Get Idri. Hurry.
I just got one thing
I gotta button up.
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey. I calculated
a portal to Tahiti.
Hold up.
No. You warned them.
You've done enough,
you get to be done.
I'm sorry. Believe
me, I'd rather...
No. None of it matters, Penny.
(WHOOSHING) Oh, come on!
Penny, you're needed at once.
I'm busy. Bit of an emergency,
we need our full staff.
Are you crazy? He's dying.
Yes, because he went
into a restricted area,
which lethally poisoned him
and puts him on strict probation,
but most assuredly does not
mean he is excused from work.
We'll take every step
to keep him comfortable.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Kady, knowledge
itself is at stake.
That is more important
than any single one of us.
I'll give you a moment
to say goodbye.
No. No. Not goodbye.
Kady, listen, I... No. I am
telling you, this isn't fair.
(WHOOSHING)
God damn it! Fuck.
(SIGHS)
MARGO: Just crack the damn lock.
Hurry, before some
Fairy asshole sees us.
JOSH: I'm going
as fast as I can.
Fen, are you okay?
Sweetie, do you
know where you are?
A plane laid atop our own,
so, the Fairy Castle and Whitespire
actually occupy the same space and time,
but two dimensions, or
possibly the same dimension,
but incredibly sped up like that
one episode of Star Trek where...
Just get the damn chain, Josh.
No.
Not without my baby.
They took her away.
You have to come with us, okay?
Get the goddamn
shackles, Hoberman.
Grab her with me.
Come on. Come on.
There you are. The
Queen will see you now.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(FROGS CROAKING)
(CROAKING)
You've been making yourself quite
at home sneaking around my castle.
It's actually more
like my castle
that you guys have made
some weird AM radio version of.
What is it that you
seek, rude little Earth girl?
The woman and child you stole.
You made a deal.
That deal was inhumane
bullshit, made under total duress.
Look, just tell me what
you want, okay, lady?
The child is mine.
Now, onto the
business at hand...
No, the baby is the business.
FAIRY QUEEN: Ember is
dangerously bored of Fillory.
You underestimated how
devastating it can be to displease a god.
We've been trying to get a
hold of Ember for months.
He ignores us.
Because you ask for things.
Offer something to him instead.
How do you know all this?
As it is in our shared interest
for your High King to succeed,
I'm inclined to let
you go help him.
Great.
Josh, Fen, the baby
and I will go right now.
You know it doesn't
work that way.
Now, are you familiar with this?
No...
Fucking goddamn... (SNIFFS)
Smells good. (LAUGHS)
Even better to a god.
It will draw Ember.
Take it, bake it into...
I know this one. Little cakes.
He loves little cakes.
Okay.
Point the way back.
Certainly.
As soon as I've
exacted the toll.
Travel from this world costs,
dear. I don't make the rules.
Oh, that's right. Yes, I do.
We'll be seeing each
other soon, I suspect.
So, how is Alice?
Okay, Eliot, I... We
need your help, Q.
You gave her the no-secret-cutting
shit from the keg, right?
Yes, physically
she's perfectly safe.
But mentally... (SIGHS HEAVILY)
What am I supposed to do?
You know what you learn
when you're a High King?
Screwing up is inevitable.
And there are some
fuckups you can never unfuck.
It's infuriating and it's
heartbreaking, but...
I think I destroyed her, Eliot.
She made plenty of her
own choices along the way.
I'm not saying it doesn't suck.
I'm saying, Fillory needs you.
You chose to be a king.
This is what that means.
We have a plan,
but we need someone
who speaks fluent fanboy.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
What on Earth are you
doing here, sad little nerd king?
You're sitting in
my chair, asshole.
Where the hell are the guards?
Fast asleep, sorry.
Watch where you
point that thing.
Dad, you're okay.
I had to do this.
You were a rat...
Can I have my throne back now?
I'll fight if you want. I've become
pretty boss with a broadsword.
You have, so don't.
(SIGHS)
Fine.
Always did like to storm out.
(DOOR SLAMS)
I should go, too.
I should be there for my
people, whatever happens.
You mean, in case I fail?
You won't.
(CHUCKLES)
You know, since
Ember banished me,
I wonder if that nullified
my whole Fillorian contract.
We could check.
Okay, so the thing is, this, um,
Blank Spot, it's coming up fast.
And it lines up with everything
that you were
saying about Ember.
Is this tree too asymmetrical?
It's nice. I...
(SIGHS)
So, there's no way that you
would want to help us, like, at all?
One cannot just show up after
one's faked one's own death.
I'm sorry.
The end of Fillory
makes me sad as well.
So Fillory really is done?
I like you. You
care about things.
Yeah, it's not really a
trait that's helped me much.
But it could be,
if it were applied to not
trying to fix the unfixable,
but rather something
fresh and more perfect.
Like, say...
Care to take a visit?
Make some notes?
Um, I, uh...
I'm sorry, but you're
acting like I'm asking you,
whereas I am a god and
you're a hairless monkey,
so nod and say thank you.
(MOUTHING) All right!
Let's go to the pocket world
formerly known as Cuba!
(WHOOSHING)
(RHYTHMIC THRUMMING)
JOSH: Whoa. (MARGO
BREATHING HEAVILY)
Coming back from the Fairy world
was a little rockier
than getting there.
You don't fucking say.
Are you okay?
Jesus.
Fen wouldn't come because
they have your daughter.
I'm sorry.
I'll keep trying. I promise, El.
First, we need to deal
with that cock Ember.
We come bearing bait. (CHUCKLES)
I look like Jack Sparrow if
he were played by a man.
I was actually thinking
more like a Fembot Nick Fury.
Look... No, I need to...
I know. Okay?
I was angry.
And scared of what
you were capable of.
But you were doing your
best in an impossible position
that would have crushed
anyone, myself included.
Wait, is your good
eye crying right now?
No...
Yes.
And it's not my good eye.
It's my only fucking eye.
(CHUCKLES)
It's not funny, you
dick. I'm a cyclops.
A mythological monster
at last. Box checked.
We're trying too hard.
Pardon?
To just blow past and banter.
It's not the same. Let's
not pretend it is, okay?
That makes it hurt worse.
I guess we'll just have to live with
the strain till the future reveals itself.
Meantime, that future's gonna be
a big, blank, post-apocalyptic nada
unless we do what we do best.
Act out with a total lack of
empathy and impulse control?
Party like the
world depends on it.
'Cause, Bambi-One-Eye, it do.
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
(LAUGHTER, CHATTER)
(MOANING SOFTLY)
Oh, my God.
I threw better orgies
when I was 10.
I give you little cakes.
(ALL APPLAUDING)
JOSH: I know they're irresistible.
It's the candied Fairy hemp.
But resist. This is
for our guest of honor.
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
NIGEL: Be brutal.
It's really...
It's really linear.
(CHAIR SCRAPING)
How's the linguini?
There's nothing wrong with it.
Excellent. That's excellent.
(CLEARS THROAT)
It's maybe a little, uh...
Chewy?
Bland.
Bland "good"? Or...
Bland is never
really good or bad.
It appeals to all tastes.
Sure.
But usually people, uh... Creatures
who can think, gods, even...
They sometimes like the unknown,
the unexpected,
even the offensive.
Little bit of, uh...
Chaos.
Happy now?
You know who'd love this?
Who'd create an entire
world out of this greasy stain?
My brother.
Yes, Ember would make a mess...
Do not speak to me of Ember!
I like you, boy, but
I have a temper.
Wait, what about
a human sacrifice?
No! Unless the cakes
are bad. (SIGHS)
Well, they smell great, but I
don't think they're working, so...
(WHOOSHING) EMBER: Little cakes.
Mmm. Oh!
Mmm. Oh, oh.
Oh, yes.
Welcome, Ember, God of Gods.
Wait, didn't I banish you?
You did, Lord of All, but...
I didn't expect
this... I can explain...
I love it.
(SIGHS) A genuine twist,
a true surprise. (GIGGLES)
When was the last time
that happened around here?
Exactly, and we're
really sorry about that.
We've fallen down on the
job, but boredom is death,
I totally agree.
Isn't it, though? It is.
But we can make Fillory more
exciting and watchable than ever.
That's our pitch.
It's a new chapter,
and the title is,
"Shit Tons of
Drama and Surprise."
Intriguing.
How?
Don't destroy Fillory.
Shake things up, yes.
Like the rats.
ELIOT: (LAUGHS) Yeah.
The rats were hilarious.
It was good, wasn't it?
We're all still laughing. Right?
Mmm-hmm. Laughing?
(ALL LAUGHING)
There's so much more to do here.
So many twists and surprises
this world can offer. Mmm.
Think back to the moment you
created the first blades of grass.
Sentient trees.
Talking animals.
ELIOT: The Wellspring.
Think back to what you
built with your brother Umber.
My brother, rest his soul,
was nothing but a simpering,
sniping, anal retentive critic.
As well as a...
Greedy, promiscuous, selfish,
credit-hogging, mouse-eating slob.
Any talk of this is mere whimsy.
And it is whimsy itself that I
am tired of and finished with.
We get it, we do.
I mean, try ruling a world
of whimsy, am I right?
Mmm. Not so whimsical, actually.
Well, then, let's
get it over with.
Why wait? Let's start right now.
No, no, no. (RUMBLING)
Okay, wait a minute. Rewind, rewind,
rewind. (PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Stop! Are you
insane, you can't...
Margo! I mean, we meant,
make it better, make it better.
Less whimsical! More
meaner maybe, more you.
Maybe. If I didn't
have to do it alone.
Say what you will about
my dear departed brother,
but he was a demon for overwork.
Hmm. He had a
strange love for this...
Poor accursed place.
Too late to be helped now.
I couldn't bear to go back.
(STUTTERS) I won't. I won't.
Um, actually,
we're already there.
Where?
Apocalypse, apocalypse,
apocalypse! (LAUGHING)
Isn't it wonderful?
What are you doing?
You're making a mess!
(GRUNTING)
I'm back? (CHUCKLES)
EMBER: You're alive.
(LAUGHS)
How is this possible, brother?
You died battling
Martin to save me.
(CHUCKLES)
Why are you afraid?
I am so pleased.
Martin told me you died...
When he banished me.
Hey, guys. How about a hug?
MARGO: This is a family reunion.
EMBER: This was
a family betrayal.
Wasn't it?
No!
No! I can't be here.
Oh! All this time, I
thought Martin so powerful.
But, no.
He was merely a
brilliant dealmaker.
My banishment for your life.
Your puny, petty, putrid,
nothing of a soul spark.
(GRUNTS)
(ALL GRUNTING)
Please.
(GRUNTS) (GROANS)
Please!
You always were the weak one.
(CHOKING) (LAUGHS)
(SWORD CLANGING)
(CHOKING)
(GRUNTS)
(CHANTING QUIETLY)
Come and get me,
you fucking baby.
You wanna know
why you're so bored?
Because you're
too stupid to get it,
you're too spoiled and
entitled to understand...
How dare you? I am a god.
Are you? Really?
I'm not impressed.
I've met scary gods. And you?
You're nothing
but a petty tyrant.
(CHOKING)
(EMBER GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
Quentin? (GROANS)
You always surprise.
(GROANS)
(EMBER WHIMPERS)
(GASPS)
Holy fuck.
ELIOT: Q?
I think you just saved
the whole world.
ELIOT: We are officially a
land of godless heathens,
making today the first day
of our societal adulthood.
I, for one, am slightly
terrified and equally excited.
And trying not to
break into Hamilton.
And so I turn over the next phase of
our maturation to our High Queen Margo.
We need a constitution.
PICKWICK: Pardon?
These are some pretty good ones
here so let's rip off the best parts.
Hungry?
I know Mayakovsky said
soft bland food for a while,
but I can see that's
not really working.
So I stopped by the farm
where Fogg gets his
weekly rasher of bacon.
No, thanks.
QUENTIN: You sure?
(GROANS)
Because I tried it
and, uh, it's amazing.
ALICE: I know what
you're trying to do.
I'm just trying to do
breakfast food. That's all.
Oh, fuck you.
Mmm.
Please.
Fuck.
Gluttony.
It's an excellent
part of being human.
I don't remember many others.
Really?
Ugh.
Hmm, my hands are all greasy.
With every good thing
no matter how small it is,
it's always married to something
so completely disgusting.
You can't escape it.
You're right. It's
gross. We are animals.
Why does that feel so good?
I don't know.
It just does.
And always did.
(BREATHING RAGGEDLY)
(CHUCKLES)
(FOGHORN BLOWING)
Look, I need your help.
I'm not gonna beg.
I'm not gonna use
guilt. I have no leverage.
But Penny is in the Library.
He can be your mole.
But to do that, he'd
have to be alive.
He'd never know.
Whatever you need, ask me
about it. He tells me, I tell you.
Who saved her man's life, so
maybe not. Big picture, right?
Deal?
Deal.
You know, I probably
shouldn't say this out loud, but...
This was kind of an okay day.
Are you bragging?
No...
Kind of.
Not about this.
Entirely.
I also kind of killed a god.
(LAUGHS, SNORTS)
Huh. Hilarious.
No. Serious.
Ember...
I mean, he was
erasing the whole thing.
Wait, you can't be serious.
Yeah.
No, no, no.
No, I didn't want to.
He just killed his brother,
he was going after Julia.
He was genocidally insane...
You don't get it.
Jesus.
When I was a Niffin,
I... I saw things.
I saw everything from
the beginning of time.
Alice, calm down.
No. I understand the
way the universe works, Q.
The Wellspring, the
hierarchies, the plumbing.
I was inside it.
Gods like Ember
have parents, you idiot.
I'm not following.
The Old Gods.
The creators of the
universe, of all magic itself.
To Ember, we're like toys,
but to the them we're cells.
When we're harmless,
they ignore us.
But when we become
malignant, they amputate.
Now, if you're gonna use
stones like this. (DOOR OPENS)
It's imperative that...
Excuse me. Excuse me. This...
QUENTIN: Okay. Wait.
There's an actual plumber, like
the Mario Brother of the gods?
Yes.
And he can just... I
guarantee you, he's doing it.
(POWER WINDING DOWN)
(ALL GASP)
(ALARM WHOOPING)
FEMALE AUTOMATED
VOICE: (ON PA) Attention.
Please keep calm and
follow all code procedures.
Please remember not to interact
and safely gather all the
things as you cautiously exit.
Attention. Please
keep calm and follow...
(CLANGS)
Professor!
Mayakovsky!
Holy shit.
All right, everyone. Open
your books to Chapter 16.
Who can translate the Borkulo
Rendering from its original Hungarian?
No point in raising
hands. Remember?
I can.
Dean Fogg? Sorry to interrupt...
Yes, Josh. Go ahead.
Well, I was online last night...
And the answer is no.
There is no actual evidence of a
magical surge in Sedona, Arizona.
Yeah, but what about... Or
Kenya or Machu Picchu or China.
Or anywhere.
Magic is gone.
The best we can
do is accept that
and continue our theoretical
studies to stay ready for its return.
So you think that's possible.
Anything is possible, Alice.
Was, anyway.
MAN: Look at you.
Playing the part of
the bright young girl.
Joseph?
Ah, yes.
I can see my
Alice in there still.
Good.
Are you all right?
I am as I appear. Dying.
So, it is true? Magic's
gone everywhere.
The creatures, cryptids,
sylphs, dragons, unicorns,
even the pointless
vampires are all as they were.
But those of us who drew on
the power of the Wellspring...
Well, as you can see.
I want to help.
I'm here, Alice, because
it is you who needs help.
What?
As a Niffin, you made enemies.
I'm here to warn you that
one of them seeks you.
Who?
The Lamprey.
You do recall what
you did to his family?
Yes.
Most amusing at the time.
But to The Lamprey,
cause for vengeance.
It knows you're weak.
It knows you're here.
What...
(GASPING)
MARGO: Democracy
has to take a backseat.
Without magic, the
people are terrified.
And that is just one
step from an angry mob...
And that's how royal
heads end up in baskets.
I get it. I get it.
This is an undereducated,
pre-industrial populace, Eliot.
They need to be ruled.
They need to be inspired.
They need to think they're being
inspired, as they're being ruled.
I'm talking curfew,
martial law, conscription
and severe and
public punishment.
Okay, can we maybe make our way
to King and Queen Caligula, please?
Maybe, uh...
How do you not recognize
me? I'm the king's wife, tell them.
Oh, my God.
ELIOT: Are you okay? Yes.
How did you get here?
Simple. (SNIFFS) I
just gave them my toes.
Gave who your toes?
The Fairies.
I wanted to stay,
to be close to our daughter,
but I had to warn you.
They're coming.
They're here.
(GASPS) (GOBLET CLATTERS)
Boo.
Hey.
QUENTIN: Jules, I...
JULIA: Hi. (LAUGHS)
How did you get in here?
Well, your fence
is a little shoddy.
Right.
Welcome to the new normal.
You know, 'cause I killed
all magic fucking everywhere.
(BOTH SCOFFING)
JULIA: Sorry, that was
definitely a two-hander,
I'll be burning in
hell right next to you.
But, hey, at least
we have each other.
Hmm.
So, how are you?
Fine.
Listen... How's law school?
I quit.
Okay. Why?
Because I need to
show you something.
And you need to promise me
that you're not going to tell anyone.
'Cause you're the
only person that I trust.
I promise.
Jules, it's not gonna work.
Just gimme a second. (SIGHS)
We all get flashes that
we can do it again, but it's...
(SIZZLING)
Oh, my God. (CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
How?
I have no idea.