Hello, glorious audience.
It is I, Ember, god of Fillory.
Feel free to bow and grovel. I'll wait.
Oh, but I've got so much to tell you.
I, with minor help from my
brother Umber... R.I.P....
created a world intricate as filigree,
and that is what I called it,
except I was a bit drunk, so... Fillory.
Chock stuffed with magic,
chatty animals,
sexy creatures.
Really, what a planet.
I calibrated everything
for maximum entertainment.
I decreed it be ruled
by children of Earth,
a glum little planet known
for its plucky magicians.
These brave souls would come,
and when they got boring, off they went.
Case in point, Martin Chatwin.
Brave, clever boy, born hero,
yet honestly,
very uncomfortable to watch
once he'd been molested.
So, I made the difficult decision
to kick him out and replace him
with someone more punchy and fun,
but Martin was more tenacious
than I gave him credit for.
He drank from the
Wellspring to get strong,
screwing Fillory in the process,
and set booby traps
for my brother and me,
and before you know it, Umber's dead
and I'm hiding in stupid Loria.
I'm so fucking bored, children of Earth.
Cut two... Martin's mutated
into a terrible beast in a dapper suit.
Enter Quentin Coldwater
and his friends...
the Addict, the Victim,
the Bitch, the Scowl,
and the Martyr.
I bestowed my blessing,
and they set out to kill The Beast.
Of course, they failed.
Twist! They had to start from scratch
with The Beast. Thrilling.
The danger of sublimated trauma
is a major theme in our story,
evidenced by Julia and Martin teaming up
to kill the Earth god who violated her.
All very ambiguous and poignant... I know!
Julia's partnership also
threw a massive wrench
into Quentin's works. Gut-wrenching!
I was forced to intervene. Cameo!
I have the befouled the Wellspring.
Wasn't it tragic when Alice died?
Wasn't it scary when
she became a niffin?
The personal nature of her story
subverted Quentin's
hero's journey nicely.
Character is destiny and, ultimately,
Quentin is a Magician of
intellect who nevertheless,
and to his detriment,
acts from his heart.
But I did other things too!
Like lead Quentin to that Candy Witch.
Don't worry, that'll pay off.
I hid the Wellspring
ball in plain sight,
made the Rainbow Bridge bloom,
stole from the River Watcher
so he'd be good and angry
when Penny stiffed him.
Oh, I know, good one.
It was I who caused
the High King's bride
to ovulate on the right day,
leading to...
Preg-nant!
Ultimately leading to...
The fairies can
bring back the Wellspring?
- They can.
- And in return?
A royal child of Whitespire.
Take her to the dungeon.
He will transport you
to the fairy realm.
I repeatedly broke the filtration system
so the Wellspring would
be unpredictable and fun.
All those pesky "brownouts"? Moi!
To be sure, the Order is on to me.
They're in a panic about
the Great Blank Spot,
surmising a fatal hit to the Wellspring.
True, I am nearly finished with Fillory.
Every chapter must end,
and on the eve of my
benevolent destruction
I'm getting it all out of my system.
Like causing sudden climate change
that kills entire tedious
species of wildlife,
turning people into delicious rats.
All the babies this week
woke up with no mouths.
Oh, horrifying!
I bet you're wondering
what happens next,
and that is how I know
I've done my job well.
Sit back, have a nice pipe of marijuana,
and enjoy my grand opus.
I call it Fillory's Last Gasp.
I just miss the fire, okay?
Drink this.
What is it?
Renders you unable to
harm your own body.
This is all pointless, Q.
You can't medicate me away.
Just fucking drink it.
All of it.
Ugh.
Why did you bring me back?
Why do you keep asking me that?
I...
I watched you almost die trying
to bring your brother back.
You loved him. I love you.
I'd like to be alone now.
I take that to mean I'm improving.
Well, your skin's healing.
Obviously, your lungs are,
to use a technical term, fucked,
but more importantly...
Just say it.
You have lesions on your spine,
and they're growing aggressively.
Cancer.
Call it cancer plus.
Whatever you were exposed to
has spell residue all over it.
So a magician did this?
Well, if so,
it may be a code we can crack.
How long?
Well, it's hard to say, but I have
my entire department working on it...
I mean how long till I
die if you don't crack it?
Two or three weeks.
But I promise you,
we are doing everything we can to...
- Yeah.
- Okay...
I'm not waiting to
die in a hospital bed.
- Okay, I don't think...
- I'm not!
- Can we talk please?
- Yes.
Hey, there, hot stuff.
No offense...
you might look as bad as I do.
I doubt that.
You're dying.
All I am is a little strung out.
Kady...
What? It's not about me.
What happened?
Tell me.
Reynard's gone.
I should be happy, but...
it wasn't how I wanted it.
It's not enough.
God, I feel like bashing
my head into a wall.
Why can't anything just be fixed?
Life, I guess.
I don't want you to die.
Of course not.
I'm the best lay of your life.
Shut up.
What are we gonna do?
Wrap our minds around it.
Kady, let's not waste time
being mad, okay?
I'm just gonna find Quentin and Eliot,
just gonna make a
couple pit stops first.
That's, um... a nice sconce.
- Did you, um...
- Spit it out.
You want something.
Yeah.
First...
Are you okay?
I'm whole again.
W...
Which is a... a good thing.
If by good you mean crying jags
and mountains of guilt
and panic attacks,
then, yeah, I'm doing fucking great.
And since I better be getting
back to one of them soon,
whether I like it or not,
how can I help you?
Q says you have an amulet
that would make me invisible to a god.
Um, I don't pretend to understand
what you've been through,
but I can tell you
the way you're relating to that couch
is not unknown to me.
Then you know I want to be alone.
And, um, also that you probably
shouldn't be right now.
Why do you care?
I... just do.
Come with me...
and help me try to convince
Ember to let us keep Fillory.
- Why?
- Because I have never met
anyone less willing to
take no for an answer.
But I betrayed you, remember?
That was a long time ago.
I need help, and you do too.
Let's kill a few birds.
What do you say? Wanna put some pants on
and help me save all of magic?
I'll go talk to Eliot and Quentin.
- Uh, Kady...
- Just tell Penny
that I went to find a quiet
place and do some dope.
I'm ready to leave when he is.
Look... here's the deal.
I just read your book
in the library, both volumes.
My book? Why?
Because it ends the way
they all do in a couple days,
with 20 blank pages.
Something's about to happen,
something magical
and really fucking bad,
and I think it's...
It's Ember. He's been doing
all sorts of fucked up shit in Fillory,
bucket list shit.
What's in my book?
You do your recon,
find out Prince Ess of Loria
has taken Whitespire.
Shit.
Then kidnap Idri, who I guess is a rat,
turn him back, then camp here
trying to find the perfect spell
to force Ember to keep
his mitts off of Fillory.
But if my book ends, then...
Then... exactly.
We know that doesn't work,
so you need to do
anything else... anything.
Pick a plan and commit.
If it's written, isn't it written?
Yes, but I think you can change it.
Okay, so we can save Fillory
if we subscribe to a "free will"
view of the universe,
which is fair.
So what am I supposed to do?
Go. Get Idri.
Hurry.
I just got one thing I gotta button up.
Hey.
I calculated a portal to Tahiti.
Hold up.
No.
You warned them.
You've done enough. You get to be done.
I'm sorry. Believe me, I'd rather...
No, none of it matters, Penny.
Oh, come on!
Penny, you're needed at once.
- I'm busy.
- Bit of an emergency.
We need our full staff.
Are you crazy?
He's dying.
Yes, because he went
into a restricted area,
which lethally poisoned him
and puts him on strict probation,
but most assuredly does not
mean he's excused from work.
We'll take every step
to keep him comfortable.
What the hell is wrong with you?
Kady, knowledge itself is at stake.
That is more important
than any single one of us.
I'll give you a moment to say good-bye.
No. No, not good-bye.
- Kady, listen, I...
- No, I'm telling you,
this isn't fair.
God damn it!
Fuck!
Just crack the damn lock.
Hurry, before some
fairy asshole sees us.
I'm going as fast as I can.
Fen? Are you okay?
Sweetie, do you know where you are?
A plane laid atop our own,
so the Fairy Castle and
Whitespire actually occupy
the same space and time,
but two dimensions.
Or possibly the same dimension,
but incredibly sped up
like that one episode of
"Star Trek" where...
Just get the damn chain, Josh.
No.
Not without my baby. They took her away.
You have to come with us, okay?
Get the goddamn shackles, Hoberman.
Grab her with me. Come on.
Hey. Come on.
There you are.
The Queen will see you now.
You've been making
yourself quite at home,
sneaking around my castle.
It's actually more like my castle
that you guys have made some
weird AM radio version of.
What is it that you seek,
rude little Earth girl?
The woman and child you stole.
You made a deal.
That deal was inhumane bullshit
made under total duress.
Look...
just tell me what you want, okay, lady?
The child is mine.
Now on to the business at hand.
No, the baby is the business.
Ember is dangerously bored of Fillory.
You underestimated how
devastating it can be
to displease a god.
We've been trying to get
ahold of Ember for months.
He ignores us.
Because you ask for things.
Offer something to him instead.
How do you know all this?
As it is in our shared interest
for your High King to succeed,
I'm inclined to let you go help him.
Great. Josh, Fen,
the baby and I will go right now.
You know it doesn't work that way.
Now, are you familiar with this?
- No.
- But goddamn.
Smells good.
Even better to a god.
It will draw Ember.
Take it. Bake it into...
I know this one. Little cakes.
He loves little cakes.
Okay.
Point the way back.
Certainly.
As soon as I've exacted the toll.
Travel from this world costs, dear.
I don't make the rules.
Oh, that's right. Yes, I do.
We'll be seeing each
other soon I suspect.
So, how's Alice?
- Eliot, I...
- We need your help, Q.
You gave her the no-secret-cutting shit
- from the keg, right?
- Yes.
Physically, she's perfectly safe,
but mentally... whew!
What am I supposed to do?
You know what you learn
when you're a High King?
Screwing up is inevitable,
and there are some fuck ups
you can never un-fuck.
It's infuriating
and it is heartbreaking, but...
Think I destroyed her, Eliot.
She made plenty of her
own choices along the way.
I'm not saying it doesn't suck.
I'm saying...
Fillory needs you.
You chose to be a king.
This is what that means.
We have a plan, but...
We need someone who
speaks fluent fanboy.
What on earth are you doing here,
sad little nerd king?
You're sitting in my chair, asshole.
Where the hell are the guards?
Fast asleep, sorry.
Watch where you point that thing.
Dad.
You're okay.
I-I had to do this. You were a rat.
Could I have my throne back now?
I'll fight if you want.
I've become pretty
boss with a broadsword.
You have...
so don't.
Fine.
Always did like to storm out.
I should go too.
I should be there for my people,
whatever happens.
You mean in case I fail?
You won't.
Hmm.
You know, since Ember banished me,
I wonder if that nullified
my whole Fillorian contract.
We could check.
Uh, okay, so the thing is,
this blank spot,
it's coming up fast, and it lines up
with everything that you
were saying about Ember.
Is this tree too asymmetrical?
It's nice. I...
So there's no way that you would
want to help us, like, at all?
One cannot just show up
after one's faked one's own death.
I'm sorry.
The end of Fillory makes me sad as well.
So Fillory really is done?
I like you.
You care about things.
Yeah, it's not really a trait
that's helped me much.
But it could be if it were applied
to not trying to fix the unfixable,
but rather something
fresh and more perfect,
like, say...
Care to take a visit? Make some notes?
- Um, I... uh...
- I'm sorry,
but you're acting like I'm asking you,
whereas I am a god and
you are a hairless monkey,
so nod and say thank you.
All right.
Let's go to the pocket world
formerly known as Cuba.
Whoa!
Coming back from the fairy world
is a little rockier than getting there.
You don't fucking say.
Are you okay?
Jesus.
Fen wouldn't come because
they have your daughter.
I'm sorry.
I'll keep trying.
I promise, El.
First we need to deal
with that cock, Ember.
We come bearing bait.
I look like Jack Sparrow
if he were played by a man.
I was actually thinking more
like a Fembot Nick Fury.
- Look...
- No, I need to...
I know, okay?
I was angry... and scared
of what you were capable of,
but you were doing your best
in an impossible position
that would've crushed anyone,
myself included.
Wait, is your good eye crying right now?
No.
Yes.
And it's not my good eye,
it's my only fucking eye.
- Eh...
- It's not funny,
you dick, I'm a Cyclops!
A mythological monster at last.
Box... checked.
We're trying too hard.
Pardon?
To just blow past it and banter.
It's not the same.
Let's not pretend it is, okay?
That makes it hurt worse.
I guess we'll just have
to live with the strain
till the future reveals itself.
Meantime, that future
is going to be a big, blank,
post-apocalyptic nada unless
we do what we do best.
Act out with a total lack of
empathy and impulse control?
Party like the world depends on it,
'cause Bambi One Eye...
it do.
Oh, my God.
I threw better orgies when I was ten.
I give you little cakes.
I know they're irresistible,
it's the candied fairy hemp,
but resist. This is
for our guest of honor.
Be brutal.
It's really... really linear.
How's the linguini?
There's nothing wrong with it.
Excellent.
That's excellent.
It's maybe a little, uh...
Chewy?
- Bland.
- Bland... good, or?
Bland is never really good or bad.
It appeals to all tastes.
Sure, but...
usually people, uh...
creatures who can think, gods even...
sometimes like the unknown,
the unexpected,
even the offensive.
Little bit of, uh...
Chaos.
Happy now?
You know who would love this,
who would create an entire
world out of this greasy stain?
My brother.
Yes, Ember would make a mess.
Do not speak to me of Ember!
I like you, boy, but I have a temper.
Wait, what about a human sacrifice?
No, unless the cakes are bad.
Well, they smell great,
but I don't think they're working, so...
Little cakes.
Mmm. Ohh. Mmm. Oh, oh.
Oh, yes.
Welcome, Ember, god of gods.
Wait, didn't I banish you?
- You did, Lord of All, but...
- I didn't expect this.
- I can explain.
- I...
love it!
- Ha.
- A genuine twist,
a true surprise.
When was the last time
that happened around here?
Exactly,
and we're really sorry about that.
We've fallen down on the job,
but boredom is death.
- I totally agree.
- Ugh, isn't it though?
- It is.
- Mm.
But... we can make Fillory more exciting
and... and watchable than ever.
That's our pitch. It's a new chapter
and the title is
"Shit Tons of Drama and Surprise."
Intriguing.
How?
Don't destroy Fillory.
Shake things up, yes.
Like the rats.
Yeah, rats, hilarious.
It was good, wasn't it?
- Yes. Yes.
- We're all still laughing.
- Right?
- Mm-hmm.
- Right, laughing?
- Laughing!
There's so much more to do here,
so many twists and surprises
this world can offer.
- Mm.
- Think back to the moment
you created the first blades of grass.
- Sentient trees.
- Talking animals.
- The Wellspring.
- Think back
to what you built with
your brother Umber.
My brother, rest his soul,
was nothing but a simpering,
sniping, anal retentive critic,
as well as a...
Greedy, promiscuous, selfish,
credit-hogging, mouse-eating slob!
Any talk of this is mere whimsy,
and it's whimsy itself that I
am tired of and finished with.
We get it, we do. I mean,
try ruling a world of whimsy.
- Am I right?
- Mm.
Not so whimsical, actually.
Well, then, let's get it over with.
Why wait?
Let's start right now.
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Not what we meant...
Rewind! Rewind! Rewind! Rewind! Rewind!
Stop! Are you insane?
No! I mean, we meant...
make it better, make it better.
Less whimsical, more...
meaner maybe, more you.
Maybe, if I didn't have to do it alone.
Say what you will about my dear,
departed brother,
but he was a demon for overwork.
Hmm. He had a strange love for this...
Poor, accursed place.
Too late to be helped now. I...
couldn't bear to go back. I-I won't.
I won't.
Um, actually, we're already there.
Where?
Apocalypse! Apocalypse! Apocalypse!
Isn't it wonderful?
What are you doing?
You're making a mess!
I'm...
back.
You're alive.
How is this possible, brother?
You died battling Martin to save me.
Why are you afraid? I...
I am... so pleased.
Martin told me you died...
when he banished me.
Hey, guys, how about a hug?
This is a family reunion.
This was a family betrayal.
Wasn't it?
- Wasn't it?
- No!
No!
I can't be here!
Oh! All this time, I thought,
"Martin, so powerful."
But no.
He was merely a brilliant dealmaker.
My banishment for your life.
Your puny, petty,
putrid nothing of a soul spark!
Brother, please?
Please!
You... always... were
the weak one.
Come and get me, you fucking baby.
You want to know why you're so bored?
Because you're too stupid to get it.
You're too spoiled and
entitled to understand...
How dare you? I am a god.
Are you? Really?
I'm not impressed.
I've met scary gods, and you?
You're nothing but a petty tyrant.
Quentin...
You... always...
surprise.
Holy fuck.
Q?
I think you just saved the whole world.
We are officially a land
of godless heathens,
making today the first day
of our societal adulthood.
I, for one, am slightly terrified
and equally excited.
And trying not to break into "Hamilton."
And so, I turn over the
next phase of our maturation
to our High Queen Margo.
We need a constitution.
Pardon?
These are some pretty good ones here,
so let's rip off the best parts.
Hungry?
I know Mayakovsky said soft,
bland food for a while, but...
I can see that's not really working.
So I stopped by the farm
where Fogg gets his
weekly rasher of bacon.
No thanks.
You sure?
Because...
I tried it...
and, uh,
it's amazing.
I know what you're trying to do.
I'm... just trying to do
breakfast food, that's all.
Oh, fuck you.
Mmm.
Please.
Fuck.
Gluttony.
It's an excellent part of being human.
I don't remember many others.
Really?
Ugh.
Hmm, my hands are all greasy.
With every good thing,
no matter how small it is,
it's always...
married to something
so completely disgusting.
You can't escape it.
You're right.
It's gross. We are animals.
Why does that feel so good?
I don't know.
It just does.
It always did.
Hmm.
Look... I need your help.
I'm not gonna beg.
I'm not gonna use guilt,
I have no leverage.
But Penny's in the Library.
He can be your mole.
But to do that, he'd have to be alive.
He'd never know.
Whatever you need, ask me about it.
He tells me, I tell you.
Who saved her man's life, so maybe not.
Big picture, right?
Deal?
Deal.
I probably shouldn't say this
out loud, but...
this was kind of an okay day.
Are you bragging?
No.
Kind of.
Not about this... entirely.
I also kind of killed a god.
Huh. Hilarious.
No, seriously.
Ember.
I mean, he was...
erasing the whole thing.
Wait, wait, you can't be serious.
Yeah.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, I didn't want to.
He had just killed his brother.
He was going after Julia.
He was genocidally insane.
You don't get it.
Jesus.
When I was a-a niffin, I saw things.
I saw everything from
the beginning of time.
- Calm down...
- No, I understand
the way the universe works, Q,
the Wellspring,
the hierarchies, the plumbing.
I was inside it.
Gods like Ember have parents, you idiot!
I-I'm not following.
The old gods,
the creators of the universe,
of all magic itself.
To Ember, we're like... we're like toys,
but to them we're... we're cells.
When we're harmless they ignore us,
but when we become malignant,
they amputate.
Now, if you're gonna use
stones like this,
it's imperative that...
Excuse me.
Excuse me, this is...
Okay, wait.
Like, so there's an actual plumber?
Like the Mario Brother of the gods?
- Yes.
- And he can just...
I guarantee you, he's doing it.
Attention, please keep calm
and follow all code green procedures.
Please remember not to
interact and simply gather...
Attention,
please keep calm and follow...
Professor?
Mayakovsky!
Holy shit.
All right, everyone,
open your books to chapter 16.
Who can translate the Borkulo Rendering
from its original Hungarian?
No point in raising hands.
Remember?
I can.
Dean Fogg? Sorry to interrupt.
Yes, Josh, go ahead.
Well, I was online last night...
The answer is no.
There is no actual evidence
of a magical surge in Sedona, Arizona.
Yeah, but what about in...
Or Kenya,
or Machu Picchu, or China...
or anywhere.
Magic is gone.
The best we can do is accept that,
and continue our theoretical studies,
to stay ready for its return.
So you think that's possible?
Anything is possible, Alice.
Was, anyway.
Look at you,
playing the part of the bright,
young girl.
Joseph?
Ah, yes.
I can see my Alice in there still.
Good.
Are you all right?
I am as I appear... dying.
So it is true.
Magic's gone everywhere.
The creatures, cryptids,
sylphs, dragons, unicorns,
even the pointless vampires
are all as they were.
But those of us who drew on
the power of the Wellspring,
well, as you can see...
- I want to help.
- I'm here, Alice,
because it is you who needs help.
- What?
- As a niffin, you made enemies.
I'm here to warn you that
one of them seeks you.
Who?
The Lamprey.
You do recall what
you did to his family?
Yes.
Most amusing at the time,
but to The Lamprey, cause for vengeance.
It knows you're weak.
It knows you're here.
What do I...
Oh...
Democracy has to take a backseat.
Without magic, the people are terrified,
and that is just one step
from an angry mob.
And that's how royal heads
end up in baskets.
I get it. I get it.
This is an undereducated,
pre-industrial populous, Eliot.
They need to be ruled.
They need to be inspired.
They need to think
they're being inspired
as they're being ruled.
I'm talking curfew,
martial law, conscription,
and severe and public punishment.
Okay. Can we maybe make our way
to King and Queen Caligula, please?
Maybe a...
How do you not recognize me?
I'm the King's wife!
- Tell them!
- Oh, my God.
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
How did you get here?
Simple.
I just gave them my toes.
Gave... who your toes?
The fairies.
I wanted to stay...
to be close to our daughter,
but I had to warn you.
They're coming.
They're here.
Boo.
Hey.
Jules, I...
Hi.
How did you get in here?
Well, your...
your fence is a little shoddy.
Right.
Welcome to the new normal.
You know, 'cause I killed
all magic fucking everywhere.
Uh... Sorry.
That was definitely a two-hander.
I'll be burning in hell
right next to you,
but hey, at least we have each other.
Hmm.
So how are you?
Fine.
- Listen...
- How's law school?
I quit.
Okay.
Why?
Because I need to show you something,
and you need to promise me that
you're not going to tell anyone,
'cause you're the only
person that I trust.
I promise.
Jules, it's not gonna work.
Just give me a second.
We all get flashes
that we can do it again, but it's...
Oh, my God.
How?
I have no idea.