QUENTIN: Previously
on The Magicians...
(ALL SCREAMING) (SHRIEKS)
RICHARD: Kady! No, no!
Don't you... ing touch her!
Fine. I'll take you first.
(SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERS) (GROWLING)
(WHIMPERS) (RICHARD GROWLING)
ELIOT: Now!
Julia!
QUENTIN: Move!
JULIA: Wait! (GRUNTS)
I had Reynard. I had The Beast.
Man, fuck this. We're out.
The chain was the only
thing keeping my hands from...
Sorry. Not my problem.
Oh, shit.
Do you know what a Niffin is?
It's when too much runs
through you. Consumes you.
Only the magic is left.
Hard to cast when
you're sliced in two.
(GRUNTS) (GASPS)
(GROANING)
What is she doing?
She can't, she'll Niffin out.
(GASPING) QUENTIN: Alice, stop!
(SHRIEKING)
Let's finally finish this.
I did it on purpose.
Alice, don't.
(GASPS)
(GROWLS)
MARGO: Five surgeries.
ELIOT: He'll recover.
I know we're being
serious right now,
but that surgeon
has the biggest dick.
Eliot, it's time we go.
(INHALES) Our kingdom awaits.
PICKWICK: With The Beast dead,
there's a power vacuum in Fillory.
MARGO: "Power vacuum."
Hello. High King
and Queen right here.
We, of course, recognize
your rule, but others...
Everyone assumes
you'll be dead soon.
Or you'll run away,
or vanish, or go mad.
HELOISE: There are stirrings of
rebellion in the Southern Orchard,
the Outer Islands.
Refusal to pay
the Crown's taxes.
You know who loves paying taxes?
People with broken legs.
(ABIGAIL SQUEAKING)
Abigail would remind you that
money cannot fill the Wellspring.
Without it, Fillory withers.
Okay, well, we
talked about this.
When someone drops
a log at a public pool,
you just send a kid
with a net to fish it out.
The befouling was
substantial, Your Majesty.
We've employed
several filtration systems,
but the Wellspring isn't
recovering fast enough.
If there was a royal
appeal to Ember himself...
Okay, we can't find him.
He's not in his temple
or his filthy sex cave.
We need to devote
more resources...
We're going to build a
monument to our fallen queen.
A statue, I think. A
hundred feet high.
Do you know what
that would cost?
I don't care how much it costs.
I want designs drawn
up and funds funded.
Immediately.
Can you give us a moment?
I said get the fuck out!
So, that's the plan, huh?
Blow all our cash on sappy
nonsense, bankrupt the kingdom?
We have to do something.
Alice was our friend.
No. She wasn't.
Alice was a package deal.
She came with Quentin.
Somebody skipped
her colonic this morning.
For whatever stupid reason,
you're the High
King of an entire land.
You have to be
responsible, Eliot.
Since when are
you Fillory Clinton?
Since I'm me.
My crown is just
as heavy as yours.
You can leave
whenever you feel like it.
You can go back to Brakebills,
you can do whatever
you goddamn want.
I don't belong here, I'm
not ready to be a king.
I wasn't done being me.
It was so much simpler
when there was just one
giant, evil dick trying to kill us.
And now we're just...
Grown-ups?
How did this happen?
I have an idea to help you.
Like a loophole? Mmm-hmm.
You're gonna ironically
abandon me here to go find it?
I'll be back. I promise.
I know you...
(SIGHS)
Will.
(PERSON COUGHING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
(BABY CRYING)
Hey.
(GROANS)
Kady.
Hey.
(GROANS)
Kady, come on,
okay? I need your help.
Let's go.
(STOMPS FOOT)
LIPSON: You haven't had any
other problems with your casting?
I've had nothing but problems.
I thought it was
because of my hands,
but it's getting
worse, not better.
Huh.
I've had a few brownouts,
you could call them.
I mean, I thought it
was the Xanax, honestly.
How many?
Two a day, if I can get them.
Oh, you mean the brownouts.
Four or five.
Hmm.
Yes.
(THUDDING) (GROANING)
(PANTING)
What happened? (PANTING)
I'm trying to get back here,
but my aim's been all off.
Okay. All right. It seems
like more than your aim.
Last three worlds I've been in
haven't had any fucking oxygen.
(STAMMERING) And my fingers,
they just keep shorting me out.
What happened?
Did we kill The Beast?
We did.
(EXHALES)
But, um, Quentin
was pretty banged up.
Alice was hurt a
lot worse, Penny.
(SIGHS) She died.
Budget? ELIOT:
Citizen petitions.
I want everyone to
stop wanting things.
Great time to ask for something.
Your father makes knives for a
living and knows where I sleep.
So... (CHUCKLES) Ask away.
I know I'm not
precisely the type
you'd most likely choose,
and I wasn't so experienced
when we were first together,
but (LAUGHING)
you're so great at it.
You're... You're
huge and it's so good.
And Eliot, I don't know how
to politely ask you to fuck me.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Oh, look, Margo's here.
You remember Lasaro?
That creep who
made the Margolem?
I twisted his arms
and/or balls a little,
and he gave up the spell.
Living clay is hard to come by,
but Fogg left his
stash so unprotected,
it's like he wanted
me to steal it.
So, I did.
(INHALES)
We're gonna make another you.
Hey. JULIA: I made
you a sandwich.
Half an hour ago. Then I ate it.
(SIGHS) I'm sorry.
It's been a long time
since I've had a hot shower.
How you feeling?
(GROANS AND EXHALES)
Better.
Nap. Seeing you
alive. Magic methadone.
Methadone. (CHUCKLES)
Thanks. For all of it.
So, uh, how'd you find me?
After asking around a bit,
I heard about a girl who was
doing miracles for a quick fix.
I called it "turning tricks."
You think I'm
judging you, I'm not.
No. No, I'm judging myself.
You...
You saved my life, and...
You know, I thought it
would be okay to run.
If I got the cavalry and I
came back to help you. But I...
I just ran.
I hid. (CHUCKLES)
Yeah, well, there was
nothing you could've done then.
But you can help me now.
(GASPS) Oh, my God.
(STAMMERING)
Julia, is that... Marina.
She helped me bait a trap
for Reynard. He killed her.
You freeze-dried her corpse?
Alonso's Reverse Thermogenesis.
But look.
She left this for a reason.
A message, or a code. I
mean, at least, I thought that.
No, no, I know
exactly what that is.
That's a locator number.
For a book in the
library at Brakebills.
Be careful.
(CHUCKLES) That's a
long drop for human legs.
We would not want to see you
get hurt so soon after being rebuilt.
Rebuilt?
It's strange, I know.
But you'll get used to it.
Is this a hospital?
Are you a doctor?
You're at the Retreat.
A few hours' gallop
north of Whitespire.
I was a patient, years ago.
The centaurs saved my
life when no one else could.
Now I try to repay that debt
by serving them as a nurse.
The centaurs? Mmm.
Horse people.
Mmm-hmm.
How long have I... Three weeks.
Your injuries were severe.
Your friends were called
away, but they left that for you.
We can start physical
therapy in the morning.
ELIOT: "Dear Q, we buried
Alice today in the gardens,
"where she'll
always be close by."
(SOBS) "We left a box of
her things, if you ever wake up.
"Please wake up.
"Your benevolent
overlord, High King Eliot."
(EXHALES)
PENNY: (CLEARS THROAT) Hey.
(SNIFFLES)
Margo sent me here to
get my hands checked out.
Look...
It sucks about Alice.
"Sucks"?
That's the best that you can do?
I cared about her, too.
For what, like, 10
minutes, including foreplay?
Are you mad at me because
I cared too much or too little?
I'm mad 'cause you
fucked up the one thing
that we were counting on
you for. You wanna blame me?
It was your cacodemon
that killed her.
That was not Alice.
Alice was gone.
So you just saved the day, huh?
Can we just...
Convalesce from our horrible
injuries separately, please?
Nice to see you, too, man.
Good day. My name is
Sawbones. I will be examining you.
(SNIFFS) Ugh!
Those are the most accursed
things I've ever smelled.
They must be removed, posthaste.
(STRAINING)
How did they
become cursed? Uh...
Some guy, this valet-type-of-dude
at Chatwin's Torrent.
The River Watcher.
You know him?
I'm sorry, I... I
can't help you.
Dude, just chop them off
or give me some magic
wooden shit, like you did Quentin.
I'm a surgeon. I can't risk the
curse spreading to my own hands.
The River Watcher... (EXHALES)
He's mercurial, and dangerous.
You erred greatly in
offending him, Penny.
(PLOPPING)
Did you...
(PLOPPING CONTINUES)
Are you shitting?
You're welcome.
(SIGHS)
What was I saying?
Me likey.
You're thinking about
banging yourself, aren't you?
Shh. Shh. Shh.
No, no, doing your clone is
more like AP-level masturbation.
Ugh. Put on a robe, would you?
Aw. Now, part two.
A variation on the
mind-control work
Mayakovsky hammered
us with first year.
You sleep here, your
mind goes into the golem.
And the golem
goes to Brakebills.
Unless, of course, we're wrong
about the fine print in my contract
and he can't leave
Fillory either...
Yeah, totally possible he touches
the button and just explodes.
Only one way to find out.
(SIGHS)
Richard's alumni key.
It gets you past the
wards at Brakebills.
I was expelled.
Alarm bells will go
off the second I pop in.
I didn't go to school there. I mean,
how am I supposed to find this book?
(READING NECKLACE)
(LAUGHS) It's the only
one the bodega had.
KADY: Okay, bitch.
Say something.
You seeing this?
Head down this row.
Wait. Yeah... That
room on your left.
It's got an anti-decay
charm on it.
It's where they
keep the good shit.
JULIA: Got it.
Wait. Wait, let
me see, hold it up.
Wait. Flip it to the back.
(SIGHS) Damn it.
It's like a library LoJack.
It'll go off if you try to take the
book outside the Brakebills wards.
JULIA: I mean, this will take hours
to copy. Someone's gonna notice me.
Well, not if you know
the right place to hide.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Okay. Didn't explode so far.
Why does everything
smell so great?
Because your doppel-banger
hasn't met cocaine yet.
Todd! Todd! Todd!
Why is everyone cheering for...
Todd?
Oh, hey! (CHUCKLES) You guys!
You made a lot of friends, huh?
I heard you guys were dead.
So, I threw this massive
rager in your honor.
The fact that you just
called it a rager sickens me.
(CHUCKLES) Thing
is, it went great,
and everyone had so
much fun, that I kind of...
Became the new me.
(CHUCKLES)
Todd, answer truthfully.
Are you wearing my vest?
I am wearing your vest.
Keep it.
New plan.
I give up on Fillory
and dedicate myself
completely to destroying Todd.
MARGO: Oh, it's just Todd.
"Just Todd"? He's usurping
me. My entire kingdom is at stake.
Your actual kingdom
is actually at stake.
There are some things more
important than saving an entire world.
Okay, I'm gonna go out on a limb
and say this isn't
really about Todd.
You don't say, Margo.
No killing Todd!
Fucking Todd.
(WIND BLOWS)
NURSE: Is this a bad time?
Come sit over here.
I saw a strange woman.
She's pale and had horn things.
You've seen The White Lady.
I'm sorry, "White Lady"?
You are fortunate she offered
herself to some centaur's sight
while you happened
to be watching.
Is that...
Skin.
It won't feel, but it might help
you forget what's underneath.
(CHOKING)
Get up, Coldwater.
What happened?
My hands tried to kill me,
so I broke my own arms.
Look, forget all that mean
shit I said to you earlier.
The bronies can't fix
me, I need your help.
Okay, I guess.
First things first. Find an ax.
Are you sure about this?
Do you know how strong booze
has to be to get a horse drunk?
(CHUCKLING)
I can't feel my face,
much less my face.
I mean, hands.
Just do it.
I'm going to, jeez.
(INHALES)
(EXHALES)
Nope.
Damn it, Quentin!
Sorry. I just... I panicked.
I don't love blood.
Who loves blood? I'm not
gonna feel anything, so fucking go!
I don't think I can
do this. Oh, my God!
I knew I fucking
couldn't count on you.
You are so fucking pathetic,
you floppy-haired,
limp-dicked dork, fucking...
No wonder Alice
couldn't get off on you,
you have no fuck... (SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
Oh, I fucking feel it!
Okay. Okay. Oh, what did you do?
I can fix it! I can fix it!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Oh, I wouldn't.
Todd made that. It's vile.
Here. (CHUCKLES)
Mmm.
Delicious. (CHUCKLES)
I'm Eliot. Javier.
You're a first-year?
Second-year.
Universidad de Asombro in Spain.
I'm here for the
Welters tournament.
Oh. Mmm-hmm.
I would make a joke
about ball-handling,
but I'm deadly serious
about ball-handling.
Me too. (LAUGHS)
Listen, Javier, I could keep
this up all night. So could I.
But I have to reclaim my title
as the life of this
and every party
by making a drink so perfect...
It seems like you need to relax.
I'm married.
To a woman. I have a boyfriend.
But he's on another
continent, so it doesn't count.
And where is your wife?
On another planet.
(SCOFFS) Definitely
doesn't count.
(SIGHS)
It's working.
Qué?
Nothing, back at it.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(MOANS AND LAUGHS)
FEN: Eliot?
(GASPS) Hey. You
were talking in your sleep.
(EXHALES) What did you do?
I'm sorry, (LAUGHS) I get a
little bit enthusiastic sometimes.
I'll be gentle.
You've been in bed all
day, I came to check on you.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
You sure you still want... I do.
What? I do...
Want to tell you I'm
sorry. I'm so sorry.
For what?
Um... (LAUGHS)
I'm gonna go. Um...
No, no, no, no, no, no. I absolutely
wanna have sex right now.
(INHALES)
You do?
Yeah.
Ah.
This is interesting.
BOTH: Do you want me to stop?
Uh...
(PANTING)
NURSE: Good morning, Quentin.
How is Penny?
He lost a lot of
blood, but he'll live.
You're ready for
physical therapy.
Some calisthenics,
maybe, or core work?
I had something
else in mind, actually.
PENNY: You're exactly as good
with a bow as you are with an ax.
Since I was a kid, The Beast
has been whispering shit in my ear.
Now that he's dead, the
world's gotten a lot quieter.
Or would be, if
not for you out here
thinking low self-esteem shit.
I'll re-do my wards.
There's something in the Declan
text about making arrows fly straight.
Show me.
If I had middle fingers, you know
what they'd be doing right now?
Start with Popper No. 31.
Now cross your
index and ring fingers.
No, under the middle.
Now slide the thumb
along the meridian.
Now draw the arrow back.
Thank you. Thank
me by shutting up.
There's a creature
called The White Lady.
I saw her yesterday.
She's one of the seven
Questing Creatures of Fillory.
If you can catch her, she has
to give you whatever you ask.
Plover wrote about her, he
called her the Winter's Doe.
She lives in the Darkling Wood.
It's just past the Flying
Forest, it's not far from here.
We could hunt her together.
Let's go hunt The White Lady?
People like me get shot
for saying shit like that.
She can give you
your hands back.
What's in it for you?
I'm gonna ask her to
bring Alice back to life.
So the river we crossed
was at the edge of it.
So, we're in the Flying Forest.
Shouldn't the trees
be, like, flying and shit?
Yes, actually. Most of
them are crepuscular.
It means they're active
at dawn and dusk.
You smell that? (SNIFFS)
It smells like... Good.
(SNIFFS)
What is that?
I don't know.
(LAUGHS) I think I'm
getting a contact high.
Yeah. Definitely
starting to feel something.
(LAUGHING)
"Flying Forest"?
Oh, my God,
the Chatwins were, like, 10
when they came through here.
They must've been
blazed the entire time.
Super inappropriate.
QUENTIN: Hey, I
take back what I said.
I fully expect to see a tree
flapping around at any second.
Listen, Quincy, if
we get a tree or...
Did you just call me Quincy?
Is that not your name?
Dude.
Dude, what the fuck?
Get away from my mouth, man.
It's my mouth. Ahh.
No, it's not.
Oh!
Oh, where, uh, where
are my stuff touchers?
Ha! Ooh!
What the fuck is going on?
Who the fuck are you?
Who am I?
I have no idea. (LAUGHS)
(EXHALES) Okay.
The Beast shit
in the Wellspring?
No. No. Ember. Ember
shat in the Wellspring.
(SIGHS) I think he meant well.
He probably didn't know how
hard it would be to clean out.
And now, magic
is failing on Earth
because of shit.
Proving once again
that comedy and tragedy
can coexist in the same
goddamn sentence.
Honestly, I am in over my head.
I am not even in control of
which world my body is awake in,
and my sexually-aggressive wife,
she could wake me up
at any moment in Fillory.
(CLEARS THROAT) Eliot, there
are certain student-teacher boundaries
which I'd prefer not to cross.
So what am I
supposed to do, Henry?
What did you think
was going to happen
when you dove headfirst
into another world?
I thought I'd die.
But you didn't.
And now you have two lives.
You're trying to live both. Yes.
Yes, but you
can't. That's stupid.
You can let it tear
you in half or pick one.
I can never leave Fillory.
The choice is easy.
I am ill-equipped to be a king.
I am no better
equipped to teach one.
Being an adult is recognizing
your responsibilities.
A bunch of my students went
and conquered another world.
They more like gave it to us.
Either way, it doesn't
look great for me.
It reeks of Earth privilege.
The very least I can
do is to help you rule it.
What do you have in mind?
Bring in the best minds we can.
Historians, politicians,
shamans, military leaders.
(CHUCKLES)
Your thesis project is...
"How to Save an
Entire Goddamn World."
Right or left?
PENNY: Right seems to
be the popular direction.
I must be an adventurer.
(LAUGHING) No, you're not.
What? I have a bow and
arrow and a cool questing outfit.
And a manservant.
(LAUGHING) Oh, you did
not just say that, white boy.
Besides, what kind of
servant has no fucking hands?
Right or left?
Right seems to be
the popular direction.
MARGO: Julia?
What the hell are
you doing here?
Look, I can explain. No.
After you jumped in and
screwed everything up with Penny,
Alice died, killing
your little friend Martin.
Then Quentin was
almost ripped in half.
And you have the
balls to come here?
Look, if you guys
had trusted me,
both Reynard and The
Beast would be dead.
None of that would've happened.
Quentin should've left
you in your little hedge hole,
trading rim jobs for spells.
You actually think because
you go to this bullshit school,
that you're better than me?
I think I didn't get
my friends killed.
You don't have friends.
You have people that are so afraid
of you, they'd rather be on your side.
There's a difference.
Well, and you have no one.
And you deserve no one.
Look, I don't expect you to care
'cause this doesn't directly
affect your hair or your social life,
but since you let Reynard free,
he has murdered
over a dozen women
and this book might be
my last shot at killing him.
The book's blank.
Put yours in the box
and wait for them to mate.
The baby should be a pretty
decent Xerox of the original.
You know what this is?
Oh. It's a girl's.
What if I'm supposed
to be rescuing her?
Ooh! Or what if
you're a stalker?
Right or left?
Right seems to be
the popular direction.
Wait, no.
If I'm supposed to find her, I have to
look where no one else is searching.
What?
(GRUNTS)
(SIGHS AND SNIFFLES)
Penny.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(LAUGHS) Douchebag.
Effect of the weed
forest is wearing off.
Oh, my God.
(PANTING) Oh.
(SOBS) It's Alice, uh...
Quentin, look. I know
how you feel, man.
Before, when your
wards were slipping, I...
I know.
I can't. No, hey,
no, no. Listen.
You can't...
You can't puss out right now.
Think about Alice.
She needs you, man.
I need you.
(SNIFFLES)
Hey.
(SIGHING) Hi.
So, I've been thinking,
is 100 feet really tall
enough for Alice's memorial?
We weren't her
friends, remember?
We owe it to her.
Because we weren't her friends.
We don't have the money.
We're Magicians.
Let's build it ourselves.
Look, what Margo
said about me was true.
So, if you wanna bail,
now's your chance.
Well, you do have
questionable judgment.
I mean, we're "Best Bitches,"
right? (BOTH LAUGH)
For better or for worse. God.
Wait a minute.
I know why Marina
wanted me to find the book.
Why? It's a necromancy spell.
As in, bring back to life?
No. No fucking way. Kady...
She killed my mother.
Look, the effects are unstable.
It'll only last a few minutes,
and then she goes away again.
Fine.
Fine, let's defrost the bitch.
It says the last ingredient
is the book itself.
Then we got one chance.
(GASPS)
Marina. (WHIMPERING)
It's okay. It's okay.
My skin is so cold.
It's okay. Look at me.
You brought me back.
You had a message
you wanted to tell me...
Now I'm gonna die. We
don't have that much time.
You don't understand.
You don't know where I was.
I don't wanna go back
there. I don't wanna go back!
Marina, your clock is
running out, okay? Please.
You are the strongest
person that I have ever met.
I need you to pull it together
now, and I need you to tell me.
I need you to tell me about
the thing that killed you.
(GASPING)
You can stop him, Julia.
It is possible, but you need
to do it. You need to do it.
Okay. What? What
do I need to do?
There was a girl.
Forty years ago, she
banished Reynard from Earth.
That's where he was
until you summoned him.
until you brought him back.
(GASPS) I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. (GASPING)
Shh.
(ARROW THUDS)
Hi.
Don't run.
Are you gonna?
What's the deal?
I don't know, she's
kind of ignoring me.
Yo, White Lady, we caught you.
Hey, show some respect.
Pardon me...
Miss... Lady?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
It hurts.
Sorry. Uh...
Why have you come?
That's my arrow. You
have to give me what I ask.
Obviously, you turd.
(SCOFFS)
Well, look at you.
Someone's been rebuilt.
And so cleverly.
Hmm.
Feel that? (KNOCKING ON WOOD)
Could you not?
Here's a riddle.
How much do you have to lose
before you're no longer yourself?
I don't know. Why
don't you tell me?
What is it, Quentin
Coldwater, that you ache for?
You have a crown
and the power to reshape
the very ether to your whim.
What else could
you possibly want?
Um, technically speaking,
we both caught you, so...
Shut up. I'll ask for your
thing with my third wish.
No, we each get a wish,
and then we have one
mutually-agreeable third wish.
You can each have one
wish or you can fuck off.
Okay.
Alice Quinn.
Bring her back to life.
Please.
I can't.
What do you mean, you can't?
You are not the only magical
creature in this fucking forest!
True.
And we all have limits.
We can give you anything,
but we cannot pierce that veil.
Alice is gone.
PENNY: My turn.
I want my hands back.
That I can do.
(CRACKING)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING STOPS)
What did you do to him?
That screaming was irritating.
He'll wake when he's healed.
Now, I can't nap until
I've granted you a wish.
I'd like to be happy.
Could you do that?
I can do wonders.
But you should know,
there is nothing I can give you
that will soothe your Shade.
There is only what
I can take away.
You'd take away my
memories of Alice?
Yes. I would free
you completely.
No.
You are wiser than you appear.
You would find your
way back to sadness,
no matter how
far you run from it.
Well, that's comforting.
Is there nothing
else you desire?
Everything I've
ever wanted, I've got.
Magic is real and it can fix
anything except what I need.
I loved a girl.
My entire life, I've
dreamed of Fillory.
That I would be
like Martin Chatwin.
I'd find a way to
stay here forever.
(SIGHS)
Send me home.