Previously on The Magicians...
Poppy Kline. Dragonologist.
Post-graduate fellow
and field researcher.
At your service.
You're from Brakebills?
I'll go to Fillory
on one condition.
That girl you saw in the
dungeon, we'll get her out.
Victoria.
You found me.
Look, I'm here.
No, I have to put
myself back together.
I need to sign out.
You are a danger to
yourself and to others.
No.
The fairies aren't
just terraforming,
they're growing an army.
We need a plan bigger than
just assassinating
the Queen. We need...
Hostages, leverage.
Don't ask questions.
Did you get the key?
I'm sorry, Your Majesty.
I'm a terrible
failure. Benedict, no!
They don't just make
portals. They are portals.
The key way to the Underworld.
It's magic. I'd do
anything to get it back.
If I could give it
to you, I would.
I see the transfer worked.
Alice, are you okay? Alice.
God! Alice!
Okay, someone's
gotta hear this, please.
I'm sorry. Husband problems.
The little weirdo
wouldn't go to sleep
until I read him
a bedtime story.
That's disturbing. Let's hustle.
Q's probably
already at the tree.
Tick, how are we doing?
Five minutes till the
fairy guards change shifts,
Your Majesties.
Now, no one knows
we're gone, okay?
If the Fairy Queen asks,
we're bedridden with
something contagious.
Like chicken pox.
Certainly, Highness.
But must you leave?
Prince Fomar's people
have been somewhat difficult.
What do you mean?
It seems your union
gave the Floaters
the distinct impression
that this land is now theirs.
They've been,
well, pillaging a lot.
I thought perhaps
a royal address...
You're thinking too small.
There's only one way
out of all of this, Tick.
Extortion. Exactly!
I need you to stay strong.
We are working on it.
But we can't deal
with the Floaters
until we deal with
the Fairies, got it?
I can't believe you paid
the Hudson River dragon
to send you to the Underworld.
That is so cool.
Yeah, well, it was a one-off.
Can't exactly go back to her
without something to trade.
I hear she's kinda withholding.
And judge-y.
Anyway, you think your
ghost friend's gonna be able
to help us? There's no "us."
I'm gonna go talk
to Penny alone,
and you're gonna go
back to whatever life
you were willing
to backstab me for.
Okay, I'm kinda sensing
some hostility here, and...
Q!
Oh, good.
Hey, I don't know if it was
just, like, a super anxious rabbit,
but your message
made things seem kinda...
Dire? They are.
- Are those supplies?
- Hostages.
Who the fuck are you? I'm Poppy.
I'm helping Quentin
find the next key.
No, she's not
helping me. We're...
Okay, can we hit
pause on the recap
until we're back where
our pasty usurpers
won't kill us all?
I've got all my life to live
I've got all my love to give
And I'll survive I will survive
Hey hey
Oh, my God.
Alice? Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Alice, can you hear me?
I told you, I'm fine.
I'm not sure what definition
of "fine" you're using.
I expected this, okay?
My body's just getting
used to Julia's magic.
There are occasional surges.
That's all this was.
I mean, was that all
this was? A surge?
Or more likely her body is
going through the equivalent
of organ transplant projection.
Attacking itself to
get rid of the invader.
Or maybe it's nothing
at all. Who knows?
Who knows?
Well, we need a
better answer than that.
You wanted to do the
spell. It's all an experiment.
I have no idea what's
going to happen.
Look, I prepared for this, okay?
Energy-balancing
spells, exercises...
I suppose that could work.
Your confidence is overwhelming.
What's the point of lying?
You people are just going to
do what you do, regardless...
Q.
Okay, you go get
the key, I got this.
No, I'm gonna
stay here and help.
I don't think more
is merrier here.
I don't know... Didn't you
notice your ex is a little...
Stubborn.
I noticed.
Alice and I got
into this together.
I'll get us out, one
way or another.
And I will make
sure that she's okay.
Okay?
Go get the key
while you still can.
We're all kinda counting on you
to bring back all of magic.
Yeah.
So you lost your
key in the Underworld
and now want me to somehow
go down there and get it.
Well, you're my only friend
who's technically dead, so...
For the millionth time,
dumbass, I'm not dead.
I'm an astral projection.
No offense, but
your corpse is ash,
so I think maybe you might
be in a little bit of denial.
I mean, look, weren't
you supposed to report
to the Underworld branch
of the Library anyway?
Yeah.
And I burned my
body to avoid that.
Look, if we do not
get to the Underworld
before Benedict moves
on... Whatever that means...
Then we will have no
idea where the key goes.
That's not my problem.
No magic is everyone's problem.
Do you think that I
like begging for help?
Especially to you?
I wouldn't even do it,
except that I know that you
occasionally stop being a
dick when the fate of the world
is at stake.
Fine. I'll help.
But it's not like I can just
travel to the Underworld.
So we need a gatekeeper.
A dragon, like Jules and I used.
What about the Library's dragon?
Sorry, couldn't
help but overhear.
At least one side of
the convo, anyway.
The Library has a
dragon? Mmm-hmm.
A brindle-coat Albanian pygmy.
They call it the Bookwyrm.
I read about it during
dissertation research.
I assume it's real. Ask
your invisible friend.
Yeah, apparently.
I hear they use it to send
books to and from
the Underworld.
'Cause dragons
are portals, right?
Yeah, except... The
Bookwyrm's too small
to send a full-size
person down there.
Well, what if the
person was a book?
Well, you said you can
project into objects, right?
Yeah, I did... Did
say that, didn't I?
Jesus Christ. Okay,
so this might work.
Except, say, I get the
key and send it back up...
It's stuck in the
Satellite Library,
which is on
another planet, so...
So, we need another Traveler.
Oh, I only know one.
And she got grabbed
by The Beast in Fillory.
Victoria, she was in my class.
Wait a minute,
you know Victoria?
Of course you know her, you...
Wait, wait. She's not dead?
No, I mean, we saved
her and she sorta took off.
I have no idea where she is.
If she's on Earth,
I can find her.
On one condition. I wanna come.
I've never seen an Albanian
pygmy dragon before.
This could be my only shot.
All right, fine. Oh, yes!
This doesn't make
us friends, you know.
Discover anything
useful for Alice?
Um, yeah, actually, there's
some pretty interesting stuff
on combining immunosuppressants
with a crystal-based
healing ritual.
I'm sorry. Forgive me.
Not long ago, you
wanted magic so badly
you fought through
a memory wipe.
And now...
It's complicated and personal.
Fine, I'll file it under
"entitled millennial bullshit."
Let's be frank, Ms. Wicker.
Whatever you and Alice
are doing, it won't work.
You don't know that.
I know a lot more than you.
You're drunk, and you're mean.
And I'm right.
Look, for whatever reason,
what you had fits you.
It doesn't fit Alice.
If she keeps it, she'll die.
So what do I do? Take it back.
Maybe you don't want it,
but I think you'd prefer it
than to have Alice's
blood on your hands.
You need magic to
initiate the transfer of magic.
Alice has it all.
She'll never do it.
Well, fine. Go get some.
Oh, sure, I'll just
pop over to the store.
Actually, I think I
may know someone
who may be of assistance.
But given their
naked opportunism,
I can't imagine it'll come free.
What if the Fairy Queen
doesn't buy our "sick day"?
Tick's a crafty son of a bitch.
He's got us covered. Okay.
Eliot. Hey, guys.
We had the most
wonderful adventure.
We went to the Square of
Time, where no one sleeps.
And it's always light.
A man urinated next to me.
Then we saw bards performing
on your famous Broadway.
You call it Cats, but it's just
humans in cat greasepaint.
And we tried a
delicacy called pizza
at an eatery that
was "Family Style."
Well, I am so glad that you
two had some bonding time.
Hi, Todd.
Hi, Dad... Eliot.
Uh, Fray, did you
enjoy anything at all?
Earth? Or the Square of Time?
I do want you to
like things, you know.
I can tell you want
to be a good father.
It's sort of sweet.
I think I might grow
to despise you less.
With time. Oh!
Let's go with that.
Not to interrupt this
Hallmark moment,
but Todd, you got a sec?
Yeah.
Wait, fairies are real?
Mmm-hmm. I thought
Fray was just nuts.
I mean, she is, but, yeah,
they're real and
they're raging dicks,
so I'm gonna need you
to keep an eye on these.
Is someone going to come
looking for your weird eggs?
Just make sure
Fray doesn't see 'em,
and if you don't hear
from me by tomorrow night,
I've got another job for you.
Oh! Thank gods you're back.
What's with the feathers?
I had to make your
"chicken pox" convincing
to the Fairy Queen.
Okay. As long as she bought it.
Everyone in the castle did.
Even Prince Fomar and the
Stone Queen headed back
to their mountain/island.
The Fairy Queen has
no idea you were gone.
Well, that's good news, right?
So what's with the face?
Well, this just
took a dark turn.
In exchange for my babies,
you want my bathtub?
You collect toes and eyeballs,
and you think that's weird?
You'll pardon me, but I'm a
bit taken aback by this sudden
curious act of extortion.
Funny, we were taken aback
by the Floaters on spikes
on the side of the road.
We thought you'd be
alarmed by that too,
given you forced
us into that alliance.
So what's it gonna
be? Your bathtub?
Or do we start making fairy
and goat cheese omelets?
It's a strange deal.
Even for me. MARGO: Right.
I should be more specific.
You're giving your bathtub
to the entire
population of Fillory.
We're gonna make a
fondue fountain out of it.
It'll be fun.
And since I'll have a
deal with all Fillorians,
everyone will then
be able to see us.
I suppose you're right.
No more shadow-puppeting.
Just straight-up
puppeting, from now on.
Or hey, you could leave.
There is another
option, you know.
I find my children, and then...
You have till tomorrow.
So have fun on
the little egg hunt,
'cause if you don't
make this deal,
we're about to boil and dye 'em
like it's motherfucking
Easter around here.
I don't know what that means.
So, if I understand
you correctly,
you had magic before,
and you lied to me about it.
Now you don't have magic and
you've come to me why, exactly?
Because I need your help.
Well, why should
I trust you now?
You've already lied to me once.
She's lied to me
several times too.
So at least you
know it's not personal.
Like it wasn't personal
when you swooped in
and bought my school,
without so much
as texting me first.
Henry, trust me,
better me than them.
Them. IRENE: Anyone but me.
And don't think the rest of
the board wasn't considering it.
You said that your family
has reserves of magic...
Limited reserves.
I just need a little bit.
I gave what I had to a friend.
Why the hell would you do that?
But it is killing her.
So without your help, she
will die and so will the magic.
All right.
Tell me about this Voltaic
Transfer you performed.
Oh, shit. Margo's gonna kill me.
You knew about this?
I thought I was very clear
about not looking
in the cubbyhole.
You were. That's why I looked.
Fray, what are those?
Fairy eggs. That
Father and Margo took.
You don't know that.
Just when I was starting
to think humans aren't
all bad, they steal babies?
The Fairy Queen
stole you from us.
No, you bargained me
away. I did no such thing.
It was a fair deal.
This is kidnapping.
Unlike you, we have honor.
You're not a fairy, Fray.
Do you honestly believe
the Queen will ever see you
as anything but human?
Because she won't.
That's not true.
Um, didn't you say she
named you Frail Human?
That's pretty cold.
Humans are complicated.
Sometimes good people
can make bad decisions.
Yeah, like, I once
donated a kidney
to this girl I really liked.
Only, it turned out she didn't
actually need it for a transplant.
No matter what you think,
I know who you truly are.
My daughter, and Eliot's. And...
You just need to trust he did
this for a very good reason.
Family is about
loyalty, my love.
Fuck you!
Thought you said Victoria
was your best friend.
She slept with Josh.
On our Fillorian spring break.
While he and I
were still dating.
Are you really still
upset about Josh?
Can't we move past that? I
mean, we were like sisters.
Yeah, do you not get that that
only makes it more fucked up?
Sorry, could we just
focus for a second?
It's just kind of important.
Look, even if magic was
back, and these tattoos worked,
I still wouldn't help you.
'Cause I don't trust you.
Okay, will you just hold
on to this for a second?
Victoria, be real with
me. You owe me that.
I know. It's just not
that simple, okay?
I work with this group
now, and I can't just...
Group?
Yeah, it's kind of about
freedom of information.
So believe me, we have no
problem dicking over the Library.
It's just... we got
something going on.
Wait, is your boss...
Is she like 40-something,
hot, mostly rolls in ASL?
Okay, so, if you know
this Harriet person,
can you get her to help?
She doesn't exactly
like me. QUENTIN: Great.
So Victoria hates
Poppy. Harriet hates you.
So it makes perfect sense.
Some people are
just so emotional.
Harriet does like Kady, though.
Okay, great, then
let's talk to Kady.
Where is she?
Shit.
Kady.
All right, I can help you.
But you'll owe me a favor.
What's the favor?
To be determined.
Trust her. What could go wrong?
Oh, Henry, don't be angry at me.
It was buy the place
or let the Hewitts liquidate
everything on eBay
and turn this place into
a... An amusement park.
At least I care.
You care about something.
Do we have a deal?
Is that cocaine?
It's the excretion of a
very rare magical creature.
But, yes, you will
have to snort it.
I'm sorry, what creature?
I thought you had batteries.
Look, you asked me for my help.
This is what I have to offer.
Okay, Kady is in
the High-Risk Ward,
down the hallway over here.
The ward is locked.
So is Kady's room.
And there's a guard station
at the entrance right here.
Okay.
Those squiggles are guards?
Yeah, see? Little guard hats.
Gotcha.
So, how are we gonna
get in past all the security?
We're not. They are
gonna bring her to us.
By law, if they wanna
hold her involuntarily
for more than 15 days...
They have to bring in
outside doctors to
certify she's crazy.
Yeah, and we will
be those doctors.
They'll buy that?
I mean, won't they check
credentials and shit?
No, it's like a state hospital.
Yeah, their computer
systems are older than we are.
By the time they find anything
on us, we'll be long gone.
Good thinking.
Should I be concerned
that you both know
so much about this?
Mmm...
There was a "crazy" time.
Okay, whatever, uh...
But it's not like you two
can just walk out of there
with a patient.
No, but Kady can
walk herself out
if she has a security badge.
And what, she's supposed to
steal one of those off a guard?
No, I will.
Here we are.
Kady, this is Dr. London,
and... I'm sorry, Dr...
Kline. Midtown
Mental Health Clinic.
Which is where we work.
Yes. We're here
to do an evaluation.
Great. Mind if I sit in?
No, not at all. Please do.
Okay, um, so, Kady,
Dr. Walton here tells us
that you've been suffering
from delusions, and that
you've been talking to someone
named Penny?
Oh, um, yeah.
Don't look at me. Stay cool.
We're breaking you out of here.
Kady, can you tell
us about Penny?
Yeah, yeah, he was a... My ex.
But I don't see him anymore.
Quentin's gonna hand
you a security badge.
It'll get you out of the ward.
When you're on
break, in the day room,
use it to sneak
out. We'll be waiting.
Oh. Someone has
lost their badge.
Great.
What now?
What if she doesn't
take the deal?
Then what do we do? Or, no...
What if she takes the deal,
and then it's all-out war?
Stop it.
It's going to be fine.
We could cut our losses.
We could head back
to Earth and regroup.
We could finish the
quest, restore magic,
and then maybe revisit this
when we stand a fighting chance.
You and I both
sacrificed a lot for Fillory.
And now we're supposed
to just hand over the kingdom
to the albino supermodel?
Bitch took my eye.
Hey, I don't wanna leave.
But what if we're
making things worse?
There wasn't a blood test
to tell me to be High Queen.
I chose it.
And I have had to fight
for every shred of authority.
And no offense,
but you can't understand,
because it was handed to you.
And now I'm supposed
to abandon my kingdom?
Those fairy bitches wanna
come for my crown, well...
I'll shove it up their
fucking eggholes.
Well, that raises some
anatomical questions, but...
I'm on board.
Maybe try the key.
What? Well, I don't know.
Like, wave it
around or something.
Maybe a keyhole
will appear in the wall.
This is stupid.
And I feel sick.
Why are you here anyway?
We already stuck
a fork in this, Penny.
We're helping you.
All of a sudden?
After I was such a ray of
sunshine to you last time.
We need you to talk to Harriet.
We need her help
getting the next key,
so we can bring magic back.
All right. And
where's the next key?
In the Underworld.
I'm the only one
who can get it, Kady.
You're doing it
again, aren't you?
Throwing your life at
a problem to solve it.
I'm tired, Penny.
What couple deals with this
kinda shit on a regular basis?
I thought we weren't a couple.
That's not funny.
It's a little funny.
Hey, yell at me.
I don't want to. I
am tired of yelling.
Yell at me.
I'm getting you
out of this room.
Come on!
Okay, Kady.
Hand over the contraband.
What's up?
Go, team.
Alice, what're you doing here?
What are you?
I thought you were
in a psych ward.
I was.
Now I'm the sanest
woman in America.
Thanks to the 14 pills
I took this morning.
I actually can't
really feel anything.
It's fantastic.
If I didn't know
better, I would say
that you were
just trying to cast
an intermediate unlocking charm.
That would mean
that I have magic,
which we both
know is impossible.
Right.
Well, don't bother. I
already looted the place.
Brakebills may be
closed. Black market's not.
Gotta make a living.
You looking for
something special?
Some Boswellia.
Bloodstone, steroids.
Fuck me.
So you do have magic.
What do you know
about transplants?
I know you'd have
to be desperate
to try something that stupid.
Well, who am I to judge?
I almost blew a
werewolf so he'd turn me.
Magical creatures...
They can hang on to
their magic just fine, so...
Please...
If you have anything
that can help me...
Well, Boswellia and
Bloodstone are total bullshit.
But steroids
might help a little.
It's more of a Band-Aid
than a cure, but...
It says take two.
You should take eight.
Thank you. We're
all screwed anyway.
Smoke 'em if you got 'em.
Dr. Bailey, you're needed
at nurse's station 204.
Dr. Bailey... Nurse coming.
I know you don't
wanna talk right now.
I sure don't. Yeah,
yeah, hate me later.
I'm going to the Underworld,
Kady, give me this.
You're the best
thing in my life.
Short life, granted, but...
I want you to know I don't
regret a fucking second.
Well, you should.
It's crazy we lived this long.
We met. We had great sex.
I got to know you.
I'm lucky.
What's your point?
Don't be mad too long.
I want you to be happy.
Jesus Christ.
I can't be.
Without you, you fucking idiot.
But isn't that just adult life?
Accepting your own misery.
MALE NURSE OVER
PA: Code Green...
Shit. I guess they
found my room.
Come on.
We need a new plan.
We can't just leave Kady
and the key
locked up in there...
I know, I know.
Quit being so twitchy.
You look suspicious.
No, I'm not. You're suspicious.
Attention, this is a Code Green.
Everyone stay in their
room. Shit. Lockdown.
And stay calm. We
are on lockdown.
We're gonna have to help her...
Attention, this is a Code Green.
You sure this is gonna work?
It's fire safety protocol.
How do you not know that?
NURSE OVER PA:
Attention, please proceed
to the nearest fire exit
- and evacuate immediately.
- See? Works every time.
How many times
have you done this?
And evacuate immediately.
Keep it moving!
I told you we'd figure it out.
Shit. PENNY: Damn it.
Whoa!
Come on, let's go.
Well.
Alice is gone.
Might be time to use this.
To cast a locator spell.
Ugh.
Reminds me of the old days.
I don't wanna know.
This magic... It
looks different.
It feels different.
If it's working,
let's not split hairs.
Find her.
Wait a minute. What's
Alice doing there?
I'm blind. Are you
going to tell me?
Eliot, Fray found the eggs.
She was upset and
tried to take them.
I stopped her, but she ran
away and we can't find her.
This is not good.
And real bad timing, El.
Yeah, Fen, we are about to
have a delicate negotiation,
and while I am worried
about our daughter,
we need to put a pin in it.
There's nothing we
can do about it right now.
Perhaps I can help. Fray.
We've been having quite a talk.
Eggs and portals and quests.
So much going on
I didn't know about.
We really should discuss.
Crap.
Fray? How could you?
Like you said, family loyalty.
I've considered your offer.
And I propose a counter.
Don't hurt my children.
I won't hurt yours.
Wait. What?
No. Don't you touch her.
But my Queen...
Let's just all calm down
and talk about this, okay?
No one needs to
get hurt. I agree.
I... I helped you. I...
Yes.
You're a perfect specimen
of human duplicity.
Betrayed your own parents.
Why would I ever trust you?
I just found the eggs and
couldn't believe they would...
I just wanted all this to stop.
So let's stop this.
We gotta give her the eggs.
There's gotta be another
way. That's our only leverage.
I know, but she's my daughter.
We have a whole
country to think about.
I can't be the dad that
turns his back on his kid.
I'm not your daughter.
I'm just a human who...
What're you saying? What?
Explain.
Now...
Or it's poached eggs tonight.
Fray isn't yours.
Your real daughter
died during childbirth.
She died?
Oh, gods, I...
Oh, no. Oh, no.
That is the sound of
your leverage dying.
You'd better shake on
this deal while you still can.
No, no way.
Please. No.
I'm asking for this favor.
Okay, okay, look.
Look, I'm... I am grateful
for everything you did for me.
For Penny.
So how about this?
What if...
Then we both get what we want.
So we're gonna rob the Library?
Oh, awesome. No, not awesome.
Stupid.
It is hard enough to
sneak one person in there.
How the hell are they
gonna get the whole group in?
It's the dumbest
fucking plan I've ever...
Penny's got some notes.
You said you wanted to do this.
You don't know the
defenses this place has.
I don't wanna see you get hurt.
Are you the only one who
gets to do something stupid?
You've been waiting to say that.
I know what I'm doing.
My head's clear now.
You got me out.
We'll get the key out.
You just... You have to go,
if that's what you wanna do.
Yeah, don't get me wrong.
Being on the
Astral Plane's great.
Just a little over
being stuck here.
Bringing magic back is the
only way I see out of this.
Wouldn't it be funny if
we made it out of this?
I'd laugh pretty hard.
Look, this tweaker's worried
the key's already moving on,
so I gotta go be a book
and get eaten by a dragon.
Yeah, I heard that one before.
I love you.
I'm sorry we're cursed.
He's gone.
What, like, gone?
Gone-gone? Like...
Like, to the Library gone?
Gone to the Underworld, gone.
So let's not fuck
it up on our end.
Are you sure you wanna do this?
It's not exactly like
everyone thinks...
Jonesing for blood.
Watching everyone you know die.
That is, if you don't
kill them yourself.
You don't seem like the fan
girls who usually come to me.
You seem smart. Too
smart to want all this.
I don't want it.
Then why... It's none
of your business.
Well, then, no.
Becoming a creature...
No offense... Is the only way
I can keep my magic.
Why are you trying
to talk me out of it?
I'm not. But are you so sure
this'll do what you want it to?
No, but I'm out of options,
so will you take
my money or not?
All right.
Alice, let's go.
Jesus, how did you find me?
Spent some desperate times
around here looking for magic.
All I found were
shitty vampires.
Can we please go?
No, just leave. Continue.
Leave or I break it.
Ah! Get off me!
How did you do that?
Get out.
No, I gave you my money.
Not enough to deal
with hedge witch Buffy.
Good luck.
Out!
When we said we'd
explore our options,
I meant research,
not joining the undead.
I researched. This
is the only way.
No, it isn't. This is reckless.
Okay. I don't need your
help, you condescending bitch.
No, Julia.
I transferred it all back.
I'm sorry.
All you did was try to help
me, and I almost killed you.
Yeah, well, my magic
almost killed you, so...
I guess we're even.
We're not, but that's
nice of you to say.
Ever since Quentin
dragged me back, I've just...
I mean, what do
people in limbo do?
It's excruciating.
You know, and I just
thought maybe if I could just...
Fix it?
I know the feeling.
Really.
I still see Reynard.
You do?
Awake, in my dreams, yep.
Do you think
maybe it's because...
I think it's because
it happened.
And there's nothing
magic about it anymore.
When things happen,
they leave a mark.
Figuring out how to
deal with it takes time.
I get what Quentin
always saw in you.
You're brave.
Just stubborn.
I think that's why
you can hold it.
All the pain, and all the
shit you didn't ask for,
that's what made you you.
And that's why this magic fits.
Maybe sometimes life is random
and unfair.
You know, it doesn't
always ask our permission.
It just is.
Honestly...
It still makes me sick
to think that it was his.
Except that it's not
his anymore, Julia.
I felt it. It... It's yours.
For whatever reason.
So what are you
gonna do with it?
Fen.
Maybe you shouldn't be
holding sharp objects right now.
My father was a knife maker.
This is how I've
always calmed down.
When our daughter was born,
they took her away.
They wouldn't let me hold
her. I never heard her cry.
I should have known.
How could I not know?
God, I was so
ready to believe Fray.
I think deep down I thought...
If we just felt like a family,
if I just willed it hard enough,
then that would be real.
'Cause this...
How am I supposed
to live with it?
Oh, God.
God, Fen, I'm so sorry.
You would've been...
No, you were such a great mom.
And I was a shitty father
and an even shittier husband.
You deserve so
much better than this.
I'm gonna need some time.
I can't be in Fillory right now.
Okay, okay.
Hey.
Okay, dude. Spill.
What's up?
What if... Penny
doesn't find Benedict
or the key?
Or he gets caught by
a Librarian, or we do,
or any part of this
ridiculous plan fails?
It seems like you're
worrying about a lot of stuff
you can't control, here.
Everything that we're
doing, if we mess it up,
it's not just me who suffers.
It's not just us who suffers.
We're talking about
the entire multiverse.
No, it's not the multiverse.
Magic doesn't exist
in this universe.
It doesn't mean it's
gone in alternate realities.
That is not the point. Oh, boy.
What're you doing?
Short-circuiting
your panic attack.
It's getting tiresome.
Okay, I'm confused.
It's sweet how much you
care about your friends.
Even the ones
that don't like you.
Let's just have some fun.
Seems like the chances
of everyone surviving
go up if we do that.
Hmm?
Your eggs, I take it, are fine?
Yes.
What have you done with Fray?
She did not want
to return with me.
Her fate is her own.
Is the rest done?
The bathtub now belongs
to the people of Fillory.
May they be clean forever.
I'm sure they'll
appreciate the gift.
While we're at it.
What was your end game anyway?
The whimsical demands,
forced alliances...
Was it all just standard
"terraforming for world domination
"mega-villain" bullshit?
It's a sign of your
human privilege
that you see things so simply.
But it is simple, Lady...
You made us look crazy.
And aligning with the
Floaters made us look stupid.
But now everyone will understand
what was really happening to us.
Will they? You made the deal.
Everyone can see you now.
True. And they can see you too.
Whoa, there! Whoa, whoa!
Why are we
stopping? I don't know.
Children of Earth have been
making a mess of things here
for some time.
I can no longer help you.
Help us with what?
Eliot... This is sounding
a little too Les
Mis for my liking.
Okay, Bambi? They're armed.
Where the hell is she? Oh, shit.
- She planned this.
- Oh, my God!
Hold on! Hold on!
I'm your Queen,
you motherfuckers!