Previously on The Magicians...
Hey, can you help me
find some information?
What are you looking for?
Well, say you have a being with
an enormous amount of power.
I'm looking for how someone
might, you know, defeat them?
The Ars Deicidium?
The art of killing gods.
Any word on the Poison Room?
Believe me, I wanna get in
there. It's above my pay grade.
Penny, Sylvia.
You really don't need
my help. With what?
Trying to break into
the Poison Room.
I am telling you the truth
because you are the one I trust.
And I really just need
your support right now.
I controlled their minds.
Of course, honey.
Just like you have
many, many times.
They said they were
just trying to summon
a little help from
some kind of goddess.
They were summoning
an evil bitch.
The benevolent Our
Lady Underground?
It is all about her.
Grinding men and gods into the
fucking dirt, and then she leaves.
That's Ms. Persephone.
That's Our Lady Underground.
Julia. Why do you
look like a 12-year-old?
Because I'm her Shade.
Shades go to the Underworld.
Alice?
Quentin.
I missed you so much.
Is there any way we
can take her with us?
Jules, what the hell? I know.
This is my one shot, and
this is what I want to do with it.
No one has ever
brought Niffin back to life.
Many try, but all...
We have something that
no one else has ever had.
We have Alice's Shade.
The meta-math has never
added up before, but with this...
Still tremendously bad idea.
Fine. Fuck him. He won't help
us, we'll take it to Dean Fogg.
With one morning fart,
I release more magic
than Henry Fogg
has in his whole life.
But you can't
get it up for this?
No, you can't. I won't.
The energy we would need
would take 100 Master Magicians.
That's a battery.
That holds magical current.
That is the biggest one that I've ever
seen. How many of those do you have?
Not enough to spare. Took
years to make. And I need it. No.
What's more
important than a life?
You talk like life
means something.
If it doesn't, then what's the
point? This is what magic is for.
Boldly spoken, for student who
lacked the balls to control a flea.
Look, I survived your
abuse, and I got off my ass
and I went into the goddamn
world. What've you done?
You've sat around
and drank. Fuck you.
No, fuck you. Do you know
why Alice went to Brakebills?
To find out what
happened to her brother.
What happened
was his friend Emily
had the bad sense to fall in
love with you and it destroyed her.
And when he tried to help
it turned him into a Niffin.
Now tell me that you hold
zero responsibility for that.
You can't erase any of
that. But you can help Alice.
You can help Alice now.
You look worried.
Just thinking about Alice. She's
gonna be really pissed at me.
Yeah, but when she has
her Shade back, she'll get it.
Trust me.
Um...
Speaking of Shades,
since this is probably
the last time I'm
going to have one...
Look, you do not
have to do this.
Yes, I do.
You're a good friend.
Better one than I deserve.
Not true.
Blah, blah, feelings bullshit.
Let's begin. First we separate
Shade, which will pull Niffin here.
You memorized? Yeah.
You can handle it? Yes.
We're going to fix
you. But we just have to
lock you in here
for a minute, okay?
Thank you.
Julia, lock the cage.
She's coming.
Quentin! I will burn
you alive for this.
When you're ready, Coldwater.
It's gonna be okay.
Please. Please, Quentin, don't.
Hey.
I brought you some
clothes, if you, um...
Okay, um.
Why don't I go get you some
food. You haven't eaten in, um...
Mayakovsky said to...
Uh, start with really
bland food, so I thought...
Oatmeal?
Why?
Why bland food? Or
why did I bring you back?
Hmm.
I couldn't leave you like that.
Alice...
Fuck you.
So, the Poison Room,
the code to the door changes
every couple hours. The
door itself is warded, alarmed.
And don't forget booby-trapped.
So instead of going through
the magical dismemberment door,
let's go through the back way.
That door isn't just a door.
It's a portal to another world.
That's where the Poison Room is.
So, if we find the
right fountain...
We can walk right in. I heard a
couple Librarians whispering about it.
The Poison Room fountain
has a stack of books for a statue.
If we split up, we could probably
find it within a matter of weeks.
Weeks? No, no. I
got this. Think hours.
What makes you so cocky?
'Cause I'm a Traveler.
And for once, it's
not totally fucking me.
It is customary to bow in the
presence of your High King.
I... We... How are you here?
I think, and by that I
mean I'm absolutely certain,
that I was banished. Had to be.
So, in the books,
Ember and Umber,
before Martin offed
him, they did this
to the Chatwins
all the time, right?
Mmm-hmm. Um...
Yeah. Uh, when the
adventure was done, or...
Or what, Q? My pregnant
wife is locked up in Fairy Gitmo,
I'm betrothed to a rat,
my pinot noir grapes
are nearly ripe.
My adventure's just begun. So
why else would Ember banish me?
Because I'm a fuck-up.
Yeah, so... So,
the button. Give me.
Uh, about that. Um...
We kind of bargained
it away to a dragon,
in exchange for tickets
to the Underworld.
You gave our only means of
traveling to Fillory to fucking Trogdor?
Oh.
Both the High King and
Queen have vanished,
leaving you the only
Child of Earth in Fillory.
Oh, my God. They
were my ride home.
Um, yes.
Also, it makes you High King.
You can go to the Rainbow
Bridge to be crowned.
Meh. Let's skip the ceremony.
On to business, then.
Half the court are still rats.
The Talking
Beavers are in revolt,
they're demanding
dental coverage.
And the Measly Mountains, they've
disappeared. Completely, just...
Stop! The thrones are cursed!
Okay, is anything not fucked?
Your High Kingliness, perhaps
this is all too much for you.
There was a great king on
Earth who had a philosophy.
Hakuna matata. Roughly
translated, it means, "No worries."
That's my philosophy, too.
Who gives a shit about
a few Measly Mountains?
But... Erase them.
Bring in the talking rats to
translate for the rat-people.
And we are giving all those beavers
braces, because they deserve it.
Say it, Tick.
Hakuna matata.
That's what I'm talking about.
I'm sorry.
I got my Shade back.
And then I lost it again.
For good. But I also discovered
that I don't have to
be like The Beast.
With the right help, I can do
good. I just have a chip missing.
What do you want from me, Julia?
To be the missing chip. Tell
me when to tap on the brakes.
"Tap"?
Slam on them.
I trust you.
I need you.
Shit.
Okay. We can try it.
Thing is, I think I kind of
need you too right now.
Something you need to know.
Does Reynard know
that you're here? No.
Okay. It's good. It's important
that we keep up appearances.
I know. I've seen what
he can do when he's angry.
John, tell her what you told me.
About Our Lady Underground.
Reynard's obsessed with her.
I think they were
lovers, but she left him.
Everything that he has
done to her followers, to you...
It's not random. It's
to get back at her.
Yeah.
Holy shit.
Persephone is Our
Lady Underground?
I saw her icons when
I was down there.
Maybe we can use
her to lure Reynard.
Didn't you just say
that she disappeared?
Well, we just need to make
Reynard believe that it's her.
If he thinks that
she's here, he'll come.
Well, okay, and then? We
still don't have a weapon.
We have him. What do you...
No! No! No! We're
not killing you
for your power,
John, that's insane.
Agreed. Off the table. What we
are gonna do is teach you magic.
I'm not a Magician.
No. You're more.
Which is why it should
be easy for you to learn.
I mean, we don't have the
juice to take Reynard on.
But you do.
Can you tell me again
what the dragon said?
You know Mayakovsky banned
me from seeing Alice for 48 hours?
He said that I am upsetting her.
Well, he's not exactly wrong.
I'm trying to help.
You did. Now maybe you can
help by letting it run its course.
What if she... Q.
The greatest Magician
on Earth is watching her.
I know Mayakovsky can
be a massive asshole,
but he's not gonna actually
let anything happen to her.
Not after what it cost
him to bring her back.
All right, let's do that.
I know it's hard right now.
But it's gonna be okay.
I think.
Now will you please tell me what
Puff the Magic Dragon said to you?
"The first portal
is still open."
I thought that might
mean Stonehenge.
The kids go there
in book three...
How many times was
that portal opened?
Once. There's always
some new, unexpected...
Except for the first
one that they used.
Um, they went back and forth
through that clock all
summer, right? Mmm-hmm.
Until their mother died, and
their uncle sold all their stuff.
Um...
I think I saw it.
At my Yale interview.
Uh, it was the same one
as the one on the cover.
I mean, the guy died.
They probably sold it
off. But what if, um...
What if the clock I
saw was "the" clock?
Why the fuck are you taking a
nap instead of looking for me?
Margo?
I thought you were banished.
No, dumbass, I'm stuck in the
Fairy Realm. How can I see you?
Oh, shit. She must've
mixed in the wrong strain.
We wanted "bang like happy
pandas," not "see other worlds."
Never let an amateur
pack your bong, okay?
Listen, dipshit.
You have to find Rafe,
the squirrelly little prick
who works for the sloth.
He got me here,
he can get me back.
You could say "please."
No, I literally could not.
I'm gonna go find Fen, you find
a goddamn way to get me back.
Okay.
Pretty sure this is it.
Book statue. Not the most
imaginative, those Librarians.
Yeah, but not stupid.
Look, it's covered.
And locked. Never
seen anything like this.
Six-stage Vermel
anti-tampering enchantment.
I can crack it.
That's pretty
varsity... for a kid.
My dad's a good teacher.
All right, so who
pissed him off?
You're going to a lot of trouble
to get at some of the most
powerful battle magic in the universe.
Somebody's about
to have a bad day.
I know it's hard for
men to imagine women
having their own
reasons for doing anything,
but I'm looking for my own book.
I've been hidden away in
a library for the last year.
No TV, no Wi-Fi. Had to find
some way to entertain myself,
so I started reading
Kanye's book.
By the way, he's
really misunderstood.
Anyway, right in the middle of a
sex scene, the book just stopped.
Kanye dies during sex?
That's the weird part. There
were 20 more pages, all blank.
It's a glitch, right?
But then every other book I
checked for somebody alive right now,
ends in 20 blank pages.
The Order's known
about it for years.
They call it the
Great Blank Spot.
Some kind of
cataclysmic badness.
Well, what causes it?
They don't know. Just that
it happens soon, like, weeks.
How's reading your
book gonna help?
Something happens
that affects the Library,
it'll be in a Librarian's book.
But right now, they're moving
all the Librarians' books
to the Poison Room.
Including mine.
The Order thinks that
once your book is written,
your fate is sealed.
Well, I've never seen
a book be wrong. You?
No. But I saw them
reshelf your book 39 times.
If time loops exist, then
I'm Team Sarah Connor,
"No fate but what we make."
Fine. I'll grab
your book for you.
I'll get it myself.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
You're not coming.
How are you gonna get back?
I can't travel anyone with me.
You think this is my first
time fountain spelunking?
Well, the fountain didn't
drop us in a lava pit,
so we've got that going for us.
When they named
it the Poison Room,
how literal do you
think they were being?
Let's just do this fast.
Yeah.
Coming in on the weekend!
Now, that is work ethic.
I was hoping to run
into you, actually.
I, uh, have questions,
and I would appreciate
some fatherly guidance.
I'd like that, too.
Here.
Struck me that I've missed
a lot of birthdays. Open it.
What is...
You went back to the witches.
Where is she? Where is my wife?
Oh.
Here and there.
I saved you the biggest piece.
Are you still trying to be a good
person, as if there is such a thing?
Left alone, you would fight
and fight against your nature,
and you would waste so
much of what you really are.
If you think doing this is
going to turn me into you,
you don't understand
people at all.
I've been at it a long time.
Oh, look at Julia.
I put a tiny black
spot on her soul,
and she scrubbed at it so much,
she put a hole in it.
She can never go
back to who she is.
And now,
neither can you.
This
is an investment
in our future, son.
Someday, when you've
embraced what you really are,
you'll come find me.
Can I help you?
Hi.
We're looking for a clock.
It belonged to my grandfather.
The auction website,
it listed this address.
Auction websites don't do that.
Fine. We bribed the webmaster.
The clock's got a lot of
sentimental value. So...
Sorry. There's no clock here.
The clock was an unremarkable
thing, on its surface.
To keep his mind off the
troubles of war and family,
Martin set out to
repair its inner workings,
and in place of a
mechanical heart...
He found a new world.
That's my favorite
chapter in the book.
Holy shit, there are two of you.
Oh, don't touch that. Oh.
Please, put that down.
Sorry. Okay.
Is that...
Screenplay for the failed
1983 feature film adaptation.
There is a Fillory movie?
No, the studio wouldn't
pay for the talking bears,
so the director,
he quit in protest.
Can I?
Yeah.
Q. Uh, I found Grampy's clock.
Wait, they changed
the Chatwins...
To skateboarding
Americans. I know, a travesty.
And they got Jane
completely wrong.
A girl that timid could never
grow up to be a Watcher Woman.
Okay, real talk.
I'll give you $1,000
for the clock.
It's a collector's item.
$20,000. It's not for sale.
Wait. The books never had
said who the Watcher Woman is.
Well, it's not hard to deduce.
Anyone who's
always wearing a hood
is clearly a character
you've met before.
You know, don't you?
That it's all real. You...
You've been to Fillory.
"Been to Fillory."
Even in Fillory, the Watcher
Woman's identity is a secret.
Who are you? Oh, my God.
Q, he has horns.
Like Ember, like...
Just like Ember. What?
Holy shit.
Umber? In the flesh.
Are they in the eye
of... What even is that?
Lightning storm, huge.
Happened every time Persephone
ascended from the Underworld.
She used to come every spring.
Now, decades, no pattern, no trace.
Except, these modern
accounts show four storms
stretched across the entire
swath of southern Europe.
And smack in the
center, Murs, France.
So, we just need to kick up
a light storm, a few twisters.
And Reynard will think Our Lady
is on Earth. He'll come running.
Are you okay? I, uh...
I need a drink.
How was spell practice?
I can barely make a spark.
I thought you said it'd be easy.
You know, no
pressure, or anything...
Do you ever think about
where you'd be, if he hadn't...
Raped me?
No. I try to focus on who I was.
It's getting harder, though.
Reynard thinks he broke you.
That there's no coming
back from what he did.
You think that's true?
I hope not.
Well, whatever happens...
Don't let him be right.
I think you should
go get some pizza.
Okay.
Food run. Listen...
I wish we had time
to talk this through,
but ultimately, I know
you'd agree with me.
What are you talking about?
Oh, my wards.
I'm sorry. Why?
Why are you doing this to me?
After everything Julia's been
through, I can't make her do this.
Do what?
This is very good.
Tea? I don't have time.
Ah! Brilliant, the
shortcut. There!
I don't have time.
I understood everything.
And now it's fading like a
dream that you woke me from.
Why can't I do magic?
You are newborn again.
You must crawl, then walk.
How long?
What's the rush?
I'm stuck in this... This
oily, disgusting cage,
and I can't even fucking
see. I can't do anything.
On the contrary, you
are finally in a position
to do something interesting.
Fuck you. What do you know?
I know, as Niffin, you care
about nothing but your own mind.
So, congratulations. A
perfect life with zero meaning.
Now, as human...
Humans are weak pieces of shit.
Do you know what magic is?
Energy capable of
making this shithole world
one fractional speck
less unbearable.
Because we shits
try so fucking hard.
And that is not
weakness, believe me.
You don't like this world? Good.
You see its faults,
it gives you focus and
solitude to actually fix it.
Adderall. To fortify you.
Makes you write like Tolstoy.
Don't make face.
Drugs are fun.
Hey, I wasn't sure what
kind you wanted so...
I know, I...
Oh, my God.
He made me.
What?
He made me do the ritual.
Collect his power.
Hey.
You get yourself cleaned up,
and I'll handle the rest, okay?
There you are,
you son of a bitch.
Ah.
Sylvia, where are you? Sylvia!
Sylvia, read it when we
get back. We gotta go.
You betrayed Ember?
I wouldn't call it that.
I just had no choice.
It was a matter of survival.
A condition of the agreement
I made with Martin Chatwin.
He had Fillory booby trapped to
the gills. He was about to filet me.
So, you faked your own death
and you moved to Vancouver?
Well, if I had to leave Fillory,
Canada was the
obvious second choice.
What is it that you
enjoy about Fillory?
It reminds me of a time before I
realized how shitty being an adult is.
And there's opium in the air.
And how do you
feel about turtles?
Indifferent, I guess.
Not a fan.
Would you sleep easier
knowing that your entire world
rested on the back of one?
Or several?
What? Why are you asking?
Because as visitors
to my previous work,
you make for an excellent
focus group for my new world.
Something I've been building.
Testing a few things out.
It's more of a
pocket world, really.
I call it Cuba.
That's already a place.
Is it? Yes.
You're sure? Absolutely sure.
Oh.
Damn it.
Look, this is all
very interesting-ish.
But I have a kingdom to fix.
You were never meant to
fix Fillory. Of course I was.
No, you were meant to
entertain like some reality TV star.
Oh! Ember must've
found you so boring.
Boring?
Fillory was created out of
the unification of opposites.
Ember is a creature
of entropy and chaos.
And you have every season
of Law & Order on DVD.
The most perfect
show in creation.
When Ember and I were
together, there was balance.
Without me, chaos reigns.
Give up, Children of Earth.
Fillory cannot be ruled.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Get up! Come on!
Just stop worrying about me
and fucking travel out already.
Look, I will carry your
ass back if I have...
You don't get it.
I don't make it
back to the rope.
My book didn't have
a blank spot. So what?
What happened to "there's
no fate but what we make"?
If you carry me back,
you die too, Penny.
I read it.
Leaving me is the only
way you have a chance.
Penny! I got your book.
What the hell? Penny? Oh, my...
Help!
Give me good news, Rafe.
Unfortunately, returning from
the Fairy Realm is problematic.
All I have is this tincture
that takes you there.
Why would I drink this?
Then I'm stuck there with Margo
and you can't get
either of us out.
Prince Ess of Loria, Your
Majesty. Where is my father?
Hey, I don't think
we've formally met.
Cut the shit. I will tear
this place apart if I have to.
So, uh, funny story.
Your dad is actually
a rat-person now.
Do it. He's...
Oh.
Break it down.
Hakuna matata has failed me.
It pains me, but I simply
cannot go back to Fillory.
So, you're just gonna let Ember
turn Fillory into a telenovela?
Well, you don't
understand how he is.
He pitted animals
against each other
by offering only the
sexiest the ability to speak.
Centaurs? Drunk off
his chair, obviously.
When he gets snacky, he talks
about turning humans into rats.
Holy shit.
Ember turned
everybody into rats.
Oh, he finally did it.
That's been on his
bucket list for centuries.
Ember cock-blocked me.
You're a god of Fillory.
Why are you just sitting here and
letting your brother shit all over it?
You let The Beast happen.
You shut out a child
who needed shelter,
and when he became
a monster, you ran.
You hate chaos?
Then fix the chaos
that you created!
You're right.
But some mistakes
cannot be repaired,
and from those we
must move forward.
And I shall try to avoid repeating
such mistakes in my new world.
Fine.
Then give us the clock.
Why do you care?
Fillory's on its last legs.
Everything you've said tells
me Ember is tired of the game.
He's likely to smash the
place like a toddler. Trust me.
That'll be it. End of Fillory.
And don't get sentimental.
We aren't ready
to walk away yet.
We know you still love Fillory.
You literally have every
memento to prove it.
If you can't fix it or won't
save it then let us try.
Please.
You love Fillory?
It's my home.
Then the clock is
yours, Your Majesty.
But heed my warning.
Nothing entertains Ember
more than a whimsical death.
Hey. Hey.
How's Penny? Still alive?
I could've worded that better.
Yeah.
Uh, they cleared out
the whole Infirmary.
Something about radiation.
That can't be good.
Not much I can do
about it right now.
So, you've got time.
Kill it with me,
killing Reynard.
Good news. I
found a spell in here
that turns metal objects
into god-piercing weapons.
And if it can be
anything, gun, right?
But it took everything John
gave us just to make one bullet.
So, we've got one shot.
Fall back! Don't
inhale the smoke.
Oh, shit.
Luckily I'm a pro.
Come on. Come on.
Fen?
Josh, you can see me?
Fen! Josh, help me!
Help me! Please, hurry.
Tick...
Tell my story.
Well, this is it.
The sign Reynard
has been waiting for.
Come on out, asshole.
Something feels so right about
tricking him with goddess omens.
Amen. Let's get
scarce. Let's go.
I know you're here.
There he is.
The lightning, the wind.
Always were a drama queen.
I can't get a clear shot.
Go around the other side.
I'll get you a clear shot. Kady.
Hey!
Ah.
I should've known.
Where's Julia?
Why don't you ask
me where John is.
What did you do?
Nothing he wasn't asking for.
Hated you so much,
he begged me to kill him.
You bitch. You liar.
Kady, what...
It's you.
You ignored us.
And now you're here?
All of a sudden?
Why?
To ask you to spare his life.
I don't understand.
Why do you care?
He's my son.
Did you know what he was doing?
Of course you did.
He raped me. Your son!
I'd be sobbing, and
telling you every detail,
but I lost my Shade
in the abortion,
so you're just gonna
have to take my word for it.
Let me deal with him.
Why would I trust you?
Come the fuck on, lady.
There are consequences
to killing a god, Julia.
I lost my friends, I lost everything.
He turned me into a monster.
You're a survivor.
You're still capable of mercy,
Julia. Don't let him rob you of that.
It's your choice.
I'm so disappointed
with what you've done.
You left me. You left me.
Well, I'm back.
And it's time to go.
No! No!
How can you do this?
After everything
we've been through?
I killed John for this.
It was the right thing.
How the hell would
you know that?
I'm sorry, Kady.
Our Lady sent me.
Hey, I'm sorry I hurt you.
I tried to do the right thing.
But I'm not sorry
that you're alive,
and maybe that makes
me selfish, but I...
The world's a better
place when you're in it.
Say the word and I'll stay.
If you want me
to leave you alone
for a while to figure
this out on your own...
I mean, let's face it, there's
probably nothing you can't figure out.
You are Alice Quinn.
Okay.
So, the plan so far is,
find a way to stay in Fillory
and never get banished again.
Find a way to stop
Ember. Or drive him out or...
I don't know, anything
but letting him get so bored,
he decides to just
shake the Etch A Sketch
and end our kingdom,
everyone I care about,
and the Wellspring
in the process, so...
Thoughts?
You're talking about
conquering Fillory.
For its own good.
Your plan is the exact
same as The Beast's was.
Shit.
Do you got a better idea?