ELIOT: Previously
on The Magicians...
No more magic means
no more idiotic Earth rulers,
and I get my kingdom back.
We are gonna hunt down
every last living slaver,
and hang them by
their own entrails.
What does Jane have
to do with The Beast?
Ember gave her the
ability to create a time loop.
A time loop.
So far, all the loops
end in your death.
How many times have I died?
Thirty-nine... the Alice
from the 23rd timeline
was the sole
survivor of The Beast.
We need to talk to her.
DEAN: Well, you can't.
JULIA: Well, what
about a Tesla Flexion?
I'm from another timeline.
We only have two minutes.
I thought I'd never
see you again.
The Beast, he...
He tore you apart,
piece by piece, but
not just your body,
but your... Your
Shade, everything.
(HOWLS) I have
sexually-transmitted lycanthropy.
It's totally curable.
There is no actual
cure. A silver bullet.
These are my students,
they are in need
of the Rhinemann Ultra. (LAUGHS)
BIGBY: No one but you can
be within 20 feet of the blast...
It will kill anyone
including your Beast.
(GRUNTS)
So, you wanna tell me where
you hooked up with your partner?
Fillory.
If he smells you
again, he won't show.
If you want him,
you might just have
to risk losing your base.
You and your companions
are on a quest for seven keys?
Yes.
We have one of the
keys in the Fairy Realm.
Without the key,
everything collapses,
which is why we can
never give it to you.
ELIOT: I don't know what they
think is going on with my nose.
Yeah, and those
are not my teeth.
And only 1,000 Fillorian
Gold Crescents for us?
Tick is cheap. It'll
be his downfall.
I'll kill him. Who
you gonna kill?
That dick, Tick Pickwick.
Your incursion
into the throne room
put that cheapskate
on red alert.
Wait, we're on there too?
You're kings and
queens of Fillory,
so you're a threat to his reign.
Yeah, well, so was Josh.
I don't see his face on there.
He was more like a
substitute teacher, didn't count.
We got news. Uh,
Julia sent a bunny.
Apparently, her and the Fairy
Queen are on good terms now.
Fucking what?
ELIOT: Hold on, so, on Earth,
the fairies are slaves,
and the Fairy Queen is...
A good guy, kind of?
Uh-uh. You know what?
Fuck Tinkerbitch. Fuck her
right in the Egg McMuffin.
Guys, we need Tinkerbitch's
help to get the Sixth Key.
Unfortunately, she's
as helpful as pubic lice.
Right, which is why
we should talk to Julia
and I think we
should do it in person.
Sorry, but we're all wanted,
and Tick's just stepped up the
patrols around the portal tree.
Well, why don't we
just send one of us?
It'll be easier to
break through.
I'll do it. You can't.
Tick wants your head,
says so right there.
Have you guys tried
this Fillorian salami?
It doesn't taste like
horse... (CHUCKLES)
What?
DEAN: Jesus, fuck.
I'm... (SCOFFS)
I'm much too sober for all this.
Yeah, well, you have to hear it.
A lot of the
McAllisters are dead,
but Irene is still out there,
and I don't know
what she's going to do.
Slavery, mass murder...
And yet, it smells
so floral in here.
Lucier's cleaning charm.
Next time, try less rosewater.
Any idea about how
to deal with Irene,
who will doubtless
want her property back?
Well, she'll have
to find it first.
Did you poke out her eyes?
No.
I replaced all the wards
and shields around Brakebills.
You did what? By yourself?
That's impossible.
That's apparently
what I can do now.
My magic's been growing,
maybe because I helped
free all those fairies.
(CHUCKLES)
This is new territory for me.
Me too.
Well, look, the school's
yours again, if you want it.
Sober up.
'Sup.
So, the Fairy Queen
can't give us the Sixth Key.
The Fairy Realm
will collapse without it.
Well, that blows.
Honestly, my instructions
ended at talk to Julia.
So what are we
supposed to do now?
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING) Uh...
How did we end
up at Burning Man?
We're inside a Tesla Flexion.
Is that a car?
A device that allows you to
communicate across timelines.
Like, alternate
universes-type shit?
Like alternate
universes-type shit.
Don't touch anything. Copy that.
Usual paradox/explosion
problems?
Someone cast
this to pull us inside.
We just need to find out who.
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
Thank God, it worked.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Holy mirror universes, Batman.
It's me.
Like, you're me...
Okay, calm your shit. I'm
from a different timeline.
You're in a Tesla
Flexion, we only have...
Two minutes. We know the rules.
Right. Of course.
You pulled Alice into
one of these before.
Wait, you're from
that same timeline?
That's right. Look,
we need your help.
There's this monster
here killing Magicians.
We call him The Beast.
12 fingers? Cloud of
moths around his face?
Yeah, I tried to get people
to call him
Mothra... Didn't stick.
Here either, can't
expect everyone
to be down with
the Kaiju classics.
Okay, guys, two minutes, right?
Right, uh, problem
is, magic vanished.
These plumber guys
showed up one day and just...
Shut it off like a faucet.
Here, too.
But you guys have no idea why?
No clue, except the problem is,
we lost magic, but
The Beast didn't.
He was suddenly unstoppable.
(STAMMERS) I don't understand.
So magic is gone,
but then how does
he still have it?
Dude, I don't know.
Maybe it has something to do
with this key around his neck.
Wait, what key?
Uh, about yea big.
Rumor is, it gives him
visions of the future.
Visions of the future...
None of our keys do that.
Look, Julia, in my timeline,
you were the best
student Brakebills ever had
until you were
horribly murdered.
Oh. But with your help,
we might stand a
chance against Mothra.
And Josh, well, you're me.
No argument there. (WATCH BEEPS)
Shit, uh, please...
You have to find
a way back here.
This is our most desperate hour.
Help us, Julia and Josh.
You're our only hope.
(EXHALES)
(EXHALES AND CHUCKLES)
Ended on a Star Wars reference?
He really knew how to get to me.
We're his new hope.
All I'm saying is, can
we even trust him?
Of course we can trust him.
It's me.
I would know if I was lying.
You said we can't
get the Sixth Key,
and visions of the future?
That has to be the seventh.
Any reason we
gotta do this in order?
I don't know.
Up until now, the book
told us where to go,
we got a key, and then
the book gave us a clue
about where to
find the next one.
Well, maybe this
time, we flip it.
The key quest
has been Q's thing.
I've been trying to
figure out my own magic.
Listen, I say we take
this problem back to him,
and see what he and the
others have to say about it.
Fine, but I will freely
admit I was getting excited
at the idea of a
Josh-Julia solo adventure.
Sorry.
Yeah, what would the
shippers even call us?
Josh? Julia? See?
You couldn't even tell that
I swapped the first letters.
Nope.
Where's the portal?
What happened?
The Time Key sent us to the lab.
Not our lab.
This place is a wreck.
Damn, that was fast.
We're in Timeline 23.
Act out.
This doesn't make sense.
The key was supposed
to take us to Fillory.
It just decided to
send us back here?
What even are the rules?
Beats me...
They're weirdly
inconsistent. Uh-huh.
I guess we have some shit
to take care of in Timeline 23,
maybe key-related.
It worked! They're here!
Marina?
Holy shit.
Wait, you know her?
Of course I do, she
was a year ahead of me,
and hot, um... (LAUGHS)
Okay, I know you by reputation,
but how do you know me?
I don't know you here?
No.
You went to Brakebills,
I'm a hedge witch, we don't mix.
So, what happened
in your timeline?
Um... I didn't go to Brakebills,
so we became friends.
Friends?
That does not sound like me.
Wait, you didn't
go to Brakebills?
That's, like, Hermione Granger
not getting into Hogwarts.
Alternate timeline
shit is weird.
Tell me about it.
Why don't we go somewhere safer?
We can talk about all this.
JOSH: Jesus, place hasn't looked
this partied out
since my first year.
So, you guys have no idea
why magic went away here?
No clue, how about in yours?
(SIGHS)
A god was killed by a human.
The old gods took it
away as punishment.
Bunch of Mount
Olympus-sized dicks.
And magic going out here was
the beginning of the end for us.
That Beast started
killing Magicians...
First Brakebills, then
the hedge witches.
So, we joined forces to survive.
Wait, so if The Beast
is killing Magicians,
is Brakebills really the safest
place for us to hang out?
Oh, he hasn't been here
since the first massacre.
Thinks everyone's dead.
We have scoured
what's left of the place
looking for a way to defeat
that moth-faced cock-whistler.
That's how we found
the Tesla Flexion,
and a battery to cast it.
And this sweet jacket.
It's not magic, but
might as well be.
Hey, speaking of magic,
we got some big news.
Julia can... (CLEARS THROAT)
Uh, tell you about it herself.
And it's not even...
It's not even big news.
I don't know why I said that...
Your Beast has some sort of key?
Mmm-hmm.
We need it.
You help us kill our Beast,
key is yours.
Deal.
Boom.
Let's celebrate, bitches...
Powerful women.
So, Marina, huh?
You know, I've always
had a crush on her.
I know.
Oh.
Right... (LAUGHS)
Hey, what happened
to the glasses?
Lasik.
You know, I've always
been too scared to do that.
You are the braver Josh.
I've been through some shit.
Tell.
Spring break Fillory
turned into a massacre.
I ended up stuck...
Stuck in the
Neitherlands, me too.
If the Physical Kids
hadn't shown up,
I don't know how long...
No one ever showed up for me.
No one made it out?
Some made it out, they
just forgot about me.
Dude.
So, I came back determined
not to need anybody.
I'd be a lone wolf...
Brave, heroic, solo.
Got Lasik, found
this sweet jacket,
and changed my fucking life.
Wow.
Is this like that time
when we got that
Kangol hat in middle school
and thought everything
was gonna be different?
No, it's not like that at all.
Cool.
Inspiring.
And, uh...
(EXHALES) Whew.
Did you...
Did you just roofie me?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GROANS)
Nighty-night.
(GROANING)
What happened?
JULIA: What the hell
are we tied up with?
It was Professor Sunderland's.
Wish I took more
classes with her.
Why are we all tied up?
'Cause we didn't have a way
to stop The Beast's attacks,
until now.
We're gonna give you to him.
This is insane.
You can't trust The Beast.
What makes you think he'll
make a deal instead of killing you?
You.
When he showed up here
with his key killing everybody,
he kept asking for you.
I don't understand, I
thought I was dead here.
You are, it was
actually pretty confusing.
So, maybe the guy
with the face full of moths
isn't in the best
place psychologically.
But it gave me an idea.
Give The Beast what he wants...
Julia, from an
alternate timeline
in exchange for
leaving us alone.
And what about me?
Sorry, bro.
You're the Cedric
Diggory of this story.
At least he died looking hot.
The Beast should be here soon.
He can sense magic.
There's no way he'd
miss that Tesla Flexion.
You have another choice.
In our timeline,
we killed The
Beast using a spell...
The Rhinemann Ultra.
(CHUCKLES) Yeah,
I've heard of that.
Don't you need
god-level power to cast it?
(SIGHS)
Yeah, you do.
(SHUDDERING)
(GASPING)
Also took care of your migraines
and smoking addiction...
You're welcome.
How did you... Long story.
Act out.
Easy, cowboy.
I promise you, it's real.
And we can use it to stop
The Beast once and for all.
So, what do you say?
You have this Rhinemann spell?
Dean Fogg will know where
to find it, if he's still alive.
Oh, he's still alive...
Not exactly the premier
educator he once was.
Kind of a walking opioid crisis.
I'll take you to him.
But Josh is our hostage
until we get back.
Enjoy swapping puberty stories.
They're the same stories.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
JULIA: So, you and Dean
Fogg are on good terms here?
I mean, he did kick
me out of Brakebills,
but he's warmed to
me a bit since then.
Nothing like watching all
of your students and friends
get murdered by a creature
from another world to open you up.
How do you know him? I
thought you didn't go to Brakebills.
It's complicated.
You fucked him. No! What?
Okay, defensive much?
He's not that bad in
bed... (CHUCKLES)
Okay...
Hey, speaking of,
what's the deal with you
and me in your timeline?
I'm sensing some
weird kinda tension.
Is it the fun kind?
Like I said, we were friends.
It wasn't always fun.
We got into a big fight,
uh, but we ended up
kinda getting over it.
That's it?
From your face, I was expecting
something a little more...
Dramatic.
Yeah, sorry to disappoint.
This way?
(MARINA 23 CLEARS THROAT)
DEAN 23: Marina.
Oh, come on.
I won't steal anything
from you this time.
What did you steal
from me last time?
Nothing, just forget
I said anything.
Just... I found an old
student of yours, okay?
(MULTIPLE LOCKS CLICKING)
Come in.
Timeline 40?
I have to live through
another 17 more of these.
Uh, you don't remember them all?
Only the ones I've
been through already.
I thought 22 was
absolutely dreadful,
until this one.
Is that really necessary?
If I'm going to experience
16 more of these fiascos,
it really doesn't matter
what I do, now does it?
No, it doesn't.
So, what about that spell,
the Rhinemann Ultra?
Ah, yes, the Rhinemann Ultra.
My friend Bigby had that.
Unfortunately, she's dead.
Everything went to
shit when magic died.
Creatures got set upon,
chopped up to steal their mojo.
That poor thing.
I killed a leprechaun once.
I'm not proud.
Just saying.
I'd forgotten how
entertaining he can be.
You wouldn't happen to
know where Bigby kept it?
The spell?
I don't.
But you're not the first
students to inquire about it.
There was this whole
puzzle thing I can skip over,
but I sent two
students to see her.
(SNIFFS) They died.
Seems to be a bit of a theme.
There's good news.
You see, their deaths were,
well, earth-shatteringly
horrible.
I mean, really
awful... (CHUCKLES)
I don't like to think
about it if I can help it.
Wait, so how is this good news?
Because they're ghosts, dear.
They still haunt the
Library, last I checked...
Pretty deep in the stacks.
They might remember the spell.
But I'd be careful
if I were you.
Ghosts, well, ghosts
can be dangerous.
Yeah.
JOSH: How could
you do this to me, man?
You're me, I'm you, we're us.
I would never betray myself.
You haven't been through
what I've been through.
Yes, I have, except the Lasik.
There's more than that.
Whatever.
You know, I thought
you were cool
and brave.
And I dug your jacket,
but now I just
think you're a dick,
which sucks, because
that means I'm a dick.
What do you expect?
My friends abandoned me.
Maybe they were right too.
What, did you roofie
and betray them too?
No.
It's not what I did,
it's what I'm gonna do.
How do you know
what you're gonna do?
The Quickening?
What's the Quickening?
I can't think about it.
I don't want all their
blood on my hands.
What the hell is the Quickening?
Nothing you need to worry about.
Just be glad you
didn't bang a werewolf.
Let's talk about
something else, okay?
Now I need an aspirin.
Yeah, the Library got ransacked
after The Beast took
out most of the school.
Honestly, I did most
of the ransacking,
but I didn't see any ghosts.
(BOTH SCREAM) Eliot, holy shit!
(EXCLAIMS) What
the hell was that?
I think I know the
students who died here.
Eliot and... ELIOT: Margo?
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
I told you we need to
get our shit together, Eliot.
I have my shit together.
No, you're holding your
shit together, barely.
There's a difference.
Don't let that pixie twat
Bigby get in your head.
She called me a lush,
which is basically just a
nice way of saying alcoholic.
(SCOFFS)
And she said I couldn't
handle the spell.
Why don't you prove her
wrong and help me, okay?
What are we doing?
Well, before we can
do the Rhinemann,
we need a power-up.
Here is a cooperative spell.
Now, if we can
cast this together,
it might just give us enough
juice to kill The Beast.
And if we cast it wrong,
kaboom.
So, let's not cast it wrong.
What if Bigby was right?
What if I am too drunk?
(STUTTERS)
What if I screw it up?
(GROANS) Ooh.
You are not gonna
cock out on me.
Cock out?
I'd say pussy,
but let's be honest.
Which one is tougher?
Point made.
(ELECTRICITY BUZZING)
(WHIMPERING) Oh, God, oh, God...
I screwed up, I screwed up,
I screwed up, I screwed...
(GROANING)
(SOBBING)
I screwed it up,
I screwed it up...
Bambi?
Where's my Bambi?
Come on. Oh!
Jesus Christ!
(SHUDDERING)
Cocks.
Oh, yuck, that was...
So yuck.
Not fun at all.
Please tell me
you got that spell.
Yeah, I think I can make it out.
(WHISPERING) I think
someone is following us.
When I give the signal,
stay out of the way.
Okay.
Now!
That's your signal?
Penny?
Julia.
So, it is you.
You're real.
You're alive.
Whoa! Um, uh...
Julia, it's me.
Yeah, I know.
God, it's like I'm...
I'm living in a dream.
Just let me short-circuit this.
If you think following
two strangers
and then kissing one of
them is dream behavior...
She's not a stranger.
She's my soul mate.
Oh, God.
(STUTTERS) I'm...
I'm actually not your Julia.
You see, I'm from
a different timeline.
One where romantic comedy
behavior gets you arrested.
I'm sorry, I thought...
No, it's... It's okay.
When I heard a rumor that
The Beast was looking for her
even though she's dead, I...
It's crazy, but I...
I had to see.
I'm sorry.
It was stupid.
Julia, we gotta get out of here.
Where are you going?
To kill The Beast.
Let me come with
you. Okay, sorry, buddy,
but we got everything we
need, no baggage necessary.
I wanna kill The Beast
as badly as you do.
He's a Traveler,
could come in handy.
Eye roll.
It's working, I can feel it.
(SIGHS)
It's just a lot of
moving pieces.
PENNY 23: So...
What's up with me
in your timeline?
Well,
you're kind of in
the Underworld.
Not good.
I'm not sure you're
technically dead.
So, in the Underworld,
but not dead?
That sounds worse.
Truth is,
you got there because
you did something heroic.
Unlike my alternate
self, who's a dick,
possibly related to
self-esteem issues,
and, I guess, lycanthropy.
Yeah, it sounds like y'all
got something to work out.
Here he comes.
Hey, can I ask
you one last time...
What is the Quickening?
No, you can't.
I don't wanna talk
about my private tragedy,
so unless you want
me to gag you...
Okay, fine, Dick Josh.
Don't call me Dick Josh.
Then don't be a dick, Josh.
I am not a dick. I've had
a harder life than you.
Did you? What makes you so sure?
(SCOFFS) Because you
get to hang out with Julia,
who is awesome,
and I get Marina, who
is mean all the time.
(CHUCKLES)
Then why do you
hang out with her?
Because when she dies,
it's not going to feel so bad.
Truth is, maybe my
friends abandoned me,
or maybe, I pushed them away.
Because whatever this
thing is that's looming...
Because unlike me,
you were dumb enough
to bang a werewolf chick.
(SCOFFS)
Don't call me Dick Josh again.
(CHUCKLES)
Wow.
(MOTHS FLUTTERING)
Oh, shit, we got company!
I hope you're ready.
(CHOKING)
Josh, go!
A Josh has to live
to tell our story.
Get back! Anything
inside of 20 feet will be ash!
Julia.
The key didn't lie.
Q?
Getting a little
sick of plot twists.
MARINA 23: Focus, we
need to get out of here.
I can travel, but I can't
take anyone with me
'cause these fucking things
don't work without magic.
JULIA: Let me try.
Quentin is The Beast.
Quentin is The Beast?
How the fuck is
Quentin The Beast?
Who's Quentin again?
He's the motherfucker
who convinced my Julia
to run away to
Fillory in the first place
and get murdered.
Yeah, by The Beast.
So, you see why
this is confusing?
Doesn't make any sense.
Alice 23 told us that
The Beast killed Quentin.
She said that he
tore out his Shade,
and destroyed him.
Uh, did he look
destroyed to any of you?
He survived a direct hit
from the Rhinemann Ultra.
I didn't even think
that was possible.
You'd have to
have a lot of power,
like a god.
Oh, we are in such deep shit.
Maybe we should just stay
here in this branch of The Library.
Hey, Penny, where
are all the Librarians?
I don't know.
It's been empty as long
as I've been coming here.
It's the first place I found
where I couldn't hear The Beast.
Now, is that The Beast beast,
or the Q Beast, or is
there another Beast?
I think we're missing some
pages of the story here
somewhere between Quentin
was killed by The Beast
and Quentin is The
Beast, only more powerful.
I know who we should talk to...
The one person who
tried to bring Quentin back.
Do any of you have
any clue where Alice is?
JULIA: Um... (CLEARS THROAT)
Is there an Alice
Quinn on this boat?
Other cabin.
Thanks.
ALICE 23: I was going
to give up on Quentin.
He died and his Shade
went to the Underworld,
and I couldn't reach it
until your Tesla
Flexion came through.
That changed everything.
Seeing him and
hearing that he loved me,
just knowing that
he was out there,
if only I could bring him back.
So, what did you do?
There's a creature
in the Northern Marsh
who can give you just
about anything for a price.
What kind of evil
creature-type deal
are we talking here?
When I die, I won't
go to the Underworld.
Now, I belong to him.
So, Harvey Weinstein-type evil.
So, um, what did he give you?
The power to bring Quentin
back without his Shade.
I was so heartbroken,
I thought that
maybe we could just
fix it together
once he returned.
It was the biggest
mistake of my life.
Without his Shade, he...
He wasn't Quentin.
No.
He wanted Fillory for himself.
So, he killed The Beast.
But that wasn't enough.
So, he found a way to kill
Ember, and steal his powers.
But because he killed a god...
The old gods took magic away.
Quentin still had the
power he stole from Ember.
He told me that Fillory was
the only thing that he truly loved.
It was always his escape.
He was afraid of magic,
of any Magician who
might bring it back.
Anyone who would oppose him,
take Fillory from him...
And the six fingers, moths...
How'd that shit happen?
I don't know.
He did tell me that he finally
understood Martin Chatwin,
that he was the only one
who appreciated
Fillory like he did.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean for
any of this to happen.
I just... I loved Quentin.
And I wanted to see him again.
It's okay.
Hell no, it's not okay.
All of our friends
died because of you,
because of what you did.
Because of what I did.
Quentin and I used
the Tesla Flexion
to talk to her.
And if we hadn't, Alice
never would've tried
to bring her Quentin back,
and none of this
would've happened.
Whoa, whoa, time
travel headache.
Okay, so, what, just because
you gave her the sads,
it's somehow your fault that
she resurrected a crazy monster
who murdered everybody
and got magic turned off?
I mean, yeah, I guess it's
kind of a little bit your fault,
but mostly it's on this blonde,
seven-fingered nutcase.
So, why you on this ship anyway?
What is with all the bunnies?
Are you trying to send a bunch
of messages or something?
No, I work for them.
They're radish smugglers, I...
I stack boxes.
It's the only thing
they can't do.
(SCOFFS)
And this ship is the only
place Quentin can't track me,
so I can try to fix my mistake.
How?
By finding a weapon
to kill Quentin.
Okay, now we're
getting somewhere.
I found this.
Don't ask me how.
Let me guess... You
traveled to the past
and made a deal
with a knife maker?
The only problem is,
I don't have enough
power to touch it.
(GASPS)
I do.
I'll tell Captain
Hopps I'm leaving.
Found some carrot wine.
The other Josh
told me something terrible
was going to happen to him.
Something did...
He fucking died.
Yeah, but...
It's gonna happen to me too.
Whatever the holy hell
was gonna happen to him
that he never goddamn told me
because I never
got past the part,
it's called the Quickening,
'cause that's not ominous.
And they told me sexually-transmitted
lycanthropy was no big deal.
That's what I always heard too.
Turns out, it's murder herpes.
So, yay.
If I find out I may turn into
a monster and kill everyone,
I'd run far away.
'Cause if you're near
Julia when that happens,
I'll kill you myself, Dick Josh.
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
We can't do that.
But it totally works.
We pop in, we throw
Alice to The Beast,
and when he's
munching on her entrails,
Penny pops you behind and
you stab Q-bert in the back.
Marina, I'm not going
to use Alice as bait.
Why not? I mean, you heard her.
This is all her fault,
she wants to fix
what she screwed up.
There are ways to do this
without sacrificing
her life, okay?
Are you getting cold
feet because The Beast
is your former best friend,
the unimpressive white guy?
No, it's not that.
Because people have
already died in this timeline.
Basically, everyone I know...
They're dead because of
short, blonde, and crazy,
and I guess you.
But why would you
give a shit about that?
You just want your stupid key.
I tried to kill a god once
with help from a friend...
You.
I used you as bait to lure him.
And when I couldn't
get back in time,
he killed you.
I screwed up, and you died.
And it was horrible.
Jesus Christ.
I'm so sorry.
I couldn't tell you
before because
it was my fault.
And I can never do
that to someone again.
So, what do you wanna do?
I mean, this shit is dangerous.
We can't just waltz
up on The Beast.
He may act like a beast, but,
deep down, he's the
Quentin I've always known.
So, what are you saying?
You wanna spare him?
I wanna use that against him.
(ALL GASPING)
Wow. He really let the place go.
What is all this shit?
The Winter's Doe...
What's left of her.
Jesus, did he eat her?
These are the polished
rocks from the Silver Banks.
That's where Martin
Chatwin learned to skip rocks.
This is a bugle from Brass City.
Rupert learned to play on this.
You guys, this isn't trash. No.
This is a "Fillory and
Further" fan boy's collection.
It's trash.
Quentin's been hoarding this.
(TRUMPET BLOWING OFF TUNE)
You're not a very good player,
whoever you are.
Hilarious.
(QUENTIN 23 SNIFFS)
Alice?
I can smell you.
Why don't you come on out?
(WHISPERING) He knows I'm here.
JULIA: Hurry, quick, let's go.
I'm trying.
Shit, he must've cast a ward.
I can't travel into
the throne room.
Fine, you don't wanna come out?
Then I will...
Fill the room with fire.
You guys stay, I'll go.
No, Alice, don't.
I have to.
If I don't, he'll
kill all of us.
(ALICE 23 BREATHING HEAVILY)
I'm here, Quentin.
Wait.
I am the only one
who can stop him.
ALICE 23: I made a mistake.
I should never
have run from you.
That's what I said.
You killed every
Magician you could find,
except me.
Why?
I thought about it,
but you were doing
such a good job
of torturing yourself.
And the others, I...
I could say that
they were a threat,
but honestly, I just realized
that I didn't like
them very much.
Doesn't sound like you.
I know you.
You knew me.
You're not Martin Chatwin,
you're not The Beast...
You hate The Beast.
True.
But you show up with
a face full of moths,
and everyone loses their shit.
People think that The Beast
is invincible.
Who wouldn't use
that to their advantage?
I think that he
would be flattered.
I did a Dread Pirate Roberts.
The Princess Bride.
Please, Quentin.
I know the man that I love
is still inside you somewhere.
QUENTIN 23: Yeah, I ate him.
Okay, this is obviously
a ploy to buy your friends time,
so why don't we just
get this over with?
(GRUNTS)
That's a familiar scent.
Julia.
You can't kill me,
you've already tried.
(GRUNTS)
(GASPING)
What did you...
What did you do to me?
It's my Shade.
And I can live
without it if I have to.
(SHUDDERING)
Everything that you
are feeling right now,
I have felt... Grief,
sadness, shame, regret.
Q?
Alice.
(PANTING)
I killed her.
I'm so sorry.
Q?
Where did you find the key?
Um...
I heard it could be used
to bring back magic,
and I couldn't have that,
so I got it first.
I know why you
were looking for me.
The key...
It showed you
visions of the future...
Me killing you.
Julia...
I'm here to tell you I'm not.
I'm not going to kill you.
I wanna help you.
The visions weren't
of you killing me.
I saw you opening a lock
at the End Of The World.
You were trying to let magic in,
but you let in
something much worse.
What?
A monster.
One even worse than me.
You should take your Shade back.
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
MARINA 23: You look dumb.
I'm trying to get this stupid
key to open up a door.
Well, isn't there, like,
some kind of ritual for that?
Or... It would be nice
if there was, but,
no, so key-waving.
Is that my Josh's jacket?
Yeah.
Hmm.
You look cooler.
You are mean.
So, the key show you anything?
Visions of the future?
Nothing.
Okay.
Then I guess you don't
know that I'm coming with you.
What?
Your Penny's dead, or,
not alive in some confusing way.
Penny, I don't...
I'm not asking permission.
Okay.
I'm not her.
I know that.
It's just, there's
nothing here for me.
But there?
Give it time.
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey, uh, Jules?
We have a door.
Um, is it bad that Marina
just ran right through?
I honestly don't know.
(DOOR SLAMS SHUT)