PENNY: Previously
on The Magicians...
Look, just go, while
you still have the chance.
SHEILA: The Library
controls the levels
of ambient magic that
flow through the pipes.
This one has a leak.
Well, what's my
birthright, you scaly shit?
It's the talking animals.
They've all been struck dumb.
So what is this?
I saved your
fucking life, bitch.
Margo, are you okay?
You're just a
brown-nose sweater boy
desperate to matter at all.
The other me, Sam,
did whatever she thought was right,
regardless of what anybody else thought.
This contract initiates our
services in exchange for...
"Unlimited manual
and magical labor"?
"Bound in service to the Library
"up to and after my death"?
Penny, where are you?
I'm in the Underworld Library.
If you stay down here,
you've got an amazing
destiny ahead of you.
DEREK: Uh, excuse
me? Mr. Adiyodi?
Come in. Have a seat.
Is...
Did I do something wrong?
I called you in to talk
about Matilda Fremont.
You shelved her
book yesterday under
"Disappointing Prodigies"?
Oh, right. Uh,
mastered the flute at seven,
but became a mediocre poet.
Unremarkable.
Did you read her brother's book?
She saved his life.
Pulled him out of a
self-destructive spiral,
and he went on to become one of
the world's greatest philanthropists.
I wouldn't call that
"unremarkable."
Okay. So, is there section
for "Sisters of Generous Men"?
You've been in the Underworld
branch, um, three weeks?
Well... (SIGHS) PENNY:
Yeah, when I died,
all I cared about was getting
back up there, and all this?
I didn't think it mattered.
Where a book goes, who reads it.
Those books I lent you, you
get a chance to read them?
DEREK: Of course.
Well, I skimmed.
How far did you get?
Alice, uh, opened a pipe,
accidentally helped blow
up the Modesto branch,
and Quentin played
Pictionary with a mummy.
Where would you file them?
DEREK: Quentin and Alice,
"Star-Crossed Romances,"
probably, or "Well-Meaning Failures."
What about the others?
Oh.
"Side Characters
in Epic Quests."
I'm a side character?
DEREK: Look,
no offense. It's just,
Quentin's the center
of the whole thing.
He's the one that
knows everybody.
He's the one the
little British girl picked
to save the world.
Or he's the one
that looks like you.
Not fair.
Todd looks like me.
He's not the center of shit.
But he could be.
All I'm saying is you think
you've seen stories like this before,
so you can guess
what's going to happen.
Who's important and who isn't.
But that's because you
are trapped in your POV.
You have a classic case of
White Male Protagonism, Derek,
and a Librarian
simply can't have that.
But that's why these
books are so important.
They're such a gift.
They can allow you to
see other points of view.
And once you start seeing that,
you'll find that the story
doesn't end the way you think,
and the most important
characters aren't who you expect.
Remember back before
all the stuff in Modesto
when Alice first
escaped from the Library?
Oh, dear.
I'm telling you, I saw a
reindeer-driven sleigh fly away.
Alice and Nick are
gone. This is not funny.
I'm not laughing now. I mean...
Let's discuss next steps.
Mmm. We should wait for
Everett. He'll know how to...
Oh, he'll agree
with me when I say
that Alice Quinn
was your project.
Holding her here was a
mistake. We aren't jailers.
What would you have done?
Alice broke her deal with us.
She tried to turn off all of magic.
That has to have consequences.
Our mission is to preserve
the knowledge of magic.
Alice Quinn is an existential
threat to that knowledge.
Are you suggesting that
we should have killed her,
and Santa Claus?
(CHUCKLES)
I'm so sorry. It's
not at all funny.
Do you agree with Cyrus?
I see.
I admit, I took a personal
interest in Alice's rehabilitation.
Perhaps it biased me.
You are correct.
We are not jailers.
Nor are we killers.
So, I'll ask again. What
would you have us do?
EVERETT: "Protect the flame
of knowledge no matter the cost."
I believe that's how
the old motto goes.
CYRUS: Everett.
Sorry I was delayed.
The renovation of our Rome
branch ran into some difficulties.
Have you been briefed on Alice?
I agree with Zelda.
We are an order of
scholars, not assassins.
So, what is the
scholarly solution?
Read their books.
Learn their intentions.
We agreed not to breach privacy
unless there was no other option.
What's the other option?
Uh, okay.
Well, Nick's book has been
taken and presumably destroyed,
but Alice's is still in the Revision
Room having the ending put in.
CYRUS: Which will take days,
and if she and Nick
split up, we'll lose them.
ZELDA: There
might be another way.
Tracking devices.
Eventually, they'll go
somewhere for help.
There isn't enough ambient to
keep either of them happy long,
so disperse a
Searcher widely and...
Disperse to whom, though?
I find it unlikely that Alice
or Nick will run into the hands
of card-carrying Magicians.
They'll go underground. Yes.
Where the hedge witches are.
And the hedge
witches don't trust us.
We'll never get
them to accept...
If we do what I'm thinking, they'll
take them without ever knowing.
Fine. Trackers.
And once Alice's book is back,
if we can verify she's
no longer a threat,
there'd be no need for
further corrective action.
Agreed?
All in favor?
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
EVERETT: You seem troubled.
Thank you, but I'm fine.
I understand.
I see something of
Harriet in Alice, too.
I wish you'd given yourself some
real time to grieve your daughter.
Leave of absence,
even. No, I'm...
(TINNITUS RINGING)
(MUFFLED) Alice, what's
wrong? (TINNITUS CONTINUES)
I'm sorry.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
EVERETT: (NORMALLY) Zelda.
(TINNITUS STOPS)
I thought I heard something.
Excuse me, I have a meeting.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
So, you're telling me
the Head Librarian,
a member of the Governing
Council of The Order,
is having a nervous breakdown?
Trust me, just 'cause
she's seeing shit
that no one else sees
doesn't mean it
isn't really there.
Then we got to get a
message to this Everett guy.
He's in charge, right?
Can't. What do you mean?
There's a dragon that connects
the Underworld to the Neitherlands.
We just take a note,
and we shove it up his...
Not how that works.
Look, being down here...
You mean being dead?
It gives you a new perspective.
There's shit we know
is going to happen
that people up there
would give anything to stop.
But we can see
the bigger picture.
It's not our job to stop the
living from doing what they do.
It's our job to
appreciate their full life.
We see, but do not intervene,
for a lot of good reasons.
I can see this is
wigging you out.
Let's start with an easier one.
Well, what's my
birthright, you scaly shit?
Wait.
I read this one last week.
High King of Fillory gets
mad at the alpaca lady,
to bring back the
talking animals' voices.
You read Margo's story.
This one is not about her.
Well, what's my
birthright, you scaly shit?
Oh, hi, there. Do you
have a message, or...
(SCREAMS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(DEREK LAUGHS)
Okay, it was a dream.
Just keep reading.
Well, what's my
birthright, you scaly shit?
RAFE: It's the talking animals.
They've all been struck dumb.
Well, shit.
All right, Fen, I
think I will do a ritual.
Earth specialty, the
Sleep of Solitude.
I pop an Ambien, everyone
leaves me alone till noon.
That'll be perfect.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDE)
Rafe, last night I had
the strangest dream.
There were these
bunnies with their throats...
You know what?
I think I predicted the
talking animals going mute.
DEREK: Okay, I think I'm starting
to get the point of these stories.
All women are just
one emotional crisis away
from a psychotic break.
Jesus, no.
Whoa, you can't say
stuff like that anymore.
What, in the afterlife?
Anywhere.
Do you remember what
Kady was doing at this time?
Didn't she just
kind of peace out
after the Library
Dewey coin heist?
Not exactly.
See, while the others
were busy bleeding a stone
to stop The Monster, Kady
was busy doing something else.
QUENTIN: Iris could
have at least left us
a stone-bleeding
how-to or something.
JULIA: Yeah, I hear
what you're saying, Q.
Hey. Don't mind me.
Oh, I'll go check
those other books.
The books in Marina's library,
'cause, yep, that's got
to be where they are.
(KADY SIGHS)
JULIA: Hey.
Haven't seen you in a while.
There was some
stuff I had to do.
Stuff I should be worried about?
I'm clean.
Good.
Who's this?
Five weeks ago, her dad picked
her up from school and disappeared.
Custody fight with her mom.
Locator spell and a few
bruised knuckles later,
she's home.
"Five weeks ago"
as in when you were
"Detective Sam Cunningham"?
You're solving
her old case files?
All right, look.
You lived as Kim for months.
The moment you got your
memory back, you just...
You dropped it like
it never happened.
I can't.
I can't go back to
being a sidekick.
You're not a sidekick. Come on.
I'm only in this group
at all because of Penny.
That's not true.
You and me...
We're friends, yeah.
And then we weren't,
and now we're what...
I don't know, whatever
you call it when
you have a lot of history that
made you two very different people.
I need my own path, Jules.
I want my life to
feel like it's about me.
No, I get that.
And I am all for
your personal growth.
It's just that we're... You know,
we're kind of under the gun here.
You're under my roof,
hidden from the McAllistairs
and the Library because I
took this place from Marina
when everyone else wanted to
hand her nuclear launch codes.
Look, I'll help, of course,
when I can, in my way.
But for now,
Sam left a few loose
ends I need to tie up.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
You're not my Postmate.
I am the Baba Yaga.
You live on my property
under my protection,
and your rent is due.
Okay, well, this isn't
exactly my place.
Well, you're here now,
and the list is clearly
posted on the premises.
Wait, Marina's weird
grocery list on the fridge?
It is not weird. You are weird.
You reek of nondairy
creamer and despair.
Okay, look, I don't have
whatever it is that you're looking for.
One Webster's Weeping Healer,
one Totem of the Plump Pelican,
and one Bag of Holding.
Pay what is owed
in two days' time
or wish I boiled you alive.
The wench will explain.
What?
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
Holy shit, you have to pay her.
"Her"? You mean you.
Okay, what the
fuck is happening?
I'm Bailey.
Sorry about the Baba Yaga.
She can be a little... (GROANS)
The Baba's the spirit of
a vengeful Slavic witch
I channel when I need to collect
rent or deal with a chatty Uber driver.
So, if you don't want
to be her next meal,
you should give
her what she wants.
Ooh, stressful.
Where am I supposed to find...
Wait a minute.
Is the...
The Totem of the Plump Pelican.
Wait, this thing?
BAILEY: Oh, yeah, that's it.
Oh, Marina must have found it.
I just thought it was
some ugly paperweight.
Shh. Don't insult it. It reacts.
So, two more to go.
(EXHALES) Oh, shit.
She's coming back.
(BAILEY BREATHING DEEPLY)
Pay me what is owed,
or I will boil your marrow
into soup, peasant.
See you Thursday.
(DOOR BELL CHIMES)
I'm looking for a guy
called "Lovelady."
Heard he has office hours here.
What is this?
Some kind of flashlight spell?
(SPEAKS OTHER LANGUAGE)
(CHUCKLES)
Jesus.
Satisfied?
What the hell was that?
I never want to see the
floor of a bar that bright.
Pete?
(SCOFFS) Wait, you're Lovelady?
Oh, shit.
Kady.
It's been a while.
Last time I saw you,
you were with Marina.
Mmm.
We parted ways. It was mutual.
Mmm-hmm. I'm sure.
So, "Lovelady,"
huh? It's a title.
When one guy's done with it,
he passes it on to the next guy,
kind of like Dread Pirate
Roberts or Senator.
That's not how senators work.
Whatever.
The guy who was
Lovelady before me
is an earl with
a private island.
People respect
the shit out of me.
It's a great sign when
you have to tell people that.
Did you come here
looking for my help or...
Sorry.
(EXHALES)
Here's a list.
I heard you can find things.
Interesting stuff.
Specific.
Landlord issue.
Have you considered moving?
The place has special features.
It just turns out it's
courtesy of a witch.
A Baba-something.
You mean the Baba Yaga?
You know her?
Just by reputation.
Hey, if I help you, in
lieu of my usual fee,
I want you to introduce me.
Not sure she's your
type. She's got great taste.
This could open up a
whole new avenue for me.
Yeah, fine, whatever.
You'll help?
One more thing. Um,
do you still see Julia?
Don't be a creep, Pete.
Where are we going?
The Black Market.
DEREK: So, Kady's moved on.
I mean, not with Pete, just...
I know what you mean,
and I'm happy for her.
You don't look happy.
So, is there some
sort of connection
I'm supposed to be
seeing between Kady,
Zelda, Fen?
You'll see.
Alice's book had been revised,
but Alice had
changed the ending.
EVERETT: Well?
Apparently, Alice feels magic
has caused her nothing but trouble.
She goes on to live out an
entirely civilian life in Portland.
She just got a job at a craft
brewery, and a Shih Tzu.
You look a little surprised.
Does that not sound like her?
The choice is unexpected,
but wouldn't be the first time
she walked away from magic.
Great, then.
Nick is still at large, so we'll
keep our trackers in circulation,
but I think we can close
the book on Alice Quinn.
It's funny,
I'd always thought
she was a cat person.
MAN: Never seen
her before. Sorry.
She would be a new hire.
(SIGHS) We're
not hiring right now.
In fact, we've had to
let some people go.
Designer hops are
getting expensive.
Well?
Alice is inside,
as her book said.
Good riddance, book tart.
Let's go get some doughnuts.
This is the Black
Market? It's so... Normal?
Yeah. Exactly.
You'd be surprised
what you can find in here.
Even Deweys.
Wait, I thought you had to
have a Library card for that?
Yeah, well, the Library should know
better than to give unlimited Black Cards
to rich druggie dickbags that
trade them in for lap dances.
Oh, so, you give
lap dances, huh?
Selectively.
Okay, so that is Whitley.
If she does not have a Bag of
Holding, she'll have a line on one.
What, you're not
gonna introduce me?
Well, I may have
had sex with her
and never called her again.
Classy.
Hey, I'm looking
for a Bag of Holding,
whatever that is.
It's a Doctor Who kind of thing.
A bag that's
bigger on the inside.
Actually, it's a D&D thing.
Yeah, I don't do nerd shit.
Expensive taste for someone who
doesn't know what they're asking for.
I can pay.
(CHUCKLES) Charisma Cufflinks
for a Bag of Holding?
Come back when you're serious.
Kraken tentacles,
helps build muscle.
I'm paleo. Cavemen didn't
eat kraken, so I don't eat kraken.
What'll you give me for these?
Aleister Crowley's ashes.
Mmm-hmm. Not bad.
Worth a Bag of Holding?
Thanks.
(PETE LAUGHING)
What the hell, Pete?
I searched the whole
goddamn market for you.
Kady, great news. I found Gordy.
Gordy's my, um...
He's great. Hi, Kaitlin.
Kady.
You were supposed to be looking
for the Webster's
Weeping whatever,
not getting wasted.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
I'll have you know
Gordy is a doctor.
Well... For animals.
You know, for dogs and cats.
Don't sell yourself short,
all right? That's a real doctor.
Not helpful.
Yes, helpful,
because Gordy knows
where to get that thing
that you're looking for.
The thing. The creepy
doll that cries healing tears.
Webster's Weeping Healer.
Got a buddy, Duke,
exotic-bird guy.
So, his cockatoo
caught bumblefoot...
Okay. Shh. Duke has the doll?
Well, yeah.
Okay, where can I find him?
(MIMICS KADY)
Hello? Anybody there?
I'm guessing no one's home.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
Well, that explains it.
No sign of blunt-force
trauma or defensive wounds.
Doesn't look like foul play.
Okay, Mariska Hargitay.
Just find the doll, will you?
No, bad touch!
Get off!
God, I hate this place.
But found the doll.
Ugh.
Healing tears or no, I would
not keep this thing in my house.
KADY: Really, Pete?
PETE: What? He's not using it.
KADY: You're disgusting.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
WOMAN: Oh, my God! Oh, my God.
Jesus, Fen!
Why the hell are you
lurking in a dark pantry?
Waiting for you.
Your soufflé fell. You're
gonna bake a new one.
How did you... Dreamt it.
You're worried Margo is
gonna blow talks with Lady Pike.
DEREK: Wait, again
with the alpaca lady?
Sorry.
Uh, some of these
pages are out of order.
Just keep reading.
But really, you're
worried that you and she
have a true connection and
you're going to screw it up,
so you're stress-baking.
Okay, ouch.
And that's a weirdly
specific and accurate dream.
I also dreamt of dancing ears of corn,
and then the farmers reported a surplus.
I dreamt about
what Tick really does
with all those peaches
he steals from the kitchen,
which is surprisingly not gross.
And they've all come true.
Prophetic dreams could
mean a lot of things.
Uh, maybe you're a psychic
or someone cast some
kind of spell on you.
Or it's Fillory, and maybe you
just ate some messed-up fruit.
You think someone
did this to me?
If you're worried,
next time it happens
just poke around
the dream a little.
Poke with what? A knife?
No. No knives.
Lucid dreaming.
They teach it first
semester at Brakebills.
The second you realize you're dreaming,
you can take control of your dream.
You don't even
need magic to do it.
Just close your
eyes... (INHALES)
Breathe, and try to push your
finger through your other hand.
Everything freezes.
Anything not supposed to be
there, that's when you'll be able to tell.
ZELDA: Alice wasn't where
her book said she'd be.
I suspect she sabotaged it.
And now I've lied
to my colleagues.
If I don't find her
before they find out...
Sounds like a personal problem.
Henry, please.
I'm trusting you.
What you mean is that you
trust that I won't report this
because it'd be worse for Alice.
We both want to spare her that.
If you could just tell
me where she is...
I comply with every request,
all your red tape and
your triplicate bullshit.
This is your mess.
Do not drag me into it.
(TINNITUS RINGING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Harriet?
(INAUDIBLE)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I don't think an ancient Slavic
witch is gonna want a mojito.
Right. Um...
Something vodka-based?
Are you actually nervous?
Baba Yaga's a really big
deal in my line of work, and...
First impressions...
What was I saying?
Pete, your arm.
That molest-y hand
gave me the clap.
Oh, shit.
GORDY: Looks like
a bad spell interaction.
Something's clashing with one
of his personal enchantments.
Which personal enchantment?
I don't know. They're personal.
Hedge spells, you know,
they're off the street at best.
They got a lot of rough edges.
There's really no telling
if they'll play nice together
until, well, they don't.
Whatever killed
Duke is killing him.
So, help him, or
I break your jaw.
Look, the only human diagnostic
spell I know costs magic,
and I'm a little
Dewey-light at the mo.
Please don't break my jaw.
Fine.
Pete has one he took
off your dead friend Duke.
Wait. Wait, you said
something's clashing with Pete.
Mmm.
Like what? Like a cursed object.
I once treated a
horse for strangles.
Turns out jockey's riding
crop interacted badly
with a hoof-protection
spell, so...
Does Pete carry a riding crop?
Okay, maybe just look at this.
(SPITS)
Cobalt. Don't touch that shit.
Not really planning to
now that you licked it.
What? It's more
accurate than lenses.
You can taste cobalt. It's
used in most tracking spells.
Tracking spells? Mmm.
I put them on pets.
This one tastes like a
real expensive Searcher.
You hold it long enough, it kind of
sends out a signal to whoever cast it.
Wait, a signal to who? Aliens.
I was thinking more
like who makes Deweys.
The Library. Oh, yeah.
That makes more sense.
Who's the Library looking for?
Oh, I can think of a few people.
Wait, how many hedges have
these personal enchantments?
Pretty much everybody.
Shit.
Take off all of Pete's, now.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna warn everybody.
Wait a second. So, the Library's
responsible for hedge witches dying?
Yeah, but they
don't know that yet.
Spoiler alert.
Zelda had some other
things on her mind at the time.
Her dead daughter.
Wait, is she, like, down here?
I thought you
didn't like spoilers.
Look, I'm sorry you see dead people,
but that is an incredibly stupid idea.
She's not dead.
Ghosts don't bleed.
I don't know how, but she
could be alive, stuck in there.
That's insane, and impossible.
It's the Mirror Realm.
We don't know what's impossible.
It's not as complicated
as a mirror bridge.
We just need to open a door
to the place between mirrors.
Listen, Zelds, if you
told me you wanted
to finger-paint your blood so you
could take a walk in the crazy dimension,
I would say, "Free country."
But this is my blood.
I can't do this
without your help.
Yes, I know that.
And I'm leaving.
She's my daughter.
Harriet,
who's older than you?
Our relationship is complicated.
Clearly.
You smashed the mirror.
You
trapped her there.
I was doing my job. I can't
live with myself if I don't
find a way to help her.
Please.
Christ.
I'm gonna regret this, aren't I?
Did you juice the beets?
Oh, I juiced the beets.
I told you I would
juice the beets.
Why wouldn't I juice the beets?
Don't make this about us.
DEREK: Wait, did
I miss something?
I thought Margo and Josh were
an unlikely yet heartwarming thing.
No, this is after the
Lady Pike incident.
Margo called Josh a sweater boy.
Forget it.
Pay attention to Fen.
MARGO: How's this shit work?
Pour it gently onto the
lizard, Your Majesty.
(LIZARD SCREECHES)
Jesus lizard-fucking Christ!
Does this feel like a weird
sort of dream to any of you?
All right, maybe
I can control this.
Ember's balls. This is a dream.
Okay, okay. Stop talking
to yourself and look around.
Hey!
Who are you?
Wait, no! Stop, please!
Freeze! Freeze!
Hey, hey, stop!
Freeze! Green lady! Hold up!
Hey, Green lady, come back!
Umber's ass, this
is getting annoying.
Hey, wait!
Wait, I just want to talk!
Why am I having
these stupid dreams?
(GASPS) Oh, no. The lizard.
You pour it gently onto
the lizard, Your Majesty.
Wait, stop! It'll catch fire!
The fuck?
I saw the lizard
blow up when Rafe...
Antidote.
What is she talking about?
Perhaps she's mad with grief over
the loss of King Eliot, Your Majesty.
I assure you, all the animals
have responded quite positively
to the antidote.
Well, this one definitely won't.
Fwoosh! Fried lizard.
And where are you
getting this information?
I... I dreamt it.
Fen has been having
kinda prophetic dreams.
She knew my soufflé was gonna
fall before that ever happened.
It's a stupid
fucking premonition.
You want to risk
the life of your lizard,
or is that a relationship you're
willing to set fire to as well?
Oh, I'll fucking
fry this lizard.
Okay, can we focus
for one minute?
Sure. Yes.
Fine. Let's.
Cool. Great.
MARGO: Okay.
Say I don't dose Newt
Scamander with beet juice.
How the shit am I supposed
to get his wrinkly ass talking?
I don't know, but I have an
idea of where to look for answers.
I lucid-dreamed.
I saw a woman in a green hood.
She has to be the one
giving me premonitions.
Awesome. You got it working.
A-plus. B-minus.
Unless,
you tell us where
this green bitch went.
Well, in my dream, I
chased her to this stream
by the Fuchsia Forest
of Corian's Land.
(GASPS) Corian's Land,
also known as Sloth's Bane.
I don't know what everything
in my dreams means... Mean.
Anyway,
I know that the answers
to our questions...
Answers lie... Lay
there? (CHUCKLES)
I'm not usually the one who
gives the big speech, so I'm going.
So, that's happening.
KADY: Gordy says,
"You're welcome."
And he left you a bill.
That guy puts a really
high value on his time.
Wait, did I miss the Baba Yaga?
Well, you snooze, you lose.
I wasn't snoozing, I was dying.
We got bigger fish to fry.
I'll explain everything
as soon as your hedge
witch friends get here.
I know every instinct is telling
you not to trust me, or anyone.
But someone put
a tracker on this.
It's a complex, expensive,
very high-level spell.
It marked him.
It looks like the Deweys you
touched are doing the same to you.
If you have any
enchantments running,
anything you got
in a safe house,
anything home-brewed,
it could kill you,
just like it did to Duke,
and almost did to Pete.
She saved my life.
I trust her, and
I vouch for her.
Who did this? The Library.
They make the Deweys,
and they don't give a shit
about what happens
to the hedges.
They're trying to find someone,
and we're just
collateral damage.
So, ask yourselves,
if this is what they do when
they're not even thinking about us,
what happens when
they decide we're a threat?
Are we just gonna let people like
them tell us we're not important?
That we're just some side characters
in their fucked-up fascist plot?
My mom was a hedge,
and she was killed
by another hedge.
You'd think that would
turn me against you.
But it didn't.
It just made me realize that
it doesn't have to be this way.
If we could stop
screwing each other over
long enough to work together,
then it's not the
Library's story.
It's our story.
Hey. Hey.
I have a buddy in Modesto.
He says there's a
leaky Library pipe there.
I say we use it to make
those assholes pay.
Look, I know what
you're going through...
Do you? They
kill your boyfriend?
Actually, yeah.
Look, we'll figure
out what to do next.
I already know what to do.
You do that, you're giving
them a reason to wipe us out.
Please just get a little
sleep. We'll talk tomorrow.
Hey, you're not alone.
We'll figure this out together
in a way that feels right for you.
Okay.
Yeah, we can do that.
ZELDA: It's a copy of
our library, but wrong.
I was gonna say
a total mindfuck.
Tomato, tomahto.
(KNOCKING) (ZELDA GASPS)
Oh, you go on.
I'll just be here cutting myself
to keep our bloody exit open.
Hey, just made a joke.
(WIND HOWLING)
Hello?
(CREAKING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(ZELDA GASPS)
Where have you been?
Your funhouse-mirror
daughter shanked me.
We have to go. Those
things weren't her.
The real Harriet could still be
in here. I can't just leave her.
I hate to break it to you, love,
she might still be in there,
but so are those monsters.
(HENRY GRUNTS)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
An attack?
On what branch?
Modesto, California.
We lost four Librarians.
Hedge witches did it.
But why?
(CLEARS THROAT)
There was some fallout
from your tracker coins.
It's not your fault.
Just unforeseen interaction.
Several hedges died.
The whole point of doing this
was to avoid having to hurt anyone.
I should have been here.
You can't blame yourself.
If anything, today we learned
the true danger we're in,
and that your trackers
might provide a solution.
What do you mean?
Complications aside,
the idea is sound.
Put whatever we have
into circulation among them.
We keep Modesto
from happening again.
Are you suggesting
we kill hedge witches?
I am suggesting that
we keep an eye on them.
"To protect the flame of
knowledge from being extinguished,
"no matter the cost."
I don't know what to say.
This is an awesome
responsibility.
You and I both know that,
but who is better suited
to bear that responsibility
than The Order?
(EXHALES)
There is no one I trust more
deeply to be fair and right than you.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR) (DOOR OPENS)
Alice.
I can't stay long.
I cast a spell to keep the Library
from eavesdropping, but it won't last.
I need your help.
They have my friend Sheila.
I know.
Hello, Ms. Quinn.
DEAN: Alice, please.
Nothing will happen to you here.
Zelda wants to talk.
Why?
I need your help.
I think I've seen enough.
To counteract a lifetime
of cis-het frat-bro bias?
I doubt it. Okay.
So, tell me, what was I
supposed to take from that?
Zelda doesn't know it yet,
but what she just set in motion
is going to change
the Library forever.
Same with Fen and Fillory,
Kady, and all of magic.
When you file people
away as sidekicks,
you don't realize their
importance to the story,
and this story belongs to a
lot more people than you think.
Where to shelve a
book, it's not a little thing.
You're telling the world
what to value, who to value.
You get our responsibility here?
It's well said.
I think you've earned
the right to move up.
Excuse me?
I know so much about you and your
friends, but you never asked me how I died.
Okay. Um,
how did you die?
Arrow to the chest
during the Crusades.
The Crusades? A
thousand years ago?
We really thought the story was all
about white guys back then, believe me.
And I'm not new at all.
I'm actually your
supervisor's supervisor.
So, you're my boss.
I fully see the irony of a
white guy giving you this test,
but ladies upstairs love a
twist, so they always send me.
Send you to what?
To promote you.
You're clearly ready
for the next level.
Which is?
Secrets Taken to the Grave.
You're gonna collect them.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
And I'm afraid we're gonna
need you to start right away.
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
Hey.
Been a while.
Welcome to the Underworld.