Previously, on "The Magicians"...
Look, just go while you still
have the chance.
The Library controls
the levels of ambient magic
that flow through the pipes.
This one has a leak.
Well, what's my Birthright,
you scaly shit?
It's the talking animals.
They've all been struck dumb.
- So what is this?
- I saved your fucking life, bitch.
Margo, are you okay?
You're just a brown-nose sweater boy
desperate to matter at all.
The other me, Sam,
did whatever she thought was right,
regardless of what anybody else thought.
This contract initiates
our services in exchange for...
"Unlimited manual and magical labor"?
"Bound in service to the Library
up to and after my death"?
- Penny, where are you?
- I'm in the Underworld Library.
If you stay down here,
you've got an amazing destiny
ahead of you.
Uh, excuse me?
Mr. Adiyodi?
Come in. Have a seat.
Is...
Did I do something wrong?
I called you in to talk
about Matilda Fremont.
You shelved her book yesterday
under "Disappointing Prodigies"?
Oh, right.
Uh, mastered the flute at seven
but became a mediocre poet.
Unremarkable.
Did you read her brother's book?
She saved his life...
pulled him out
of a self-destructive spiral,
and he went on to become
one of the world's
greatest philanthropists.
I wouldn't call that "unremarkable."
Uh, okay. So is there section for,
uh, "Sisters of Generous Men"?
You've been in the Underworld branch,
- um, three weeks?
- Well...
Yeah, when I died, all I cared about
was getting back up there,
and... and all this?
I didn't think it mattered...
where a book goes, who reads it.
Those books I lent you,
you get a chance to read them?
Of course.
Well, I skimmed.
How far did you get?
Alice, uh, opened a pipe,
accidentally helped blow up
the Modesto branch,
and Quentin played Pictionary
with a mummy.
Where would you file them?
Quentin and Alice...
"Star-Crossed Romances," probably,
or "Well-Meaning Failures."
- What about the others?
- Oh...
"Side Characters in Epic Quests."
I'm a side character?
Look, no offense.
It's just... Quentin's the center
of the whole thing.
He's the one that knows everybody.
He's the one the little
British girl picked
to save the world.
Or he's the one that looks like you.
Not fair.
Todd looks like me.
He's not the center of shit.
But he could be.
All I'm saying is you think you've
seen stories like this before,
so you can guess
what's going to happen...
who's important and who isn't.
But that's because you are
trapped in your POV.
You have a classic case of
White Male Protagonism, Derek,
and a Librarian simply can't have that.
But that's why these books
are so important.
They're such a gift.
They... they can allow you
to see other points of view.
And once you start seeing that,
you'll find that the story
doesn't end the way you think,
and the most important characters
aren't who you expect.
Remember back before
all the stuff in Modesto
when Alice first escaped
from the Library?
Oh, dear.
I'm telling you, I saw
a reindeer-driven sleigh fly away.
Alice and Nick are gone.
This is not funny.
I'm not laughing... now.
- I mean...
- Lets discuss next steps.
Mm, we should wait for Everett.
He'll know how to...
Oh, he'll agree with me when I say
that Alice Quinn was your project.
Holding her here was a mistake.
We aren't jailers.
What would you have done?
Alice broke her deal with us.
She tried to turn off all of magic.
That has to have consequences.
Our mission is to preserve
the knowledge of magic.
Alice Quinn is an existential
threat to that knowledge.
Are you suggesting that
we should have killed her...
And Santa Claus?
I'm so sorry. It's not at all funny.
Do you agree with Cyrus?
I see.
I admit, I took a personal interest
in Alice's rehabilitation.
Perhaps it biased me.
You are correct.
We are not jailers.
Nor are we killers.
So I'll ask again...
what would you have us do?
"Protect the flame of knowledge
no matter the cost."
I believe that's how the old motto goes.
Everett.
Sorry I was delayed.
The renovation of our Rome branch
ran into some difficulties.
Have you been briefed on Alice?
I agree with Zelda.
We are an order of scholars,
not assassins.
So what is the scholarly solution?
Read their books.
Learn their intentions.
We agreed not to breach privacy
unless there was no other option.
What's the other option?
Uh, okay.
Well, Nick's book has been taken
and presumably destroyed,
but Alice's is still in the Revision
Room having the ending put in.
Which will take days,
and if she and Nick split up,
we'll lose them.
There might be another way.
Tracking devices.
Eventually, they'll go
somewhere for help.
There isn't enough ambient
to keep either of them happy long,
so disperse a Searcher widely and...
Disperse to whom, though?
I find it unlikely that Alice or Nick
will run into the hands
of card-carrying Magicians.
- They'll go underground.
- Yes.
Where the hedge witches are.
And the hedge witches don't trust us.
- We'll never get them to accept...
- If we do what I'm thinking,
they'll take them without ever knowing.
Fine. Trackers.
And once Alice's book is back,
if we can verify
she's no longer a threat,
there'd be no need
for further corrective action.
Agreed?
All in favor?
You seem troubled.
Thank you, but I'm fine.
I understand.
I see something of Harriet
in Alice, too.
I wish you'd given yourself some
real time to grieve your daughter.
- Leave of absence, even.
- No, I'm...
Uh, I'm sorry.
Zelda.
I thought I heard something.
Excuse me, I have a meeting.
- Synced and corrected by Shazi89 -
- www.addic7ed.com -
So you're telling me the Head Librarian,
a member of the
Governing Council of the Order,
is having a nervous breakdown?
Trust me, just 'cause she's
seeing shit that no one else sees
doesn't mean it isn't really there.
Uh, then we got to get
a message to this Everett guy.
He's in charge, right?
Can't.
What do you mean? There's
a dragon that connects
the Underworld to the Neitherlands.
We just take a note, and
we shove it up his...
Not how that works.
- Look, being down here...
- You mean being dead?
It gives you a new perspective.
There's shit we know is going to happen
that people up there would
give anything to stop.
But we can see the bigger picture.
It's not our job to stop the
living from doing what they do.
It's our job to appreciate
their full life.
We see but do not intervene...
for a lot of good reasons.
I can see this is wigging you out.
Let's start with an easier one.
Well, what's my Birthright,
you scaly shit?
Wait...
I read this one last week.
High King of Fillory gets mad
at, uh, the alpaca lady,
uh, to bring back
the talking animals' voices.
You read Margo's story.
This one is not about her.
Well, what's my Birthright,
you scaly shit?
Oh, hi, there.
Do you have a message, or...?
Okay, it was a dream.
Just keep reading.
Well, what's my Birthright,
you scaly shit?
It's the talking animals.
They've all been struck dumb.
Well, shit.
All right, Fen, I think
I will do a ritual.
Earth specialty...
the Sleep of Solitude.
I pop an Ambien, everyone
leaves me alone till noon.
That'll be perfect.
Rafe, last night I had
the strangest dream.
There were these bunnies
with their throats...
You know what?
I think I projected
the talking animals going mute.
Okay, I think I'm starting to
get the point of these stories.
All women are just one emotional
crisis away from a psychotic break.
Jesus, no.
Whoa, you can't say stuff
like that anymore.
What, in the afterlife?
Anywhere.
Do you remember what Kady
was doing at this time?
Didn't she just kind of peace out
after the Library Dewey coin heist?
Not exactly.
See, while the others
were busy bleeding a stone
to stop the monster, Kady...
was busy doing something else.
Iris could have at least left us
a stone-bleeding how-to or something.
Yeah, I hear what you're saying, Q.
- Hey.
- Don't mind me.
Uh, I'll go check those other books.
The books in, uh, Marina's library,
'cause, uh, yep, that's got
to be where they are.
Hey.
Haven't seen you in a while.
There was some stuff I had to do.
Stuff I should be worried about?
I'm clean.
Good.
Who's this?
Five weeks ago, her dad picked her
up from school and disappeared...
custody fight with her mom.
Locator spell and a few
bruised knuckles later,
she's home.
"Five weeks ago" as in when you
were "Detective Sam Cunningham"?
You're solving her old case files?
All right, look...
you lived as Kim for months.
The moment you got
your memory back, you just...
you dropped it like it never happened.
I-I can't.
I can't go back to being a sidekick.
- You're not a sidekick.
- Come on.
I'm only in this group at all
because of Penny.
That's not true.
- You and me...
- We're friends, yeah.
And then we weren't,
and now we're what...
I don't know,
whatever you call it when...
you have a lot of history
that made you two very different people.
I need my own path, Jules.
I want my life to feel
like it's about me.
No, I get that.
And I am all for your personal growth.
It's just that we're...
you know, we're kind of
under the gun here.
You're under my roof,
hidden from the McAllistairs
and the Library because I took
this place from Marina
when everyone else wanted
to hand her nuclear launch codes.
Look, I'll help, of course...
when I can, in my way.
But for now...
Sam left a few loose ends
I need to tie up.
You're not my Postmate.
I am the Baba Yaga.
You live on my property
under my protection,
and your rent is due.
Okay, well, this isn't exactly my place.
Well, you're here now,
and the list is clearly posted
on the premises.
Wait, Marina's weird
grocery list on the fridge?
It is not weird.
You are weird.
You reek of nondairy creamer
and despair.
Okay, look, I don't have
whatever it is that you're looking for.
One Webster's Weeping Healer,
one Totem of the Plump Pelican,
and one Bag of Holding.
Pay what is owed in two days' time
or wish I boiled you alive.
The wench will explain.
What?
Holy shit, you have to pay her.
"Her"? You mean you.
Okay, what the fuck is happening?
I'm Bailey.
Sorry about the Baba Yaga. She
can be a little...
The Baba's the spirit
of a vengeful Slavic witch
I channel when I need to collect rent
or deal with a chatty Uber driver.
So if you don't want to be
her next meal,
you should give her what she wants.
Ooh, stressful.
Where am I supposed to find...
Wait a minute.
Is the...
The Totem of the Plump Pelican.
Wait, this thing?
Oh, yeah, that's it.
Oh. Marina must have found it.
I just thought it was some
ugly paperweight.
Shh, don't insult it.
It reacts.
So two more to go.
Oh, shit.
She's coming back.
Pay me what is owed,
or I will boil your marrow
into soup, peasant.
See you Thursday.
I'm looking for a guy called "Lovelady."
Heard he has office hours here.
What is this?
- Some kind of flashlight spell?
- Isik.
- Jesus.
- Whoa!
Satisfied?
What the hell was that? I never want
to see the floor of a bar that bright.
Pete?
Wait, you're Lovelady?
Oh, shit.
Kady.
It's been a while.
Last time I saw you,
you were with Marina.
We parted ways. It was mutual.
Mm, I'm sure.
- So "Lovelady," huh?
- It's a title.
When one guy's done with it, he
passes it on to the next guy,
kind of like "Dread Pirate
Roberts" or "Senator."
That's not how Senators work.
Whatever.
The guy who was "Lovelady before me"
is an Earl with a private island.
People respect the shit out of me.
It's a great sign when
you have to tell people that.
Did you come here looking
for my help or...?
Sorry.
Here's a list.
I heard you can find things.
Interesting stuff.
Specific.
Landlord issue.
Have you considered moving?
The place has special features.
It just turns out it's courtesy
of a-a witch...
uh, Baba-something.
You mean the Baba Yaga?
- You know her?
- Just by reputation.
Hey, if I help you,
in lieu of my usual fee,
I want you to introduce me.
- Not sure she's your type.
- She's got great taste.
This could open up
a whole new avenue for me.
Yeah, fine, whatever. You'll help?
One more thing.
Um, do you still see Julia?
Don't be a creep, Pete.
Where are we going?
Black Market.
So Kady's moved on.
I mean, not with Pete, just...
I know what you mean,
and I'm happy for her.
You don't look happy.
So is there some sort of connection
I'm supposed to be seeing between Kady,
Zelda, Fen...
You'll see.
Alice's book had been revised, but
Alice had changed the ending.
- Well?
- Apparently, Alice feels
magic has caused her
nothing but trouble.
She goes on to live out an entirely
civilian life in Portland.
She just got a job at a craft brewery,
and a Shih Tzu.
You look a little surprised.
Does that not sound like her?
The choice is unexpected, but...
wouldn't be the first time
she walked away from magic.
Great, then.
Nick is still at large, so we'll
keep our trackers in circulation,
but I think we can close
the book on Alice Quinn.
It's funny...
I'd always thought she was a cat person.
Never seen her before. Sorry.
She would be a new hire.
We're not hiring right now.
In fact, we've had to
let some people go.
Designer hops are getting expensive.
Well?
Alice is inside, as her book said.
Hmm. Good riddance, book tart.
Let's go get some doughnuts.
This is the Black Market?
- It's so...
- Normal?
- Yeah.
- Exactly.
You'd be surprised
what you can find in here.
Even Deweys.
Wait, I thought you had to
have a Library card for that?
Yeah, well, the Library
should know better
than to give unlimited black cards
to rich druggie dickbags that
trade them in for lap dances.
Oh, so you give lap dances, huh?
Selectively.
Okay, so that is Whitley.
If she does not have a Bag of
Holding, she'll have a line on one.
What, you're not gonna introduce me?
Well, I may have had sex with her
and never called her again.
Classy.
Hey, I'm looking for a Bag of Holding...
whatever that is.
It's a "Doctor Who" kind of thing.
A bag that's bigger on the inside.
Actually, it's a D&D thing.
Yeah, I don't do nerd shit.
Expensive taste for someone who
doesn't know what they're asking for.
I can pay.
Charisma Cufflinks...
for a Bag of Holding?
Come back when you're serious.
Kraken tentacles... helps build muscle.
I'm paleo.
Cavemen didn't eat kraken,
so I don't eat kraken.
What'll you give me for these?
Aleister Crowley's ashes.
Not bad.
Worth a Bag of Holding?
Thanks.
What the hell, Pete? I searched
the whole goddamn market for you.
Kady, great news.
I found Gordy. Gordy's my, um...
- He's great.
- Hi, Kaitlin.
Kady.
You were supposed to be looking for
the Webster's Weeping Whatever,
not getting wasted.
¿Por qué no los dos, mamacita?
I'll have you know Gordy is a doctor.
- Well...
- For animals.
You know, for dogs and cats.
Don't sell yourself short, all right?
- That's a real doctor.
- Ok... shh, shh, shh. Not helpful.
Yes, helpful, because Gordy knows
where to get that thing
that you're looking for.
The thing. The creepy doll
that cries healing tears.
Webster's Weeping Healer.
Got a buddy, Duke... exotic-bird guy.
So his cockatoo caught bumblefoot...
Okay, shh.
Duke has the doll?
Well, yeah.
Okay, where can I find him?
Hello? Anybody there?
I'm guessing no one's home.
Well, that explains it.
No sign of blunt-force trauma
or defensive wounds.
Doesn't look like foul play.
Okay, Mariska Hargitay.
Just find the doll, will you?
No, bad touch!
Get off!
God, I hate this place.
But...
found the doll.
Healing tears or no,
I would not keep this thing in my house.
Really, Pete?
What? He's not using it.
You're disgusting.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God.
Jesus, Fen!
Why the hell are you lurking
in a dark pantry?
Waiting for you.
Your soufflé fell.
You're gonna bake a new one.
- How did you...
- Dreamt it.
You're worried Margo is gonna
blow talks with Lady Pike.
Wait, again with the alpaca lady?
Sorry.
Uh, some of these pages
are out of order.
Just keep reading.
But really, you're worried
that you and she have
a true connection and you're
going to screw it up,
- so you're stress-baking.
- Okay, ouch.
And that's a weirdly specific
and accurate dream.
I also dreamt of dancing ears of corn,
and then the farmers reported a surplus.
I dreamt about what Tick really does
with all those peaches
he steals from the kitchen,
which is surprisingly not gross.
And they've all come true.
Prophetic dreams could mean
a lot of things.
Uh, maybe you're a psychic
or someone cast some kind
of spell on you.
Or... or it's Fillory, and maybe
you just ate some messed-up fruit.
You think someone did this to me?
If you're worried, next time it happens
just poke around the dream a little.
Poke with what? A knife?
No. No knives. Lucid dreaming.
They teach it first semester
at Brakebills.
The second you realize you're dreaming,
you can take control of your dream.
You don't even need magic to do it.
Just close your eyes...
Breathe, and try to push your finger
through your other hand.
Everything freezes.
Anything not supposed to be there,
that's when you'll be able to tell.
Alice wasn't where
her book said she'd be.
I suspect she sabotaged it.
And now I've lied to my colleagues.
If I don't find her
before they find out...
Sounds like a personal problem.
Henry, please.
I'm trusting you.
What you mean is that you trust
that I won't report this
- because it'd be worse for Alice.
- We both want to spare her that.
If you could just tell me
where she is...
I comply with every request...
all your red tape
and your triplicate bullshit.
This is your mess.
Do not drag me into it.
Harriet?
_
I don't think an ancient Slavic
witch is gonna want a mojito.
Right, um...
something vodka-based?
Are you actually nervous?
Baba Yaga's a really big deal
in my line of work, and...
First impressions...
- What was I saying?
- Pete, your arm.
that molest-y hand gave me the clap.
Oh, shit.
Looks like a bad spell interaction.
Something's clashing with one
of his personal enchantments.
Which personal enchantment?
I don't know. They're personal.
Hedge spells, you know,
they're off the street at best.
They got a lot of rough edges.
There's really no telling
if they'll play nice together
until, well, they don't.
Whatever killed Duke is killing him.
So help him, or I break your jaw.
Look, the only human
diagnostic spell I know
costs magic, and I'm a little
Dewey-light at the mo...
Please don't break my jaw.
Fine.
Pete has one he took off
your friend Duke.
Wait. Wait, you said
something's clashing with Pete.
- Like what?
- Like a cursed object.
I once treated a horse for strangles.
Turns out jockey's riding crop
interacted badly
with a hoof-protection spell, so...
Does Pete carry a riding crop?
Okay, maybe just look at this.
Cobalt.
Don't touch that shit.
Not really planning to
now that you licked it.
What? It's more accurate than lenses.
You can taste cobalt.
It's used in most tracking spells.
- "Tracking spells"?
- Mm-hmm.
I put them on pets. This one tastes
like a real expensive Searcher.
You hold it long enough,
it kind of sends out
a signal to whoever cast it.
Wait, a-a signal to wh... who?
Aliens.
I was thinking more
like who makes Deweys.
- The Library.
- Oh, yeah.
That makes more sense.
Who's the Library looking for?
Oh, I can think of a few people.
Wait, how many hedges have
these personal enchantments?
Pretty much everybody.
Shit.
- Take off all of Pete's, now.
- What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna warn everybody.
Wait a second. So the Library's
responsible for hedge witches dying?
Yeah, but they don't know that yet.
Spoiler alert.
Zelda had some other things
on her mind at the time.
Her dead daughter.
Wait, is she, like, down here?
I thought you didn't like spoilers.
Look, I'm sorry you see dead people,
but that is an incredibly stupid idea.
She's not dead. Ghosts don't bleed.
I don't know how, but she could
be alive stuck in there.
That's insane... and impossible.
It's the Mirror Realm.
We don't know what's impossible.
It's not as complicated
as a mirror bridge.
We just need to open a door
to the place between mirrors.
Listen, Zelds, if you told me you wanted
to finger-paint your blood
so you could take a walk
in the crazy dimension
I would say, "Free country."
But this is my blood.
I can't do this...
without your help.
Yes, I know that.
- And I'm leaving.
- She's my daughter.
Harriet...
who's older than you?
Our relationship is complicated.
Clearly.
You smashed the mirror.
You...
trapped her there.
I was doing my job.
I can't...
Live with myself if I don't
find a way to help her.
Please.
Christ.
I'm gonna regret this, aren't I?
- Did you juice the beets?
- Oh, I juiced the beets.
I told you I would juice the beets.
- Why wouldn't I juice the beets?
- Don't make this about us.
Wait, did I miss something?
I thought Margo and Josh were an
unlikely yet heartwarming thing.
No, this is after
the Lady Pike incident.
Margo called Josh a sweater boy.
Forget it.
Pay attention to Fen.
How's this shit work?
Pour it gently
onto the lizard, Your Majesty.
Jesus lizard-fucking Christ!
Does this feel like a weird
sort of dream to any of you?
All right, maybe I can control this.
Ember's balls. This is a dream.
Okay, okay. Stop talking to
yourself and, uh, look around.
Hey!
Who are you?
Wait, no! Stop, please!
Freeze! Freeze!
Hey, hey, stop!
Freeze! Green Lady!
Hold up!
Hey, Green Lady, come back!
Umber's ass, this is getting annoying.
Hey, wait!
Wait, I just want to talk!
Why am I having these stupid dreams?
Oh, no.
The lizard.
You pour it gently
onto the lizard, Your Majesty.
Wait, stop! It'll catch fire!
The fuck?
I saw the lizard blow up
when Rafe...
Antidote.
What is she talking about?
Perhaps she's mad with grief
over the loss of King Eliot,
Your Majesty.
I assure you, all the animals
have responded quite positively
to the antidote.
Well, this one definitely won't.
Foosh. Fried Lizard.
And where are you getting
this information?
I...
I dreamt it.
Fen has been having
kind of prophetic dreams.
She knew my soufflé was gonna
fall before that ever happened.
It's a stupid fucking premonition.
You want to risk the life of your
lizard, or is that a relationship
- you're willing to set fire to as well?
- Oh, I'll fucking fry this lizard.
Okay, can we... can we focus
for one minute?
- Sure.
- Yes.
- Fine.
- Let's.
- Cool.
- Great.
Okay.
Say I don't dose
Newt Scamander with beet juice.
How the shit am I supposed
to get his wrinkly ass talking?
I don't know, but I have an idea
of where to look for answers.
I lucid-dreamed.
I saw a woman in a green hood.
She has to be the one
giving me premonitions.
Awesome. You got it working.
- A-plus.
- B-minus.
Unless...
you tell us where this green bitch went.
Well, in my dream,
I chased her to this stream
by the Fuschia Forest of Corian's Land.
Corian's Land...
also known as Sloth's Bane.
I don't know what everything
in my dreams means... mean.
Anyway, I know that the answers
to our questions...
answers lie... lay there?
I-I'm not usually the one
who gives the big speech,
so I'm... I'm going.
So that... that's happening.
Gordy says "you're welcome."
And he left you a bill.
That guy puts a really
high value on his time.
Wait, did I miss the Baba Yaga?
Well, you snooze, you lose.
I wasn't snoozing, I was dying.
We got bigger fish to fry.
I'll explain everything
as soon as your hedge witch
friends get here.
I know every instinct is telling you
not to trust me... or anyone.
But someone put a tracker on this.
It's a complex, expensive,
very high-level spell.
It marked him.
It looks like the Deweys you touched
are doing the same to you.
If you have any enchantments running...
anything you got in a safe house,
anything homebrewed...
it could kill you...
just like it did to Duke
and almost did to Pete.
She saved my life.
I trust her, and I vouch for her.
- Who did this?
- The Library.
They make the Deweys,
and they don't give a shit
about what happens to the hedges.
They're trying to find someone,
and we're just collateral damage.
So ask yourselves...
if this is what they do
when they're not even thinking about us,
what happens when they decide
we're a threat?
Are we just gonna let people like them
tell us we're not important?
That we're just some side characters
in their fucked-up fascist plot?
My mom was a hedge...
and she was killed by another hedge.
You'd think that would
turn me against you.
But it didn't.
It just made me realize that
it doesn't have to be this way.
If we could stop
screwing each other over
long enough to work together,
then it's not the Library's story.
It's our story.
Hey.
I have a buddy in Modesto.
He says there's a leaky
Library pipe there.
I say we use it
to make those assholes pay.
Look, I know
what you're going through...
Do you? They kill your boyfriend?
Actually, yeah.
Look, we'll figure out what to do next.
I already know what to do.
You do that, you're giving
them a reason to wipe us out.
Please just get a little sleep.
We'll talk tomorrow.
Hey, you're not alone, okay?
We'll figure this out together in
a way that feels right for you.
Okay.
Yeah, we can do that.
It's a copy of our library, but wrong.
I was gonna say a total mindfuck.
Tomato, tomah-to.
Oh, you go on.
I'll just be here cutting myself
to keep our bloody exit open.
Hey, just made a joke.
Hello?
Where have you been?
Your funhouse-mirror daughter
shanked me. We have to go.
Those things weren't her. The real
Harriet could still be in here.
- I can't just leave her.
- I hate to break it to you, love...
she might still be in there,
but so are those monsters.
An attack?
On what branch?
Modesto, California.
We lost four Librarians.
Hedge witches did it.
But... but why?
There was some fallout
from your tracker coins.
It's not your fault.
Just unforeseen interaction.
Several hedges died.
The whole point of doing this was
to avoid having to hurt anyone.
I should have been here.
You can't blame yourself.
If anything, today we learned
the true danger we're in
and that your trackers
might provide a solution.
What do you mean?
Complications aside...
the idea is sound.
Put whatever we have
into circulation among them.
We keep Modesto from happening again.
Are you suggesting
we kill hedge witches?
I am suggesting
that we keep an eye on them.
To "protect the flame of knowledge"
from ever being extinguished,
no matter the cost."
I don't know what to say.
This is an awesome responsibility.
You and I both know that,
but who is better suited
to bear that responsibility
than The Order?
There is no one I trust more deeply
to be fair and right than you.
Alice.
I can't stay long. I-I cast a spell to
keep the Library from eavesdropping,
but it won't last.
I need your help.
They have my friend Sheila.
I know.
Hello, Ms. Quinn.
Alice, please.
Nothing will happen to you here.
Zelda wants to talk.
Why?
I need your help.
I think I've seen enough.
To counteract a lifetime
of cis-het frat-bro bias?
- I-I doubt it.
- Okay.
So tell me, what was I supposed
to take from that?
Zelda doesn't know it yet,
but what she just set in motion
is going to change the Library forever.
Same with Fen and Fillory,
Kady and all of magic.
When you file people away as sidekicks,
you don't realize
their importance to the story,
and this story belongs
to a lot more people than you think.
Where to shelve a book,
it's not a little thing.
You're telling the world what to value,
who to value.
You get our responsibility here?
Well said.
I think you've earned
the right to move up.
Excuse me?
I know so much about you
and your friends,
but you never asked me how I died.
O-okay, um...
- How did you die?
- Arrow to the chest...
during the Crusades.
"The Crusades"?
1,000 years ago?
We really thought the story
was all about white guys
back then, believe me.
And I'm not new at all.
I'm actually
your supervisor's supervisor.
So you're my boss.
I fully see the irony of a white
guy giving you this test,
but ladies upstairs love a
twist, so they always send me.
Send you to what?
To promote you.
You're clearly ready for the next level.
Which is?
Secrets Taken to the Grave.
You're gonna collect them.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Oh, and, um, I'm afraid we're gonna
need you to start right away.
- Synced and corrected by Shazi89 -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Hey.
Been a while.
Welcome to the Underworld.