Previously, on
"The Magicians"...
Look, just go while you still
have the chance.
The Library controls
the levels of ambient magic
that flow through the pipes.
This one has a leak.
Well, what's my Birthright,
you scaly shit?
It's the talking animals.
They've all been struck dumb.
So what is this?
I saved your
fucking life, bitch.
(smooches)
Margo, are you okay?
You're just a brown-nose sweater
boy desperate to matter at all.
The other me, Sam,
did whatever she thought was right,
regardless of what anybody else thought.
This contract initiates
our services in exchange for...
"Unlimited manual and magical labor"?
"Bound in service to the Library
up to and after my death"?
- Penny, where are you?
- I'm in the Underworld Library.
If you stay down here, you've got
an amazing destiny ahead of you.
(suspenseful music)
♪ ♪
(melancholy music box tune)
Uh, excuse me?
- Mr. Adiyodi?
- Come in. Have a seat.
Is...
Did I do something wrong?
I called you in to talk
about Matilda Fremont.
You shelved her book yesterday
under "Disappointing Prodigies"?
Oh, right.
Uh, mastered the flute at seven
but became a mediocre poet.
Unremarkable.
Did you read her brother's book?
She saved his life...
Pulled him out of a self-destructive
spiral, and he went on to become
one of the world's
greatest philanthropists.
I wouldn't call that
"unremarkable."
Uh, okay. So is there section for,
uh, "Sisters of Generous Men"?
You've been
in the Underworld branch,
um, three weeks?
Well...
Yeah, when I died,
all I cared about
was getting back up there,
and... and all this?
I didn't think it mattered...
Where a book goes, who reads it.
Those books I lent you,
you get a chance to read them?
Of course.
Well, I skimmed.
How far did you get?
Alice, uh, opened a pipe,
accidentally helped blow up
the Modesto branch,
and Quentin played Pictionary
with a mummy.
Where would you file them?
Quentin and Alice...
"Star-Crossed Romances,"
probably,
or "Well-Meaning Failures."
- What about the others?
- Oh...
"Side Characters in Epic Quests."
I'm a side character?
Look, no offense.
It's just... Quentin's the
center of the whole thing.
He's the one
that knows everybody.
He's the one the little British
girl picked to save the world.
Or he's the one
that looks like you.
Not fair. Todd looks like me.
He's not the center of shit.
But he could be.
All I'm saying is you think
you've seen stories
like this before,
so you can guess
what's going to happen...
Who's important and who isn't.
But that's because you are
trapped in your POV.
You have a classic case of
White Male Protagonism, Derek,
and a Librarian simply can't have that. But
that's why these books are so important.
They're such a gift. They... they can
allow you to see other points of view.
And once you start seeing that,
you'll find that the story
doesn't end the way you think,
and the most important
characters aren't who you expect.
(curious music)
♪ ♪
Remember back before
all the stuff in Modesto
when Alice first escaped
from the Library?
Oh, dear.
I'm telling you,
I saw a reindeer-driven sleigh fly away.
Alice and Nick are gone.
This is not funny.
(stammers)
I'm not laughing... now.
I mean...
Lets discuss next steps.
Mm, we should wait for Everett.
He'll know how to...
Oh, he'll agree with me
when I say
that Alice Quinn
was your project.
Holding her here was a mistake.
We aren't jailers.
What would you have done?
Alice broke her deal with us.
She tried to turn off all of magic.
That has to have consequences.
Our mission is to preserve
the knowledge of magic.
Alice Quinn is an existential
threat to that knowledge.
Are you suggesting that
we should have killed her...
- (scoffs)
- And Santa Claus?
(stifled laugh)
I'm so sorry.
It's not at all funny.
Do you agree with Cyrus?
I see.
I admit, I took a personal
interest in Alice's rehabilitation.
Perhaps it biased me.
You are correct.
We are not jailers.
Nor are we killers.
So I'll ask again...
What would you have us do?
"Protect the flame of knowledge
no matter the cost."
I believe that's
how the old motto goes.
Everett.
Sorry I was delayed.
The renovation of our Rome branch
ran into some difficulties.
- Have you been briefed on Alice?
- I agree with Zelda.
We are an order of scholars,
not assassins.
So what is
the scholarly solution?
Read their books.
Learn their intentions.
We agreed not to breach privacy
unless there was no other option.
What's the other option?
Uh, okay.
Well, Nick's book has been
taken and presumably destroyed,
but Alice's is still in the Revision Room
having the ending put in.
Which will take days, and if she
and Nick split up, we'll lose them.
There might be another way.
Tracking devices.
Eventually, they'll go
somewhere for help.
There isn't enough ambient to
keep either of them happy long,
- so disperse a Searcher widely and...
- Disperse to whom, though?
I find it unlikely that
Alice or Nick will run into
the hands of
card-carrying Magicians.
- They'll go underground.
- Yes.
- Where the hedge witches are.
- And the hedge witches don't trust us.
- We'll never get them to accept...
- If we do what I'm thinking,
they'll take them
without ever knowing.
Fine. Trackers.
And once Alice's book is back,
if we can verify
she's no longer a threat,
there'd be no need
for further corrective action.
Agreed?
All in favor?
(sighs)
Hmm.
- You seem troubled.
- Thank you, but I'm fine.
- I understand.
- (sighs)
I see something of Harriet
in Alice, too.
I wish you'd given yourself some
real time to grieve your daughter.
- Leave of absence, even.
- No, I'm... (high-pitched ringing)
(muffled speech)
(ringing fades)
(echoing, muffled)
Uh, I'm sorry.
(muffled speech)
(object shatters)
(breathing heavily)
Zelda.
(gasps)
I thought I heard something.
Excuse me, I have a meeting.
(eerie music)
Synced & corrected by MaxPayne
== https://subscene.com ==
So you're telling me
the Head Librarian,
a member of the
Governing Council of the Order,
is having a nervous breakdown?
Trust me, just 'cause she's
seeing shit that no one else sees
doesn't mean
it isn't really there.
Uh, then we got to get
a message to this Everett guy.
- He's in charge, right?
- Can't.
What do you mean?
There's a dragon that connects
the Underworld to the Neitherlands.
We just take a note,
and we shove it up his...
Not how that works.
Look, being down here...
You mean being dead?
It gives you a new perspective.
There's shit we know
is going to happen
that people up there would
give anything to stop.
But we can see
the bigger picture.
It's not our job to stop the
living from doing what they do.
It's our job to appreciate their full life.
We see but do not intervene...
for a lot of good reasons.
I can see this is wigging you out.
Let's start with an easier one.
Well, what's my Birthright,
you scaly shit?
Wait...
I read this one last week.
High King of Fillory gets mad
at, uh, the alpaca lady,
uh, to bring back
the talking animals' voices.
You read Margo's story.
This one is not about her.
Well, what's my Birthright,
you scaly shit?
(whooshing)
Oh, hi, there.
Do you have a message, or...?
(rabbit gurgling)
(gasps, screaming)
(gasps, panting)
Oh!
(laughing)
Okay, it was a dream.
Just keep reading.
Well, what's my Birthright,
you scaly shit?
It's the talking animals.
They've all been struck dumb.
Well, shit.
All right, Fen, I think
I will do a ritual.
Earth specialty...
The Sleep of Solitude.
I pop an Ambien, everyone leaves me
alone till noon. That'll be perfect.
Rafe, last night I had
the strangest dream.
There were these bunnies
with their throats...
You know what?
I think I projected
the talking animals going mute.
Okay, I think I'm starting to
get the point of these stories.
All women are just one
emotional crisis away
from a psychotic break.
Jesus, no.
Whoa, you can't say stuff
like that anymore.
- What, in the afterlife?
- Anywhere.
Do you remember what Kady
was doing at this time?
Didn't she just kind of peace out
after the Library Dewey coin heist?
Not exactly. See, while the
others were busy bleeding a stone
to stop the monster, Kady...
was busy doing something else.
Iris could have at least left us a
stone-bleeding how-to or something.
Yeah, I hear
what you're saying, Q.
- Hey.
- Don't mind me.
(sighs)
Uh, I'll go check those other books.
The books in, uh, Marina's library,
'cause, uh, yep, that's got
to be where they are.
- (sighs)
- Hey. Haven't seen you in a while.
There was some stuff
I had to do.
- Stuff I should be worried about?
- I'm clean.
Good.
Who's this?
Five weeks ago, her dad picked her
up from school and disappeared...
Custody fight with her mom.
Locator spell and a few bruised
knuckles later, she's home.
"Five weeks ago" as in when you
were "Detective Sam Cunningham"?
- You're solving her old case files?
- All right, look...
you lived as Kim for months.
The moment you got
your memory back, you just...
You dropped it
like it never happened.
(sighs) I-I can't.
I can't go back
to being a sidekick.
- You're not a sidekick.
- Come on.
I'm only in this group at all
because of Penny.
That's not true.
- You and me...
- We're friends, yeah.
And then we weren't,
and now we're what...
I don't know,
whatever you call it when...
you have a lot of history that
made you two very different people.
I need my own path, Jules.
I want my life to feel
like it's about me.
No, I get that.
And I am all for your personal growth.
It's just that we're... You know,
we're kind of under the gun here.
You're under my roof,
hidden from the McAllistairs
and the Library because I took
this place from Marina
when everyone else wanted to
hand her nuclear launch codes.
Look, I'll help, of course...
when I can, in my way.
But for now...
Sam left a few loose ends
I need to tie up.
(soft music)
(knocking on door)
You're not my Postmate.
(deep voice)
I am the Baba Yaga.
You live on my property
under my protection,
and your rent is due.
Okay, well, this isn't
exactly my place.
Well, you're here now,
and the list is clearly posted
on the premises.
Wait, Marina's weird
grocery list on the fridge?
It is not weird.
You are weird.
You reek of nondairy creamer
and despair.
Okay, look, I don't have
whatever it is
that you're looking for.
One Webster's Weeping Healer,
one Totem of the Plump Pelican,
and one Bag of Holding.
Pay what is owed in two days'
time or wish I boiled you alive.
The wench will explain.
What?
(gagging, coughing)
(gasps)
(normal voice)
Holy shit, you have to pay her.
"Her"? You mean you.
Okay, what the fuck is happening?
I'm Bailey. Sorry about the Baba Yaga.
She can be a little... (groans)
The Baba's the spirit
of a vengeful Slavic witch
I channel when I need
to collect rent
or deal with a chatty
Uber driver.
So if you don't want to be
her next meal,
you should give her
what she wants.
Ooh, stressful.
Where am I supposed to find...
Wait a minute.
Is the...
The Totem of the Plump Pelican.
Wait, this thing?
Oh, yeah, that's it.
Oh. Marina must have found it. I just
thought it was some ugly paperweight.
Shh, don't insult it.
It reacts.
So two more to go.
(sighs) Oh, shit.
She's coming back.
(gasps, wheezes)
(deep voice) Pay me what is owed, or I
will boil your marrow into soup, peasant.
See you Thursday.
(door bells jingle)
I'm looking for a guy
called "Lovelady."
(door closes)
Heard he has office hours here.
What is this?
Some kind of flashlight spell?
Isik.
(chuckles)
(speaking Aramaic)
- Jesus.
- Whoa!
Satisfied?
What the hell was that?
I never want to see the floor
of a bar that bright.
Pete?
(scoffs)
Wait, you're Lovelady?
Oh, shit.
Kady.
It's been a while.
Last time I saw you,
you were with Marina.
Mm.
We parted ways.
It was mutual.
Mm, I'm sure.
- So "Lovelady," huh?
- It's a title.
When one guy's done with it,
he passes it on to the next guy,
kind of like "Dread Pirate Roberts"
or "Senator."
That's not how Senators work.
Whatever.
The guy who was "Lovelady
before me
is an Earl
with a private island.
People respect
the shit out of me.
It's a great sign when
you have to tell people that.
Did you come here looking
for my help or...?
Sorry.
(sighs)
Here's a list.
I heard you can find things.
Interesting stuff.
Specific.
Landlord issue.
Have you considered moving?
The place has special features.
It just turns out it's courtesy
of a-a witch...
- Uh, Baba-something.
- You mean the Baba Yaga?
- You know her?
- Just by reputation.
Hey, if I help you,
in lieu of my usual fee,
I want you to introduce me.
- Not sure she's your type.
- She's got great taste.
This could open up
a whole new avenue for me.
Yeah, fine, whatever.
You'll help?
One more thing.
Um, do you still see Julia?
Don't be a creep, Pete.
Where are we going?
Black Market.
So Kady's moved on.
I mean, not with Pete, just...
I know what you mean,
and I'm happy for her.
You don't look happy.
So is there some sort of connection
I'm supposed to be seeing between Kady,
Zelda, Fen...
You'll see.
Alice's book had been revised,
but Alice had changed
the ending.
- Well?
- Apparently, Alice feels
magic has caused her
nothing but trouble.
She goes on to live out
an entirely civilian life
in Portland.
She just got a job
at a craft brewery,
and a Shih Tzu.
You look a little surprised.
Does that not sound like her?
The choice is unexpected, but...
wouldn't be the first time
she walked away from magic.
Great, then.
Nick is still at large,
so we'll keep our trackers
in circulation,
but I think we can close
the book on Alice Quinn.
It's funny...
I'd always thought
she was a cat person.
Never seen her before.
Sorry.
She would be a new hire.
(sighs)
We're not hiring right now.
In fact, we've had
to let some people go.
Designer hops
are getting expensive.
(indistinct chatter)
Well?
Alice is inside,
as her book said.
Hmm.
Good riddance, book tart.
Let's go get some doughnuts.
This is the Black Market?
It's so...
Normal?
- Yeah.
- Exactly.
You'd be surprised
what you can find in here.
Even Deweys.
Wait, I thought you had to
have a Library card for that?
Yeah, well, the Library
should know better
than to give
unlimited black cards
to rich druggie dickbags
that trade them in
for lap dances.
Oh, so you give lap dances, huh?
Selectively.
Okay, so that is Whitley.
If she does not have
a Bag of Holding,
she'll have a line on one.
What, you're not gonna
introduce me?
Well, I may have
had sex with her
and never called her again.
Classy.
Hey, I'm looking
for a Bag of Holding...
whatever that is.
It's a "Doctor Who"
kind of thing.
A bag that's bigger
on the inside.
Actually, it's a D&D thing.
Yeah, I don't do nerd shit.
Expensive taste for someone
who doesn't know
what they're asking for.
I can pay.
- (scoffs)
- Charisma Cufflinks...
for a Bag of Holding?
Come back when you're serious.
(dramatic electronic music)
♪ ♪
Kraken tentacles...
Helps build muscle.
I'm paleo.
Cavemen didn't eat kraken,
so I don't eat kraken.
♪ ♪
What'll you give me for these?
Aleister Crowley's ashes.
- Mm-hmm.
- Not bad.
Worth a Bag of Holding?
Thanks.
(men laughing)
What the hell, Pete?
I searched the whole
goddamn market for you.
Kady, great news.
I found Gordy.
Gordy's my, um...
He's great.
Hi, Kaitlin.
Kady.
You were supposed to be looking
for the Webster's
Weeping Whatever,
not getting wasted.
¿Por qué no los dos, mamacita?
I'll have you know
Gordy is a doctor.
- Well...
- For animals.
You know, for dogs and cats.
Don't sell yourself short,
all right?
That's a real doctor.
Ok... shh, shh, shh.
Not helpful.
Yes, helpful,
because Gordy knows
where to get that thing
that you're looking for.
The thing. The creepy doll
that cries healing tears.
Webster's Weeping Healer.
Got a buddy, Duke...
Exotic-bird guy.
So his cockatoo
caught bumblefoot...
Okay, shh.
Duke has the doll?
Well, yeah.
Okay, where can I find him?
(chuckles)
(knocking on door)
Hello?
Anybody there?
I'm guessing no one's home.
(snaps fingers)
(lock clicks)
Well, that explains it.
No sign of blunt-force trauma
or defensive wounds.
Doesn't look like foul play.
(laughs)
Okay, Mariska Hargitay.
Just find the doll, will you?
No, bad touch!
Get off!
God, I hate this place.
But...
found the doll.
Ugh.
Healing tears or no,
I would not keep this thing in my house.
Really, Pete?
What?
He's not using it.
You're disgusting.
(dramatic music)
(sighs)
(indistinct chatter)
♪ ♪
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
(birds chirping)
Jesus, Fen!
Why the hell are you lurking
in a dark pantry?
Waiting for you.
Your soufflé fell.
You're gonna bake a new one.
- How did you...
- Dreamt it.
You're worried Margo is gonna
blow talks with Lady Pike.
Wait, again with
the alpaca lady?
Sorry.
Uh, some of these pages
are out of order.
Just keep reading.
But really, you're worried
that you and she have
a true connection and you're
going to screw it up,
so you're stress-baking.
Okay, ouch.
And that's a weirdly specific
and accurate dream.
I also dreamt
of dancing ears of corn,
and then the farmers reported
a surplus.
I dreamt about what Tick
really does
with all those peaches
he steals from the kitchen,
which is surprisingly not gross.
And they've all come true.
Prophetic dreams could mean
a lot of things.
Uh, maybe you're a psychic
or someone cast some kind
of spell on you.
Or... or it's Fillory, and maybe
you just ate some messed-up fruit.
You think someone
did this to me?
If you're worried,
next time it happens
just poke around the dream
a little.
Poke with what?
A knife?
No.
No knives.
Lucid dreaming.
They teach it first semester
at Brakebills.
The second you realize
you're dreaming,
you can take control
of your dream.
You don't even need magic to do it.
Just close your eyes... (inhales deeply)
Breathe, and try to push your
finger through your other hand.
Everything freezes.
Anything not supposed to be there,
that's when you'll be able to tell.
Alice wasn't where
her book said she'd be.
I suspect she sabotaged it.
And now I've lied
to my colleagues.
If I don't find her
before they find out...
Sounds like a personal problem.
Henry, please.
I'm trusting you.
What you mean is that you trust
that I won't report this
because it'd be worse for Alice.
We both want to spare her that.
If you could just tell me
where she is...
I comply with every request...
All your red tape
and your triplicate bullshit.
This is your mess.
Do not drag me into it.
(high-pitched ringing)
(dramatic music)
♪ ♪
(breathing shakily)
Harriet?
♪ ♪
(gasps)
(breathing heavily)
(ice crunching)
I don't think an ancient Slavic
witch is gonna want a mojito.
Right, um...
something vodka-based?
- Are you actually nervous?
- Baba Yaga's a really big deal
in my line of work, and...
(grunts softly, gulps)
First impressions...
(sighs)
- What was I saying?
- Pete, your arm.
Ah... that molest-y
hand gave me the clap.
Oh, shit.
Looks like
a bad spell interaction.
Something's clashing with one
of his personal enchantments.
Which personal enchantment?
I don't know.
They're personal.
Hedge spells, you know,
they're off the street at best.
They got a lot of rough edges.
There's really no telling
if they'll play nice together
until, well, they don't.
Whatever killed Duke
is killing him.
So help him,
or I break your jaw.
Look, the only human
diagnostic spell I know
costs magic, and I'm a little
Dewey-light at the mo...
Please don't break my jaw.
Fine.
Pete has one he took off
your friend Duke.
Wait. Wait, you said
something's clashing with Pete.
Mm-hmm.
- Like what?
- Like a cursed object.
I once treated a horse
for strangles.
Turns out jockey's riding crop
interacted badly
with a hoof-protection
spell, so...
Does Pete carry a riding crop?
Okay, maybe just look at this.
(sniffs)
(spits)
Cobalt.
Don't touch that shit.
Not really planning to
now that you licked it.
What?
It's more accurate than lenses.
You can taste cobalt.
It's used in most
tracking spells.
- "Tracking spells"?
- Mm-hmm.
I put them on pets.
This one tastes like
a real expensive Searcher.
You hold it long enough,
it kind of sends out
a signal to whoever cast it.
- Wait, a-a signal to wh... who?
- Aliens.
I was thinking more like
who makes Deweys.
- The Library.
- Oh, yeah.
That makes more sense.
Who's the Library looking for?
Oh, I can think of a few people.
Wait, how many hedges have
these personal enchantments?
Pretty much everybody.
Shit.
Take off all of Pete's, now.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna warn everybody.
Wait a second.
So the Library's responsible
for hedge witches dying?
Yeah, but they don't
know that yet.
Spoiler alert.
Zelda had some other things
on her mind at the time.
Her dead daughter.
Wait, is she, like, down here?
I thought you didn't
like spoilers.
Look, I'm sorry
you see dead people,
but that is
an incredibly stupid idea.
She's not dead.
Ghosts don't bleed.
I don't know how,
but she could be alive stuck in there.
That's insane...
And impossible.
It's the Mirror Realm.
We don't know what's impossible.
It's not as complicated
as a mirror bridge.
We just need to open a door
to the place between mirrors.
Listen, Zelds,
if you told me you wanted
to finger-paint your blood
so you could take a walk
in the crazy dimension
I would say, "Free country."
But this is my blood.
I can't do this...
without your help.
Yes, I know that.
And I'm leaving.
She's my daughter.
(somber music)
Harriet...
who's older than you?
Our relationship is complicated.
Clearly.
You smashed the mirror.
You...
trapped her there.
I was doing my job.
I can't...
(inhales sharply)
Live with myself if I don't
find a way to help her.
♪ ♪
Please.
Christ.
I'm gonna regret this, aren't I?
(chuckles softly)
- Did you juice the beets?
- Oh, I juiced the beets.
I told you I would
juice the beets.
Why wouldn't I juice the beets?
Don't make this about us.
Wait, did I miss something?
I thought Margo and Josh
were an unlikely
yet heartwarming thing.
No, this is after
the Lady Pike incident.
Margo called Josh a sweater boy.
Forget it.
Pay attention to Fen.
How's this shit work?
Pour it gently
onto the lizard, Your Majesty.
(cork pops)
(lizard screeches)
Jesus lizard-fucking Christ!
Does this feel like a weird
sort of dream to any of you?
All right, maybe I can
control this.
(exhales deeply)
Ember's balls.
This is a dream.
Okay, okay. Stop talking to
yourself and, uh, look around.
(gasps) Hey! Who are you?
Wait, no! Stop, please!
Freeze! Freeze!
Hey, hey, stop!
Freeze! Green Lady! Hold up!
Hey, Green Lady, come back!
Umber's ass,
this is getting annoying.
Hey, wait!
Wait, I just want to talk!
Why am I having
these stupid dreams?
(gasps) Oh, no. The lizard.
You pour it gently
onto the lizard, Your Majesty.
Wait, stop!
It'll catch fire!
The fuck?
(panting) I saw the lizard
blow up when Rafe...
Antidote.
What is she talking about?
Perhaps she's mad with grief
over the loss of King Eliot,
Your Majesty.
I assure you, all the animals have
responded quite positively to the antidote.
Well, this one definitely won't.
Foosh.
Fried Lizard.
And where are you getting
this information?
I...
I dreamt it.
Fen has been having
kind of prophetic dreams.
She knew my soufflé was gonna
fall before that ever happened.
- It's a stupid fucking premonition.
- You want to risk the life of your lizard,
or is that a relationship you're
willing to set fire to as well?
Oh, I'll fucking fry
this lizard.
Okay, can we...
can we focus for one minute?
- Sure.
- Yes.
- Fine.
- Let's.
- Cool.
- Great.
Okay.
Say I don't dose
Newt Scamander with beet juice.
How the shit am I supposed
to get his wrinkly ass talking?
I don't know, but I have an idea
of where to look for answers.
I lucid-dreamed.
I saw a woman in a green hood.
She has to be the one
giving me premonitions.
- Awesome. You got it working. A-plus.
- B minus.
Unless...
you tell us
where this green bitch went.
Well, in my dream,
I chased her to this stream
by the Fuschia Forest
of Corian's Land.
(gasps) Corian's Land...
also known as Sloth's Bane.
I don't know what everything
in my dreams means... mean.
Anyway, I know that the answers to our
questions... Answers lie... lay there?
(laughs)
I-I'm not usually the one
who gives the big speech, so I'm...
I'm going.
So that... that's happening.
(groans)
Gordy says "you're welcome."
And he left you a bill.
That guy puts a really
high value on his time.
Wait, did I miss the Baba Yaga?
Well, you snooze, you lose.
I wasn't snoozing, I was dying.
We got bigger fish to fry.
I'll explain everything as soon as
your hedge witch friends get here.
(sighs)
I know every instinct is telling
you not to trust me... or anyone.
But someone put a tracker on this.
It's a complex, expensive,
very high-level spell.
It marked him.
It looks like the Deweys you touched
are doing the same to you. (People gasp)
If you have any
enchantments running...
Anything you got in a safe house,
anything homebrewed... It could kill you...
just like it did to Duke
and almost did to Pete.
She saved my life.
I trust her, and I vouch for her.
- Who did this?
- The Library.
They make the Deweys,
and they don't give a shit
about what happens
to the hedges.
They're trying to find someone,
and we're just
collateral damage.
So ask yourselves...
If this is what they do
when they're not even
thinking about us,
what happens when they decide
we're a threat?
(dramatic music)
Are we just gonna let people like
them tell us we're not important?
♪ ♪
That we're just some side characters
in their fucked-up fascist plot?
My mom was a hedge...
and she was killed by another hedge.
You'd think that would
turn me against you.
♪ ♪
But it didn't.
It just made me realize that
it doesn't have to be this way.
If we could stop screwing each other
over long enough to work together,
then it's not
the Library's story.
It's our story.
♪ ♪
(indistinct chatter)
- Hey.
I have a buddy in Modesto.
He says there's a leaky
Library pipe there.
I say we use it
to make those assholes pay.
Look, I know
what you're going through...
Do you?
They kill your boyfriend?
Actually, yeah.
Look, we'll figure out
what to do next.
I already know what to do.
You do that, you're giving
them a reason to wipe us out.
Please just get a little sleep.
We'll talk tomorrow.
Hey, you're not alone, okay?
We'll figure this out together in
a way that feels right for you.
Okay.
Yeah, we can do that.
It's a copy of our library,
but wrong.
(wind whistling)
I was gonna say
a total mindfuck.
Tomato, tomah-to.
(door clatters)
(gasps)
Oh, you go on.
I'll just be here cutting myself
to keep our bloody exit open.
Hey, just made a joke.
(doors creaking)
(wind howls)
Hello?
(object clatters)
(suspenseful music)
♪ ♪
(glass squeaking)
(exhales sharply)
(chuckles)
♪ ♪
(panting, gasps)
(Gavin screams)
(panting)
Where have you been?
Your funhouse-mirror daughter
shanked me. We have to go.
Those things weren't her.
(pounding on door)
The real Harriet
could still be in here.
I can't just leave her.
I hate to break it
to you, love...
She might still be in there,
but so are those monsters.
- (whimpering)
- (grunts)
(pounding intensifies)
(breathing deeply)
(air hissing)
An attack?
On what branch?
Modesto, California.
We lost four Librarians.
Hedge witches did it.
But... but why?
(clears throat)
There was some fallout
from your tracker coins.
- (gasps)
- It's not your fault.
Just unforeseen interaction.
Several hedges died.
The whole point of doing this was
to avoid having to hurt anyone.
I should have been here.
You can't blame yourself.
If anything, today we learned
the true danger we're in
and that your trackers
might provide a solution.
What do you mean?
Complications aside...
the idea is sound.
Put whatever we have
into circulation among them.
We keep Modesto
from happening again.
Are you suggesting
we kill hedge witches?
I am suggesting
that we keep an eye on them.
To "protect the flame
of knowledge from ever
being extinguished,
no matter the cost."
I don't know what to say.
This is an awesome responsibility.
You and I both know that,
but who is better suited
to bear that responsibility
than The Order?
(sighs deeply)
There is no one I trust
more deeply
to be fair and right than you.
(chuckles)
(knocking on door, door opens)
Alice.
I can't stay long.
I-I cast a spell to keep
the Library from eavesdropping,
but it won't last.
I need your help.
They have my friend Sheila.
I know.
Hello, Ms. Quinn.
Alice, please.
Nothing will happen to you here.
Zelda wants to talk.
Why?
I need your help.
I think I've seen enough.
To counteract a lifetime of cis-het
frat-bro bias? I-I doubt it.
Okay. So tell me, what was
I supposed to take from that?
Zelda doesn't know it yet,
but what she just set in motion
is going to change
the Library forever.
Same with Fen and Fillory,
Kady and all of magic.
When you file people away
as sidekicks,
you don't realize
their importance to the story,
and this story belongs to a
lot more people than you think.
Where to shelve a book,
it's not a little thing.
You're telling the world
what to value, who to value.
- You get our responsibility here?
- Well said.
I think you've earned
the right to move up.
Excuse me?
I know so much about you
and your friends,
but you never asked me
how I died.
O-okay, um...
(chuckles nervously)
- How did you die?
- Arrow to the chest...
- during the Crusades.
- "The Crusades"?
(stammers)
1,000 years ago?
We really thought the story
was all about white guys
back then, believe me.
And I'm not new at all.
I'm actually
your supervisor's supervisor.
So you're my boss.
I fully see the irony of a
white guy giving you this test,
but ladies upstairs love a twist,
so they always send me.
- Send you to what?
- To promote you.
You're clearly ready
for the next level.
Which is?
Secrets Taken to the Grave.
You're gonna collect them.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Oh, and, um, I'm afraid
we're gonna need you
to start right away.
(dramatic music)
♪ ♪
(elevator bell dings)
Hey. Been a while.
Welcome to the Underworld.