ELIOT: Previously
on The Magicians...
A huge reservoir of magic,
hidden underneath the castle?
Where does it lead? To
Roderick's secret chamber?
THE BINDER: The
Binder had a theory.
When a being of great
power, such as a god, is killed,
their energy is lost.
But he believed it
could be preserved,
effectively turning the
magician into a god.
Oh, thank Christ. I
didn't think I'd get through.
Listen, I don't have a lot
of time. We need your help.
Surviving first-year students,
I am here to teach
you what not to do.
The Library, they don't
want you to know it.
Before we go in,
there's a small
matter of protection.
What is it? Insects.
The bugs only last an
hour, so we need to be quick.
Everett's been
lying to all of us.
To do what?
To become a god.
It's locked. Don't
you have the key?
Someone locked us in.
Who's dying? My sister.
I found her a body,
but I need to find one
that is more durable.
Like yours. (GRUNTS)
(THE MONSTER HUMMING)
(CHUCKLES)
No running away, little not-god.
I'd hate to damage
my sister's new body.
Good news, sister.
I have found you
a much more durable body.
But I am going to have
to momentarily kill you again.
(THE MONSTER SHUSHING)
(SIGHS)
I beseech you, Our
Lady Underground.
You know what, fuck this.
You said you chose me,
so now's your
chance to prove it.
Julia.
Kinda cutting it
close, don't you think?
I didn't come here to fix it.
I can't.
You still have a chance.
A choice of what you want to be.
You're saying this whole time
me being a human and a god,
this was all just a test?
Well...
Both options are shit.
I mean, you're saying
one is pass and one is fail?
You will not fail as long
as the decision is yours.
Now go, I can only
hold him for so long.
JULIA: Oh, shit. OLU: Run!
(GASPING)
(GASPS) (NECK SNAPS)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Jesus Christ, so The
Monster took Julia.
We need to find them.
Do something now.
We have the axes
and the demon bottles.
You have the incorporate bond.
You didn't give two wet shits
when it was Eliot's
life on the line,
and now that it's Julia
you're suddenly leaning in?
Look, we all care
about both of them,
but based on
Mayakovsky's formula
casting an incorporate bond
strong enough to hold a god
would take an insane
amount of power.
Now we need twice as much.
If we go in there
without enough juice
they'll just body hop.
They'll kill us all. Great.
Where the hell are we
gonna find that kind of magic?
Hey, Dean.
I would not go in your
office right now, if I were you.
If you shit in my
private bathroom again...
No. Well, see,
there's kind of a few Librarian
dudes here to arrest you.
Yeah, they're pretty pissed
about some lecture you gave
while you were pissed.
I've been expecting
them. Come with me.
Thank Christ I wore
the right suit today.
The right suit for
being arrested, or...
Wait. (SNIFFS)
Are you still drunk?
That's entirely
beside the point.
We have a bigger problem.
Kady and Zelda haven't
returned from the Poison Room,
and they're running out of time.
Oh, shit.
Who are they, and what
does that mean, exactly?
God damn it, focus, Todd. Yes.
If I'm going to be arrested,
there still may be a chance
that something good
can come from it.
Here.
Yes, here.
Take this to the Library
book drop immediately.
Tell no one, do you understand?
Sure, keep it confidench. On it.
And try not to "Todd" this up.
I will try not to be myself.
Well, so much for
getting Fogg's help.
(COUGHING)
(SPITTING)
Well, that's the last
of our protection.
On the upside,
tasted minty fresh.
Hmm.
Let's go.
(SIGHS)
Wait.
What the hell?
PLOVER: Hello, there.
Apologies, I was
trying not to startle you.
Christopher Plover. Pleasure.
The children's book author?
Oh, you're familiar
with my work.
You could say that.
I've read Martin Chatwin's book.
Yes, well, not exactly
the highlight of my oeuvre.
You're the pervert who
turned him into The Beast.
I'm the man who survived
in this place for weeks.
And I can show you how
if you help me escape.
Look, it sucks that
Fogg's out of commish,
but who else can we shake down?
Kady was trying to find
the Library stockpile.
If we knew where that was.
Found magic, need help!
Who sent you?
Found magic, need
help! Okay, where?
Vague as shit. Oh, sorry.
It's Fen.
GUARD: Right this way.
High King Fen awaits.
QUENTIN: Whoa.
Sort of incredible.
Trippy.
Oh, good, you're here.
Fen, what is this? And
what's with the fish?
Follow me, come on.
Holy shit.
This is the reservoir?
QUENTIN: An ocean of pure magic.
Pretty amazing, right?
I found it. Well, Josh and me.
And Tick was there too, I guess.
But, no, a lot of it
was me. (SIGHS)
One small problem...
don't touch it!
That's the tiny little problem.
It seems to be protected
by some sort of curse.
Look what it did to Josh.
MARGO: You're saying
Josh is a fucking fish?
Well, of course not. He's
a Fillorian Dying Fish.
A Fillorian Fucking Fish
is a totally different species.
Wait, "Dying Fish"?
I really hope that's a metaphor.
Nope, they only
live a couple days.
And you're sure that's Josh?
Oh, I saw it happen.
We were gonna come
straight to you guys,
tell you all about
how we saved the day,
and then he touches the water
and next thing I know, boom,
Josh Fish.
Him and his damn showmanship.
So is it bad if it turns white?
Great Umber's taint.
What are you doing?
Dying Fish need eye contact,
almost constantly.
Usually they get it from their
fish moms, but we'll have to fill in.
Every pet I ever had ended
up in a shoebox or the toilet.
This one's all you. It's
just until we figure out
how to turn him
back into a person.
Or the rest of his life.
I'm not babysitting Nemo
when we're this
close to saving Eliot.
I've got bigger fish to
fry. FEN: Shh, Margo!
Don't say "fry" and "fish."
It's not working. He's
not getting better.
Margo, please. For Josh?
Damn it.
So I just look at him? (EXHALES)
My Gods.
He perked right up.
(CHUCKLES)
He's bonded to you.
He thinks you're his mother.
Unfortunately, that's not
the first time that's happened.
Closest thing to the
reservoir in the books
is the Secret Sea.
It's an underground ocean.
Chatwins sailed across it
with a crew full
of rabbit pirates.
Are those pirates
who steal rabbits,
or pirates who are rabbits?
Kind of both.
But it doesn't say anything
about the Secret Sea
being full of magic or cursed,
so maybe there's a
clue that I'm missing.
And if your nerdy
bullshit leads us nowhere?
We need a backup plan.
Speaking of bunnies, where
are the ones that Fen sent?
I have an idea.
So do all rabbits talk, or...
Some of them you have
to bribe with cigarettes first.
Look, about my message...
No, I know. I owe you.
But I can't slip you
that kind of power
behind The Order's back.
The monsters have
two of my friends,
and who knows what kind
of chaos they're causing
while the Library does nothing.
Look, Alice...
I am no stranger to
messing up a good thing.
I'm not gonna do
that with the Library.
Well, if we don't do something,
there might not be a Library anymore.
Then why don't you work with us?
Because your bosses
would arrest all of us on sight.
You wanna do some good?
This is your best chance.
I hope you find
what you need, Alice.
We're not setting him loose.
All we're promising is to take
him with us if we find an exit.
Well?
Do we have a deal?
Moss?
My theory is it
counteracts the poison.
Probably why it's the
only other living thing
in this place.
(CHUCKLES) Been
eating it since I got here
and I'm as healthy as a horse.
How did you get here?
Former prisoner of yours,
Alice Quinn,
seemed to think this was
the place I deserved to be.
I can't say I disagree.
Don't bite the hand
that feeds you, dear.
Shall we?
Huh.
At least give me my dignity.
Sorry. Protocol.
Well, this was a new suit.
It's a bit loud.
Yes.
It certainly is.
(CHUCKLES)
Damn, the history of this
place is depressing as shit.
Most world histories are.
Nothing about a way out.
Kady?
Oh, shit.
PLOVER: What?
The moss should have
protected you from...
Oh. "Oh," what?
The age-suspension spells
Martin used to keep me
alive while he tortured me,
it must still be
keeping me alive.
Perfect.
So I'm gonna die in the
most ironic way possible.
Just like Penny.
Well...
Not necessarily.
If we get back in time...
Wait,
(SCOFFS)
all this time
the Library had a cure?
Kady... No, you...
you chose not to save Penny?
If it were up to me... It was.
It's called "The Poison Room."
The name is a warning
Penny chose to ignore.
No, no, no, you don't get
to hide behind the Library.
You think if you're a
cog in a fascist machine
that you're not responsible
for the people that it kills?
I'll admit, the Library veered
in an authoritarian direction.
Because of Everett. Once
we remove him from power...
No, no, it is not just Everett.
It's the whole goddamn Order.
It all needs to be burned down.
Not if it can be reformed.
Look, as someone
who lived through
two world wars, I can tell you,
authoritarian regimes,
they fail eventually.
See?
Look, even the
pedophile agrees with me.
Oh, hardly.
(SCOFFS) Problem is,
no one will ever let you change.
People always see you
for what you've done,
never for who you are.
So at the end of the day,
no matter what
you try to become,
some judgmental blonde bitch
always shoves you
down a poison well.
Yeah?
Well, then I'm
Team Blonde Bitch.
Where's Fen? I sent
her out for fish flakes
three hours ago.
Wait, you sent her out
alone in Manhattan?
Well, I kind of implied it
was her fault Josh was a fish
and blah, blah, blah,
I'd blame her forever,
so she's cooling
off at Benihana.
She never could
resist a sharp knife.
Meanwhile, I'm trying to
read up on a damn cure
while maintaining constant
eye contact with an anchovy.
And they say girls are
the ones who get needy
once you fuck them.
Wait, were you and Josh...
Wait, you know about
the werewolf stuff, right?
Who gives a shit?
Nothing matters. Okay.
Look, it's not a
big deal, all right?
Sometimes we bang.
He makes me laugh.
And I like having him around
'cause of the
aforementioned banging,
and he just you know, he
kind of gets me. So what?
It's not like I'm in love
with Josh Hoberman.
It kinda sounds
like you are, though.
Have you met me?
I don't do feelings.
I'm the bitch with the ice axes.
You can still care about a guy,
werewolf, fish.
And it doesn't make
you any less you.
I mean, you can still
be a bitch if you want to.
Hmm. Shit.
Maybe I do love
this goddamn guppy.
Uh, I think this is
the Hedge doctor
that Kady called to fix Pete.
Says he's a veterinarian.
Maybe he can help
with the fish-Josh.
Josh-fish.
Way to be useful, Coldwater.
Is this Gordy?
Yeah, I've got fish problems.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Josh and Margo. Yeah.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Okay, here's my thing,
um...
I didn't think that I could
ever trust you again.
And now...
"And now"?
I find myself wanting to.
(SIGHS)
(GROANS)
When we first met,
I was clinging onto some
naive, idealistic notions of
what the world should be.
How people should be.
And I think that I have realized
if I just throw away
all that childish bullshit,
I can forgive people.
(INHALES SHAKILY)
For not living up to
my stupid expectations.
Like yourself?
(CHUCKLES)
What if we try again?
I want you in my life, Alice.
I want that, too.
Cyrus.
(CLEARS THROAT)
There was an intrusion
in the Poison Room.
It's Zelda.
With a hedge witch.
Did you follow protocol?
Yes, they're locked in.
But do we really just
leave her to die in there?
(KADY COUGHING)
How long do you think we have?
If we got out now? A few days.
In here? A few hours.
The after-effects of the
bugs slowed the... (THUDS)
Zelda? Shit.
Sorry to knock
you out like that.
It's the only way we could talk.
(SIGHS)
You could have freed me.
You brought a hedge witch
into our most protected archive.
I read your book.
You're hoarding magic.
Trying to become a god. Why?
I put in centuries of work
before you ever knew
the Library existed.
Oh, so I wouldn't understand.
No, you should understand.
How...
(SIGHS) futile it all is.
We work so hard to protect
the flame of knowledge,
but there will always be
things we can't understand.
Knowledge of the Gods.
By becoming one of them, I can
rip their secrets away from them
and bring them
back to the Library.
At what cost?
An unkillable god is on
the loose as we speak.
In the body of Eliot Waugh.
You intend to take his power.
He has the power
to destroy everything,
and all we have are books.
If we want to face
that kind of threat,
we need power, too.
Isn't that what Bacchus and
the others were trying to do?
They got drunk
on their own power.
Some of them literally.
What makes you think you
won't fall prey to the same hubris?
Well, I thought I had you.
Excuse me, but isn't
this book banned?
Like, really, really banned?
Fuck me. Uh,
we need to get that
to the Poison Room.
Immediately. Now, now, now.
(KEYS JANGLING)
(CLINKING)
(PUPPIES WHINING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
You wanted me.
To do what, exactly?
To take over the
Library once I'm gone.
To see to the human concerns,
and to fix my mistakes
with the benefit of all the knowledge
and the power I would bring.
I wish you'd told
me the truth sooner.
So do I.
So, do what you must.
Follow protocol. There is
a way you can still help me.
I redirected the power
I need into a reservoir,
but it triggered
a protective spell.
A puzzle I can't solve.
But I've discovered
someone who can.
Quentin Coldwater.
(SIGHS)
Get Quentin to
open the reservoir,
and the Library can
still be yours to lead if...
(GRUNTS) (GASPS)
Did you slap me?
We need to move, fast.
No. I didn't risk my life
to save a child molester.
He can stay. What? No.
(STAMMERING) We
had a deal! Tell him!
Well, your moss didn't
do shit for us, so...
But I can help you
get to the reservoir.
It was a secret of Martin's,
and I know all his secrets.
I could share them with you.
(ALARM BELL RINGING)
Incursion protocol.
They're patrolling.
Come on.
Get to the Earth fountain,
I'll hold them off. Go!
(CHOKING)
(GRUNTS) (YELPS)
(GROANS)
Damn it.
Quite a trip you sent
me on. (GRUNTING)
You ruined my suit.
But the good news is,
you're just about my size.
(GROWLS)
(DOG BARKING)
Keep barking, you
schnauzer fuck.
It won't bring back your balls.
(DOG CONTINUES
BARKING) God, I hate animals.
So...
Goldfish troubles? Not exactly.
I see. Not a goldfish.
Some kind of hybrid?
Oh, my God.
I am sorry to be the
bearer of bad news,
but your fish is a werewolf.
Wait. So are you.
Did...
Did you fuck this fish?
Look, he's a human
who's been cursed,
and I need to
know how to undo it.
Well, it's definitely
not a hedge spell.
And without knowing
how it was cast,
not much I can do about it.
So, should I just go
ahead and flush it, or...
Again, he's a person.
I'm gonna need you to
try a little harder, all right?
Now, if I look away
for literally 10 seconds,
he starts to die, and at some
point, I'm gonna need to sleep
or drop a deuce, and I
don't allow spectators.
Yeah, there is some kind
of bond happening there.
Whoa. Your eye is crazy.
Is that a wolf thing, or...
Fairy thing.
Can we focus on
fish boy, please?
It's not even
attached to your head.
You ever pop it out?
Why the shit would I pop
out my own eyeball, Gordy?
So you can point it
at your gilled lover
while you attend
to lady business.
I don't know, man. It
feels pretty stuck in there.
Ahh!
Holy shit, it's working.
I can still see out of it.
You ever touch me
again, I'll pop out your balls.
Uh...
(LAUGHS)
See? Problem solved.
I don't know. This
seems kind of problematic.
Oh, I got just the thing.
Really?
Why does a veterinarian have
a pirate-themed eye patch?
Maybe it's best we don't ask
a lot of follow-up questions.
Jesus, what happened to you?
Hey.
Just... Hello, Alice.
QUENTIN: Thought he was
dead. Why'd you bring him here?
Because I just might
be the only person alive
who knows how to
access the reservoir
and save your friends.
Mmm. Okay, so, the reservoir.
Yes, well, that's
what Martin called it.
I thought it lacked
a certain poetry.
So I renamed it the Secret Sea.
Right, the fourth Fillory book.
Mmm. Oh, I see
you have a copy here.
Ah.
Oh.
First edition That
must be valuable. Yes.
Well, even more so
now. (CHUCKLES)
The Watcher Woman in the books,
she was trying to steal all
of magic for herself, right?
And then Martin stops her.
Most of that book is pure tosh.
I had to invent that
plot from whole cloth
since, well,
I couldn't exactly
publish the stories
as the children told
them to me, could I?
I mean, the Flying Forest,
where the Chatwins
discovered recreational drug use?
Poor little Jane hearing
all about the birds
and the bees from a...
Did you know that
centaurs view necrophilia
as a way of honoring the dead?
Don't think I'd get
a Carnegie Medal
for explaining that to children.
I mean, then there's all the
exaggerations and the lies.
I mean, Martin slaying
a dozen mercenaries,
and Jane riding on top of
a horse, what, 100 feet tall?
I mean, what did she
call it? Cozy Horse.
(CHUCKLING) "Cozy Horse."
Utter nonsense thrown in there
just to see how much
they'd get me to believe,
and then Jane
insisted I keep it.
In real life, the ending
was much darker.
Oh, Martin did stop the
Watcher Woman, that's true.
The Secret Sea
was built by the
thirteenth king of Fillory
to consolidate
power for himself.
Martin wanted to make
sure that no one ever tried
to do the same thing again
so he drained the Secret Sea
using the last few
drops to set a trap
for anyone who might,
one day, try to refill it.
A curse.
Right, so now, one
of our friends is a fish.
(CHUCKLES) Well,
he was 13 at the time.
You have to forgive his rather
adolescent sense of humor.
You know how to fix it?
Mmm.
There's a garden just
outside the reservoir.
The Drowned
Garden, Martin called it.
Never did know why.
It reacts to your emotions.
You feel happy, a flower blooms.
You feel sad, another one.
So, one of the
plants is the antidote?
Indeed.
To make it bloom,
you have to truly love Fillory.
Maybe when I was 12, but...
I don't know, Fillory's taken
away a lot of the shit I love.
Martin had the same problem.
He returned as an adult
and could not make
the flower bloom.
His innocent love for Fillory
had soured.
I think we can all say why.
Quentin.
It has to be you.
I'm familiar with your books.
Even considering your
recent experiences,
Quentin has the
best chance of...
making the garden grow.
(SIGHS)
ZELDA: We don't have much time.
There's a contractor
the Library uses
who might be willing to...
Text me if you find somebody.
(COUGHING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
So it's true? The
Library has a cure?
(SIGHS)
I know, it's bullshit.
Go with her
before it's too late.
If this is some noble shit
about you not owing
the Library anything...
Oh.
You don't want to be cured.
(SNIFFLES)
'Cause for all the terrible
shit we've been through,
at least the upside is
that you know that
there's a life after death
and you get to spend
forever with the other Penny.
And what part of
that sounds bad?
The part where you're dead.
(SCOFFS)
I may not know
you the way he did,
but I know that that
would be a hell of a waste.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
Well, most things are.
A lot's changed
since I've been gone.
Yes.
The humans made
lots of good stuff.
They spend their small
lives building things
that we could
smash in a heartbeat.
Sounds fun.
Perhaps you can
tell me... (SIGHS)
Do I have a name?
Why would you need one?
Starbucks, mostly.
This whole time I
felt so sorry for you.
Lost and alone.
But you weren't alone.
You were with the humans.
You talk like them,
you think like them.
I ate a few of them.
Yes, but you care about them.
(SIGHS)
You think I'm disappointed.
I'm not.
Are you scared of
me, little brother?
Would I have worked
so hard to bring you back
if I was scared of you?
All I thought about was you.
After I remembered
you existed, anyway.
And all I thought
about was revenge.
And I got it for you already.
I killed Bacchus.
Iris.
All of them.
Everyone who hurt you.
The question is who put us here?
Our parents.
They made us,
called us mistakes.
Abandoned us.
So, what do we do?
I like murder as much as anyone,
but I did all of this
just to be with you.
Can't we enjoy it
just for a little while?
That's not what
we were made for.
It's not that I am terrified
of the Old Gods in any way.
It's just, how do you kill
an intangible thought creature?
Where do you even stab?
They're more
vulnerable than you think.
If we can get to their realm.
Which we cannot.
We have a key. A scroll.
Found it a very long
time ago on this world.
The Order took it from us.
They didn't even
know what they had.
Now,
where would a
bunch of Librarians
keep a very, very
important scroll?
Oh.
Here.
This has to be it.
It's exactly as
Martin described it.
(STAMMERING)
Think happy thoughts
about Fillory.
Pure.
Innocent.
Maybe try talking to it.
Okay, can you just...
Well...
Um, Fillory is...
obviously great.
You know, talking bears, right?
Who could hate that?
And opium in the air.
That was...
smart.
And...
socialized centaur medicine.
Are we screwed
because Quentin can't
get it up for Fillory? Just...
Look, why don't you try...
Okay, no, stop.
I can't... Look, you're
the one that ruined this.
I can't do it with you
over my shoulder,
so just, please, just go.
God damn it.
(SIGHS)
Okay, um...
When I was a kid, I
loved the Fizzy River
that they found in book two.
And I loved...
I loved the Upside-Down Desert.
(STAMMERING) You know, the...
I can't really picture it,
but, you know, it sounds...
It sounds cool.
I don't know, I
can't, I'm sorry.
I just... I can't... Hey. Hey.
I used to love Fillory
when I was a kid
because I didn't
know what it was.
Plover left out all
of the terrible shit,
and most of the good
stuff he just made up.
Even the fucking
Cozy Horse is a lie.
Remember what you told me
about letting go of
who you used to be?
I know, I'm trying.
Don't.
I don't want you to.
Believing in something,
really believing,
is almost impossible.
But the Quentin I first met...
he believed in magic.
And in Fillory.
He changed.
He grew up.
Being an adult doesn't mean
that you have to throw away
what you used to love.
Then what does it mean?
Seeing the world
through new eyes.
And for what it's worth,
the Cozy Horse is real.
I saw her when I was a Niffin.
So big you could
build a house on it.
So...
Let's go.
(SIGHS)
Okay, it's just you and me.
You know the worst part
of getting exactly
what you want?
When it's not good enough.
Then what do you do?
If this can't make me
happy, then what would?
Fillory was supposed
to mean something.
I was supposed to
mean something here.
But it's all... It's
just... It's random.
It's so random that the
only way to save my friends
is to yell at a fucking plant!
Honestly, fuck Fillory
for being so disappointing.
You know what,
maybe I was better off
just believing
that it was fiction.
The idea of Fillory
is what saved my life!
(CHUCKLING RUEFULLY)
This promise...
that...
people like me...
(CRYING)
People like me...
Can somehow...
Find an escape.
There has gotta be
some power in that.
Shouldn't loving the
idea of Fillory be enough?
(SIGHS)
Guys.
Guys, something's happening!
(WOMAN SHRIEKS)
(GROANS)
(YELPS)
Here's the door.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(SCREAMING)
The key to the realm
of the Old Gods.
(NECK SNAPS) (GROANS)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
How the hell does
this thing work?
Give this to Margo.
If Plover's right, it
should cure Josh.
Monsters in Library!
Sheila must have sent
it. Monsters in Library!
All right, we have to
go before they leave.
Okay, I'll grab
Margo and the axes.
Hey, you sure
this is gonna work?
Well, either it will,
or when you come
back we'll both be fish.
Well, that'd be an improvement.
Okay. Okay.
Do you feel anything?
Super stressed out?
Okay.
Ugh.
Yeah, I'm totally feeling that.
Okay. (CLEARS THROAT)
Grab your axes.
Monsters in the Library.
Are you baking for a fish?
He has a refined palate.
Yeah, here, this should
fix the whole fish deal.
And, yes, I noticed
that your eyeball isn't in your head,
but honestly, we do not have time
for me to hear that story.
How long does the
leaf take? I don't know.
But you know it works?
I can't believe I'm saying this,
but I can't go until he's cured.
If I leave, Josh will die.
It's okay. Penny.
I'll bring Eliot back.
I promise.
Damn cheap bastards.
WOMAN: No, no, please!
MAN: No! (BOTH SCREAM)
Shit.
(CLEARS THROAT)
What did you do to
get locked in this cage?
Well, I...
I went against
every instinct I had.
I tried to make a
goddamn difference.
Which, for the record,
you should never, ever do.
Julia...
if you're in there,
then I'm sorry...
for everything that
happened to you...
Because of me.
QUENTIN: Hey, Monster...
Lady.
Adorable.