Previously on The Magicians...
You didn't just
save their lives.
You changed their lives as
much as they changed yours.
You didn't want
to leave all that.
Pardon me, sir. Fillory is still
ruled by Acting High King Fen, right?
The Dark King reigns.
Glory to his rule.
High King Fen and
Josh the Fresh Prince
were overthrown 300 years ago.
We need you to go find someone,
and do your very best to
convince them to come and help us.
Alice Quinn.
Get a blood worm
and cast, you boil alive.
Reed's Mark would prevent
them from triggering the parasite.
Then once this Serpent
group have been dealt with,
the mark is removed
free of charge.
The one that I'm the
most worried about is Julia.
Thank you for deciding that
I'll never get to do magic again.
She's been in a weird place.
And magic...
Comes from pain.
Did you... Did
you just see that?
Yeah.
So, what are you
going to do with it?
Okay.
I had a dream, I had a dream
That I was your neighbor
About to give birth and then...
Julia, you, uh, ready?
Wow. Wow,
you look... Overdressed?
Great.
I thought you said
this was a date.
I said I was taking you out,
and to dress appropriately.
That means dress up.
You totally told me to dress up.
I should have been
more specific. Good.
Glad to hear you
accept the blame.
Only problem is we gotta
go now or we're gonna miss it.
Where's your coat?
But it's 75 degrees out.
Not where we're going.
Okay.
Here.
Do you consent to be traveled?
I consent to be...
Traveled. Where are we?
Other side of the planet. Look.
So, my friend Seth is an artist,
but there hasn't
been enough magic
for him to work with
meteors until now.
It's incredible.
See, there are a lot of ways to use
magic to make the world a better place.
Wait. What?
Is that why you brought me here?
No, that's not really the...
I mean, you've been working
so hard to try to figure this out.
I told you, it's my business.
And I'm just trying to help.
You know, to brainstorm.
I need to choose that.
You understand what
that means, right?
You feel that?
It's another surge.
Shit.
Uh, Penny...
How does making pretty patterns
in the sky help the world when
this type of a thing can happen?
No one knows when a
magic surge is coming.
So, what? We shouldn't
try and make things nicer?
The surges are getting worse.
I'm just saying, this
is the type of thing
I should be using
my magic to fix.
Julia, I... I just wanted you
to have a break for one night.
Yeah, but this is
why I'm working.
I'm...
I only have magic
because I lost Q.
I... I just have to find
something to do with it that...
That's worth that.
Julia, there's nothing that you will
ever be able to do that's worth losing him.
You know what kills me?
I just keep thinking, like,
oh, I should talk to Q.
He'd know what I should do.
And then I think, "Oh, right."
It's only been a month.
This kind of thing
takes a while.
Ugh. God damn it. Shit.
My apologies. Dean Fogg?
I was waiting for the
right moment to interject.
And, well, that never came.
Are you drunk? No. And
I'm sorry about the scotch.
I was, um, smelling it.
You're not trying to get me to
go to Brakebills again, are you?
Hardly, dear.
I accepted your refusal,
as any gentleman should.
Truth is, I'm actually
here for Penny.
Jesus Christ. What
happened here?
Everett drank a
reservoir of magic
and exploded.
It had to go somewhere.
Too much magic means
too many people with potential
are discovering their gift.
Lately, more people have been
able to pass than we can handle.
And now look at this place.
Might as well be a
goddamn state school.
Overcrowded.
Discipline problems.
Did you know someone stole
the school's supply of living clay?
No. Of course,
thanks to the surges,
a few of them have
blown themselves up.
Which isn't very
good for morale,
but yes, it helps with the
goddamn over-enrollment.
With the rise in students
has come a simultaneous rise
in some of the
rarer disciplines.
Like yours.
So, who better to
teach them than you?
Whoa, I'm no professor.
Penny, you're the only
Brakebills-educated Traveler
currently alive on this planet.
Which makes you far more qualified
to teach them than anyone else I have.
Including me.
But what if one of them
gets killed because of me?
Excellent point.
This indemnifies you against
any claims, legal or magical,
that your students might make.
That doesn't actually
solve my problem.
Penny, I can assure you
that without your instruction,
one of them will
absolutely get killed.
Fine.
To our pretty corpses.
Goddamn gorgeous corpses.
I'd fuck our corpses.
What are we doing here, Eliot?
We're despairing in style, as befits
two former High Kings of Fillory.
On that note, it's 3:00,
when I usually ask you if
you'd like to talk about Quentin.
And I usually
respond, "I'm fine."
With the help of some
liberally-applied libations.
I would prefer to focus on
our current hopeless situation.
You know, I gotta
give it to this Dark King.
All the patrols and
heightened security
have made it impossible
to get into his castle.
We tried for a week.
That seems like enough.
Although "Dark
King" is a little generic
as villain names go. Mmm.
Wouldn't you say? I have notes.
Like, we get it. You're a despot.
You're the fucking Dark King.
Although he is
somewhat effective.
Everyone seems terrified
of him, like the bunnies.
They did seem unusually
scared. They did.
I hope they got our
warning to 23. Mmm.
You know, I know we told him not
to travel here because of time shit,
but maybe we should just take the
Portal Tree back to Earth and regroup.
I think it's not safe to leave
until we figure out the time shit.
What if we go back and bam,
it's 300 years later on Earth?
If we could just figure
out a way into his castle
and find out what happened to Josh
and Fen, we might be in a better position.
Bambi, we're 300
years in the future.
All signs point to "not good."
Look, Josh is a
fucking Magician.
Maybe he baked an
immortality cake or something.
Plus, it's Fillory.
Weirdness abounds.
Huh.
I guess these people didn't get
the memo they're living in a dystopia.
A fine unshackling
to you, pilgrims.
Hello.
I see you've gotten a head
start on today's festivities.
Right.
I'm... I'm Pree.
And, uh, you two must
be High King Margo
and High King Eliot.
Um, what? Now, guess who I am.
Come on.
High King Fen the Toeless.
Not bad, right? They're
cosplaying as us.
Hey, so where's this big party?
- Yeah.
You two really
have been drinking.
There's only one place to
celebrate the Great Unshackling.
Castle Whitespire.
Castle Whitespire. Of
course. Where else?
We want to get there before all the
good seats are gone, so come with us.
Come on. Come on.
It can't be that easy,
can it? I guess so.
Good afternoon, Alice.
It is afternoon, you know.
You got another
letter from the Library.
You know, they're just gonna keep
sending them unless you respond.
I know.
I already told them no.
I'm just bad at listening.
Alice, you know, I have no
problem with you living here.
And it is your business if
you want to let yourself go.
But right now I
need you to put on,
you know, whatever
fits and help me.
It's an emergency.
You want my help to cheat?
Not cheat. Pick.
It's my ladies' garden club
perennial orchid competition,
and, well, I want to win.
But none of them
are Magicians, right?
Yeah, but that doesn't mean
they're not a bunch
of mean old twats.
Mom, this is not an
emergency. Yes, it is.
There's too much magic, Alice.
Everything that I touch just...
It grows like
crazy. I'll get it.
Hey. Uh, can I come in?
Uh, welcome to Introductory
Psychic Translocation.
My name is Professor Adiyodi.
I see you have your
Umar, Kaminsky, Aurora.
See, I... I always
thought books would help.
Only problem is books make you think
you can do something that you shouldn't.
Anyone here know other
people's thoughts yet?
Cool.
You're gonna want to get some psychic
wards to block that shit out right now.
The truth? Being a
Traveler is a curse.
Best case scenario, you end
up a taxi service for your friends.
Worst case, you dream about
volcanoes and then you wake up in one.
What?
Yeah, are you actually
gonna teach us something,
or are you just gonna
keep trying to scare us?
Look, man. I'm trying
to be real with you.
You should be scared.
I mean, have you
even actually Travelled?
Anyone? Okay, seriously?
Get an anti-Travelling
tattoo and then just go.
Enjoy your life.
'Cause it'll be a hell of a lot longer
than if you stick around with this shit.
End of class. Peace.
I miss him, too, but a seance?
Well, I wanted to talk to him,
and then I realized, what if I could?
You know, what if we could?
Actually talking to
the dead is wild magic.
It's way too dangerous.
Well, then what should I do?
Because I don't know,
and the person I want to ask
is Q.
I miss him every day, too.
I honestly don't know how
to move on without him.
I just... But we have to, right?
I found it. It was his.
Uh, his notes are
written in the margin.
What a nerd.
Can't talk to him,
but can read it.
Picture what he was thinking.
Next best thing.
Um...
Is Kady here?
Let me get this straight.
Your friend tried to remove your
Reed's Mark with magic and...
Blew my arm off. Yeah.
I still can't cast, either.
Why not go to a hospital? I
don't have health insurance.
Well, I know a spell.
Might make you vomit,
though. Like, a lot?
One-armed beggars can't
be one-armed choosers.
Ugh.
Oh. KADY: Hold his arm in place.
Wait, wait, wait. How
much throw-up, really?
Wow.
Thank you.
Uh-oh.
You got that look, boss.
That guy. He was so
afraid of not having magic,
he was willing to risk blowing
his own arm off to get it back.
That guy was an idiot.
Or maybe just desperate.
So, what? It's hard to be a
Hedge? It's always been hard.
We could at least
defend ourselves.
I thought with magic back
things would get better.
The Library promised they'd remove
all of Reed's Marks, and they haven't.
Are you surprised?
I hear the Library's
falling apart,
so I doubt that fixing hedge
witches ranks high on their to-do list.
I'm done waiting.
There's tons of magic now.
So let's figure out a way
to remove them ourselves.
If you're serious,
I heard about a guy
who might be able to help.
An Order of the Library of the
Neitherlands medical manual
should have the
ritual you're looking for.
And why should we trust you?
'Cause I don't give a rat's tit
about the Library. Never have.
I don't even read books.
But you worked for them?
Not anymore. Contracts aren't
valid once the place collapses.
Besides, I'm chaotic neutral,
so I do a lot of crazy shit.
For cash.
And since we're not here to fuck
spiders, you can pay, can't you?
We can pay.
How soon can you
get us the manual?
I'm not getting it for you. I'll
just tell you where you can find it.
A former Library book depository
no one's hit yet. They'll have one.
And a lot more goodies besides.
And you're not grabbing
these goodies for yourself. Why?
Mate, if I knew how to rob that
place without getting decapitated,
I'd be robbing it right now.
You have all come to hear the
story of the Great Unshackling.
First, there was I,
Ember, god of Fillory.
Then came my
boring brother, Umber.
Together, we created this world.
But I thought it would be funny
if Fillory were ruled
by Children of Earth.
I am High King Eliot,
and I am drunk all the time.
That's original.
I am High King Margo,
and I am angry all the time.
I am King Quentin, and I
am dissatisfied all the time.
I am Queen Alice, and I died.
Sort of.
It's complicated.
The Children of
Earth came and went,
doing their Children
of Earth things,
like chewing loudly and texting.
One of them even killed me.
Which was not funny, but
at least it was unexpected.
He neglected to mention he
was gonna destroy the world.
True that, girl. Shh.
No matter who was in charge,
Fillory remained shackled to them.
Which brings us to these two.
Ooh.
I am High King Fen the Toeless,
and I like knives.
I am Josh the Fresh
Prince, and I love to eat.
Also, I have a mustache.
Oh.
Guess Josh must have gone
through a mustache phase.
So they weren't paying
attention when it happened.
The Takers came into Fillory.
The borderlands became overrun.
The people fled for their lives.
Boo.
What's a Taker? I don't know.
No one knows where the Takers
came from, but they were everywhere.
- The people asked for help.
- But we didn't do anything.
The people prayed.
There were no
more gods in Fillory,
yet their prayers were
answered anyway.
I will save the
people of Fillory.
Who was this mysterious hero?
Oh, just a humble wizard
coming to you out of the darkness.
Eventually, the
people would decide
to make this dark
wizard their king.
The Dark King.
I promise to protect
you as long as I live.
And I shall live forever.
But before this could happen,
the people handed out just deserts.
To the gallows!
Did somebody say "desert"?
As we cast off the
shackles of our past,
I declare today will be known
hence as the Great Unshackling.
And the people of Fillory
lived happily ever after.
Margo, for God's sake,
would you just come back?
They murdered them. They
murdered the shit out of them.
Okay, yeah, like, 300
years ago. All right?
Look, maybe you didn't have
time to prepare yourself for this,
but you have to know it
didn't end well for them.
Yeah, well, it's not over yet.
We're gonna Endgame this shit.
When did you have
time to go see Endgame?
Does it matter?
All I'm saying is we're
gonna time-fix this bitch.
In the center of Fillory is a
clockwork heart built by dwarves.
They're the ones who taught
Jane Chatwin how to do time magic.
Jesus Helena Bonham Christ.
Read the books already, El.
Uh...
We're gonna dial back the clock
300 years to before
all this bullshit.
Right. So I guess we just
have to somehow find our way
to the center of the world then?
When I was High King, I
started excavations to reach it.
I wanted to meet
the Clock dwarf,
who takes care of
the clockwork heart.
Come on.
So, we're actually going to
slide to the center of the world?
Oh, grow a clit, will you?
Bitch, I would if I could.
So what made you
change your mind?
I need to get out of the house,
and your request
seemed the least annoying.
You promise you won't
ask me to join the Library?
Promise. I just need a
phosphoromancer for, like, an afternoon.
Fine.
Motherfucker. I have a
serious case of slide-ass.
Yeah. I think I lost several
pounds to friction burn, as well.
Welcome, adventurers.
Wait. You're the Clock Dwarf?
Huh. I thought you'd be smaller.
'Cause I deal with clocks?
'Cause on Earth,
"dwarf" means small.
Really? Is Earth really big?
So, tell me. Did you happen
to bring any food with you?
Uh...
Were we supposed to
bring you some food?
I mean, you didn't have to.
I just figured if you came
all that way from the surface,
you might have some
hearty adventuring snacks,
like bread and maybe ham,
and cheese and lettuce and
perhaps some assorted condiments.
Sounds like you
want a ham sandwich.
If you're offering
a ham sandwich...
I'm not.
Ah. I see. It's just...
I don't get out much on account
of the massive disruptions
in the flow of time that
happens when I do.
I get by on cave mushrooms.
They're fine.
Um, we were hoping you
might be able to help us.
Earth and Fillory
kinda fell out of sync.
On Earth, barely any time has
passed, while here, it's been 300 years.
Uh, big old surge of magic
skipped the gears forward.
I had to crank down on
it before it went too far.
Okay, how about you just
wind it back 300 years then?
Eh, can't. These clock gears
aren't made to go backward.
I could probably jump you
forward 300 years if you want.
Why the shit would we want to
go another 300 years in the future?
Why would you want to
go 300 years in the past?
Because all our friends are
dead and the world is fucked.
Oh, wow.
Sorry.
These mushrooms,
they also get me high,
so I don't always pick
up on emotional cues.
Look.
You're a smart
dwarf, right? Yeah.
There's got to be
some way to skip back.
I mean, this whole thing is
already impossible, isn't it?
We're sorry we didn't
bring you snacks.
No, this isn't even
about the snacks.
If I wound the clock
backward, it would just be bad.
How bad? 'Cause it's bad now.
Like apocalypse bad.
It would destroy Fillory.
So, I'm sorry. I wish
I could help you.
You guys want some
cave mushrooms?
Look on the bright side, Bambi.
We just got to slide
up back to the surface,
which hurt a lot less
than on the way down,
and now we get to hole up in a
lovely villa on the Grand Canal
and sip Bellinis
until we pass out.
We can't leave Fillory.
I don't want to tell you
that things are hopeless,
but they're not
looking very good.
And I hate to see
you feeling like this.
I'm not gonna feel better.
What the hell is wrong with
you? You should feel just as upset.
Uh... I don't know. I guess
it takes a lot to upset me.
I think you're gloriously medicated
and in some textbook denial.
I'm managing.
I'm fine. Sure. You're fine.
A monster rode you around for
months while he murdered people.
And then one of your
closest friends died.
You know, I don't remember
anything from in there.
As if that changes
a goddamn thing.
Quentin died, and it hurts.
And I don't really
want to talk about it.
Everything I have to
say, you already know.
So, why?
Well, if it were me,
I'd be driving a fucking
semi down Fury Road.
Yeah, well, feelings are gauche,
and I'm sparing you mine, and
I thought you would be grateful.
I don't care what you're
like out there, but with me,
I thought you'd at
least try to be real.
Bambi. Don't "Bambi" me.
If you're gonna be this stupid, I
need some time alone to calm down.
Fine.
Hey. Banished scum.
What happened here?
Been a rough couple of weeks.
Everyone's abandoned us.
We've lost most of the branches.
Can't even reach our
people in the Underworld.
Where's Zelda?
- Oh, God, who knows?
- She's a mess.
Look, no bullshit.
After you refused to help
her for, like, the fifteenth time,
I think it broke her brain. She said
she can't be trusted to lead and ran off.
Then who's leading the Library?
Well, not me, that's for
sure. I'm just doing my job.
That's a Library
Branch Index, isn't it?
You know about these?
I've heard a couple things.
Okay, well, it shows you the location
of every volume and how to access it.
Mmm. So, what's
the problem then?
The phosphoromancer
who did this is dead.
I need you to unlock it.
If you're gonna
watch, I'll need a drink.
Yeah, I could use one myself.
Ugh.
I think there's a bit of confusion
about the nature of your job.
You told me they'd get
killed if I didn't talk to them,
so I told them how
not to get killed.
Well, how very
thoughtful of you.
Look, man.
I was doing you a solid,
but I don't think I'm your guy.
This is the time, as a dean, where
I usually dig deep to find a funny
or sad anecdote to win you back.
But since I've stopped drinking,
those no longer come easy.
You stopped drinking? Yes.
I've lost the taste
for it, I'm afraid.
Maybe it's what
happened to Quentin.
Maybe it's just my liver.
Either way, I'm a bit
raw at the moment,
so you will forgive
my bluntness.
You signed a contract.
I thought that was,
like, to protect me.
I lied.
It was an employment contract,
which forbids you from quitting.
I've never met a Penny
who read the fine print.
So what if I break it?
Well, I will sue
you into oblivion.
Could you fight it?
Yes. Would you win? No.
Could you run?
- Well, yes, of course.
- You're a Traveler.
But I doubt a world exists
where you could
hide from our lawyers.
I will see you at
school, Professor.
Not that there's anything
wrong with masturbation.
There's a tradition of
librarians masturbating.
It goes back centuries. But
just the way he did it was creepy.
Mmm. Whew.
God damn. I need to pee.
Holy shit.
Apologies, my good lady, for
the intrusion into your maison.
And... And for startling you.
And for raiding your magical
winter box of comestibles.
It has been a long
and arduous journey.
Find...
Who are you?
I am Sir Hargreave Mcgrubney Cubbins
Archibald Brian Effingham the Third.
But you can call
me Sir Effingham.
Are you from Fillory?
Why, yes, I am. Well deduced.
You are a credit to your sex.
Gonna move past that. Um...
What brings you here to Earth?
I am here on a mission
of dreadful import.
It is not an exaggeration to say
that the very fate of both of
our worlds lies in the balance.
You're here to bestow a quest.
I am here to bestow a quest.
You know, this
timing is perfect.
Because, honestly, I've
been feeling a little lost lately.
And I've been looking for
something to do with my magic
to make a difference. You
know, searching for a sign.
And here you are. Here I am.
So, tell me. How can I help you?
You can help me find
Quentin Coldwater.
Oh...
Yeah. Um... No, that's not...
Perhaps you have
been beset by hysteria.
Is your corset too tight?
It can cause the womb to
wander. I've seen it happen.
Um, no, you can't talk to
Quentin because he's dead.
He died.
Oh, dear. Oh, dear, oh dear,
oh, dear, oh, dear, oh, dear.
I do believe I'm
having the hog sweats.
Are you... Are you all right?
No, my dear lady. I
do not believe that I am.
You see, this matter
that brings me here,
it is somewhat
apocalyptic in nature.
Oh, I find that I do
not feel at all well.
Perhaps you could pour me
a draft of medicinal cocaine?
Oh.
Yeah, that's not a
thing we use anymore.
Have you not modern medicine
in this godforsaken world?
Oh, this is truly the end times.
Well, maybe I could
help you to save the world.
Yes. Very good.
Oh, you're serious?
No, no, no. You see, I'm afraid
that that would be far too difficult
for someone like you to handle.
You know, I have saved the world
before. I was an actual goddess.
And you are still quite
fetching, albeit unmarried.
Look, the nature of the
quest that I must deliver,
well, it requires a
certain kind of hero.
And what kind of
hero would that be?
Well, that is to say, to
use the common tongue,
a hero with a pork loin.
So, the apocalypse is
happening, or whatever,
and this little piggy
comes all this way,
but you won't accept my
help because I'm a woman?
Quite right. Well, I have a
long journey ahead of me.
This has been a
dreadful setback,
but I am sure that
a hero will rise,
and he will save us.
Madam, I have heard
from many trusted sources
that hysteria such as
yours can be cured,
temporarily, through
pelvic massage.
I must go.
Look familiar?
This building, our
target. It's missing.
Maybe it's some kind of
optical displacement spell?
Like the building's hidden?
Come on.
Hey, man, can you tell me, did
there used to be a building here?
Don't think so. Are you sure?
I mean, I've only worked in
this park for, like, eight years.
But, yeah, maybe
I'm wrong about it.
Well, guy says there
was never a building here.
So, looks like
Gavin ripped us off.
He didn't rip us off.
There was a building.
I can still see the
residue from the wards.
So what happened to it?
I think someone stole it, then
mind-wiped everyone in the area.
Do you know what kind of skills
it would take to steal a building
with Level Five wards?
That's like, Gandalf-level skills.
That's like... Wait.
Gandalf was a wizard, right?
Pete, just... Shit.
I think we might have
some competition.
So, the apocalypse is coming,
but don't worry your pretty little
head about it? What are we gonna do?
It's not like he's the first guy
to tell me I'm not good enough.
Right. And how screwed is the
universe that it doesn't even realize
Quentin's dead
and plan around it?
Truth? I don't think the universe
is really looking out for anyone.
Try saying that
to your students.
I think I've already told
them all the depressing things.
I can't believe I
have to go back.
What the fuck am I
gonna say to them?
Well, what would you say if you
could say anything you wanted?
'Cause you can.
What would you say to the pig?
I'd say,
"Hey, Porky.
"If I wait for you to
tell me to be the hero,
"then I'm just buying
into your bullshit."
In real life you don't get
chosen. You choose your quest.
And I'm choosing mine. Yeah.
You know, I got magic
back because Quentin died,
and I think I know what
I'm gonna do with it.
I'm gonna figure out what's causing
the apocalypse, and I'm gonna stop it.
When I got to Brakebills, I
thought I'd die before I turned 30.
That's all anyone ever
told me. Travelers die.
And bad shit has happened
to me, but not to you.
Not yet, anyway.
You still get a choice
about your path.
And since I already
talked about the bad side,
I should probably show
you the good side, too.
Anyone who wants
to see that, come here.
Cool. You brought us to rocks.
Look up.
Whoa.
A few years ago, I was
running from some bad shit,
and I found this place.
It's not on any map.
You guys can breathe.
There's no one here. Just us.
Oh, my God.
When you master your powers,
you can wake up anywhere,
in any world.
If you want to still do this, I'll
help you. Just think about it.
For now, I'm gonna shut up
and let you enjoy this place.
Professor Adiyodi?
Merritt, right? Yeah.
I had a question.
You said you heard
voices from other worlds.
You hearing something?
It's not a voice. It's
more like, um, a signal.
Okay. Um... Uh, sit down.
Yeah.
I'm gonna take down my
wards so you can show me.
You just, uh, close
your eyes, okay? Okay.
All right.
Professor?
Oh. Professor, what happened?
I don't... I couldn't
control myself.
Did the signal make you do that?
Hello? Anybody there?
Just great. What are you
gonna do now, Margo?
It's gonna be okay.
It's... Who am I kidding?
They're gonna chop
my goddamn head off.
Josh? Josh. Josh.
Of course I get trapped in here
with the ghost loop version of him.
Margo, wherever you
are, I hope you're okay.
I wish you were here.
I wish I wasn't gonna die alone.
Oh.
Why are you
smoking? I don't know.
Quentin did sometimes.
Can I have one?
You know, you're the only person in
the world who can smoke judgmentally.
I know what you're
going through.
When your father died, I was a
wreck. I didn't know what to do.
I wasn't ready to be alone. I
didn't even know how to be alone.
I did some pretty insane
things just to get by.
Insane even for me. But
I'll spare you the details.
Doesn't sound like you.
Well, I could tell
you, if you prefer.
What's your point, Mom?
That everything's just
gonna get better eventually?
No one gets to tell
you how to grieve, Alice.
You're on this
journey by yourself.
Only you know where
it's gonna take you.
If you need to do something
crazy to get through it,
do something crazy, okay?