QUENTIN: Previously
on The Magicians...
I killed a god.
ALICE: The old gods.
When we're harmless,
they ignore us.
But when we become
malignant, they amputate.
(POWERING DOWN) (PEOPLE GASP)
Magic is gone. I need
to show you something.
Oh, my God.
JULIA: I have magic.
THE GREAT COCK: Do you
want your magic back or not?
I'll send you on an epic quest.
QUENTIN: "The Tale
of the Seven Keys."
Jules, this is our quest.
(MONSTER ROARING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SWALLOWS)
JULIA: I think I'm leveling up.
I'm... A full-on goddess.
You're here about the
fountain? The backdoor to magic.
QUENTIN: Alice,
what are you doing?
KADY: She's destroying the keys!
JULIA: I know you thought
this was for everyone's good.
You'll see someday, it wasn't.
Julia, you could
lose your power.
(SCREAMS)
Once magic is flowing again, you
have 30 seconds to attach the Siphon.
ALICE: I hear you have
an experimental potion
that not only wipes your memory,
but creates a whole new persona.
ZELDA: She made a
deal with us, then broke it.
Unlike the others, she
belongs to the Library.
That thing! It can jump bodies.
It's seen them.
It knows magic is back.
It knows they're
Magicians, even if they don't.
If they don't know who they
are, if they don't have magic,
they can't protect themselves.
Will you play with me?
I think you've got me
mistaken for somebody else.
I think anything is more fun
when you do it with a friend.
(LAUGHING) Feels like there's
never a reason to last that long.
KIMBER: Um, I will catch
you guys tomorrow, yeah?
Okay.
Shit!
(SOFTLY) Shit.
(CHUCKLES) My God.
(SIGHS)
(GATE RATTLING)
Shit.
(SIGHS)
(GRUNTS)
(EXHALES)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Uh, hi. Um, hello. Hi.
Kimber D'Antoni?
Uh-huh.
(COUGHING)
I'm Todd.
You're late.
Follow me.
Uh, I... I'm sorry. Where am I?
Upstate New York.
Brakebills University.
Okay, uh, hold on. How...
Good afternoon. Nice to see you.
How is that possible? Pro tip,
in case you
remember any of this.
Always be polite to Librarians.
They look harmless, but they do
regulate the good stuff, you know?
Make them cranky,
all of a sudden,
there's this lag time
when you put in a request.
I mean, New World Order,
definitely better than it was,
but in my humble "O," a
little worse than the old days.
Okay, uh, stop.
I'm sorry, what's happening?
Oh. You've been offered
a preliminary exam
for entry into the
graduate program.
Am I hallucinating?
I mean, if I say no, that
could be part of it, right?
But, I mean, no.
Um, really, no. Nope.
Okay, yeah.
That definitely
wasn't helpful at all.
So... Sorry.
Come on. We gotta hustle.
Late! (DOOR CLOSES)
Welcome.
You may address me as Dean.
I know you all have questions.
They will be answered in time.
For the next hour, your
task is to complete your test.
Best of luck to you all.
Begin.
PROFESSOR LIPSON:
You know, this would go faster
if we could just do them all
in one batch, like we used to.
You know we don't
have that kind of supply.
Yeah. I'm just saying.
I mean, how many extra
hours of our time is this taking,
when the Library
could just give it to us?
Come on. You know
you're thinking it. (SCOFFS)
Well, looks like the
weird one's a dud.
DEAN: Is she the one you said...
PROFESSOR LIPSON:
Shorted out the globe? Yeah.
Never seen that before.
It was late in the day, no?
Supply runs low.
Could be that.
True.
I'll pull her and wipe her as soon
as she's done the written portion.
(GROANS) Damn it.
What was that?
I'm not quite
sure. Let me see...
I'd advise against it.
I didn't see anything.
I've got a splitting headache.
Okay.
I'll take your word for it.
So, keep or lose the
migraine? Let's keep.
For now.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
SHAYNA: Saw it with my own eyes.
Periplaneta americana.
Huge.
Wow, a cockroach can't
be good for the books.
Exactly.
I'm thinking of posting a
sign to remind everyone
that their mother
doesn't work here
and they should clean
up their own crumbs.
That's funny. Very clever.
Thank you.
Should I use Helvetica
or Times New Roman?
Would Comic Sans
communicate good cheer
or undercut the
seriousness of the message?
(SIGHS)
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
MAN: Even your breathing
is depressing today.
You know that, Alice?
Hey, I have an idea.
Yeah? Yeah, go fuck yourself.
I'm not here to
entertain you. Huh.
If you say so.
'Cause the other day,
when you tried to escape,
that was funny. (SIGHS)
All that kicking and shrieking.
Gives me a big chuckle
every time I think of it.
(SLIDES, THUDS)
(LOCK CLICKS) (DOOR OPENS)
Good day, Miss Quinn.
Lunch.
I thought you had
slaves for that.
Junior Librarians.
I must insist you eat today.
Fine. Insist away.
Ew.
You nosy bitch.
Ah... Excuse me?
You read my book, huh?
Right up to the
great blank spot.
Did you read that whole chapter?
Hmm? You wanna talk
about all the positions
Quentin and I were in?
Did my book tell you
how many times I came?
I can't let you starve and I
don't want to force you to eat.
Neither of us would enjoy that.
Keep cooperating and
you may continue to receive
approved reading material.
Wait.
(SIGHS) I have a question.
I'm sorry.
Dean Fogg's not coming.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Dean Fogg.
The new students?
Appreciate you coming all
the way here to deliver this.
Yes, well, you did...
What's the word?
Mandate that I do so.
A formality.
We have the utmost faith
in your selection methods.
This is merely for our records.
Hmm.
(SIGHS) This one.
Professor Lipson reported
she caused an unusual reaction
on your globe.
Do you know why?
I'm sure it'll become clear.
She shows great potential.
In what way?
I'm not sure yet,
but that's why
she's at Brakebills.
Well, I trust your instinct.
Approved.
Always a pleasure.
(SIGHS)
Alice is fine.
Depressed, surly.
Still asking to see you again.
She's fixated on the thing
she says she saw in the castle.
You told her, didn't you?
That your
independent contractors
are looking into
the threat, yes,
but she's not worried
about mass destruction.
She's worried about her friends.
I can't think of anyone
better protected than they.
DEAN: Let's be frank, Zelda.
My students saved magic.
The world may throw
flowers at the feet of The Order
and Irene McAllistair,
but you and I both
know the goddamn truth.
The Order stepped into
an oversight position.
Everything we do is to preserve
knowledge, to make things safer.
I'm not arguing the benefits.
But you are, because
they come at a cost.
Bottom line, if your
students resurface,
I can't stop Irene from
doing what she will
to ensure their silence.
We have certain
agreements with her as well.
So...
They must stay where
they are, as they are.
They'll be fine.
Your spellwork was masterful.
You know my one solace, Zelda?
When my attempts to protect them
inevitably fail,
their blood will
be on your hands.
(SINGING) Take your time with me
I need to feel alive
Have a good day, Zelda.
(DEAN CLEARS THROAT)
(SIGHS)
SAM: Don't tell me
to relax. I'm pissed.
Okay. I get it.
But you're overreacting.
I should throw this at you.
Sam, come on.
You made three
very strong arrests.
And this douchewater just
walks away, based on what?
Explain that to me.
That douchewater
always gets away.
What are you talking about?
Seen him booked six times.
Never sticks.
Hey, what can I say?
Some people are lucky.
(CHUCKLES) Or their lawyers
are. My advice is, let it go.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
(PANTING)
(SHOP BELL TINKLING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
SHOP OWNER: Uh, excuse me, miss?
Can I help you?
That guy.
He was just here.
Uh, I must not have heard.
Have a good day, sir.
Hmm...
(SIGHS)
(MOUSE SCROLLING)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
"Hedge witch."
Oh, shit.
Oh, come on.
(BANGING)
Piece of shit.
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
Damn it.
(SCOFFS)
Get your shit
together, Cunningham.
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(EXPLODES)
Shit!
(SIGHS) Of course.
(WHISPERING) Seattle graffiti.
(NOTIFICATION CHIMES)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(GRUNTS)
Hi, Mark.
Listen, I know you're a cop.
Yeah, and, uh, I
know what you are.
I was just, uh, leaving.
Yeah, I've noticed
you're good at that.
Six arrests,
nothing ever sticks.
Look, I don't hurt anyone.
It's all strictly side hustle.
Cut the shit.
I know there's more of you.
That you call yourself, what? Hedge
witches? (HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
What the hell?
I'm not selling anything
that's gonna hurt anyone.
Minor shit. Charms,
enhancements.
Nothing dark and...
Look, I have no interest
in poking whatever kind
of witness-protection spell
you've got going, okay?
That thing tried to
kill me for looking at it.
What are you talking about?
Charms, enchantments.
What, is that French
for "crystal meth"?
You have no idea, do you?
You just think you're you.
Not so fast.
What is that?
Spelling bee medal?
Give that back. What is it?
Protection.
From? You.
Wait, stop!
(HORN BLOWS)
EMBER: Yoo-hoo!
Arise, Your Majesty.
Arise.
What the hell?
EMBER: You may
approach, High King.
Come, come.
Let's take a look at you.
Hi.
What the fuck is going on?
Hmm.
It's a little bit worrying
that you don't seem
to know, considering.
"Considering"?
Are those horns?
Wait.
Am I at Jeff Goldblum's
house right now?
What did I take?
EMBER: You are asleep.
I, Ember, greatest-ever
god of Fillory,
am blessing a
visitation of my person
on your prone
and receptive state.
Well, more technically,
I, an energetic emanation
previously placed here
by the great god, Ember,
have been activated
to contact you.
"Activated."
Activated,
by a disturbance of great
magnitude. (MEOWING)
Alarums, Majesty!
I have emanated to warn you.
Great ill is afoot.
Okay.
We're gonna have to take
this from the top, all right?
Because I literally
haven't been this confused
since the time I woke
up in bed with Banksy.
This is concerning.
Which part?
For one thing, you
look awfully like
a female.
It's chilling.
No matter.
You must get to work
immediately, High King.
Great, sure.
Work on?
Well, this glorious emanation
can only be
triggered by world war,
pandemic, arrival of hostile
or uninvited gods
onto Fillorian soil,
revolt of dwarves, or
mass rising of the dead.
Not sure they'd be able
to do much, the dead.
They're sort of
feeble and rotting.
It just struck me as creepy,
and I'd rather
you put a stop to it.
Okay, horn person?
My name is Janet.
I'm not a king.
I'm an editor, a fashion editor.
You're not even wearing pants.
I don't think this
message is for me.
Wait.
I am Ember, you
insolent, little Janet.
There is no walking away.
Only doing what I say. Quickly.
I'm telling you, I
don't know what...
Fix this now!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Fuck me.
(SIGHS)
Fuck it. (SCOFFS)
Okay.
(SIGHS)
(TYPING)
(MOUSE SCROLLING)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
What?
What the...
Fuck!
The color correction on this
model is so bad, it's racist.
Set a call.
Did Dr. Liu call back?
Yes, he said that all
the tests were normal.
My eye is weird.
Colors are weird.
How is that normal, Sophie?
Well, uh, he suggested this,
and he says he can
see you next week
if the problem doesn't resolve.
Next week?
Perfect.
Well,
now I've definitely seen
this year's ugliest accessory.
It... It was the
only one they had.
JANET: I'll deal with it.
It's fine.
Oh, and Sophie.
SOPHIE: Mmm-hmm.
Did you order
those books for me?
Fillory and Further.
Oh, um, The Amazon account
locked me out, and... Sorry, I...
I'm calling around, but
bookstores are sold out of it.
I'll keep trying.
That was a lot of words.
Just get it done.
(JANET SQUEALS)
Hey! (GRUNTS)
What the hell?
Janet Pluchinsky?
Am I under arrest? No.
Well, what's going on, then?
And why are you wearing that
ridiculous spelling bee medal?
It's a magical amulet. Mmm.
Look, I am not crazy, okay?
There's something
you need to know,
and as soon as I start
telling you about this,
bad shit is gonna
start flying at our heads,
and this helps.
But not completely.
That makes no sense.
Would you just keep your mind
open for two seconds, okay?
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
My name is Sam Cunningham.
I'm a narcotics officer
with the Seattle PD.
Flip to Chapter 3.
It's your life.
And mine.
(GLASS BREAKS)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING STOPS)
Look, this medal thing,
it has some sort of...
I don't know what to call
it... Like, a field of effect,
and it is bouncing
shit away from us.
I'm sorry, do... Do
you hear yourself?
Tell me things haven't
been weird for you lately.
Well... Something
was done to us.
This guy, he told
me that he is a witch.
I know how that
sounds, but he was real.
And, okay... And I
know how that sounds.
Just spit it out.
He told me that I wasn't me.
That this
wasn't my identity.
And then I found this.
Well, I've never
heard of this book.
It's super obscure,
but my whole life is in it.
My parents, the Academy,
my last shitty boyfriend.
"Janet Pluchinsky
"had stabbed her way to
the accessory editor's desk."
That's a dumb way of putting it.
The writing isn't award-winning.
And my boobs look
insane in this drawing.
A man wrote this, correct?
Correct, but the details.
Did you have a pet sugar
glider when you were eight?
Ate white cheddar popcorn
with Tabasco for breakfast?
You have a dedicated closet
for wigs and fetish underwear?
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(GLASS BREAKING)
(BOTH SCREAMING)
SAM: Shit. Come on!
(JANET SCREAMING)
It's okay.
What the hell?
I don't know, but there
are other characters
that are out there, too.
Look, I think we
need to find them.
(JANET SCREAMING) Let's
get the fuck out of here! Come on!
MAN: Hey.
Hey.
I know you're not sleeping.
Go away. MAN: Love to.
Locked in a cell.
Look, uh...
I'm not good at comforting,
but for what it's worth,
it's gonna be okay.
ALICE: No, don't
lie. MAN: I'm not.
I've been where you are.
Did I ever tell you why
they locked me up?
Talking too much?
I was obsessed with
perfecting this spell.
You ever hear of Diogenes?
Yeah, sad-sack philosopher
with a lantern, in search
of one honest man.
MAN: I was finishing his
work to find good people.
Why?
MAN: Feel less alone.
Biggest obstacle being that
almost no good people exist.
(SCOFFS) Anyway,
I kept refining it
and I realized that I
had to focus on children,
because sometimes, they're
not rotten to the core yet.
Anyway, that's all I wanted,
was to find some good kids
and in some small
way, reward them.
Come to a point where
I needed this book.
Restricted.
They kept it in a
place they call, uh...
The Poison Room.
Yeah, killed one of my friends.
MAN: Yeah.
It killed some of mine, too.
I was working with
these elf gentlemen.
Uh, it was bad.
Elves... Elves are real?
Sweet guys.
All that weird sex stuff
you hear about is
only partially true.
Anyway, the Library
came after me.
Possession, murder
on Library property,
like I personally
murdered anyone.
Please.
Great.
A spell that rewards
good children,
and you and your elves...
That was a long time ago.
Are you Santa Claus?
Well... (SIGHS)
Well, I'm not, not that.
But I don't like that name.
It got very commercial,
very shopping-mall.
Look, just call
me Nick, asshole.
(CHUCKLES)
NICK: I tried to
escape early on.
Ended up lost in the stacks.
They found me, of course,
and that's when I
tried to kill myself.
Really?
How... How did you
cast in your room?
I can't do any magic.
NICK: Of course you can't.
I mean, the entire cell is
coated with deadening paint.
I mean, you'd have to
scrape off an entire wall
to get anywhere. How?
NICK: Uh, I did it the
old-fashioned way.
I pulled the edge
off of my food tray.
Uh, well, the point is...
Is that I'm glad I'm not dead.
I'm not gonna die in here.
And neither are you.
We're both smart.
We'll figure it out.
Why do you care?
Okay.
(SIGHS) Christmas 2004.
The pink diary that your parents
thought your brother
got you and vice versa...
Wait, are you saying
that that was you?
Alice, you are good.
You're nice.
Honestly, most
kids as smart as you
were naughty as shit.
I... I know
you hurt people
and you think that
means you should hurt.
But I know.
I know you are not a bad person.
Promise me.
Promise me you'll hang in there.
(SIGHS) I promise,
Santa. (CHUCKLES)
Hey! Help! Guard! Help! Help!
Alice!
Help!
Somebody, help!
Help me! Over here!
Here! Alice!
Alice!
Help! Help! ZELDA: Alice?
We need help in here!
Alice! Help!
Alice.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(GRUNTS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
ZELDA: I should
have seen this coming.
You're here because
you knowingly
broke a contract with The Order.
Not for causing what
happened to your friends.
You didn't cause that.
They made their own choice.
I know
something about guilt.
You wonder why I care.
After all, you
betrayed The Order.
You probably think
I've singled you
out for punishment.
I did single you out.
For rehabilitation.
You have the
makings of a Master.
You could go further
than anyone you know.
Fogg, your father, Mayakovsky.
That can happen
here. There's work.
Some in your situation
may be invited to participate,
and then...
This isn't a prison,
because what could
be more fulfilling
than immersion in the
great work of The Order?
I know you hate this place.
Given what you
did to those keys,
I gather you hate
magic itself, so...
I won't ask
until you're ready.
I hope that day comes.
I'm also not going
to let you kill yourself.
Don't try that again.
The wounds should be healed.
Rona will bring you
back to your room.
(RETCHES)
NICK: I thought you were smart.
That was so stupid.
Sorry if I scared you.
No, you didn't scare me.
You disappointed
the shit out of me,
you histrionic little idiot.
I thought you were strong.
ALICE: I don't know
why you would think that.
(SCOFFS)
Uh, well, yeah, me neither.
Look, I wasn't
trying to kill myself.
Really?
Look, I was just
trying to figure out
a way out of here,
and I think that...
(SIGHS)
I... I just need to think.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
DEAN: Kim.
Have a seat. (KIM SIGHS)
Um...
I just wanted to talk to
you about my progress.
See, everyone got
their discipline today.
Oh, yes. Always
an interesting day.
Except for me. (CHUCKLES)
I heard.
It's not super
surprising, given the fact
that I haven't been able to
do a single piece of magic.
DEAN: Well, so far. (CHUCKLES)
Heard that as well.
They're calling me a squib.
I even heard Professor Lipson
say it when she thought
I was out of the room.
Ah, I'll talk to her about that.
We discourage that term.
It's considered hate speech.
I mean, but don't you agree?
Do you?
Well, I...
I mean, I think I got
the highest math scores
in the history of
my high school,
and I graduated Harvard
on my 19th birthday.
Who didn't? (CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
I... I'm just saying, I...
Look, of course I
want to keep trying.
It's like
the moment that I
found out magic was real,
that was the moment
that I discovered who I am.
You remind me of a
young woman I once knew.
Similar tenacious mind.
I rejected her from Brakebills.
Why?
Suffice to say,
I had much evidence I
was doing the right thing,
but out on her own,
she got hurt, badly.
I had chosen not to protect her.
I'm simply not willing to repeat
that choice with you.
So,
patience.
ISAAC: Magic is real.
(LAUGHING) Magic is real!
HANSEL: This is the
trippiest thing I have ever seen.
I gotta say, you're
taking this pretty well.
Well, you know,
it's all an illusion.
The Grand Maya.
Right, yeah.
The Grand Maya. Of course, man.
Can I just say one thing?
I cannot believe... SAM: Hey.
You're DJ Hansel.
Stay close, okay?
This medal thing, it works
better the closer you are.
I've been listening to your
Taylor Swift remix nonstop.
Is it true that you
guys hooked up?
SOPHIE: Um, Janet? (GASPS)
Sorry. You always do that.
I was just wondering
what you want me to say
about all these plane tickets.
I don't want you
to say anything.
I want you to expense them.
Oh, well, it's just that they
don't usually allow so many.
Yeah, huge feature, okay?
That's DJ Hansel.
Hey, how you doing?
JANET: Yeah,
these are his minions.
Put that, okay?
And lattes, Sophie,
from the other place.
You know, the one
that... The little thing I like.
Okay, okay. Yeah, yeah, and...
And almond milk,
please, if you don't mind.
She's young. I'm
working with her.
HANSEL: You were
Now, who knows?
Who knows anything? (CHUCKLES)
Right, 'cause magic
is real. You know?
Literally. Like in movies, except
literally real. (HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
JANET: So, no one can
find Kim, the architect,
Nigel, the bastard
son of a British lord,
was reported
missing by his family,
and Brian, the
English professor,
also reported missing.
Not worrying, not worrying.
Or another way to look at it
is that the whole
goddamn thing is worrying
and no one thing is any
more or less worrying
than anything else.
Whoa, whoa, hey, hey,
hey. (RINGING STOPS)
You need breath work, man.
So, how do we figure out who we
really... (HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
Oh, don't say it.
Shh. (TRILLING STOPS)
Okay, just...
I don't know how we're
supposed to talk about this
if we're not allowed
to talk about this.
HANSEL: Yeah, I
mean, shouldn't all of us
being in a room
together be enough to...
I don't know, I
mean... Okay, look.
Apparently, you have to
poke the fake ID aspect
of the situation
pretty directly.
Okay, just talk around it, okay?
Okay, okay, okay. Okay,
okay, okay, okay, okay.
I say we find the writer
of this comic book, right?
James Tiberius R. Martin
is clearly a pen name,
but whoever he is, maybe he
knows something that can help us.
Yeah, but... But that
was written 14 years ago.
I mean, what does
that even mean?
Because I have
memories from before,
but they're not really mine because
I'm... (HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Never mind!
Never mind, I said!
Oh, God.
You know, the guy
that got hit by a truck...
Did he die? He's
still in the hospital.
Well, if he's alive,
then we can ask
him some questions.
MARINA: (SIGHS)
I wish you wouldn't.
I really feel you've
done enough for him.
Hi.
I'm Marina.
You almost killed a
good friend of mine
and stole that from him,
which he was borrowing.
So, really, you
stole it from me.
Okay, relax.
I'm here to help.
(LIVELY MUSIC PLAYING)
Are you even listening?
Yeah, of course. Of course I am.
We should get you cleaned up.
You've got so much blood
on you from that boring waiter.
Anyway, we'll have to
do it once we get there.
We have to hurry now.
Where... Where are we going?
Scoop of pistachio with jimmies.
I said I wanted sprinkles.
Jimmies are sprinkles.
No, stop that,
jimmies are sprinkles!
(GROANS)
Mmm, Jimmies are sprinkles.
Anyway, Greece. A temple.
He'll be there for his transit.
It's the only time to catch him.
Flay that bastard's
flesh clean off his bones.
Oh, remind me to get a coat.
Am I remembering
you kill these little bodies
if you get them too cold?
Hey, is there another
game that we can play?
One where we don't flay anybody?
Oh, but he deserves it,
sad little man we
are calling Brian.
Why? What did he do? He knows.
Just like how all your
friends know, too.
Friends? What... What friends?
But we can't talk about
it, Brian-Not-Brian.
Your glamour gets very angry
if I even say your
name too much.
Look, it's better you have
no idea what I'm talking about.
These friends, I'm
going to kill them,
and we have to assume it's
going to happen in front of you.
It will hurt less if you
don't know who they are.
I like you.
Make yourselves at home.
HANSEL: Nice digs. Thank you.
I worked really
hard to steal them.
What is that?
(SIGHS) Protection.
From?
Whatever the hell's
going on with you people.
Well, I didn't say
you could move in.
Come on, let's go.
All right. (SIGHS)
Well, we know it's big.
Big magic.
Well, okay.
We know that you don't
know what the fuck it is.
That's fun.
And we know if we poke it,
it pokes us back with a truck.
Oh, wow. (CHUCKLES)
Now I know how the
gold prospectors felt.
It's just dripping off you.
And you have no
idea what that means.
That's fine.
You're all just very, very,
extremely juiced up
on a level that's,
quite frankly,
not legal these days.
I'm just a little curious
how you all got like this.
You... You and us both.
Okay, let's take a
peek underneath
and see what
you really look like.
I don't think that
whatever that is...
Spell, illusion,
charm, whatever.
Yeah, I don't think
it's gonna let you.
Relax, sweetie.
This place is
warded up to the vag,
and I'm very good... Hey.
At what I do.
Just hold still.
So, you're like some
powerful, benevolent
white witch?
Uh-huh.
Well, that's good.
(CHANTING SPELL)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTING)
(ALL COUGHING)
(GASPING)
(COUGHING)
(TAPPING)
What in creation is the
matter with you, High King?
Where to start with that?
EMBER: Is this our little game?
I have to ask you
to do things twice
because you're such a
handsome king. (LAUGHS)
Enough flirtation.
It's unseemly that a
simulacrum of this magnificence
should be bothered
so repeatedly.
Fix it.
Fix what?
I don't know what
you want me to fix!
Whatever the matter is
in Fillory, you simple boy!
Find the bother.
Find it, fix it.
A, fuck you.
B, I'm not in Fillory.
What?
I'm in New York City, along
with everyone else that matters.
Fillory is fiction.
It's a kid's book. Why
didn't you say so?
Time to wake up, High King.
Many blessings.
(JANET GASPS)
(COUGHING)
Guys?
Sam?
Hansel?
What the high holy Jesus freak?
Wake up. Wake up.
Wake up.
Wake the fuck up!
Wake up!
Fuck!
Hello?