QUENTIN: Previously on
The Magicians...
- I killed a god.
- ALICE: The old gods.
When we're harmless,
they ignore us.
But when we become malignant,
they amputate.
- (POWERING DOWN)
- (PEOPLE GASP)
- Magic is gone.
- I need to show you something.
Oh, my God.
JULIA: I have magic.
THE GREAT COCK: Do you want
your magic back or not?
I'll send you
on an epic quest.
QUENTIN:
"The Tale of the Seven Keys."
Jules, this is our quest.
- (MONSTER ROARING)
- (ALL SCREAMING)
(SWALLOWS)
JULIA:
I think I'm leveling up.
- I'm...
- A full-on goddess.
You're here about the fountain?
The backdoor to magic.
QUENTIN: Alice,
what are you doing?
KADY:
She's destroying the keys!
JULIA: I know you thought
this was for everyone's good.
You'll see someday, it wasn't.
Julia, you could
lose your power.
(SCREAMS)
Once magic is flowing again,
you have 30 seconds to attach the Siphon.
ALICE: I hear you have
an experimental potion
that not only
wipes your memory,
but creates
a whole new persona.
ZELDA: She made
a deal with us, then broke it.
Unlike the others,
she belongs to the Library.
That thing!
It can jump bodies.
It's seen them.
It knows magic is back.
It knows they're Magicians,
even if they don't.
If they don't know who they are,
if they don't have magic,
they can't protect themselves.
Will you play with me?
I think you've got me mistaken
for somebody else.
I think anything is more fun
when you do it with a friend.
(LAUGHING) Feels like there's never
a reason to last that long.
KIMBER: Um, I will
catch you guys tomorrow, yeah?
Okay.
Shit!
(SOFTLY) Shit.
(CHUCKLES) My God.
(SIGHS)
(GATE RATTLING)
Shit.
(SIGHS)
(GRUNTS)
(EXHALES)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Uh, hi. Um, hello. Hi.
Kimber D'Antoni?
Uh-huh.
(COUGHING)
I'm Todd.
You're late.
Follow me.
Uh, I... I'm sorry.
Where am I?
Upstate New York.
- Brakebills University.
- Okay, uh, hold on. How...
Good afternoon.
Nice to see you.
- How is that possible?
- Pro tip,
in case you remember
any of this.
Always be polite
to Librarians.
They look harmless, but they do
regulate the good stuff, you know?
Make them cranky,
all of a sudden,
there's this lag time
when you put in a request.
I mean, New World Order,
definitely better than it was,
but in my humble "O,"
a little worse than the old days.
Okay, uh, stop.
I'm sorry,
what's happening?
Oh. You've been offered
a preliminary exam
for entry
into the graduate program.
Am I hallucinating?
I mean, if I say no,
that could be part of it, right?
But, I mean, no.
Um, really, no. Nope.
Okay, yeah.
That definitely
wasn't helpful at all.
- So...
- Sorry.
Come on. We gotta hustle.
- Late!
- (DOOR CLOSES)
Welcome.
You may address me as Dean.
I know you all
have questions.
They will be answered in time.
For the next hour,
your task is to complete your test.
Best of luck to you all.
Begin.
PROFESSOR LIPSON: You know,
this would go faster
if we could just do them all
in one batch, like we used to.
You know we don't have
that kind of supply.
Yeah. I'm just saying.
I mean, how many extra hours
of our time is this taking,
when the Library
could just give it to us?
Come on. You know
you're thinking it. (SCOFFS)
Well, looks like
the weird one's a dud.
DEAN:
Is she the one you said...
PROFESSOR LIPSON:
Shorted out the globe? Yeah.
Never seen that before.
It was late
in the day, no?
Supply runs low.
Could be that.
True.
I'll pull her and wipe her as soon
as she's done the written portion.
(GROANS) Damn it.
What was that?
- I'm not quite sure.
- Let me see...
I'd advise against it.
I didn't see anything.
I've got
a splitting headache.
Okay.
I'll take your word for it.
- So, keep or lose the migraine?
- Let's keep.
For now.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
SHAYNA: Saw it
with my own eyes.
Periplaneta americana.
Huge.
Wow, a cockroach
can't be good for the books.
Exactly.
I'm thinking of posting a sign
to remind everyone
that their mother
doesn't work here
and they should clean up
their own crumbs.
That's funny.
Very clever.
Thank you.
Should I use Helvetica
or Times New Roman?
Would Comic Sans
communicate good cheer
or undercut the seriousness
of the message?
(SIGHS)
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
MAN: Even your breathing
is depressing today.
You know that, Alice?
Hey, I have an idea.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, go fuck yourself.
- I'm not here to entertain you.
- Huh.
If you say so.
'Cause the other day,
when you tried to escape,
- that was funny.
- (SIGHS)
All that kicking
and shrieking.
Gives me a big chuckle
every time I think of it.
(SLIDES, THUDS)
- (LOCK CLICKS)
- (DOOR OPENS)
Good day, Miss Quinn.
Lunch.
I thought you had
slaves for that.
Junior Librarians.
I must insist you eat today.
Fine. Insist away.
Ew.
You nosy bitch.
Ah... Excuse me?
You read my book, huh?
Right up
to the great blank spot.
Did you read
that whole chapter?
Hmm? You wanna talk about
all the positions
Quentin and I were in?
Did my book tell you
how many times I came?
I can't let you starve
and I don't want to force you to eat.
Neither of us
would enjoy that.
Keep cooperating and you
may continue to receive
approved reading material.
Wait.
(SIGHS) I have a question.
I'm sorry.
Dean Fogg's not coming.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Dean Fogg.
The new students?
Appreciate you coming
all the way here to deliver this.
Yes, well, you did...
What's the word?
Mandate that I do so.
A formality.
We have the utmost faith
in your selection methods.
This is merely
for our records.
Hmm.
- (SIGHS)
- This one.
Professor Lipson reported
she caused an unusual reaction
on your globe.
Do you know why?
I'm sure it'll become clear.
She shows great potential.
In what way?
I'm not sure yet,
but that's why
she's at Brakebills.
Well, I trust your instinct.
Approved.
Always a pleasure.
(SIGHS)
Alice is fine.
Depressed, surly.
Still asking to see you again.
She's fixated on the thing
she says she saw
in the castle.
You told her, didn't you?
That your
independent contractors
are looking
into the threat, yes,
but she's not worried
about mass destruction.
She's worried
about her friends.
I can't think of anyone
better protected than they.
DEAN: Let's be frank, Zelda.
My students saved magic.
The world may throw flowers
at the feet of The Order
and Irene McAllistair,
but you and I both know
the goddamn truth.
The Order stepped
into an oversight position.
Everything we do is to preserve knowledge,
to make things safer.
I'm not arguing the benefits.
But you are,
because they come at a cost.
Bottom line,
if your students resurface,
I can't stop Irene
from doing what she will
to ensure their silence.
We have certain
agreements with her as well.
So...
They must stay where they are,
as they are.
They'll be fine.
Your spellwork was masterful.
You know my one solace, Zelda?
When my attempts
to protect them
inevitably fail,
their blood will be
on your hands.
(SINGING)
Take your time with me
I need to feel alive
Have a good day, Zelda.
(DEAN CLEARS THROAT)
(SIGHS)
SAM: Don't tell me to relax.
I'm pissed.
Okay. I get it.
- But you're overreacting.
- I should throw this at you.
Sam, come on.
You made
three very strong arrests.
And this douchewater just walks away,
based on what?
Explain that to me.
That douchewater
always gets away.
What are you talking about?
Seen him booked six times.
Never sticks.
Hey, what can I say?
Some people are lucky.
(CHUCKLES) Or their lawyers are.
My advice is, let it go.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING
INDISTINCTLY)
(PANTING)
(SHOP BELL TINKLING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
SHOP OWNER:
Uh, excuse me, miss?
Can I help you?
That guy.
He was just here.
Uh, I must not have heard.
Have a good day, sir.
Hmm...
(SIGHS)
(MOUSE SCROLLING)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
"Hedge witch."
Oh, shit.
Oh, come on.
(BANGING)
Piece of shit.
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
Damn it.
(SCOFFS)
Get your shit together,
Cunningham.
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(EXPLODES)
Shit!
(SIGHS) Of course.
(WHISPERING)
Seattle graffiti.
(NOTIFICATION CHIMES)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(GRUNTS)
Hi, Mark.
Listen, I know you're a cop.
Yeah, and, uh, I know
what you are.
I was just, uh, leaving.
Yeah, I've noticed
you're good at that.
Six arrests,
nothing ever sticks.
Look, I don't hurt anyone.
It's all strictly side hustle.
Cut the shit.
I know there's more of you.
- That you call yourself, what? Hedge witches?
- (HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
What the hell?
I'm not selling anything
that's gonna hurt anyone.
Minor shit. Charms,
enhancements.
Nothing dark and...
Look, I have no interest
in poking whatever kind
of witness-protection spell
you've got going, okay?
That thing tried to kill me
for looking at it.
What are you talking about?
Charms, enchantments.
What, is that French for
"crystal meth"?
You have no idea, do you?
You just think you're you.
Not so fast.
What is that?
Spelling bee medal?
- Give that back.
- What is it?
Protection.
- From?
- You.
Wait, stop!
(HORN BLOWS)
EMBER: Yoo-hoo!
Arise, Your Majesty.
Arise.
What the hell?
EMBER: You may approach,
High King.
Come, come.
Let's take a look at you.
Hi.
What the fuck is going on?
Hmm.
It's a little bit worrying
that you don't seem
to know, considering.
"Considering"?
Are those horns?
Wait.
Am I at Jeff Goldblum's
house right now?
What did I take?
EMBER: You are asleep.
I, Ember, greatest-ever
god of Fillory,
am blessing a visitation
of my person
on your prone
and receptive state.
Well, more technically,
I, an energetic emanation
previously placed here
by the great god, Ember,
have been activated
to contact you.
"Activated."
Activated,
- by a disturbance of great magnitude.
- (MEOWING)
Alarums, Majesty!
I have emanated to warn you.
Great ill is afoot.
Okay.
We're gonna have to take this
from the top, all right?
Because I literally
haven't been this confused
since the time I woke up
in bed with Banksy.
This is concerning.
Which part?
For one thing, you look
awfully like
a female.
It's chilling.
No matter.
You must get to work
immediately, High King.
Great, sure.
Work on?
Well, this glorious emanation
can only be triggered
by world war,
pandemic,
arrival of hostile
or uninvited gods
onto Fillorian soil,
revolt of dwarves,
or mass rising of the dead.
Not sure they'd be able
to do much, the dead.
They're sort of
feeble and rotting.
It just struck me as creepy,
and I'd rather
you put a stop to it.
Okay, horn person?
My name is Janet.
I'm not a king.
I'm an editor,
a fashion editor.
You're not even
wearing pants.
I don't think this message
is for me.
Wait.
I am Ember, you insolent,
little Janet.
There is no walking away.
Only doing what
I say. Quickly.
I'm telling you,
I don't know what...
Fix this now!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Fuck me.
(SIGHS)
Fuck it. (SCOFFS)
Okay.
(SIGHS)
(TYPING)
(MOUSE SCROLLING)
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
What?
What the...
Fuck!
The color correction on this
model is so bad, it's racist.
Set a call.
Did Dr. Liu call back?
Yes, he said that
all the tests were normal.
My eye is weird.
Colors are weird.
How is that normal, Sophie?
Well, uh, he suggested this,
and he says he can
see you next week
if the problem
doesn't resolve.
Next week?
Perfect.
Well,
now I've definitely seen
this year's ugliest accessory.
It... It was the only one
they had.
JANET: I'll deal with it.
It's fine.
Oh, and Sophie.
SOPHIE: Mmm-hmm.
Did you order
those books for me?
Fillory and Further.
Oh, um, The Amazon account
locked me out, and... Sorry, I...
I'm calling around, but
bookstores are sold out of it.
I'll keep trying.
That was a lot of words.
Just get it done.
(JANET SQUEALS)
Hey! (GRUNTS)
What the hell?
Janet Pluchinsky?
- Am I under arrest?
- No.
Well, what's going on, then?
And why are you wearing that
ridiculous spelling bee medal?
- It's a magical amulet.
- Mmm.
Look, I am not crazy, okay?
There's something
you need to know,
and as soon as I start
telling you about this,
bad shit is gonna start
flying at our heads,
and this helps.
But not completely.
That makes no sense.
Would you just keep your mind
open for two seconds, okay?
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
My name is Sam Cunningham.
I'm a narcotics officer
with the Seattle PD.
Flip to Chapter 3.
It's your life.
And mine.
- (GLASS BREAKS)
- (HIGH-PITCHED RINGING STOPS)
Look, this medal thing,
it has some sort of...
I don't know what to call it...
Like, a field of effect,
and it is bouncing
shit away from us.
I'm sorry, do...
Do you hear yourself?
Tell me things haven't
been weird for you lately.
- Well...
- Something was done to us.
This guy, he told me
that he is a witch.
I know how that sounds,
but he was real.
And, okay... And I know
how that sounds.
Just spit it out.
He told me that I wasn't me.
That this
wasn't my identity.
And then I found this.
Well, I've never heard
of this book.
It's super obscure,
but my whole life is in it.
My parents, the Academy,
my last shitty boyfriend.
"Janet Pluchinsky
"had stabbed her way to
the accessory editor's desk."
That's a dumb way
of putting it.
The writing
isn't award-winning.
And my boobs look
insane in this drawing.
A man wrote this, correct?
Correct, but the details.
Did you have a pet sugar glider
when you were eight?
Ate white cheddar popcorn
with Tabasco for breakfast?
You have a dedicated closet
for wigs and fetish underwear?
(HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
- (GLASS BREAKING)
- (BOTH SCREAMING)
SAM: Shit. Come on!
(JANET SCREAMING)
It's okay.
What the hell?
I don't know,
but there are other characters
that are out there, too.
Look, I think we need
to find them.
- (JANET SCREAMING)
- Let's get the fuck out of here! Come on!
MAN: Hey.
Hey.
I know you're not sleeping.
- Go away.
- MAN: Love to.
Locked in a cell.
Look, uh...
I'm not good at comforting,
but for what it's worth,
it's gonna be okay.
- ALICE: No, don't lie.
- MAN: I'm not.
I've been where you are.
Did I ever tell you
why they locked me up?
Talking too much?
I was obsessed with
perfecting this spell.
You ever hear of Diogenes?
Yeah, sad-sack philosopher
with a lantern, in search
of one honest man.
MAN: I was finishing his work
to find good people.
Why?
MAN: Feel less alone.
Biggest obstacle being that
almost no good people exist.
(SCOFFS) Anyway,
I kept refining it
and I realized that
I had to focus on children,
because sometimes, they're
not rotten to the core yet.
Anyway,
that's all I wanted,
was to find some good kids
and in some small way,
reward them.
Come to a point
where I needed this book.
Restricted.
They kept it in a place
they call, uh...
The Poison Room.
Yeah, killed one
of my friends.
MAN: Yeah.
It killed some
of mine, too.
I was working
with these elf gentlemen.
Uh, it was bad.
Elves...
Elves are real?
Sweet guys.
All that weird sex stuff
you hear about
is only partially true.
Anyway, the Library
came after me.
Possession, murder
on Library property,
like I personally
murdered anyone.
Please.
Great.
A spell that rewards
good children,
and you and your
elves...
That was a long time ago.
Are you Santa Claus?
Well... (SIGHS)
Well, I'm not, not that.
But I don't like that name.
It got very commercial,
very shopping-mall.
Look, just call me Nick,
asshole.
(CHUCKLES)
NICK: I tried to escape
early on.
Ended up lost in the stacks.
They found me, of course,
and that's when
I tried to kill myself.
Really?
How... How did you
cast in your room?
- I can't do any magic.
- NICK: Of course you can't.
I mean, the entire cell
is coated with deadening paint.
I mean, you'd have
to scrape off an entire wall
- to get anywhere.
- How?
NICK: Uh, I did it
the old-fashioned way.
I pulled the edge off
of my food tray.
Uh, well, the point is...
Is that I'm glad
I'm not dead.
I'm not gonna die in here.
And neither are you.
We're both smart.
We'll figure it out.
Why do you care?
Okay.
(SIGHS) Christmas 2004.
The pink diary
that your parents
thought your brother
got you and vice versa...
Wait, are you saying that
that was you?
Alice, you are good.
You're nice.
Honestly, most kids
as smart as you
were naughty as shit.
I... I know
you hurt people
and you think that means
you should hurt.
But I know.
I know you are
not a bad person.
Promise me.
Promise me
you'll hang in there.
(SIGHS) I promise,
Santa. (CHUCKLES)
Hey! Help!
Guard! Help! Help!
Alice!
Help!
Somebody, help!
Help me! Over here!
Here! Alice!
Alice!
- Help! Help!
- ZELDA: Alice?
We need help in here!
Alice! Help!
Alice.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(GRUNTS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
ZELDA: I should have
seen this coming.
You're here
because you knowingly
broke a contract
with The Order.
Not for causing what
happened to your friends.
You didn't cause that.
They made their own choice.
I know
something about guilt.
You wonder why I care.
After all, you betrayed
The Order.
You probably think
I've singled you out
for punishment.
I did single you out.
For rehabilitation.
You have the makings
of a Master.
You could go further
than anyone you know.
Fogg, your father,
Mayakovsky.
That can happen here.
There's work.
Some in your situation
may be invited to participate,
and then...
This isn't a prison,
because what could
be more fulfilling
than immersion in
the great work of The Order?
I know you hate this place.
Given what you
did to those keys,
I gather you hate
magic itself, so...
I won't ask
until you're ready.
I hope that day comes.
I'm also not going
to let you kill yourself.
Don't try that again.
The wounds should be healed.
Rona will bring you
back to your room.
(RETCHES)
NICK: I thought
you were smart.
That was so stupid.
Sorry if I scared you.
No, you didn't scare me.
You disappointed
the shit out of me,
you histrionic little idiot.
I thought you were strong.
ALICE: I don't know
why you would think that.
(SCOFFS)
Uh, well, yeah, me neither.
Look, I wasn't trying
to kill myself.
Really?
Look, I was just
trying to figure out
a way out of here,
and I think that...
(SIGHS)
I... I just need to think.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
DEAN: Kim.
- Have a seat.
- (KIM SIGHS)
Um...
I just wanted to talk
to you about my progress.
See, everyone got their
discipline today.
Oh, yes. Always an
interesting day.
Except for me. (CHUCKLES)
I heard.
It's not super surprising,
given the fact
that I haven't been able
to do a single piece of magic.
DEAN: Well, so far. (CHUCKLES)
Heard that as well.
They're calling me a squib.
I even heard
Professor Lipson
say it when she thought
I was out of the room.
Ah, I'll talk to her
about that.
We discourage that term.
It's considered hate speech.
I mean,
but don't you agree?
Do you?
Well, I...
I mean, I think I got
the highest math scores
in the history
of my high school,
and I graduated Harvard
on my 19th birthday.
Who didn't? (CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
I... I'm just saying, I...
Look, of course I want
to keep trying.
It's like
the moment that
I found out magic was real,
that was the moment
that I discovered who I am.
You remind me
of a young woman I once knew.
Similar tenacious mind.
I rejected her
from Brakebills.
Why?
Suffice to say,
I had much evidence
I was doing the right thing,
but out on her own,
she got hurt, badly.
I had chosen
not to protect her.
I'm simply
not willing to repeat
that choice with you.
So,
patience.
ISAAC: Magic is real.
(LAUGHING) Magic is real!
HANSEL: This is the trippiest thing
I have ever seen.
I gotta say,
you're taking this pretty well.
Well, you know,
it's all an illusion.
The Grand Maya.
Right, yeah.
Of course, man.
Can I just say one thing?
- I cannot believe...
- SAM: Hey.
- ...you're DJ Hansel.
- Stay close, okay?
This medal thing, it works
better the closer you are.
I've been listening
to your Taylor Swift remix nonstop.
Is it true that
you guys hooked up?
- SOPHIE: Um, Janet?
- (GASPS)
- Sorry.
- You always do that.
I was just wondering
what you want me to say
about all these plane tickets.
I don't want you
to say anything.
I want you to expense them.
Oh, well, it's just that
they don't usually allow so many.
Yeah, huge feature, okay?
- That's DJ Hansel.
- Hey, how you doing?
JANET: Yeah, these are
his minions.
Put that, okay?
And lattes, Sophie,
from the other place.
You know, the one that...
The little thing I like.
- Okay, okay.
- Yeah, yeah, and...
And almond milk, please,
if you don't mind.
She's young.
I'm working with her.
HANSEL: You were
working with her.
Now, who knows?
Who knows anything?
(CHUCKLES)
- Right, 'cause magic is real.
- You know?
- Literally. Like in movies, except literally real.
- (HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
JANET: So, no one
can find Kim, the architect,
Nigel, the bastard son
of a British lord,
was reported missing
by his family,
and Brian,
the English professor,
also reported missing.
- Not worrying, not worrying.
- Or another way to look at it
is that the whole
goddamn thing is worrying
and no one thing
is any more or less worrying
than anything else.
- Whoa, whoa, hey, hey, hey.
- (RINGING STOPS)
You need breath work, man.
- So, how do we figure out who we really...
- (HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
Oh, don't say it.
- Shh.
- (TRILLING STOPS)
Okay, just...
I don't know how we're supposed
to talk about this
if we're not allowed
to talk about this.
HANSEL: Yeah, I mean,
shouldn't all of us
being in a room
together be enough to...
- I don't know, I mean...
- Okay, look.
Apparently, you have
to poke the fake ID aspect
of the situation
pretty directly.
Okay, just talk
around it, okay?
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
I say we find the writer
of this comic book, right?
James Tiberius R. Martin
is clearly a pen name,
but whoever he is, maybe he knows
something that can help us.
Yeah, but...
But that was written 14 years ago.
I mean, what does
that even mean?
Because I have memories
from before,
- but they're not really mine because I'm...
- (HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Never mind!
Never mind, I said!
Oh, God.
You know, the guy
that got hit by a truck...
- Did he die?
- He's still in the hospital.
Well, if he's alive,
then we can ask
him some questions.
MARINA: (SIGHS)
I wish you wouldn't.
I really feel you've
done enough for him.
Hi.
I'm Marina.
You almost killed
a good friend of mine
and stole that from him,
which he was borrowing.
So, really,
you stole it from me.
Okay, relax.
I'm here to help.