Previously on The Magicians...
Charlton?
I was a passenger
in your unconscious.
Now...
I'm still in your head.
But the conscious part.
Whoa, I'm no professor.
Penny, you're the only
Brakebills-educated Traveler
currently alive on this planet.
Which makes you far more qualified
to teach them than anyone else I have.
It's Fogg.
He's stuck in the Etheric
Realm, and it's my fault.
Hello. I am Bick of the
esteemed House Pickwick.
Grab it.
I've been on the inside,
and I'm telling you,
it's a goddamn goose-stepping,
Fairy-snatching, ethnic-cleansing Gestapo.
Jesus.
So, this pig dude told me
I'm supposed to do a quest.
Yeah, it's fine,
Todd. We fixed it.
The Harmonic Convergence
isn't happening anymore.
Uh, no. He was
talking about Fillory.
The end of Fillory?
So, we saved the wrong world?
Something, something
Fillory A most amazing land
Butt-fucked by catastrophe
And way before we planned
La-la, bla-bla
Fillory
A land without a god
Needs a brand-new hero
A strapping lad named...
Todd, please stop. Okay.
Okay. I just wanna
get this straight.
So, Pig Man gave you the
quest in the form of a song?
Yeah. I might have changed
some of the lines, but that's the gist.
There's also, like,
three more verses,
and the key change is tricky.
Or you could just
write it down. Oh, I did.
The parts I could remember,
anyway, on a couple of napkins,
and then on the back of
my hand, but don't worry.
I transferred that
to another napkin.
But short version... Thank you.
Fillory is in real trouble.
He said death is
coming. For everyone.
And then he rhymed
that with "smeveryone."
Anyway, could you
please help me?
I'm not going to help you.
I'm going to take
over entirely for you.
Oh, thank God,
because I am dangerously
underqualified for this.
I know. My notes
are at Brakebills.
I probably should have brought
them. Okay. So, I'll meet you there.
Okay, bye. Okay.
Yeah, no shit
Fillory's in trouble.
Goes by the name
of the Dark King.
Or whoever's ordering dark shit on
his behalf. We're still investigating.
Which we were kinda in the
middle of till you dragged us here
'cause you were sure
Bacon McSwine Flu
was talking about the
Harmonic Convergence.
Oops, we accidentally stopped
billions of people from dying. I'm sorry.
Hmm. Look, I guessed wrong,
which is why you
guys should wait
until I've finished reading
Todd's notes before you rush off.
Mmm. I don't need Todd to tell me
which twat's messing up my kingdom,
but if he gives you a clue
how to stop the Dark King,
you know where to find us.
Oh, and tell Josh to meet me once
he's done with his nephew's bar mitzvah.
Dude drops everything
for family. It's weird.
Oh, shit.
Sorry I missed the
meeting. I can't travel.
None of us can, but we
all made it here on time.
'Cause emergency
faculty meeting.
Yeah, what's going on?
What did Lipson say?
Well, she's in a coma,
so not much. What?
I don't know if you tried
casting yet today, but FYI, don't.
Circumstances are jacked.
Some asshole moved the moon.
Oh, shit.
Acting Dean Lipson was
resetting the campus wards,
didn't realize the
Circumstances had changed.
Fogg's security system
was sicced on her instead.
Is she gonna be
okay? From what I hear,
she didn't lose anything vital.
Most of it'll grow back. But we
can't even heal her, because...
Some asshole moved the moon.
Yeah, I got it. Yeah.
Oh... Oh...
Can you shut the
security system down
before anyone else gets hurt?
The Dean of Brakebills
can, with this. In theory.
Although, that's what Lipson
was doing when she got...
Okay, so what? Are
you in charge then?
You missed the vote.
It's cool. I honestly
couldn't give less of a shit.
No, Penny. It's a horrible
job. Nobody wants it.
We all voted for you.
You assholes.
What the hell am I even
supposed to do with this?
Well, if I knew that, I
wouldn't be giving it to you.
Good luck.
Where the hell
could Fen have gone?
I know. Right?
I gave her one, two...
Well, several jobs.
But the headline was stay put
and find the creep with the
hard-on for hunting Fairies.
Okay, was he afraid of you? Yup.
They all think it's
my time of the month.
Woman or wolf? Who cares?
Either way, I've got them
scared they'll end up bleeding, too,
so I'm off the hook
for a few weeks.
Perk of marching with a bunch of scrotes
who have no clue how lady parts work.
Mmm.
Yes, Your Most Excellent
Pouchful-ness. It'll be done straight away.
I also brewed clover
tea. Your favorite.
Odious veldt marmot.
Problems with the
new boss, Rafe?
I hear she's a
handful. Between us.
Between us,
Her High Leapus
Gertrude is a nightmare.
Who's got the King's ear.
- Sadly. Yes.
I took the job with her to try and make
the King's Council more animal-friendly,
but that creature is a traitor to her
own. Never trust an animal with a pouch.
She's nothing but a puppet
to the King's Chief Advisor.
Which is who
again? Bick Pickwick.
The sexist douche
who ran the tournament?
He offered Her Long-footedness
a handsome deal
to permanently "relocate" all
talking animals beyond the walls.
Bick has a deep hatred
for anything non-human.
Non-human meaning Fairies?
- Mm-hmm.
Bick's position
could also explain
why there might be
species-cleansing without Seb knowing.
What are you, dick-matized?
No way Seb doesn't know.
There was plenty happening I didn't
know about when I was High King.
Which was fine
because you had me.
And Her Slowness, Abigail.
Aw.
Look, we'll argue
and I'll win later.
Right now, we gotta find
Fen, and see if she did her job
and got any new
intel on the Fairies.
Oh. I was supposed to tell you.
Um, before she left, Fen said,
"The Maid on the Outside
will soon be on the Inside."
And by "Inside" she meant...
I'm not sure.
At times, she's what the
animals call "human crazy."
Anything else?
Just that she was venturing
into the Windward Woods.
Oh. I'm gonna bank she's
doing her actual job, Fairy-wise,
and not just bird-watching.
Let's find her. You go ahead.
I'll go pursue a
different line of inquiry.
Yeah?
Professor... I mean,
Dean Adiyodi?
Yeah. Come in.
I have a problem.
A very big problem.
Someone stole my pencil case.
Full of drugs?
Pencils. Special pencils.
And you thought, "Hey, this is a
problem I should bring to the Dean."
I think there's a
conspiracy afoot.
A league of mischief makers
with a taste for high-end graphite.
So we tried to cast a cleansing
spell and instead it made live chickens.
So many chickens.
So, apparently the fertility and
contraception charms got switched,
so, um, we have
a bit of a situation.
They're special because of
their smear resistance and...
I don't think you're
taking me very seriously.
I promise you I am not.
All the air in there
just turned to water.
I shouldn't have to be able
to swim to take astronomy.
Go away.
We really did it this time, huh.
Zelda warned us it would happen.
We changed the Circumstances
of the moon for good.
What do we do? We try
to live with what we did.
Back to basics.
Figure out how to
cast again. Magic 101.
It's why I'm here. But we
have to figure it out fast.
We stopped the
Harmonic Convergence,
but there's still
too much magic.
Right. And if a surge happens,
every spell already jacked is
gonna get re-amped up to 11.
Christ!
It's too bad Fogg was
sober when he left.
What is it? I don't know.
But I'd say this is an
emergency, wouldn't you?
"For emergencies only."
That's not ominous at all.
Based on the locator spells on it,
we thought maybe it was built to...
To summon Fogg.
Think it could reach
the Etheric Realm?
I mean, Kady
said he can't leave,
but maybe we could
get a message out.
Even if we could
get it to reach Fogg,
using any magic right now
could backfire, like it did to Lipson.
Look, students are
in actual danger.
This campus is going haywire. No
one knows when the next surge'll hit,
and I have no idea how to help.
I hate to admit it, but I
think Fogg was doing
way more work than
we gave him credit for.
We need him back.
And if this thing can
at least contact him...
Sounds like it's worth the risk.
Okay.
Whew!
If this shit messes me up...
What the hell, Julia?
I'm fine. Did it work?
It's probably broken like
everything else in this school.
Duty calls.
Jesus. Hi. Where have you been?
Well, I have to sleep sometimes.
And everything you
do isn't that interesting.
I think, whatever I miss, I'll
just find in your brain later.
What do you people call
it? Um, binge-watching?
I fear outright rebellion.
The best and
swiftest way to get it...
To get what? Your Majesty.
Gold. Our reserves are depleted.
The salaries of our
soldiers and barrier builders
haven't been paid in weeks,
and both are threatening to strike.
The slightest work stoppage
could imperil all of us.
As reports indicate,
the Takers are
gathering in force.
Which is why I must lead a cohort of
Centurions into the Windward Woods,
and find the gold the
Fairies steal and hoard.
Okay, but that
really doesn't track.
Fairies are into
mushrooms and milk baths.
You have experience with them?
I do, sire.
Mostly bad, right?
According to your memory.
Then you know that they're as
untrustworthy as they are greedy.
They have purloined our
citizens' gold for years.
My men and I will get it back.
If I may, Your Majesty.
I do have experience
with Fairies,
and while they are
crafty negotiators,
they're not thieves.
If they have our citizens' gold,
perhaps it's from a misunderstanding
that can be worked out diplomatically.
Payments are due no
later than tomorrow's sunset.
I'm quite aware.
And diplomacy...
Can always be followed by force.
But the reverse is rarely true.
Okay, I get the charisma.
His intelligence.
He's royal but down
to earth. That's true.
- It works.
- Mm-hmm.
But trust him?
Truly?
We need five pounds of gold by
tomorrow, and another 15 by the week's end.
Or the life of every
Fillorian is in peril.
Accompany Pickwick.
If you find the
Fairies' encampment,
you have one hour to negotiate.
If that fails,
you'll stand down and let the
Centurions do whatever is necessary.
I trust your wisdom, sire.
Whoa. Hey, easy.
I'm High King Margo. We
were all pals back in the day.
Oh, we know who you are.
Look. My friend was
supposed to find you.
I think we can help each other.
Margo?
It's okay, Rowan. She's with me.
Ugh.
If that's from the selkie
in the east fountain,
you might want to
get tested for the clap.
Holy shit, am I glad to see you.
How'd you get out
of the Etheric Realm?
Long story.
Point is, I heard your call.
I'm here, and yes, I could
use a goddamn drink.
Weren't you sober?
Ah. Yes, right.
Well, the Etheric
Realm was a lot.
Let's find a bottle
and you can fill me in.
Okay.
The Traveler Professor who
cannot travel is now the Acting Dean.
Students are blowing
themselves up,
and I presume you are the aforementioned
assholes who moved the moon.
Yes, but I found a workaround.
If you cast as if your
altitude's is 1,000 feet lower
and the Pleiades are six degrees
further to the north, well, then...
Huh.
If we apply this
tweak to every spell,
we can teach people to cast without
exploding or turning things into chickens.
What happened to your hand?
I thought the Etheric Realm
was supposed to be a fun trip.
Yes.
Leaving it, less so.
But I had no choice.
I couldn't risk anyone else getting
hurt by the security system I built.
Yes, I can deactivate it,
and I will need the
master key, please.
Thank you. Oh, hold up, hold up.
I've still got student
problems to put on your radar.
Penny, I have to go
save hundreds of lives.
I think you can handle
a few whiny students.
See? Delegating.
Look, we got a
common enemy here.
The Dark King's goons are
itching to make your life hell.
We've always dealt
with hostile humans.
Yeah, well, this one's got
an army. In which you serve.
I'm undercover so I can
get information on him.
Which we could be sharing
with each other right now,
if you'd just set your
motherfucker to receive.
Okay, let's dial it down, guys.
We're all friends here.
Forgive my bluntness, Fen,
but your choice of friends
makes me doubt our choice of ally.
Maybe you're too young
or dumb to remember,
but I'm the king who made
peace with your people.
Is that what you think you did?
Yeah.
Rowan, wait.
Okay. What does she think I did?
Well, very few Fairies who
knew you are still alive today,
and the rest just know the
story of High King Margo,
which, over the centuries,
shifted with each retelling.
So I'm being boned by a
giant game of telephone.
No, no, no. Phone games
are fun. This, not so much.
See, you say you made peace.
They say you destroyed their realm
and allowed Fairy hunts for sport.
It's a real potato, potato.
No, it's potato,
po-massive fucking lie.
Look, I found them,
gained their trust.
You think that was
easy for me after...
what happened to my baby?
But I did it.
And then you barrel in
and just completely
screw the pooch.
And not in a good way. Okay.
You know what? You're right.
I... Uh...
Yeah, I am.
And now the Fairies
need to trust us both.
How can I help make that happen?
You won't like it.
Uh, that's not right.
I know what I'm
doing, if you don't mind.
It's a mistake. For sure.
I'm correcting spells for the
new Circumstances. It's math.
I don't make mistakes at math.
No, I mean that is a spell
for cooking without a fire,
but for real, that's gonna
be a pretty terrible steak.
You need flame to
denature the proteins.
What do I know, though?
You a teacher here?
We could be colleagues.
I'm interviewing
for the botany job.
Hamish Bax.
Alice Quinn.
Not related to Stephanie
Quinn, are you?
We met at a rare flower expo.
I found her orchid
quite impressive.
Oh, God.
Uh, no, no, nothing like that.
I would never date
another botanist.
Wait. Shit.
I don't understand.
My fix was working.
Ugh.
According to Todd's napkins,
there are evil forces
coming from a
distant realm to invade.
You think this is
enough to go on?
Oh, Fillory was overrun by these
Taker creatures, so it's gotta be them.
So you're going.
We could use your
help. I could use yours.
Fogg's back.
You didn't even want
to be a professor.
We're talking about the
fate of an entire world.
Didn't we just do this, though?
One minute it's the
Harmonic Convergence,
then it's the moon
and now Fillory?
Can't we just... What?
Sit back and relax?
No, but... Come on, Penny.
Look, you know what I'm after.
A life. With you, here,
or wherever, honestly.
Why not Fillory?
Because not every
apocalypse is our problem.
We just survived
the last one by a hair,
and what is it all for
if we can't kick back
on a beach
somewhere and enjoy it?
Let me tell you something.
The world doesn't wait
for timing to be right.
I want to know how
long I've gotta wait.
You live to 35, and
then you get to be done?
Or is this forever?
I get you need magic
to mean something, but...
Oh, I see what this is.
You think it's some irrational
reaction to my best friend dying,
and eventually
I'll just get over it?
Well, your math
was right before.
Okay, but it's
definitely not now.
I don't know why, but I think the
Circumstances just changed again.
Oh, shit. I told
Fogg it was safe.
If he tries to use my
fix and it backfires...
I have to warn him,
before he tries to disable
the security system.
Julia, I'm not judging you.
You're allowed to
grieve however you want.
Thank you for your permission.
Yeah, but the shit
you do affects me, too.
I think I can't do
what I need to do
if I'm worried about
how it's gonna affect you.
Worry about me?
I'm worried about you.
Yeah, that's the problem.
So, what are you saying?
I think we need to be done.
Emergency protocols are
active. For your own safety...
The hell?
Please stay in place
and await instructions.
Emergency protocols are
active. For your own safety,
please stay in place
and await instructions.
Okay, hurry up.
Emergency protocols are active.
For your own safety, please
stay in place and await instructions.
Looks like you're not
going to Fillory after all.
Look, I really thought I
was doing the right thing.
By robbing us of our homeland?
By giving you a place
where you and your weird
mushroom eggs could survive.
You promised sanctuary
and left us vulnerable.
When your people persecuted us
because we had no
way to defend ourselves.
You abandoned us.
And you can understand how
that would make the Fairies feel,
can't you, Margo?
Okay, yeah. Of course I'm
sorry you went through that.
But it was after my reign ended.
You really think that justifies
the harm you set into motion?
Jesus. You step out
for 300 goddamn years
and a bunch of gossip girls turn your
whole life into the Nuremberg trials?
Margo.
Look, this diplomatic
milk bath is all very kabuki,
but let me tell you what
my dad always said.
"You can't fix stupid."
Skipping past the fact he
always said it to me, I'll add,
I'm not the problem here.
And if you don't work with me
to bring down the Dark King,
you're
Olympic-gold-medal stupid.
Ember's balls, Margo. Get out.
Bick coming. Run. Hide.
Emergency protocols are active.
Dean. Dean...
Please stay in place
and await instructions.
Emergency protocols are active.
Penny. The hell is going on?
I'm afraid Alice's Circumstantial
mediation didn't work.
When I tried to shut
down the security system,
it set off all the school's
defenses at once.
And you can't shut
it down? I'm trying.
In the meanwhile, I strongly suggest
you stay put so you don't get blown up,
sprayed with acid,
eaten by centipedes,
or turned into one.
This is a school.
Hey, I got most of
it. But we still need...
Yes, I know what
we need. Let's go.
Well, how can we help?
Stay put.
Eliot and I have it covered.
You mean Todd?
Yes. Of course.
Isn't that what I said?
Wait. Todd, I just...
I had a quick question about
something the Pig Man said.
Of course. Yeah.
Which professor's Pig Man?
The Pig Man. From Fillory.
What about him? DEAN: Todd!
Sorry. Gotta bounce.
You saw that, right?
He had no clue what
I was talking about.
It's Todd. He's always clueless.
No, I'm telling you.
Something's up.
Fogg's acting off, too, right?
The drinking? The
burns on his hands?
I just figured the Etheric
Realm did a number on him.
And you saw what Todd
was carrying, too, right?
I mean, Azurite. Bondoc
Prisms, beech ash.
That's all reserved
for Major Arcana.
Or they could just be trying
to fix the security spells.
We should follow them.
And get turned into
centipedes or whatever?
No thanks.
Also, no offense, rather
not be around you right now.
What? Yeah, cool. Okay, stay
here by yourself. I'm gonna go.
And get turned into
a centipede. Fuck.
Well, this is definitely the most
exciting job interview I've ever been on.
I don't understand why you're
still hoping to reach Fogg.
He clearly tried your
casting tweak and it backfired.
Why we're trapped in
here in the first place.
If he's trying to fix it,
he'll need to understand how
to adjust to our current situation.
Getting the sense you're not a
fan of things you can't calculate.
I'm starting to see why you
spend all your time around plants.
Emergency protocols are active.
For your own safety, please
stay in place and await...
Shit.
How do the Circumstances
keep changing?
Okay, what do you
say we forget the note,
take down those wards and
go find the Dean ourselves?
We can't even cast properly.
Undoing the spell doesn't
require the same rigor.
It's like pulling up a
weed with a deep taproot.
Just need to get under it
at the right point, and voilà.
Okay, okay, maybe I'm just
paying for that botanist's confidence.
I don't think I should
try a healing spell.
I think it might make
things worse. The infirmary?
It's all the way across campus.
Okay, can we make
it to the greenhouse?
There might be
something there I can use.
They were just here.
Someone must have warned them.
Search the tents.
Search here. - Clear.
Hey. Didn't you hear the
order? Check the tents. Now.
Okay.
Go.
Well, well. Look what I found.
He planted that.
He planted that gold. Like a
bad cop. Like that show you...
Like Vic Mackey on The Shield.
You were lecturing me on
the true nature of Fairies?
They've changed,
it would appear.
Janet of House Pluchinsky,
what are you doing here?
I've been with you guys
the whole time. Jesus.
Women are just invisible
to you, aren't they, sir?
Congratulations, Bick.
Now, shouldn't we get this gold
back to our king as soon as possible?
We'll hunt the Fairies
down another day.
And no doubt, find more gold.
Centurions, back to Whitespire.
- Thanks for the heads-up.
- You're welcome.
Careful. Landmines. Jesus.
Oh! Hey, guys.
Um... Aren't you supposed
to be on lockdown?
Wanted to help. What you up to?
Ah, nothing. Just,
like, getting supplies.
That's cinnabar.
That shit's pretty toxic.
No. This is cinnamon. Cinnamon?
How's cinnamon gonna
help with the security system?
Dean Fogg asked if I could...
Why are you acting so squirrely?
I always act this way, okay?
You know, whatever. I have
to get this for Fogg. To Fogg.
Because of the... For
his toast. I don't know.
Wait. Careful.
There are landmines.
Thank you.
Holy shit.
Oh, my God. Did I just die?
You see anything we
can use for an antidote?
Is there a section
for healing herbs?
Uh...
Look for variants of
Plantago lanceolata.
Okay.
Yeah, found it.
Okay. You need to make
a poultice from the leaves.
That blossom, it's
from a different world.
Shouldn't even be able
to grow here. Why not?
Different Circumstances.
Everyone thought she
died before she cracked it.
What are you talking about?
Your late exo-botany professor was working
on a sort of terrarium for magical plants.
They don't need
just water or light,
they require specific
Circumstances to survive.
That's to make the Circumstances
match to any growing conditions.
Moon, body of water, altitude.
Holy shit, I think you're right.
Wait, wait, wait. You
might kill the flower.
Yeah, or find the fix for magic.
Wow. That actually worked.
Just shut up for a second.
What is it?
If Fogg gets my note,
I might actually be
able to fix this mess.
So, other Todd tied you up
and locked you in a closet?
Yeah, but I've never
been great with knots,
so it was pretty easy
for me to escape.
Only question is why
would evil twin me
want to get rid of
me in the first place?
Of course. Evil.
He wasn't your twin. I think
he's from another time line.
- Wait. For realsies?
- No, it adds up.
You know, the two
Todds, plus cinnabar,
which, last time I saw, was
being used for time magic.
I always wanted to meet
someone from another time line.
Wait a minute, guys. What
if Dean Fogg isn't our Fogg?
Describe him. I transcribed
his memoir. I know all 40 Foggs.
Even got nicknames
for some of them.
"Fedora Fogg," "Cocaine
Fogg," "Swinger Fogg."
Actually, those last
two are the same Fogg.
Well, this one's
a heavy drinker.
No, that doesn't
really narrow it down.
Okay, he has burns on his hands.
He calls you, other you, "Eliot."
He... Oh, poop.
What?
I call that one "Psycho Fogg."
See, in time line 17,
Brakebills kinda blew up.
Killed almost everybody.
And those burns on Fogg's hands,
they're 'cause he's
the one who did it.
Well, what would
he be doing here?
Psycho Fogg? Let's
not wait to find out, okay?
Let's go. Okay.
Just over six pounds.
Enough to mollify the
soldiers and workers
for tonight at least.
You're confident you
can retrieve more?
No, sire. Certain.
Ugh!
Smells like shit.
I don't control where the
Fairies hide their stolen wealth.
Well, as long as
it pays like gold.
This scalawag is so Vic Mackey.
Gold-shitting beetles.
Everybody said they've been
extinct for hundreds of years.
A rumor started by
the Pickwicks, I bet.
I think we're looking
at a little family secret.
Thank God I got
your note in time.
I think we might able to actually shut
down this goddamn security system.
If I'm right,
this should adjust Circumstances
in the entire greenhouse.
Allowing us to cast.
Let's test it first, shall we?
Not bad, Quinn.
Can we fix the lockdown now?
- I think so.
I just need one
last thing from Todd.
Cinnabar, right?
Todd couldn't make it.
Sorry.
What's going on?
Fogg's not who he
says he is. So who is he?
He's Dean Fogg
from time line 17.
Lockdown wasn't an accident,
was it? You made it happen.
Perhaps I did.
Take one more step
and I will hurt them.
Now, please, hand
me the cinnabar.
What are you gonna do
with it? I'm going to fix things.
I've seen that thing before.
That's the device Stoppard
built to travel between time lines.
Yes. I took it from him to get
here, then made a few modifications.
Enough to take all of
Brakebills back home with me.
Whoa. Listen. Hey. Look, I get
it. My time line was a mess also.
But you have a Brakebills
here with no Fogg.
Why don't you just stay?
Penny, sure.
When things start to go wrong,
just fuck off to the next time line.
How very appropriate.
But didn't you destroy your
Brakebills and everyone died?
Yes. A measure I took to try to
contain the damage The Beast could do.
And when that failed,
Jane Chatwin got to
go to the next time loop,
while I had to stay behind and live
with the goddamn consequences.
Your time line continued
even though Jane reset it?
Yes, dear.
Were you dropped on
your head in this time line?
You should be well familiar
with the multiverse hypothesis.
As it turns out, one of the
goddamn consequences
is I discovered I have
a grown daughter.
Currently living in my
post-apocalyptic shitshow of a time line
with hardly any living
Magicians and no resources.
I need this Brakebills and everyone
in it to fix where I came from.
You cannot uproot
everyone in this time line
just to be a good dad, okay?
Watch me.
Fucking Father of the Year.
Penny, if you're smart, you will
hand me that cinnabar and join me.
Doesn't sound too smart to me.
Well, you can't
travel anymore. Yes?
I know a psychic in my time
line who might be able to fix you.
Her specialty is
unlocking latent abilities.
She's done extensive
studies on Travelers.
And I'm fucking her.
Penny, you're not
actually considering...
And get my GPS fixed? Why not?
Because everyone in this
time line deserves a Brakebills.
Yeah, well, I'm not
from this time line.
Wait. Dean Fogg, no!
Damn it. What happened?
That cinnabar we gave you?
We swapped it out for cinnamon.
Doesn't play too
nice with time magic.
We actually got the idea
from Todd before he...
You know what? Never mind.
Now, how about you show
us how to lift that lockdown?
The smell is how you knew?
I'd read about the
beetles who excreted gold,
but we were all told they
disappeared generations ago.
Surprisingly, Bick's all about
saving endangered species.
Ridiculous, sire.
Your apartments have
already been searched, Bick.
Obviously, the Fairies
never had any gold,
and Bick never had
any reason to hate them.
They are not Fillorian.
That's reason enough.
You'd have had their
innocent blood on my hands?
What Fairy is innocent?
Um... All of them.
Sire, please. This
is outrageous.
Be reasonable!
That was satisfying.
I'm so sorry.
That can't have been easy.
I know how much you trusted him.
No. Thank you.
For bringing a little
honesty to this castle.
Bick didn't make Seb dark.
He is dark.
I like him, okay?
Maybe I like him because
I hope he's not fucked up.
Maybe I like him
because I hope he is.
Because I am, too.
Maybe all I deserve
is fucked up.
You know, when you think
that way, it's all you'll ever get.
Why do you care so much?
What? I don't.
But what happens to
you, happens to me.
And I don't want
him happening to me.
I know I deserve better.
Wild guess.
Your mother and your father
both loved you unconditionally.
How did you know?
How could I not?
What did you do with Fogg 17?
Can't arrest him,
can't let him go,
so we put him in the Clean Room.
He can't cast in there,
so at least this way, if there's something
else that goes wrong at Brakebills
there's a Fogg I
can talk to about it.
There's one thing
I'm certain of.
Things are absolutely going
to keep going wrong here.
I have a theory why
magic isn't working right.
I've been studying
the control panel
and there's a readout on prevailing
Circumstances outside the tank.
And, well, the moon
was all over the place.
I don't understand. I thought...
I mean, when we fixed the moon,
it was like we
never even broke it.
I think the Lunatics were right,
and the moon's got feelings.
And apparently she's pissed at us.
Great. How do we fix that?
I have no idea,
so I'm just gonna keep studying
the control panel at the greenhouse
and see what solution
I can come up with.
Thank you.
Oh. Speaking of, I hear your
botanist friend is doing better.
Not my friend. Just
somebody I helped out.
Okay. Well, the hiring
committee gave him an offer,
so you might run into
him in Botany Bay.
Hmm.
Fucking great.
Yeah, I should probably go, too.
Yeah.
Still going to Fillory?
Somebody's gotta
stop the apocalypse.
And it's gotta be you.
Penny.
Just...
In my time line, I let you go
on a quest to Fillory without me
and you never came back.
I'm not that Julia.
I know. I'm not... I didn't just
come here and swap Julias. That's...
You're totally different.
Christ, you have no idea.
The only thing you for
sure have in common
is I could not stop her when she
set her mind to something either.
I have to do this, Penny.
I know.
I just can't go
through that again.
And so here we are.
Here we are.
Be safe, Julia.
Yeah.
As I told Margo, we
are deeply grateful.
You risked everything for us.
The least we can do
is to show you the truth.
This way.
The evil forces
enter a forest glade
Coming from a
distant realm to invade
We have to seal
the door of death
We'll come for every one
Destroying all of nature
Blah, blah, blah Smeveryone
Remember? JULIA: Mmm-hmm.
The horny, horny...