ALICE: Previously
on The Magicians...
(VOICES MURMURING)
God, shut up
What's happening to you
looks just like what
happened to my mom.
The episodes didn't
stop when I was born.
They got worse.
When she's alone, everything's
normal. But when you show up...
PENNY: I still mess her up.
HADES: The creatures you call
Takers, do you know what they are?
They're guard dogs.
Their realm is a
security measure.
A barrier between your world
and the World of the Dead.
The dead will ruin Fillory.
You must stop this,
whatever the cost.
Well, the cost is blowing
up the entire planet,
which is... A decent option?
MARGO: In the center of Fillory
is a clockwork heart
built by dwarves.
CLOCK DWARF: If I wound
the clock backward, it would...
It would destroy Fillory.
What about the World Seed?
From Q's page. If we could find it,
we could use it to build a
new world, a new Fillory.
I intended to rescue my
people from this chaotic place,
so I also built an ark.
KADY: How do they feel?
ALICE: Like ghost fingers.
They work, but magically,
they still feel severed.
PENNY: The Couple just
got the last thing they need.
They have the Seed,
the page and the panel.
We gotta tell the others. They
need to steal that Seed now.
Guys, Alice has an
exit. Get to the roof.
NICK: Ho-ho-ho,
motherfuckers. (BELLS CHIMING)
(FESTIVE MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh, hey, Alice.
Did I sleep till December?
I couldn't resist giving out a
few more gifts while I'm here.
Given your
quest-heavy lifestyle,
there's no guarantee that any
of you will live to see Christmas.
Sit, have a cookie.
(BELLS JINGLING)
What is that?
No idea. It's for Eliot.
Is that a microplane for
Josh? He already has six.
Do you question
how you bend light?
Well, I don't question
how I pick gifts.
Here, put your finger
right here, please?
Looking for yours?
You already got it. Huh?
Long time back.
I put it in the locked
drawer of Quentin's desk.
You... You gave me that?
So, what did the
page turn out to say?
It was...
It's a spell that grew
a seed into a world.
But why did you put it there?
What if I'd ignored it, or...
But you didn't.
You needed something,
get back in the game.
You weren't gonna pass on a mystery
you thought your guy was working on.
I'm very sorry for your loss.
It really sucks.
Well, now you know,
that page, and wherever that
quest took you, wasn't his story,
it was yours, Alice.
For what it's worth, I think
he'd be really proud of you.
The way you keep on fighting.
I told you.
I told you, you were good.
(SCOFFS)
I still don't know
if that's true.
Hey, this is how it works.
You do your best, you
fuck up, get hurt, people die,
and except for the
odd microplane,
jack shit gets
wrapped up in a bow.
(SCOFFS)
You know, you're a real
ray of sunshine, Santa.
Ho-ho-ho.
(DOOR OPENS)
Oh, shit, creatures
stirring. JOSH: Mm-hmm.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(GASPS)
What the pumpkin
spice fuck? Huh.
Oh, my God.
These are sold out
literally everywhere.
Thanks, Santa! JULIA: Oh.
This was wrapped really tight.
ELIOT: Santa got me a bracelet?
JOSH: It's the exact right grade
for this truffle-shaving technique
José Andrés showed
me last time we hung out.
PENNY: What is this
even for? (GASPING)
MARGO: A-fucking-plus.
This is handy and sort of chic.
FEN: Oh, it's a
surprise. I love surprises.
PENNY: Is this baby shit?
JULIA: Yeah, it's baby shit.
RABBIT: Fillory needs you. Now!
ELIOT: Achtung, miscreants.
There is no un-crucial
portion of this.
As per several super-chatty
bunnies from our super buddy Rafe,
the Dark King is planning on opening
a portal to the Underworld tonight.
Now, here's the plan.
Part the first,
rapture Fillory.
Margo and I will go to
Fillory, activate Umber's Ark.
And then we go to
the Clockwork Heart.
How will you know they're
all raptured? Everyone?
Wait, um, I know a thingy.
It's in the castle, so if we
just go there and grab it.
Great. Moving on, we
will turn back the clock,
and then we get ready
to say goodbye to Fillory.
With you still on it?
Obviously not. We need to GTFO.
JULIA: You need a Traveler.
23 can't aim.
His pervo buddy Hyman's
not speaking to us.
Gavin's still in the hospital.
Oh.
Peach, or whatever your name is?
Unfortunately, when I
travel, it's kind of through time.
And puts you in the cross-hairs
of a time psycho, so no.
ELIOT: Meanwhile, on Earth.
Team World Seed.
Alice, Fen and Zelda,
you will retrieve the Seed from
its special container and bloom it.
Where?
It's in my vagina.
Uh, great. I mean, Circumstances
are wacky. Won't that make it tough to...
Neitherlands. More stable there.
MERRITT: Wouldn't
Fillory be better since...
Not at all. In fact,
counterproductive, given imploding.
MARGO: Okay, Peach,
I get you're nervous,
but this isn't our
first donkey show.
Which leads me to something
actually crucial to the plan.
No presh, but...
New Fillory better
have a Wellspring.
Or we permanently lose magic.
The spell says we can
make the Seed anything,
so it should be doable.
Great. Now.
Questions? Anyone? MARGO: No?
And, break.
(CHUCKLES, GASPS)
(LIQUID SPLOSHING)
Was I funny?
No, my water just broke.
Whoa! JOSH: Oh!
JOSH: Okay. Go
time. Just calm down.
PENNY: You okay?
JOSH: Go. Let's go.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
Ready as we can be. ETA?
Julia should be here under five.
Help! I need help.
LIPSON: What the
hell happened to him?
The Etheric Realm.
(EXHALES) A lot of it.
This is our Fogg?
You're sure? Yeah.
When we sent Psycho
Fogg to the Realm,
it spit ours back out.
He called me,
couldn't really talk. I just...
Okay, Henry? Are you in there?
(SCREAMING)
PENNY: Hey, we're here.
Push fluids, cast
Adler's Sedation.
Henry, be with you soon.
With me. Showtime.
HYMAN: No.
Hard pass, as the kids say.
Nyet.
Indian yes. (IN CHINESE
ACCENT) Oh, hell, no.
Anyway, I'm not speaking to you.
Just wait. Do you
not understand?
Do you not understand?
You're asking me to travel as
a world (LAUGHS) explodes?
Can you promise me
no debris will hit
me on my head?
Well, no, but... Things
on my head hurt.
Life is pain. Ovary up.
I'm not a hero.
I am a man tethered to a
machine for poop and humiliation,
and I abhor it.
I said good day.
I have an idea. Oh.
Hi. How was your nap?
Refreshing. You
need him to travel?
Yeah.
What? (SCOFFS)
He would never. Yes, he would.
No way. Absolutely.
Hey, (CLEARS THROAT) Hyman?
Can't squawk, getting blistered.
Listen. I have a man in my head.
(CLEARS THROAT)
He's looking for a body
and you have one that...
(CHUCKLES)
You don't even really want.
Jesus. No way he goes for this.
You're an idiot, Charlton.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
He wants to take this?
And I would, what,
stay in the astral forever?
Well, you could, or you can...
Emphatically, yes! (CHUCKLES)
Oh, my God. On one
condition. ELIOT: Okay?
Your head pal...
has to do weird
things with my body.
Sex things.
ELIOT: Uh, okay.
HYMAN: What's his name?
Charlton.
No act too depraved, Charlton.
(EXCLAIMS EXCITEDLY)
I'll be watching.
Whether you like it or not.
What have we done?
I'm prepped to sever the energetic
umbilical once the baby's here,
but I've never done it.
What?
It's a unicorn baby. It's
your kid, it is what it is.
Anyway, listen, you want
drugs, girl, say it now.
(EXHALES)
Unicorn baby
time. Let's do this.
(GASPING)
It's okay. It's okay.
Eliot? Hyman? Charlton? Wake up.
(EXHALES) Did it work?
Oh, Gods,
I'm tall!
MARGO: Great. Let's
test that Traveling out.
(LAUGHS)
This is the best episode ever.
Just relax. Okay? Breathe.
(SIGHS IN EXASPERATION)
Why can't I do this?
Just give it a minute.
We don't have a minute. We
have a world to destroy/save.
He just got in that
body. He can't travel.
I want to help. We'll be okay.
Will we? Yes.
I know a shortcut
to the portal tree.
We just gotta run.
What shortcut?
Yeah, you never
mentioned that before.
I wanted one shortcut
just for me! Let's go.
Thanks for trying, Charlton.
Andale.
Eliot. Come back safe.
Of course.
NURSE: Dean Fogg?
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Way easier to get in than out.
Like so many things in life.
This will keep the Seed
safe, for a short time.
We should begin.
(DOOR OPENS)
Fogg, why aren't you in bed?
Henry, are you all
right? JULIA: Fogg?
ZELDA: Henry,
what are you doing?
(WHOOSHING) (GRUNTS)
Wait here. I'll get him.
(DARK KING SPEAKING
IN OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) You
are my last messenger.
Listen carefully.
Tell High King Margo to...
RABBIT: Hurry!
MARGO: We're goddamn
trying, thanks. Got it!
What's this now?
A royal census scroll.
Oh.
See? Two people just
died and a Fairy was born.
Hatched.
So we can see when
they're being raptured.
I love it when a good
lay turns out to have
a working brain, don't you?
Yeah. That Josh is a keeper.
JOSH: Well, there's
a button under here.
It begins.
Hey, I think it's working.
Great, but go faster.
I think it's picking up speed
now that all the
squirrels are in.
Hey, El, you think we should...
Raptured? He's not Fillorian.
(GRUNTS)
DARK KING: You okay? (GASPS)
I'm not great at that spell,
even with enhancement.
(SHUDDERS)
Don't worry, he's
dead. They're all dead.
So it's time. Follow me
close. (THUNDER RUMBLING)
Figured you'd come to Fillory.
What with your translator
spying so diligently.
I thought I'd cut to the chase
and just bring you here
to the Taker Realm
to ask for your help.
Well, not ask.
The Final Door.
(BABY CRYING)
NURSE: It's a girl?
She's beautiful.
Not that it's about that.
I mean, she's healthy.
Okay, let's celebrate on
the B-side of the surgery.
You are a warrior.
Is she... Is she
okay? Is Lipson...
Yeah, she's as
prepped as she can be.
Okay. Okay, cool.
NURSE: Goggles?
(BABY CONTINUES CRYING)
Okay. No. 14 scalpel, selenite.
(EXHALES)
Okay, start with the baby.
Shouldn't hurt either of you.
Just, you know, don't move.
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
Dean Fogg? What are
you doing? (GRUNTS)
Wait. Wait, Dean, please.
(GRUNTS)
Where the hell is the Seed?
Julia? Julia? NURSE: She okay?
Lipson! Julia! LIPSON: Jules!
DARK KING: I
know you're worried,
but it's all going to be okay.
Because of you.
There is a danger once this door
opens more dead will come through.
This is insane.
Not if you seal it fast.
You didn't just bring
me here to help you.
You knew that I
would try to stop you.
And deep down, I
know you want that, too.
If I wanted you to stop me,
I wouldn't have cast on
that door 20 minutes ago.
Right on time.
Seb... Seb, don't do this.
LANCE: Rupert! Rupert!
DARK KING: Lance.
Eliot, seal the door.
My love. My stars. My heart.
(LAUGHING) We did it.
Touch me.
I can't.
You can't kill me. I can't die.
I'll have to be
alive. You mean it?
LANCE: We can? We can. Forever.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
No.
(LAUGHING) No.
Hello, big brother.
(IN LANCE'S VOICE)
Save me, Rupert.
I love you so.
You're still so
predictable. Your soft heart,
your stubbornness,
your stupidity.
What did you do to
him? Who? Lance?
Never even met him.
He must've moved
on centuries ago.
(KNUCKLES CRACKING)
(ELIOT YELPING)
(MAGIC WARBLES)
Spent some time in the Library
with my batty old
writer friend Cassandra,
reading about the
lengths you were going to,
to save him.
You didn't work nearly so hard
to save me from Plover, did you?
(MAGIC WARBLES)
Of course I did,
until I couldn't.
I had to save everyone from you.
You chose the dark
path. (MAGIC WARBLES)
(CHUCKLES) Says the Dark King.
Anyways, reading about
you made me realize,
after everything
you did to stop me,
you were going to give
me everything I needed
to have Fillory forever.
All I needed to do (SIGHS)
was make a few
judicious political promises.
(CHUCKLES)
(DOOR OPENING)
Leave it open. More will follow.
And of course, I had to
make peace with the fact
that we would need
to kill everyone.
But what good are
the living, really?
The world's better off with me.
You're the sad little addict
that tagged along
with Julia and Quentin.
How in the blazes are you
still alive after all this time?
No matter.
So much to do. Let's go.
Onward to the land
of the living, friends.
All the lands of the living.
Kady should be back by now.
This doesn't feel right.
We should leave. We can't.
I'm certain we won't be able to cast
precisely enough if... (DOOR BANGS)
(GASPS) What was that?
(OBJECT CLATTERS) (PANTS)
Kady? Is that you?
(DOOR BANGS) (GASPS)
(THE BEAST SINGING)
A-hunting we will go
Heigh-ho, the dairy-o
a-hunting we will go
I know that voice.
It's The Beast.
No, I killed him myself.
Then the dead have
risen. Follow me.
THE BEAST: Hello, friends. We've
come to bring death everywhere.
This room is warded,
but not for long.
That way. A portal will
take you to Brakebills.
Go. Alice?
When you recover the Seed...
I only have one good
hand. We need you. I can't...
There's something
Master Magicians know.
You can never fully control
external Circumstances.
They may even
be actively hostile.
But you can control
the ones inside you.
And one hand is plenty.
I've always known
you'll get there.
But today? Try. Okay?
Just try.
Go. Now. Hurry.
Come with us. I can't.
I'm going to have
to initiate Permafrost.
It'll stop the dead using the
fountains to get to other worlds.
Once I initiate,
every portal will
close within minutes.
We can't just leave you here.
For a Librarian,
death isn't the end.
It is merely a transfer
to another branch.
Go.
Wait, Zelda.
(DOOR OPENS)
Thank you. For everything.
Hello, noble Librarian.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
Did you just...
Mm.
We have to run, before the
sodding fountain to Fillory's locked.
I'll find another way. Hmm.
Not that you'll
be here to see it.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(EXHALES)
THE BEAST: So lovely.
Eliot, stop. Eliot, wait.
(PANTING AND YELPING)
(PANTING)
You took your shot, you
destroyed the entire world.
Could you just leave
it? (GROANING)
Please, please, let me
just at least heal your hands.
(PANTING) (SHUSHES)
I survived the
war, losing Lance,
my family's torn
apart by a monster
who said he would take care of
my brother, and I thought one thing.
I just want to use magic
for one thing I want.
You knew better.
I had to try. You
couldn't understand that.
But I do understand.
I always did.
Eliot, what was the
plan? Before I, uh...
(SIGHS)
My friends are here,
they're rapturing everyone.
So we can destroy this
planet that we love, by the way.
But we have to, to destroy you.
(PANTING)
You left us no choice, Seb.
That could still work.
I could cut off the
door to the Underworld,
stop Martin bringing
anymore dead through.
(DOOR BANGS)
Don't try to cast,
you'll hurt yourself.
(SIGHS) Great, not like
the zombies are coming.
Go. Find your friends.
I can hold off the dead.
It's not like they can kill me.
No. They can rip you to shreds,
and then we'd kill you anyway.
Eliot. Go.
Do you not get that I
don't want you to die?
(SIGHS) You're
not evil. You're just...
You're just some
deluded asshole.
(LAUGHS)
That I care about.
Who says I'll die?
(SIGHS)
Your daughter is healthy.
Good. And Julia?
Has not regained consciousness.
When do you expect...
Her organs are shutting down.
We are trying everything, but...
Can I see her? Yeah.
Hold tight. Okay.
Hey, I got you some
food. You should really eat.
I know I told you
you shouldn't do it.
But I will protect
you, okay, somehow.
I know a way to get to
Jane Chatwin. She'll help us,
and you can go back
to before. Professor.
You can go back and
stop Julia from dying.
Please. We can't.
Why the fuck not?
Because we already did.
(SIGHS)
(STUTTERS) What do
you mean, we already did?
This is the do-over.
It got so much
worse, so fast, before.
So you took me to
my grandmother, Jane.
JANE: Time loop.
Only way to undo
time without getting that
grouchy Time Traveler's
knickers in a knot.
(SIGHS) Clean start.
Big magic, though. (SIGHS)
MERRITT:
Unfortunately, she told me
that I only had enough
plasma to do it once.
(STUTTERS) Okay,
but what did you change?
Only Josh had escaped Fillory.
And the rest, they
had no way of knowing
if the Ark even worked,
so they got trapped waiting.
I pushed Josh to find a way.
And the Seed, they
tried it here, and failed.
Then Zelda took them
to the Neitherlands.
They never came back.
Why didn't you tell them
not to do that, either?
I tried!
They wouldn't listen.
And Jane said not to do too much
or that might do more damage.
It's a tricky business.
But she was adamant that I try.
Professor, we have to tell her.
She's trapped here,
and insane to think about
it, pregnant with my mother?
Yes.
Tell me what, my dears?
We are going to destroy Fillory.
With you on it.
It is the only way
to stop your brother.
Best we can do is to try to stop
our legacy from hurting anybody else.
You're doing the
right thing. Both of you.
(SIGHS)
But I won't be gone.
I'll still be here, in
the Clock Barrens.
Without Fillory, it would be
a little bit harder to find me.
So, Julia?
Look, I had no idea that Fogg
would suddenly attack her.
Fogg didn't attack last time?
No. I have no idea why
he would. Wait. Wait.
Fogg remembers time loops.
What if he remembered
something and is...
He's trying to change this one.
LIPSON: The Etheric Realm
shook loose most of his screws.
He's useless, as you can see.
MERRITT: But there's
still Fogg under there.
You know, it's like
hardwood under shag.
Well, how do we
get rid of the shag?
(SIGHS) I'm not
doing this. Okay?
This is banned in 14 countries.
(SIGHS)
Okay.
The cat will hold all his crazy,
but only while he's touching it.
What happens to the cat?
It goes, well, crazy.
Don't tell PETA.
All right. (SIGHS) Are we ready?
(SOBBING)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Thank you, Professor.
The cat looks normal.
(SCOFFS) Trust me,
this cat's having a shit day.
Did I manage to get everyone
out of the Neitherlands in time?
Plum may not know, but yes,
they are going to be attacked.
Well, it seems you did
manage, in your way.
Good. Tell Kady
the Seed is in the lab.
Why did you attack Julia?
Because she and
your child would die
if Eleanor had performed
the goddamn surgery.
Yeah, well, she's
dying now, so...
DEAN: If you had succeeded
in delicately separating the cord,
it would be rendered useless.
Quick, rough cut?
Counterintuitive, yes, I know.
The cord goes into a
state of shock. (SIGHS)
Allowing it a chance
for implantation.
DEAN: Yes. Shit.
DEAN: This will
let Julia recover.
Last time you
realized far too late.
The only catch is,
you need to attach
it to someone else.
Someone who can handle
the psychic input from,
well, a clearly very
powerful Traveler baby.
It looks still alive. For now.
The Circumstances
control panel is gone,
and the moon is not
gonna make this easy.
So the choice is, do it here
where the casting's jacked,
or let it die?
If we do it here, who
knows what it'll make.
I think the people of Fillory
deserve a place to go.
Even if it doesn't
end up as Fillory.
Okay. I'll get started. (SIGHS)
What about Eliot,
Margo and Josh?
We still haven't
heard from them.
Do you think they've
been able to...
Let's just hope they're
having more luck than we are.
ELIOT: The slide
to the Clock Dwarf
is at the end of the hall.
It takes 10 minutes
just to slide down,
and even longer to get back up.
Sorry, I was really stoned
the last time I did this.
Time to discuss
your shortcut, Margo.
Yeah. There isn't one.
What do you want me to say?
Somebody had to egg up and do
this. And I am Margo the Destroyer.
I didn't name you
that just so you'd...
Get destroyed while
destroying? ELIOT: Yeah.
Yeah, I'm not
wild about it either,
but this thing's
gotta get done, so...
We'll all go. Yes. We'll all go.
Stop.
You know, if I learned
one thing from Quentin...
One...
it's that sometimes you
sacrifice for those you love.
I'm doing this so
you two can live.
So don't you dare follow me.
In case the Clock Dwarf
wasn't raptured, a bribe.
A ham sandwich?
JOSH: Ham sandwich?
That is culatello,
capicola, speck,
a bit of Jamón Ibérico, shaved
black truffle from the microplane.
That is the best goddamn
ham sandwich ever made.
(CHUCKLES)
(POPS)
(SNIFFLES)
This way I'll know
you guys are safe.
I'll wait until you get
through the tree to do it.
Bambi, wait. (SCREAMING)
Come on.
Penny?
Hey. (STUTTERS) You're up.
How are you...
How are you feeling?
Oh, decent, considering.
Where's baby?
Uh, Lipson took
her to get changed.
How come I can't hear her?
Up here?
You're fixed.
How?
Here she is, baby Eleanor.
I don't remember
naming her Eleanor.
Yes, 'cause we didn't.
People name their kid
after their doctor all the time.
It's a thing that happens. Sure.
LIPSON: (SIGHS)
All right, Eleanor.
Well, I think she, uh...
She may have just
pooped. (LAUGHS)
Oh, hey, uh, I got this.
I've been practicing.
I'm ready.
Hope.
I like that.
I never said that.
I thought it, and...
Yes, I can live with
Quentin as her middle name.
Good. Again, what the hell?
LIPSON: Side effect.
Uh, we had to attach
the cord to Penny.
And when we did, you got better.
Wait, so got your...
You're psychic again.
Only when I'm holding her.
What else can you
do while holding her?
(MARGO SCREAMING AND LAUGHING)
(GRUNTS)
(YELLS)
Hello?
Anybody there?
Of course not.
(MARGO READING)
Guess he got raptured. (SIGHS)
Okay, boys.
Show me you were able
to make it out of here.
Hey, Margo.
In case you can read lips,
I just wanna say,
you're the love of my life.
I know. Duh.
Anyway, um, we're here.
ELIOT: Okay, we
are officially at zero.
Which means...
Oh, she looks very pregnant.
Actually, the male seahorse
carries the young and gives birth.
Margo would've dug
that. ELIOT: Yeah.
Are we really doing this?
I don't think I can do this.
We'll do this together.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Here we go, Bambi.
JOSH: Bye.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
One last goodbye
Fade away into the night
Say my name
One more time
One last goodbye
Fade away into the night
She's not coming back.
You don't know that.
(RUMBLING)
One last goodbye
Say my name...
What is this?
The end of Fillory.
Well, that hardly
seems sporting.
(YELPS)
Come with me if
you want to live.
Penny?
Yeah, sorry. Josh
wanted me to say it.
It seemed real important
to him. Come on.
I've never cast magic before.
And you're not casting now, Fen.
FEN: I'm just happy
to be included.
I feel all tingly. (CHUCKLES)
Is that what casting
magic feels like?
Too late to swap her out for
Kady? JOSH: Don't be mean.
Look, I haven't
spent time in Fillory,
unless you want your new world
looking like the Lower
East Side, then...
ELIOT: I could try.
Lipson said it's too
soon. Permanent damage.
I just want to help.
The moon is
cranky, Zelda's gone,
and Alice is down a hand, so...
(DOOR CLOSES) ALICE: Um...
I know something
that might help.
You cracked the code on
moon Circumstances? Nope.
Then what the hell is your plan?
My plan is, I'm going to accept
exactly everything I am right now.
Instagram that nonsense
later, girl. (LAUGHS) I mean...
Every single good
and shitty part.
And especially the shit.
I suggest we all do it.
We have to acknowledge it in
order to adjust for it in your casting.
Internal Circumstances.
It's the one thing
we can control.
(SOFTLY) One hand is plenty.
(EXHALES)
I'm ready. Are you ready?
Hold Fillory in
your minds, okay?
Too late to pee?
You know what? It's
fine. It's fine. Sorry.
(HUMMING)
(ALL HUMMING)
It's ready, Fen.
(ALL CONTINUE HUMMING)
Do I just...
Talk to it.
Your memories.
Um, okay. Okay.
Uh, I remember the...
The Silver Banks,
and Chatwin's Torrent
and, uh, (INHALES)
the Chankly Bore.
Whoa, that was
weird. (CHUCKLING)
I, uh... There's, uh,
Broken Bay. And...
Nothing's happening.
The fuck, Fen?
ALICE: You can't
just describe it.
You need to give
it your memories.
Oh.
Okay.
My Fillory.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
I remember the first time...
I saw a Pegasus.
I was 10.
Only in Fillory.
I remember the first time
I saw my dad use
magic to make a knife.
And then he wouldn't show me
'cause I'm a girl.
I remember my dad gave
me away to a stranger.
And that's where I realized
Fillory kind of sucks sometimes.
What are you doing?
FEN: I'm talking
about my Fillory.
That place could be,
uh, backwards as shit.
And I'm thinking I don't
want to replicate that.
We kind of need
a Wellspring, so...
(LAUGHS) Right.
Can't I just have
the best of Fillory,
the best of us, of Earth.
Plus the best of those cool movies
Todd and I watched. (LAUGHS)
That's the home I want.
That's what we deserve.
It's happening. It's happening.
Keep going. Keep going.
(WIND HOWLING)
Where'd they go? I don't know.
Well, how's it feel?
Like I'm holding a
goddamn crazy cat.
And the fur is ruining
my custom suits.
No wonder all those Bond
villains were always so pissy.
Bright side? You can actually
complain while you're holding it.
Oh, what a joy.
And magic hasn't vanished.
There's that.
The moon's more wonked
than ever, of course.
Why should anything be easy?
Maybe we should take a
cue from the hedge witches.
MOONBRAINED HEDGE:
Safehouses are starting to keep
a moon-brain
lunatic on retainer.
So, can we count
on Circumstances
holding through tonight, or...
Yeah, I'd move fast, though.
That we can do. Right, boss?
FOGG: Speaking of adjustments,
how's the newest member
of our faculty holding up?
LIPSON: His hands are healed.
He just has to get used to the
fact that half of his friends are gone.
Charlton, in Hyman-esque form.
Here you are in your happy
place, but you don't seem happy.
I thought, uh, being here
and teaching would help,
but it hasn't.
I miss them.
I feel lost and
alone without them.
Margo. All of them.
I even miss Fillory.
Do you think, um...
There's no way
Seb survived, huh?
CHARLTON: Probably not.
Fillory's gone.
But maybe it's better now.
Maybe now he's somewhere,
with someone who loves him.
You're not alone,
you know, Eliot.
(COUGHS)
Oh, Gods. (INHALES)
I am still not used to
how strong alcohol is.
Keep drinking. It'll come.
So, I have a surprise for you.
I have had a lot of terrible
surprises of late, Charlton.
I've been getting
help from Pete.
The hedge witch who
deals in magical objects.
Good Lord, why?
He helped me figure this out.
Santa left it for you?
Charlton...
You look like you.
I also feel like me.
If you touch me,
but also inside.
(EXHALES)
It's nice.
(EXHALING)
Well, this is weird.
Good weird.
So...
I have an awkward question.
I often ask myself
what you'd say,
and the answer is, "Of course
not, don't be stupid, Charlton,
"Eliot isn't the kind
of guy..." Charlton.
Ask.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
I wonder whether you could
ever be romantically inclined
towards someone like me.
A 1,000-year-old Fillorian
in a pervert ghost's body,
wearing a
transfiguration amulet?
A man who knows you well,
is emotionally available
and plans to stick around.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Well, shit, Charlton.
(ELIOT CLEARS THROAT)
Are we going somewhere?
Upstairs. To
explore this further.
Fuck.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
And what of the efforts to
find our missing students?
Eliot send those?
Hey. Where should we start?
Mm, I guess at the top.
I'm sorry there's
always another quest.
I know you wanted to just, uh...
Make a home?
Hmm, yeah. Yeah.
And this is a
batshit way to do it.
But it is a way.
Plus, someone's
gotta find those idiots.
Shit's never what
we think it's gonna be.
Very occasionally, it's better.
(BABY CRYING)
Right, H.Q.? Right?
Yeah. H.Q.?
Yeah. Just hold my hand up here.
Where do you think they are?
Maybe they got sucked
into the World Seed
because it needed matter
to turn into a new world.
Maybe it didn't work
and they got vaporized.
And yet...
we still have magic.
Somewhere, a
Wellspring exists. Yeah.
Look what I found!
(EXCLAIMS EXCITEDLY)
Turns out this
place has knife trees!
I mean, if Josh could find
naturally occurring pizza
ovens, then why not?
JOSH: Hey, guys.
Found a margherita
here if anyone is hungry.
(SIGHS) This
definitely isn't Fillory.
ALICE: Yeah, but
it's not not Fillory.
Kind of smells the same, right?
The opium made
it, that's a plus.
I passed a field
of bacon, crispy.
Is that a Fillory thing? Mm.
More of a me thing.
Well, the air is breathable,
food galore,
no predators in the vicinity.
Is it time?
No?
If we let them out, we have
to tell them we're utterly lost.
No idea where we are,
and not a bunny in sight
to get a message to our friends.
And they'll be homesick and
scared and cranky and hungry.
We'll have to build
infrastructure from scratch.
So, who wants to do the honors?
You carried the whole
world in your cooch.
You earned it.
(LAUGHS)
Thanks for saying that.
But new Fillory needs a leader.
And as its literal birth mother,
I feel I get to say,
I hereby dub thee High
King Margo the Creator.
Whoo!
Fine.
Make a meal out of it.
You guys know our lives
are about to get even weirder,
in some insane way we
can't possibly predict?
ALICE: I mean, yes. Yes.
I mean... Yes. FEN: Yes.
But I find that somehow...
perversely comforting.
ALICE: So do I.
That's how I
know it's our story.
(CLICKS)
(PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)