- Previously
on "The Magicians"...
- God.
Shut up.
What's happening to you
looks just like what
happened to my mom.
The episodes didn't stop
when I was born.
They got worse.
- When she's alone,
everything's normal,
but when you show up...
- I still mess her up.
- The creatures
you call Takers...
Do you know what they are?
They are guard dogs.
Their realm is
a security measure,
a barrier between your world
and the world of the Dead.
- The Dead will ruin Fillory.
We must stop this,
whatever the cost.
- Well, the cost is blowing up
the entire planet, which is...
- A decent option.
- In the center of Fillory
is a clockwork heart
built by dwarves.
- If I wound the clock
backward, it would...
It would destroy Fillory.
- What about the World Seed,
from Q's page?
If we could find it, we could
use it to build a new world...
A new Fillory.
- I intended to rescue my people
from this chaotic place,
so I also built an ark.
- How do they feel?
- Like ghost fingers.
They work, but magically
they still feel severed.
- The Couple just got
the last thing they need.
They have the Seed,
the Page, and the Panel.
We got to tell the others.
They need to steal
that seed now.
- Guys, Alice has an exit.
Get to the roof.
Ho, ho, ho, motherfuckers.
Extracted & corrected by
DvX3M
Hey, Alice.
- Ooh, did I sleep
till December?
- I couldn't resist giving out
a few more gifts
while I'm here.
Given your quest-heavy
lifestyle,
there's no guarantee
that any of you
will live to see Christmas.
Sit.
Have a cookie.
- What is that?
- No idea.
It's for Eliot.
- Is that a Microplane for Josh?
He already has six.
- Do you question
how you bend light?
Well, I don't question
how I pick gifts.
Here, put your finger
right here, please.
Looking for yours?
You already got it.
Long time back.
I put it in a locked drawer
in Quentin's desk.
- What, you... you gave me that?
- So what did the page
turn out to say?
- It was... was a spell.
It...
grew a seed into a world,
but why did you put it there?
What if I'd ignored it or...
- But you didn't.
You needed something-
get back in the game.
You weren't gonna pass
on a mystery
you thought your guy
was working on.
I'm very sorry for your loss.
- It really sucks.
- Well, now you know.
That page and wherever
that quest took you,
wasn't his story.
It was yours, Alice.
For what it's worth, I think
he'd be really proud of you...
The way you keep on fighting.
I told you... I told you
you were good.
I still don't know
if that's true.
- Hey.
This is how it works.
You do your best.
You fuck up, get hurt.
People die.
Except for the odd Microplane,
jack shit gets wrapped
up in a bow.
you know, you're
a real ray of sunshine, Santa.
- Ho, ho, ho.
Shit.
Creatures stirring.
What the pumpkin spice fuck?
My God.
These are sold out
literally everywhere.
Thanks, Santa.
This is wrapped
really tight.
- Santa got me a bracelet?
- It's the exact right grade
for the truffle-shaving
technique...
- This is so thoughtful.
- José Andrés showed me
the last time we hung out.
What is this even for?
- A-fucking-plus.
This is handy and sort of chic.
- It's a surprise!
I love surprises.
- Is this baby shit?
- Yep.
It's baby shit.
- Fillory needs you.
Now!
- Achtung, miscreants.
There is no uncrucial
portion of this.
As per several
super-chatty bunnies
from our super buddy Rafe,
the Dark King
is planning on opening
a portal
to the Underworld tonight.
Now, here's the plan.
Part the first...
Rapture Fillory.
Margo and I will go to Fillory.
Activate Umber's Ark.
And then we go
to the Clockwork Heart.
- How will you know
they're all raptured?
Everyone?
- Wait, um, I know a thingy.
It's in the castle,
so if we just go there
and grab it...
- Great.
Moving on.
We will turn back the clock,
and then we get ready
to say good-bye to Fillory.
- W-with you still on it?
- Obviously not.
We need to GTFO.
- You need a traveler.
- 23 can't aim.
His pervo buddy Hyman's
not speaking to us,
Gavin's still in the hospital.
Peach,
or whatever your name is.
- Unfortunately, when I travel,
it's kind of through time.
- And puts you in the crosshairs
of a time psycho, so, no.
- Meanwhile, on Earth,
Team WorldSeed...
Alice, Fen, Zelda,
you will retrieve the Seed
from its special container
and... bloom it.
- Where?
- It's in my vagina.
Great.
I mean, circumstances are wacky.
Won't that make it tough to...
- Neitherlands.
More stable there.
- Wouldn't Fillory
be better, since...
- Not at all.
In fact, counterproductive,
given imploding.
- Okay, Peach,
I get you're nervous,
but this isn't
our first donkey show,
which leads me to something
actually crucial to the plan.
No presh, but...
New Fillory better
have a wellspring.
Or we permanently lose magic.
- The spell says we can make
the Seed anything,
so it should be doable.
- Great. Now...
questions, anyone?
- No?
And break.
- Was I funny?
- No.
My water just broke.
Whoa!
- Ooh, okay.
- Go time!
- Okay.
Just calm down.
- Are you okay?
- Go, let's go.
- Ready as we can be.
ETA?
- Julia should be here
in under five.
- Help!
I need help!
- What the hell happened to him?
The etheric realm.
A lot of it.
- This is our Fogg?
You're sure?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- When we sent Psycho Fogg
to the realm,
it spit ours back out.
- He called me.
He couldn't really talk.
- Okay, Henry?
Are you in there?
- Hey.
We're here!
- Push fluids,
cast Adler's Sedation.
Henry, be with you soon.
With me.
Showtime.
- No!
Hard pass, as the kids say.
Nyet!
Indian yes.
Hell, no.
Anyway, I'm not speaking to you.
- Just wait.
Do you not understand?
- Do you not understand?
You're asking me to travel
as a world explodes?
Can you promise me
no debris will hit me
on my head?
- Well, no, but...
- Things on my head hurt!
- Life is pain.
Ovary up.
- I am not a hero.
I am a man tethered to a machine
for poop and humiliation,
and I abhor it.
I said good day.
I have an idea.
Hi.
How was your nap?
- Refreshing.
You need him to travel?
- Yeah.
What?
He would never.
- Yes, he would.
- No way.
- Absolutely.
Hey.
Hyman?
- Can't squawk.
Getting blistered.
- Listen.
I have a man in my head.
He's looking for a body.
And you have one that...
You don't even really want.
- Jesus.
No way he goes for this.
You're an idiot, Charlton.
- He wants to take this?
And I would... what?
Stay in the Astral forever?
- Well, you could,
or you could...
- Emphatically yes!
My God!
On one condition.
- Okay.
- Your head pal
has to do weird things
with my body.
S... sex things.
- Okay.
- What's his name?
- Charlton.
- No act too depraved, Charlton.
I'll be watching...
whether you like it or not.
- What have we done?
- I'm prepped to sever
the energetic umbilical
once baby's here, but, um...
well, I've never done it.
- What?
- It's a unicorn baby.
It's your kid.
It is what it is.
Anyway, listen.
You want drugs, girl?
Say it now.
Unicorn baby time.
Let's do this.
- It's okay.
It's okay.
- Eliot, Hyman, Charlton,
wake up.
- Did it work?
Gods.
I'm tall.
- Great.
Let's test that traveling out.
This is the best episode ever.
- Just relax, okay?
Breathe.
Why can't I do this?
- Just give it a minute.
- We don't have a minute.
We have a world to destroy/save.
- He just got in that body!
- He can't travel!
- I want to help.
- We'll be okay.
- Will we?
- Yes.
I know a shortcut
to the portal tree.
We just got to run.
- What, shortcut?
- Yeah, you never
mentioned that before...
- I wanted one shortcut
just for me.
Let's go.
Thanks for trying, Charlton.
Andale.
- Hey...
- Eliot.
Come back safe.
- Of course.
- Dean Fogg?
- Way easier to get in than out.
Like so many things in life.
This will keep the Seed safe...
for a short time.
We should begin.
- Fogg?
Why aren't you in bed?
- Henry, are you all right?
- Fogg?
Henry, what are you doing?
- Wait here.
I'll get him.
- You're my last messenger.
Listen carefully.
Tell High King Margo to...
- Hurry!
- We're goddamn trying!
Thanks!
- Got it.
- What's this now?
- A royal census scroll.
You see?
Two people just died,
and a fairy was born.
- Hatched. So we can see
when they're being raptured.
- I love it when a good lay
turns out to have
a working brain, don't you?
- Yeah.
That Josh is a keeper.
- Well, there's a button
under here.
It begins!
- Hey, I think it's working.
- Great, but go faster.
- I think it's picking up speed
now that all
the squirrels are in.
- Hey, El, you think we should...
- Raptured?
He's not Fillorian.
- You okay?
I'm not great at that spell,
even with enhancement.
- Don't worry.
He's dead.
They're all dead.
So it's time.
Follow me close.
Figured you'd come to Fillory...
what, with your translator
spying so diligently.
I thought I'd cut to the chase.
And just bring you here
to the Taker Realm
to ask for your help.
Well...
not ask.
The final door.
- It's a girl.
She's beautiful.
Not that it's about that.
I mean, she's healthy.
- Okay, let's celebrate
on the B-side of surgery.
- You are a warrior.
- Is she up?
Is she okay?
Is Lipson?
- Yeah.
She's as prepped as she can be.
- Okay.
You doing okay?
- Okay, good.
Goggles?
All right.
Okay.
Number 14 scalpel, Selenite.
Okay, start with the baby.
Shouldn't hurt either of you.
Just, you know, don't move.
- Dean Fogg?
What are you doing?
Wait.
Wait, Dean.
Please.
- Where the hell is the Seed?
- Julia?
Julia?
- Is she okay?
- Lipson!
Jules!
Julia.
- I know you're worried.
But it's all going to be okay...
because of you.
There is a danger,
once this door opens,
more dead will come through.
- This is insane.
- Not if you seal it fast.
- You didn't just
bring me here to help you.
You knew that
I would try to stop you.
And deep down...
I know you want that, too.
- If I wanted you to stop me,
I wouldn't have cast
on that door 20 minutes ago.
Right on time.
- Seb.
Seb, don't do this.
- Rupert!
Rupert.
- Lance.
Eliot, seal the door.
My love, my stars, my heart.
We did it.
Touch me.
- I can't.
- You can't kill me.
I can't die.
- You mean it?
We can...
- We can... forever.
No!
No.
- Hello, big brother.
Save me, Rupert. I love you so.
You're still so predictable.
Your soft heart,
your stubbornness,
your stupidity.
- What did you do to him?
- Who?
Lance?
Never even met him.
He must have moved on
centuries ago.
- Spent some time in the Library
with my batty old
writer friend, Cassandra,
reading about the lengths
you were going to
to save him.
You didn't work nearly
so hard to save me...
from Plover.
Did you?
- Of course I did...
until I couldn't.
I had to save everyone from you.
You chose the dark path.
Says the Dark King.
Anyways, reading about you
made me realize,
after everything you
did to stop me,
you were going to give me
everything I needed
to have Fillory...
forever.
All I needed to do
was make a few judicious
political promises.
Leave it open.
More will follow.
And of, course, I had
to make peace with the fact
that we would need
to kill everyone.
But what good
are the living, really?
The world's better off with me.
You're the sad little addict
that tagged along
with Julia and Quentin.
How in the blazes are you still
alive after all this time?
No matter.
So much to do!
Let's go.
Onward to the land
of the living, friends.
All the lands of the living.
- Kady should be back by now.
This doesn't feel right.
We should leave.
- We can't.
I'm certain we won't be able
to cast precisely enough
if we...
What was that?
- Kady?
Is that you?
- # A-hunting we will go #
# A-hunting we will go #
# Heigh-ho the derry-o #
- # A-hunting we will go #
- I know that voice.
It's The Beast.
No, I killed him myself!
- Then the Dead have risen.
Follow me.
- Hello, friends.
We've come to bring
death everywhere.
- This room is warded,
but not for long.
That way... a portal will take
you to Brakebills.
Go. Alice...
when you recover the Seed...
- I-I only have one good hand.
We need you. I can't...
- There's something
Master Magicians know.
You can never fully control
external circumstances.
They may even be
actively hostile.
But you can control
the ones inside you.
And one hand...
is plenty.
I've always known
you'll get there.
- But today?
- Try.
Okay?
Just try.
Go now.
Hurry.
- Come with us.
- I can't.
I'm going to have
to initiate Permafrost.
It'll stop the Dead
using the fountains
to get to other worlds.
Once I initiate, every portal
will close within minutes.
- We can't just leave you here.
For a librarian,
death isn't the end.
It is merely a transfer
to another branch.
Go.
Wait, Zelda.
Thank you...
for everything.
- Hello, noble Librarian.
- Did you just...
- We have to run...
before the sodding fountain
to Fillory's locked.
I'll find another way.
Not that you'll be
here to see it.
So lovely.
- Eliot, stop!
Eliot, wait!
You took your shot.
You destroyed the entire world.
Will you just leave it...
- Please... please, let me just
at least heal your hand.
- Shh.
I survived war, losing Lance,
my family torn apart
by a monster
who said he would take care
of my brother,
and I thought one thing...
I just want to use magic
for one thing I want...
- You knew better.
- I had to try!
You couldn't understand that.
- But I do understand.
I always did.
- Eliot, what was the plan?
Before I...
My friends are here.
They're rapturing everyone
so we can destroy this planet
that we love, by the way.
But we have to to destroy you.
You left us no choice, Seb.
- That could still work.
I could cut off the door
to the Underworld,
stop Martin bringing
anymore Dead through.
Don't try to cast.
You'll hurt yourself.
- Great, not like
the zombies are coming.
- Go.
Find your friends.
I can hold off the Dead.
It's not like they can kill me.
- No, they can rip you
to shreds,
and then we'd kill you anyway.
- Eliot, go.
- Do you not get that
I don't want you to die?
You're not evil.
You're just...
You're just
some deluded asshole...
- That I care about.
- Who says I'll die?
- Your daughter is healthy.
- Good.
- And Julia?
- Has not regained
consciousness.
- When do you expect?
- Her organs are shutting down.
We are trying everything, but...
- Can I see her?
- Yeah.
Hold tight.
- Okay.
- Hey.
I got you some food.
You should really eat...
- I know I told you
you shouldn't do it.
But... but I will protect you,
okay, somehow.
I know a way to get
to Jane Chatwin.
She'll help us, and you can
go back to before...
- Professor...
- You can go back and stop
Julie from dying, please.
- We can't.
- Why the fuck not?
- Because we already did.
- What... what... what do
you mean "we already did"?
- This is the do-over.
It got so much worse,
so fast before...
So you took me
to my grandmother, Jane.
- Time loop...
Only way to undo time
without getting
that grouchy time traveler's
knickers in a knot.
Clean start.
Big magic, though.
- Unfortunately, she told me
that I only had enough plasma
to do it once.
- Okay, but what...
What did you change?
- Only Josh had escaped Fillory.
In the West, they had
no way of knowing
if the Ark even worked,
so they got trapped waiting.
I pushed Josh to find a way.
And the Seed,
they tried it here and failed.
And Zelda took them
to the Neitherlands.
They never came back.
- Why didn't you tell them
not to do that either?
- I tried!
They wouldn't listen!
And Jane said
not to do too much,
or that might do more damage.
It's a tricky business.
But she was adamant that I try.
Professor, we have to tell her.
She is trapped here
and... insane to think
about it... pregnant
with my mother.
- Yes.
Tell me what, my dears?
- We are going
to destroy Fillory.
With you on it.
It is the only way
to stop your brother.
- Best we can do is
to try to stop our legacy
from hurting anybody else.
You're doing the right thing,
both of you.
But I won't be gone.
I'll still be here
in the Clock Barrens.
Without Fillory,
it'll be a little bit
harder to find me.
- So Julia...
- Look, I had no idea that Fogg
would suddenly attack her.
- Fogg didn't attack last time?
- No, I-I have no idea
why he would.
- Wait.
Wait!
Fogg remembers time loops.
What if he remembered
something and... and is...
Is trying to change this one?
- The etheric realm shook loose
most of his screws.
He's useless, as you can see.
But there's still
Fogg under there.
You know, it's like
hardwood under shag.
- Well, how do we
get rid of the shag?
I'm not doing this, okay?
This is banned in 14 countries.
Okay.
The cat will hold all his crazy,
but only while he's touching it.
- What happens to the cat?
- It goes, well...
crazy.
Don't tell PETA.
All right.
We ready?
Hey.
Thank you, Professor
- The cat looks normal.
Trust me.
This cat's having a shit day.
- But I managed to get everyone
out of the Neitherlands in time.
Plum may not know, but, yes,
they are going to be attacked.
- Well, it seems you did
manage in your way.
- Good.
Tell Kady the Seed
is in the lab.
- Why did you attack Julia?
- Because she
and your child would die
if Eleanor had performed
the goddamn surgery.
- Yeah, well,
she's dying now, so...
- If you had succeeded in
delicately separating the cord,
it would be rendered useless.
Quick, rough cut...
Counterintuitive, yes, I know.
The cord goes
into a state of shock.
Allowing it a chance
for implantation.
- Yes.
- Shit.
- This will let Julia recover.
Last time
you realized far too late.
The only catch is
you need to attach it
to someone else,
someone who can handle
the physic input from, well...
a clearly very powerful
traveler baby.
- It looks still alive...
for now.
- The Circumstances
control panel is gone,
and the Moon
is not gonna make this easy.
- So choice is, do it here
where the casting's jacked
or let it die?
If we do it here,
who knows what it'll make?
- I think the people of Fillory
deserve a place to go,
even if it doesn't end up
as Fillory.
- Okay.
I'll get started.
- What about Eliot, Margo,
and Josh?
We still haven't heard
from them.
Do you think
they've been able to...
- Let's just hope they're
having more luck than we are.
- The slide to the Clock Dwarf
is at the end of the hall.
It takes ten minutes
just to slide down
and even longer to get back up.
- Sorry, I was really stoned
the last time I did this.
Time to discuss
your shortcut, Margo.
- Yeah.
There isn't one.
What do you want me to say?
Somebody had to egg up
and do this,
and I am Margo the Destroyer.
- I didn't name you that
just so you...
- Get destroyed
while destroying?
Both: Yeah.
- I'm not wild about it either.
But... this thing's got to
get done, so...
- We'll all go.
- Yes, we'll all go.
- Stop.
You know, if I learned
one thing from Quentin...
one...
it's that sometimes you
sacrifice for those you love.
I'm doing this
so you two can live,
so don't you dare follow me.
- In case the Clock Dwarf
wasn't raptured, a bribe,
- A ham sandwich?
- A ham sandwich.
That is culatello,
capicola, speck,
a bit of Jamón Ibérico,
shaved black truffle
from the Microplane.
That is the best goddamn
ham sandwich ever made.
This way I'll know
you guys are safe.
I'll wait until you get
through the tree to do it.
- Bambi, wait!
- Come on.
- Penny?
- Hey.
You're... you're, um...
You're up.
How are you...
How are you feeling?
Decent, considering.
Where's baby?
Lipson took her
to get changed.
- How come I can't hear her?
- Up here?
You're fixed.
- How?
- Here she is, baby Eleanor.
- I don't remember
naming her Eleanor.
- Yeah, it's 'cause we didn't.
- People name their kid after
their doctor all the time.
It's a thing that happens.
- Sure.
All right, Eleanor.
- I think she...
She may have just pooped.
Hey, I got this.
I've been practicing.
I'm ready.
Hope...
I like that.
- I never said that.
I thought it and...
- Yes, I can...
live with Quentin
as her middle name.
- Good.
Again, what the hell?
- Side effect.
We had to attach
the cord to Penny,
and when we did, you got better.
- Wait, so you got your...
You're psychic again?
- Only when I'm holding her.
- What else can you do
while holding her?
Hello?
Anybody there?
Of course not.
"Do not turn backward,
or Fillory will be destroyed.
Management."
Guess he got raptured.
Okay, boys.
Show me you were able
to make it out of here.
- Hey, Margo.
In case you can read lips,
I just want to say,
you're the love of my life.
I know.
Duh.
Anyway, um, we're here.
- Okay, we are
officially at zero,
which means...
She looks very pregnant.
- Actually, the male seahorse
carries the young
and gives birth.
Margo would have dug that.
- Yeah.
Are we really doing this?
I don't think I can do this.
- We'll do this together.
Okay.
Here we go, Bambi.
- Bye.
- # One last good-bye #
# Fade away into the night #
# One last good-bye #
# Say my name #
# One more time #
# One last good-bye #
# Fade away into... #
- She's not coming back.
- You don't know that.
- # One last good-bye #
# Say my name #
- What is this?
- # One more time #
- They ended Fillory.
- Well, that hardly
seems sporting!
Aah!
- Come with me
if you want to live!
- Penny?
- Yeah, sorry!
Josh wanted me to say it!
It seemed real important to him!
Come on!
- # Say, say #
- I've never cast magic before.
- You're not casting now, Fen.
- Just... I'm just happy
to be included.
I feel all tingly.
Is that what
casting magic feels like?
- Too late to swap
her out for Kady?
- Don't be mean.
- Look, I haven't spent time
in Fillory.
Unless you want your new world
looking like
the Lower East Side?
Then...
- I could try.
- Lipson said it's too soon.
Permanent damage.
- I just want to help.
The Moon is cranky.
Zelda's gone, and Alice
is down a hand, so...
- Um, I know something
that might help.
- You cracked the code
on Moon circumstances?
- Nope.
- Then what the hell
is your plan?
- My plan is I'm going to accept
exactly everything
I am right now.
- Instagram that nonsense
later, girl. I mean...
- Every single good
and shitty part
and especially the shit.
I suggest we all do it.
We have to acknowledge it
in order to adjust for it
in your casting.
Internal circumstances...
It's the one thing
we can control.
One hand is plenty.
I'm ready.
Are you ready?
Hold Fillory
in your minds, okay?
- Too late to pee?
You know what?
It's... it's fine.
It's fine.
Sorry.
It's ready, Fen.
- Do I just...
- Talk to it.
Your memories.
- Um, okay.
Okay.
I remember
the... the Silver Banks
and Chatwin's Torrent
and...
the Chankly Bore?
That was weird.
There's Broken Bay
and...
- Nothing's happening.
- What the fuck, Fen?
- You can't just describe it.
You need to give it
your memories.
Okay.
My Fillory...
I remember...
the first time...
I saw a Pegasus.
I was ten.
Only in Fillory.
I remember the first time...
I saw my dad use magic
to make a knife.
And then he wouldn't show me
'cause I'm a girl.
I remember
my dad gave me away
to a stranger.
And that's where I realized
Fillory kind of sucks sometimes.
- What are you doing?
- I'm talking about my Fillory.
That place could be,
backwards as shit.
And I'm thinking I don't want
to replicate that.
- We kind of need
a wellspring, so...
Right.
Can't I just...
have the best of Fillory?
The best of us, of Earth.
Plus the best of those cool
movies Todd and I watched.
That's the home I want.
That's what we deserve.
- It's happening.
It's happening!
Keep going!
- Where'd they go?
- I don't know.
- Well, how's it feel?
- Like I'm holding
a goddamn crazy cat
and the fur is ruining
my custom suits.
- No wonder all those Bond
villains were always so pissy.
Bright side...
You can actually complain
while you're holding it.
What a joy.
- And magic hasn't vanished.
There's that.
The Moon's more wonked
than ever, of course.
- Why should anything be easy?
Maybe we should take a cue
from the Hedge Witches.
Safehouses are starting to keep
a moon-brained lunatic
on retainer.
- So can we count
on circumstances holding
through tonight or...?
- Yeah, I'd move fast, though.
- That we can do.
Right, boss?
- Speaking of adjustments,
how's the newest member
of our faculty holding up?
- His hands are healed.
He just has
to get used to the fact
that half of his friends
are gone.
- Charlton, in Hymanesque form.
- Here you are
in your happy place, but...
you don't seem happy.
- I thought being here
and teaching
would help, but...
it hasn't.
- # For the rest of your life #
# You're gonna be high #
# Come home #
- I...
I miss them.
I feel lost and alone
without them...
Margo, all of them.
I even miss Fillory.
Do you think, um...
There's no way
Seb survived?
- Probably not.
Fillory's gone.
But maybe it's better now.
Maybe now he's somewhere
with someone who loves him.
You're not alone, you know?
Eliot.
Gods.
I am still not used
to how strong alcohol is.
- Keep drinking.
It'll come.
- So I have a surprise for you.
- I have had a lot of terrible
surprises of late, Charlton.
- I've been getting
help from Pete...
the Hedge Witch who deals
in magical objects?
- Good Lord.
Why?
- He helped me figure this out.
Santa left it for you.
- Charlton.
You look like you.
- I also feel like me.
If you touch me
but also inside...
It's nice.
- Well, this is weird.
- Good weird?
- So...
- I have an awkward question.
I often ask myself
what you'd say,
and the answer's,
"Of course not.
Don't be stupid, Charlton.
Eliot's isn't the kind of... "
- Charlton.
Ask.
- I wonder whether you could
ever be romantically inclined
with some someone like me?
- A thousand-year-old Fillorian
in a pervert ghost's body
wearing
a transfiguration amulet?
- A man who knows you well,
is emotionally available,
and plans to stick around.
Well, shit, Charlton.
Are we going somewhere?
- Upstairs to explore
this further.
- Fuck.
- And what of the efforts
to find our missing students?
- Eliot send those?
- Hey.
Where should we start?
- I guess at the top.
- I'm sorry there's
always another quest.
- I know you wanted to just...
- Make a home.
Yeah.
- Yeah.
And this is a batshit way
to do it, but it is a way.
Plus, someone's got to
find those idiots.
- Shit's never what we think
it's gonna be.
- Very occasionally it's better.
Right, HQ?
Right?
Yeah.
- HQ?
- Yeah.
Here, just hold my hand.
- Where do you think they are?
- Maybe they got sucked
into the World Seed
because it needed matter
to turn into a new world.
Maybe it didn't work,
and they got vaporized.
- And yet...
we still have magic.
Somewhere a wellspring exists.
- Yeah.
Look what I found.
Turns out this place
has knife trees.
- I mean, if Josh could find
naturally occurring
pizza ovens, then why not?
- Hey, guys.
Found a margherita here,
if anyone is hungry.
This definitely isn't Fillory.
- Yeah, but it's not
not Fillory.
Kind of smells the same, right?
- The opium made it.
That's a plus.
- I passed a field
of bacon... crispy.
- Is that a Fillory thing?
- More of a me thing.
- Well, the air is breathable,
food galore,
no predators in the vicinity.
Is it time?
No?
- If we let them out,
we have to tell them
we're utterly lost.
No idea where we are
and not a bunny in sight
to get a message to our friends.
- And they'll be
homesick and scared
and cranky and hungry.
- We'll have to build
infrastructure from scratch.
- So...
Who wants to do the honors?
- You carried the whole world
in your cooch.
You earned it.
Thanks for saying that.
But New Fillory needs a leader.
And...
as its literal birth mother...
I feel I get to say...
I hereby dub thee
High King Margo, the Creator.
- Whoo!
- Fine.
Make a meal out of it.
You guys know our lives
are about to get even weirder
in some insane way
we can't possibly predict?
- I mean, yes.
- Yes.
- I find that somehow...
perversely comforting.
- So do I.
That's how I know
it's our story.