ELIOT: Previously
on The Magicians...
You may address me
as Reynard the Fox,
trickster of the
faithful, the very stupid.
(WHIMPERS) (GROWLING)
You must be Marina.
I need you to tell me about
the thing that killed you.
There was a girl.
Forty years ago, she
banished Reynard from Earth.
ALICE: Charlie, my brother...
He was really, really good.
You know that spell I did
on the first day of class?
With The Glass Horse?
He taught me that.
I fell for this professor.
He was married.
I thought I could make
him love me again.
If I could make
myself prettier...
I really believed
he might actually be
able to undo what I did.
It burned...
Until he wasn't there anymore.
I gave up magic, and
never looked back.
(GASPING)
(SHRIEKING)
No!
QUENTIN: Alice was gone.
There's a creature. It's
called the White Lady.
I want my hands back.
(SCREAMING)
Alice Quinn. Bring
her back to life.
I can't.
Is there nothing
else you desire?
Send me home.
I spoke with Professor
Lipson about the tests she ran.
But, I'm sorry to say that we
don't even know where to start.
Okay, is this a normal
candle, or what...
Of course. You cure
your own hands just fine,
but mine, you can't do a
fucking thing about, huh?
Broken or not, my
hands are my hands.
Yours are something else.
There's nothing we can do.
And Brakebills continues
its tradition of fucking my shit!
There's nothing we can do here.
There are other options.
One, I send you to someone
who may know more.
Yes, who is it?
Professor Mayakovsky.
The drunk perv
in the igloo? Pass.
What's option two?
Hmm, well.
You won't have to worry about
your hands, or magic at all.
It's actually where
I sent Quentin.
Where's Quentin?
MAN: So we finally get to
the cashier, and guess what?
Hmm? Left my wallet in the car.
Oh, man.
Talk about bad timing.
Yeah.
Hey, does "Donut House"...
Does that taste like donuts?
I just use that thing for soup.
Soup?
The fuck?
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
(SIGHS)
(COMPUTER CHIMES)
(WIND HOWLING)
(METAL CLANGING AT A DISTANCE)
Hello?
(CLANGING, HAMMERING)
Professor Mayakovsky?
(WHOOSHING)
(GRUNTS)
Shit!
Hey.
Hey, let me down, I'm a student!
(CLANGING, HAMMERING)
Dick.
Chicago Register, July '76.
You know, dead or not, Marina
could have been a little more specific.
I still don't know
what I'm looking for.
Look, banishing Reynard had to
take an insane amount of energy.
So, any sort of strange
event or aberration.
Yeah, that's literally
the definition of news.
We'll know it when we see it.
(SIGHS)
(STAMMERS) I need some fuel.
(SNIFFS)
(GAGS)
You okay?
(COUGHING)
What is it, the
second time today?
Third.
Oh, God. Jules, I...
Fuck!
Fuck! Fuck! Why...
Come on, come on. Sit.
Why won't it just end?
Why does it just keep
getting worse and worse?
I'm so sorry.
Whatever. What's the spell
to terminate it or whatever?
There's stuff out there, but
it's all shady dark ages shit
from before modern medicine.
You don't cauterize a paper cut
with a crazy medieval blowtorch.
That sounds like
exactly what I want to do.
Not if it erases your uterus
and kidneys along with the fetus.
Jesus.
Hey, it's...
It's okay, Jules. This is a simple,
totally mundane procedure.
Is it? 'Cause it might not be a "simple,
totally mundane" human embryo.
I mean...
I don't even know if it's
Reynard's or Richard's.
Right now, it is
just a clump of cells.
Okay, so let's just put
a pin in all this, okay?
We'll make an appointment.
Your Majesty...
It's ready.
At the very least, I hope you
solved the carbonation issue.
We had to dump that last
glass in another world, you know.
Still bubbling.
Oh, the miles we must walk.
(SIGHS)
My King, I have the best news!
If that rabbit was a
prosecco, I'd agree.
This isn't just a rabbit.
Pregnant.
Jesus.
We're going to be parents!
That rabbit knows
if you're, uh...
Pregnant. Okay, okay.
You're not smiling.
I'm sorry. It's just, you see...
Pregnant. Okay, rabbit, chill!
Uh-uh, where do you
think you're going?
It may suck all the
moisture from my tongue,
but damned if I'm not
going to toast to this shit.
To our violently
attractive progeny.
(GULPS)
Hey, yo! Let me down! Okay?
What the fuck is this shit?
What do you want?
My hands can't
cast spells anymore.
This is not Mayakovsky's
Home For Magically Inert.
But, maybe an exchange...
What do you got in mind?
I'm in the middle of a project.
Help me, I do what I can.
I'm in. Okay.
(SNAPS FINGERS)
(THUDS)
QUENTIN: Is everybody
out here really so lifeless?
Yes. We are. We are.
That's why we drink.
Well, I drank just
fine as a Magician.
Yeah, because your world
was so overwhelming and scary,
and you needed
a break from it all.
Now you're going to drink because
each day is so goddamn dull,
and that takes a lot more booze.
Do you ever cast
anymore? God, no.
I'm sorry, that was stupid.
No, it's okay.
I mean, nobody ever gives up
magic because everything's peachy.
You want to tell me?
Uh... I'm sorry.
No, I shouldn't have asked.
I can see that it's recent.
It's fucking madness.
Teaching that stuff
to kids. I mean, kids.
It's like, what's the point?
You know? 'Cause it feels like
for every one thing that we fix,
five shitty things
spring up in its place.
Because each spell is
just another complication.
That we cast
another spell to fix.
Repeat, repeat, repeat.
Until there's no spell
left, and you're just...
You're left with... A
big fucking problem.
Oh, shit! I have
a meeting in 15.
Ooh.
I'm sorry. That was just reflex.
Uh, that... I... Um...
Just...
Just put this on the company
card. They won't notice.
(SIGHS)
I am happy. Yay, a baby.
Eliot. What is this about?
(SIGHS)
I really want to know.
(SIGHS) My father
was not the best.
Wine, Your Majesty.
Bad dad.
So, I suppose I don't
exactly have the proper,
uh, uh...
Template to...
(GASPS) (SCREAMS)
Quiet!
You are not welcome
here, Child of Earth!
Eliot!
(BAYLER GROANS)
Wait!
This is not over,
Child of Earth.
(PANTING)
Dungeon.
What the hell was that about?
I tried expressing my emotions.
Lesson learned.
Shittiest security ever.
So, what are we supposed
to do? Ship him back to Loria?
Actually, Your Highness,
he's not from Loria.
He's a native Fillorian.
My own people are trying
to kill me? (CHUCKLES)
So French.
They're commoners. Not to worry.
Oh, whoa, whoa. I'm worried.
I urge a public execution today.
Might I suggest strangulation?
For the symbolism.
PICKWICK: We don't
wish to fall to his level.
The Bed of a Thousand
Spikes should do just fine.
(ABIGAIL SQUEAKING)
Her Slowness suggests tying
each of his limbs to a centaur,
and as they stretch
him inch by inch,
a fifth centaur "sets
the spike," if you will.
Jesus! No.
Everyone, out. This is a
matter for the Queen and me.
That sloth is psychotic.
They're all psychotic. (SIGHS)
Did you hear how
Tick said "commoners?"
When we're the least
snobby people in a room,
there's something
wrong with the room.
(KNOCKING)
Yes?
I wanted to apologize.
I'm sorry, um...
Okay.
What?
I just... I don't know if
you accepted my apology.
Yes.
Okay. Actually, no.
No, I don't.
We had just talked about
how terrible magic is,
and then you went and did it.
That was just a tiny spell.
There are a lot of
companies like this.
I'm sure Fogg can find
another one for you.
(SIGHS)
Okay.
(MOUSE CLICKING)
PENNY: They're useless, right?
Well, maybe not "useless."
You can still grab hold
of things, wave hello,
rub away a lonely night.
Okay, but for magic?
For magic, useless.
How's your travel?
Fine.
Aim's good. I just can't
take people with me.
Some might call that blessing.
Yeah, well, the option
would be nice, so...
I mean, can you help me?
What are we doing here?
I can help you. But
first, your end of deal.
(SIGHS)
Take out all the knots.
What the hell?
Miss Wicker? Uh, Julia.
The test was positive.
If you'd like, we can
discuss your options.
I want an abortion.
Okay. That's something that
we can perform here in-office.
Great. Uh, today?
Unfortunately, we
do have a waiting list,
but it should just
be a couple of days.
Days?
Doctor, I can't wait a
couple of days. Please. I...
If I suspect abuse, I'm
obligated to report it.
Julia, you're safe here.
You can talk about
what happened.
No one is above the law.
(LAUGHS)
Uh, I'm sorry.
I wish that were true.
Look, I just want
this to be over.
And you can help me.
Please.
Okay.
We'll set you up for
an ultrasound today.
Tomorrow we can
perform the procedure.
We open at 8:00.
Thank you. I'll see you then.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Hi.
Leave. You don't
get to say that.
And why not?
Uh,
because you're in our castle.
Which is on my land.
Uh, excuse me, my manners.
Um, I'm Eliot, High King of Fillory.
And I'm Bayler. A proud
soldier of Fillorians United.
A FU Fighter.
Did you say "Foo
Fighter?" Margo, behave.
And we will not rest until a
Fillorian sits upon the throne.
Okay. Tell Ember.
He issued the decree.
We will execute every Child of
Earth that crosses into our land,
until there are
none left to kill.
(LAUGHS)
And yet, you laugh.
I mean, a "Foo Fighter?"
Margo.
ELIOT: If we execute
him, then he's a martyr.
Shit.
When was the
last time either of us
dealt with a
political insurgency?
Unless getting kicked out of a
five-some counts, first for me.
Same.
I'm thinking we should
probably bone up.
Like, study?
I'll grab what I can from the
Brakebills library. (GROANS)
Fine. And grab some
Adderall while you're there.
Okay! I'm done!
Shit! What... Do not... Don't
sneak up on me like that!
This is my house.
Look, I finished untying your
bondage kit. You gonna teach me now?
You finish first step.
Next, that table.
(SIGHS)
What about it?
You make it sawdust.
Do not worry, I give you tool.
Enjoy.
(SPUTTERS)
What're you still doing here?
I'm just finishing up.
Gonna jerk it?
Break in the office?
No! What? No! I'm...
It's the only place I can. Wife
and two kids, no privacy at home.
I'm not doing that...
Here.
Just saying,
there's no judgment.
Adiós.
(DOOR CLOSES)
I owe you an apology
for being a bitch.
Could you knock, please?
What, were you
masturbating in your office?
No.
Whatever, I do.
What is this place?
(SIGHS)
I'm sorry again about the spell.
I'm sorry for making you feel
sorry. It was just a stupid spell.
Thank you.
Want some?
Vodka, bit of lime.
You should stay.
Forget what I said earlier. I
think we'd be good friends.
(GULPS) I would like that.
What the hell are we still
doing in the office, right?
Let's get out of here.
Mmm. Finish that. Come on!
Okay.
Yes!
(FILE SCRAPING)
Take a break.
No trick, no test, I promise.
That's it?
Take your balls out of
your purse and drink!
No, if we're gonna
talk about what we did,
then we have to
call it what it is.
It's stupid! It's
so fucking stupid!
It's the stupidest I've
ever fucking been.
Reynard set us up.
Yeah, but I should
have known better.
You know, I knew the difference
between magic and miracles.
One is real, and one
is a lie with sparkles.
Like a nice, female god was
gonna glide in and save us...
It sounds so naive
to ever believe in that.
Look, there is one
way through this,
and that is to find out what
happened 40 years ago.
Yeah, and banish the
fuck out of Reynard.
Yeah, so let's just get this
pesky abortion out of the way,
and that's next on the list.
I know this is a
straightforward procedure.
It's probably, you
know, the simplest thing
I've had to deal with in months.
But I'm nervous.
(SIGHS)
I had one.
He was a drummer.
And he said he couldn't
get it up with a condom.
(SCOFFS)
I remember the night before.
It...
It felt...
It felt lonely.
Yeah.
But you're not alone.
I'm your best bitch, remember?
Okay. Yeah.
QUENTIN: Okay,
your turn. Truth or dare?
EMILY: Truth.
QUENTIN: Do you
still blame yourself?
Shit.
Okay.
Sorry. No, I think I'm
drunker than I think I am.
Was that a sentence?
No, I said truth.
So, do you know what happened?
I mean, just what Alice told me.
That you changed
your face for a professor,
and it got screwed up, and
Charlie tried to save you.
Yeah, that's the gist.
How is Alice?
Uh, Alice is dead.
I don't blame myself.
Except for when I first wake up.
And when I go to bed,
and all the time in between.
Your turn.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Dare.
Dare...
(BOTH LAUGH)
My dare is to smoke weed?
That's very middle school.
Oh, oh.
Do you know...
Do you know Weizenheim's Third?
A tiny little weather
suspension spell.
I thought you didn't... I don't.
This doesn't count.
Today's a cheat day.
Right.
Oh, the trick to this one is
that you enchant your lips.
And you're a smoke artiste. Mmm.
Okay. Your turn.
Don't burn yourself.
How do you do it? Oh, um...
Okay, let me.
(LAUGHS)
You're a fucking dork. (SNORTS)
You're just jealous I'm such a
quick study. (CLEARS THROAT)
Yeah.
Okay.
What is it?
(WHISPERS) This
one's my favorite.
It's my favorite, too.
Ooh! Come on in.
Okay.
(EMILY SIGHS)
(WHISTLES)
Emily Greenstreet,
living the loft life, huh?
Yeah. (LAUGHS)
Wine opener?
One of those
drawers. One of them.
Wine opener.
Uh, wine opener, wine opener.
Hey.
I want to do a spell.
Why don't we keep drinking and
make some really, really bad decisions?
That sounds, I don't
know, kind of fun. Okay.
You'll like it.
Mmm. Come on.
Cheat day.
MARGO: The
Defenestration of Prague.
ELIOT: No, you
already said that.
There were two. Mmm.
Look, any hope you had of
saving this guy is out the window.
Like the guys in Prague.
Shit.
Eliot, we said we'd do
whatever actually works.
Fine. I'll tell the
Council in the morning.
But I'll do it. The man's
life is my burden to bear.
Get over yourself, Ned Stark.
(GASPS)
Ned Stark.
Do you even like magic?
Yeah, like...
Like I like money, or food,
or any other useful shit.
Money or food don't
explode in your face.
You came to Brakebills
only to ease your suffering.
The voices. It was
all chore and burden,
but you saved
yourself, Traveler.
Good.
Maybe you're simply done.
Now is your chance. Walk away.
Why? Chance at what?
Few years of happy life.
(LAUGHS)
There is bad surprise
in store. For everyone.
What surprise?
Energy currents
should be constant.
But it's not?
Why?
There is something
happening to magic.
PENNY: The
Wellspring in Fillory.
MAYAKOVSKY: The
current is sputtering.
PENNY: And
they're trying to fix it.
Maybe it's going to
disappear. If that's the case...
Shit could get real.
If magic goes, it will be
very bad time to be Magician,
so, consider the advantage
of getting out now.
All right. Okay, thank you.
I'll meditate on it. I...
Right now I'm staying.
Then you're just a fancy
scarf wrapped around an idiot!
You know what, if it's
so bad, you get out!
You leave, I'll leave.
I cannot leave.
Thanks for reminder.
What? What, you're trapped here?
Remarkably like that.
In corporate bond.
Even I cannot break.
Why?
What did you do? (SIGHS)
I'm not drunk
enough to talk about it.
Okay!
I make love to many students.
And then, I fuck the wrong one.
Oops.
And they sent you here? God.
It was that...
Or give up magic.
Like you're telling me to?
Yes.
I made my choice.
(BANGS) Wakey-wakey.
You have 15 minutes
to save your life.
Tell me, if you were in charge,
how would the FU
Fighters fix Fillory?
It's an illusion spell.
Party trick, really. Only lasts
as long as your skin's wet.
You first.
Yeah? You know, this
is the weirdest foreplay.
Oh, my God, stop. Robe off.
(LAUGHS)
Whoa, what is that?
Oh, right, I...
You joined some kind of gang?
Yes.
Okay. Hop in.
(LAUGHS)
(SPEAKING COPTIC)
Did it work?
Oh, shit.
Don't judge me, please.
I'm not. I'm just
putting it all together.
You. Charlie.
That's why he's
at Brakebills South.
I mean, I had a
lot of theories. Shh.
You're ruining it.
Just tell me what you
think when you look at me.
And could you, maybe,
try a Russian accent?
You didn't wanna...
This is what I missed the most.
So...
Your turn.
(SIGHS)
(WATER RUNNING)
It's her.
It's your memories.
Well?
Anything you wanna say?
I just really fucking miss you.
(SIGHS)
(SNIFFLES)
What is... (KNOCKING)
Is that...
Yeah.
Um, hey, I...
I've gotta get home. Um...
I had a good time.
You don't have to
go, we can do it again.
You said yesterday was
"cheat day." You can't...
You can't cheat every day.
I won't tell.
(SIGHS) No, I don't want to.
So what? You're done
with me? I was helping you.
That's not what I said.
Well, tell me then.
What are you saying?
Last night was...
It felt really
good, and it was...
Probably exactly
what I needed, but I...
It was also really
weird and sad.
And I feel awful.
I feel worse than before.
Apologies for my terrible life.
(SIGHS)
I just don't want to
use magic like that.
I'm sorry for
everything you lost.
I'll see you at work.
(DOOR CLOSES)
It is after much deliberation
that I have decided...
We will not execute
the prisoner.
What?
Your Majesty, I'm...
(ABIGAIL SQUEAKING)
It is in Fillory's
best interest.
We agreed to have the
prisoner executed today.
We did. But I changed my mind.
Well, I didn't. And
I'm High Queen.
The Queen may voice her opinion,
but ultimate judgment
belongs to the King.
So this is what the
patriarchy smells like.
It's not the freshest.
You're a king. Act like it.
I'm not just a king.
Fen is pregnant.
(CROWD MURMURING)
I'm gonna be a father.
Mmm.
And I would like to
raise my child in a world
that does not just
kill its problems away.
We hear them, and we
address them accordingly.
That is fucking stupid.
You want to rule a kingdom?
Guess what, people are
going to die, no matter what.
Just try to make sure
that it isn't you, okay?
(SIGHS)
LIA: Julia? I'll check you in.
Dr. Higgins will be ready shortly.
Okay... (SIGHS)
I'm sorry, you're not in here.
Excuse me? You don't
have an appointment.
The doctor gave me one. I
mean, there must be a mistake.
I'm sorry, but without an
appointment, I can't let you in.
Look, it's Wicker, Julia Wicker.
You just said my
name two seconds ago.
Can you just pick up
the phone and ask her?
Doctor, there's a woman
claiming she's a patient.
No, she doesn't.
Uh, Julia Wicker.
But, Doctor...
Okay.
You can go ahead.
Yeah, thanks.
I'll be right here.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
No geese!
Oh.
(GROANS)
Phew.
You finish table. Good work.
Yeah, so can we get to this?
Enough Karate Kid bullshit!
Not bullshit.
Ask yourself a question.
What will a Magician
need if dark days come?
Answer, magic.
"But if it is gone, it is
gone," you say. Not so.
If you store it. Like a battery.
That's what I'm building!
Those knots?
Old class project,
tied with magic.
That table, stained
through with magic.
You release the energy,
I store it. For rainy day.
So, my hands? Are you
gonna teach me or what?
You can travel to Fillory.
It's the worst place
in the universe, yeah.
You go there. Get this.
"Moss"? You need moss?
It's amazing. Can
carry current...
Do not care!
I'll get it.
(CHUCKLES)
Gods, it's good to
see you. You asshole!
You come here with no warning
and try to kill my husband?
Of course, I did. I
thought you were waiting.
I'm not a FU Fighter anymore.
You always knew that
one day I'd have to...
Marry him, yes, and then
you'd be here, on the inside.
You can't tell me that you
don't care about Fillory anymore.
I'm pregnant.
Then for the child... What?
All I ask is you get us
information we need to...
Bayler!
Did I say "ask"?
I meant "help us,"
or I go to your king
and tell him exactly
how well I know his wife.
Then I'll tell him myself.
Word travels fast
about the High King.
Emotional.
Easily wounded.
Try it and see.
Or help the cause.
(KNOCKS)
If the FU Fighters make
another move, I'll kill you myself.
That should do it.
How are you feeling?
Like I finally understand why
people take these kind of drugs.
Okay, we'll start the procedure.
You may feel some cramping,
and that's perfectly normal.
What...
What's wrong?
(SIGHS) Morning
cobwebs. Excuse me.
Just relax.
Okay.
What are you doing?
Wait.
Stop.
(GASPING)
Stop it! Wait! I can't.
Stop! What are you doing? No!
(STABBING SOUND)
Kady! Kady! (SOBS)
Kady! (GASPING)
(DOCTOR GASPING)
JULIA: Stop!
(SCREAMING)
(GASPING, WHIMPERING)
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. Fuck.
Oh, my...
Do it. What?
Do it. You have wards.
The thing... It got to her...
Just get it out of me, Kady.
Julia, that is a dead body. We
need to get rid of it right now.
Look, Jules. We'll
find another way.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(MOUTHING) Help me.