Previously on "Us"...
What? Just imagine a montage.
A group of fine-looking grad students
were invited to a secret school for magic
where a bunch of stuff happened
that doesn't really matter,
until they ran into
a mysterious figure.
The answer to a riddle
they didn't even know to ask.
It's you.
Do you want this recap or not?
So, yeah, it was me.
Things were awesome.
For a minute. We
became kings and queens.
Well, everybody but you.
Everyone hooked up. I had
a threesome with two harpies.
Skip to the parts about me.
JOSH: You had a lot of
drama with your hands.
You signed a billion-year
contract with the Library
to help out Kady.
Wait, who's that?
JOSH: Kady Orloff-Diaz?
Love of your life?
Looks like she could crack
open your balls, because she can?
Well, it was a
love for the ages.
Despite the fact that Kady
got in way over her head
with some hedge witches.
Especially her best bitch, Julia
Wicker. Their term, not mine.
(STAMMERS) I would never.
Whatever went down
definitely made them ex-best...
Witches.
Truthfully, the only person
Kady can stand is you.
And that pretty
much cut both ways.
No, come on, Penny,
don't... Don't... Come on.
JOSH: And then
you died. Kind of.
Meanwhile, magic
got all jacked up.
You know what's weird,
that "jacked up" is bad,
but "jacked off" is great.
Focus, dude.
So, with magic gone,
a bunch of fairy dicks
invaded Fillory, made Eliot
and Margo look like derps,
so the people revolted.
Only ray of hope?
Julia mysteriously
still has magic.
Why? Question mark!
We got sent on a dope quest to
find the Seven Keys that unlock magic.
But the fourth one got dragon-gobbled
and lost in the Underworld.
The other Penny sent us
the key, but never came back.
Then came my grand adventure.
Hard pass.
I also saved the day
in your dumb timeline.
And snagged up key seven.
Yeah, I was there for that.
You didn't save shit.
Now wait, you
skipped the Sixth Key.
This makes no goddamn sense.
No, it's intentionally
confusing.
You see, Julia saved a
bunch of fairies from slavery,
so the Fairy Queen was
like, "I have the Sixth Key,
"but I'm not going to give
it to you because she's..."
A creamy bitch is what she is.
JULIA: Meanwhile, Alice
has been acting real fishy.
Quentin was all like...
Are you working for the Library?
And she was all... Yes.
And now, if you would please
refer to the hookup/murder chart.
Penny got with the other Alice.
Interesting.
Now that we know
who porked whom,
let's go over who murdered whom.
KADY: Penny?
(EXCLAIMS)
You're Kady.
What's going on?
I'm not your Penny.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT WHISPERS)
QUENTIN: Julia?
Sorry, uh, what?
What I'm saying is, if there's
a monster behind the door,
opening the door is
probably not the smartest plan.
But that's where magic is, like...
What, we can't exactly just stop.
Plus, this didn't come from
the most reliable source.
He was you.
He was The Beast.
Making decisions like this without
understanding the consequences
is exactly why magic is gone.
So we figure out if it's true.
We... We search the
castle, find out what's inside.
We could ask the Library.
Yeah, you're right.
You should ask them.
They say they want to help.
It'd be nice if
they actually did.
I'll let you know what they say.
Q...
Do you have a better plan?
JULIA: Yeah, maybe
don't trust the Library?
They literally snort
the bones of fairies.
We don't have to trust them.
The Penny that you
brought with you,
the... Penny 23.
Yeah, look.
Ask him to follow
Alice to the Library.
He can Astral Project, they'll
never even know he was there.
Catching up on the news?
My timeline was
post-apocalyptic,
and it wasn't this fucked up.
Alice is meeting
with the Library.
We need you to follow
her on the Astral Plane.
Q thinks you're more
likely to say yes if I ask,
because you and the
other me shared a thing.
But we both know that
we're total strangers.
So... Go on.
Well... See, this is a
chance to unfuck magic.
And as a new
citizen of Timeline 40,
that should be something
you would want to do.
Whoever asks.
I have heard of the Castle
at the End of the World.
It was built by the gods, but its
contents are secret by design.
All we mortals know is that
we are not meant to know.
Why wouldn't they want
you to know what's inside?
Perhaps it is indeed the
lair of a horrifying monster.
Or perhaps they simply
enjoy tormenting those of us
who dedicate our lives
to cataloging information.
Well, whatever their motive,
we'd be idiots to
go in totally blind.
Then ask someone
who's been inside.
A god.
I believe your friends have
had encounters with them.
Now, there is another matter.
ALICE: That's the Siphon?
We thought it'd be bigger.
It needs to be powered,
and it requires a lot of energy.
Our intended source has not
fulfilled their end of our bargain.
Well, how am I
supposed to use it?
Your friend Julia.
She's powerful enough.
If her magic were
implanted into the Siphon...
She'd never go for that if
she knew what this does.
Then you'll have to take
the power from her by force.
That could kill her.
We've all made sacrifices in
pursuit of our greater purpose.
We need the Siphon
charged before...
I know.
Hmm.
I just need some time to
figure out another way, or...
I'll be in touch.
Remember.
Once magic is flowing again, you
have 30 seconds to attach the Siphon.
If you miss that window,
our chance is gone forever.
JOSH: I come bearing gifts.
This is, like, 80%
taco supplies.
I'm sorry, do they not
have Tuesdays in Fillory?
Feel free to do your own
grocery shopping next time.
No, no. If I have to
catch, pluck, or boil
one more pigeon, I'm going
to hurl myself off this ship.
I was gone a lot longer
than I thought I would be.
(SIGHS)
Listen, Fen.
Before you were born, you
were promised to a stranger.
A king.
And I'm not one anymore.
You don't have to
stay for my sake.
I'm guessing you've never thought about
where I would be if you never showed up.
I have.
Still in that same
village where I was born,
married to one of the three
obnoxious boys I lived next to.
Now those boys want
to drop you off a waterfall,
and that's them being polite.
What do you think they would
do if they got their hands on me?
That got less
touching as you went.
I can't go back to my old life.
I'm stuck with you, and that
means you're stuck with me.
We've been trying to
negotiate with the Fairy Queen
for the last key, but
this is what we got back.
Eat my ass! We're not sure if...
BUNNY: Eat my ass!
We're not sure
if... Eat. My. Ass!
If this was the Fairy Queen's
response or this is one very kinky rabbit.
Maybe there's something
we can do to get her attention?
BUNNY: Eat. My. Ass.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
FRAY: These are on the house.
For you saving my life.
We need to talk to your Queen.
You must know how
to get her to come.
It's an emergency. FRAY: No.
The last time I saw her,
she threatened to murder me.
Glass half full. She didn't
actually go through with it.
But you must have fairy stepsisters
or someone you can talk to?
There were no fairy
children in the Realm.
Just humans they bargained
away from their real parents.
Like me.
Being sent to you
ruined everything.
I can't go back to
the Fairy Realm,
I don't fit in with humans.
Why do you think I
work at an animal bar?
No, really, really,
I'm not judging you.
Trust me, I'm not judging you.
Now you show up and want
to make things even worse.
Look, it's too late for me to
fix your fucked-up childhood.
But what we want
to offer the Queen
would mean real peace
for humans and fairies.
Maybe the distance between
us can finally start to close.
And maybe then, you
won't feel so alone.
That's kind.
But just so you
know, I'm not alone.
MARGO: No, really.
Bye, Margo.
Bye, Humbledrum.
I love that bear.
So do I.
Yeah, hooray for bears, but we
were kind of having a moment.
No, honey, she "loves" him.
Uh, so not bear
boss. Bear boyfriend?
Is that a thing in Fillory?
Apparently, very taboo.
But like I told Humbledrum,
as long as it's consensual,
if I got my way, I'd say go
hog-wild or bear-wild or bull-wild.
He's very concerned
about getting your approval.
I don't think he quite gets that
you're not even Fray's real dad.
Well, then...
I will say what I wish
my father had said to me.
I'm so happy
you're dating a bear.
Thanks...
Dad.
HUMBLEDRUM: Thanks, Fray's dad.
No problem.
ALICE: That's all
the Librarian knows.
We have to find someone
who's been inside the castle.
So...
A god. You say
that like it's easy.
Our Lady Underground
hasn't answered me in months.
Yeah, the only way to track
Bacchus down was his Instagram
and it looks like it got deleted
for terms of service violations.
Nipples, apparently.
Well, that's bullshit.
I'll ask Dean Fogg.
If I can catch him
when he's sober, maybe.
She's lying.
Not about the god
stuff, that's true.
It's what she's leaving out.
They have some sort of
metal thing called a "Siphon."
She's supposed to charge it
up by ripping out Julia's power,
which could kill her.
She didn't seem psyched about
the idea, but she didn't say no.
So, now what?
PENNY 23: What's
that? Truth Key?
If it was, I'd tell
you to go away.
Unity.
The walkie-talkie key.
You're trying to talk
to the other Penny.
No offense... You're
the "other Penny".
Look.
I don't blame you. You're
just trying to survive.
It's... It's everyone else.
Acting like finding
you is enough,
when our Penny, the
real Penny, is out there.
Down there.
And maybe if...
If we talk to him,
we could help him.
What?
Just... All that shit that
you did for the other me.
The only person that
would have done that for me
on my timeline is Julia.
Yeah, well...
(SNIFFLES)
Our Julia is different.
She is not the person you loved.
You don't owe me anything.
But for what it's worth, it'd
be helpful if you explained it.
How she's different.
What about Reynard?
What happened to him
after OLU. took him away?
I don't know.
But it was his spark that
Our Lady gave to Julia.
I know it's not about me.
None of it ever
really felt about me.
So I've, uh...
Never really known how to deal
with how angry I am at all of it.
Wait, so he could be out there?
Still a god, but powerless?
I guess.
And only gods know
what's behind the door.
No.
We have to find Reynard.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Thank you for coming. I actually
have nothing to say to you.
I know what you want.
And I can't give it to you.
We get it.
Humans will chop you
up and snort your innards.
But not all humans are
like that, you know that.
FEN: We aren't.
I told Julia about our key
to give you all a chance
to give up on your quest.
We aren't questing,
we are surrendering.
We are giving you what you want,
a nice, quiet, moist-as-hell
spot on Fillory for you to settle.
And you give us the key.
Or... I walk away.
And when the Lorians,
Floaters, and Western Hordes
are done with
Fillory, I can take it.
All of it.
Our lifespans dwarf
even the dwarves.
We can wait for what we want.
Oh, but you can't, can you?
You see, Fray, well, she told us
that there are no fairy
children in your realm.
So... That's a prob.
ELIOT: That's why you planted your
eggs in the Northern Orchard, isn't it?
You can't reproduce
in the Fairy Realm.
Without Fillory, you go extinct.
MARGO: Fine, ignore the problem.
Your egg hole's
only getting dustier.
You no longer speak
for the people of Fillory.
Tick Pickwick does.
And he has no
interest in a deal.
If you want my key,
come back with a crown.
Or an army.
I pray to you, Our
Lady Underground.
Please don't be
withholding for once.
(INDISTINCT WHISPERS)
DEAN: God damn it!
Hello?
(WHISPERING STOPS)
JULIA: Dean Fogg?
Were you talking in here?
No, I was not. Why?
I... I woke up this morning
with this ringing in my ears.
You should get that checked.
By someone who isn't me.
But it's not just that.
I can feel what other
people are feeling.
You were given
the power of a god.
Spiritual people might say
that you're hearing prayers.
I heard you.
I felt something
coming from you.
What, exactly?
Desperation.
(CHUCKLES)
Look, I think that I'm
supposed to help you...
No, I do not need your help.
Yes, you do.
Your eyes...
Were injured magically, and fixing
them with magic risks changing
the very core of who I am.
Do you understand?
Yes.
If you did it, or
another Magician.
But that's not
what I am, exactly.
If I'm hearing prayers, I'm supposed
to do something about them.
Why give me this otherwise?
(SIGHING HEAVILY)
(WIND BLOWING)
You know, I put a little
leftover pigeon in my taco,
and it's really... Really bad.
MARGO: We need the
key to get back magic.
We need our
thrones to get the key.
We need magic
to get our thrones.
It is an ouroboros of ass.
Maybe King Idri and the Stone
Queen will back our claims.
We defeat Tick's
army, storm the castle...
JOSH: Yes, and,
what if we replace the part
where we kill everyone with...
Oh, off the top of
my head, democracy?
Like we were going to do
before magic got borked?
Tick's the only one who
can call for an election,
and he's got nothing to gain.
Oh, he'll call
for it, all right.
Josh, I need you
to go to Kinko's.
PICKWICK:
Election? What is this?
There are thousands of them.
They were falling from the sky.
Over villages,
farms, a brothel...
I... Happened
to... Be walking by.
Collect them all and burn them.
Of course, your grumpiness.
But as Abigail
wisely reminded me,
the citizens now believe
they're getting elections.
You'd have to be the one
to announce they're not.
Given the revolutionary mood
the people have been in recently...
Your plan worked.
Tick already started putting
up his own campaign flyers.
Of course it worked.
Giving people shit is easy.
Taking it away is
almost impossible.
Like Obamacare.
Or herpes.
ELIOT: Too true, Bambi.
Speaking of difficult conversations with
a former lover, do you have a second?
Why the fuck shouldn't
my name be on that ballot?
Because we are running for king.
We can call the job whatever
we want after we win it.
It has been a struggle to bring
this place into the 20th century.
Yes, 20th,
because when we got here,
it was straight-up Dark Ages,
and we have to start somewhere.
Yeah, we're really
civilizing them.
What should we teach
them next, to outlaw abortion?
Women don't want to work?
Wage gaps? Thigh gaps?
Fillory is patriarchal.
And we've got to put
our best foot forward.
And I'm sorry, but in this case,
our foot should have a dick.
What, Josh?
Do you have some patronizing
bullshit to tell me, too?
No. Could you drop me
off at the Earth portal tree?
I have an idea, but I need...
JULIA: Me?
How did you...
Yeah, I have no idea.
Hi, Margo.
I felt you needed my help.
And now I'm here.
It's been a weird day.
JULIA: Can't believe I did this.
This forest fed so many people.
Not for nothing, but when
I was at my lowest point,
that tiny spell you showed me,
it's what got me
back in the fight.
Magic is the thing that makes
the Children of Earth special.
All I'm asking is, try.
(SIGHS)
(GROUND CRACKING)
(GROUND RUMBLING)
Vote Children of Earth.
Vote the Children of Earth!
Step right up, grab a poster.
(INDISTINCT WHISPERS)
We need to talk.
Look, Quentin...
What is a Siphon?
And why do you
need Julia to power it?
You spied on me?
What does it do?
It's a safeguard. That's all.
The Library wants
to turn magic back on.
And once it's back on,
they want to make sure
it doesn't get used for the
wrong things by the wrong people.
So, the Siphon diverts
magic to the Library so that
they can choose who can use it?
Look, you took a test
to get into Brakebills.
If you failed, you would
have gotten sent away,
with no memory of magic.
Happily ignorant.
But because a group of smart individuals
made a judgment call, they let you in.
Why should the
Library get to choose?
They're corrupt,
they're killers.
Yeah, so are we.
At least they have the
information, the perspective.
You love magic, and you're
probably the best there is at it.
You're terrified of
what you'll do with it.
I have reason to be.
I don't know everything
that you did as a Niffin,
but I know that people make mistakes
so that they can change and do better.
But only if they're
given the chance.
Taking away choice
is not the answer.
There are seven keys,
and we have eight questers.
We can do this
without you, and we will.
Unless you give me the Siphon.
Just remember that
when magic was turned off,
your dad went into remission, Q.
And once you turn it back on,
his cancer comes
back, and he dies.
Straw polls are in, and
our ratings are way up.
I mean, off the charts.
Julia has done us
the solidest solid.
After the trees, she grew
food for the starving peasants.
She fixed the dry wells.
She even helped this one
guy's bajanked case of head lice.
I mean, Children of
Earth are back on top!
(JOSH EXCLAIMS)
Her Flealessness suggests that your
time as high king has been so brief,
the Fillorian people don't
yet know what you stand for.
I stand for them.
I stand for economic stability.
For a solid,
well-researched strategy.
PICKWICK: That's it.
I'm going to tell them,
in detail, my plan.
Rafe, write this down.
My fellow Fillorians, I hereby
set forth my policy to restore
economic and societal
growth to a reunified Fillory...
Blah, blah, blah, blah.
(SIGHS) So uninspiring.
Does he really think he can
win by boring them to death?
Josh!
I hereby declare
all native Fillorians
shall receive ten free
sacks of grain every year.
MARGO: And how exactly are we
supposed to grow that much grain,
even with magic?
You're making a
promise you can't keep.
Bambi, first rule
of politics on Earth.
All you have to do is say it.
It doesn't have to be
true. (EXCITED CHATTER)
I hereby declare,
under my administration,
low-interest loans for
all new infrastructure.
Easy. No-interest loans.
And we're going to
build Fillory's first...
"Power... Plants."
Like, geraniums?
Will Tick's granular policies
keep you warm at night?
No. You know what will?
Extending the Fillorian summer.
My proposition for
growth in new sectors...
Free healthcare for
all! Based on rigorous
survey research...
Champagne fountains
in every village. PICKWICK:
The abatement of dependency
on the Golden Goose standard.
Wealth!
PICKWICK: Regulation of agricultural
waste to prevent environmental runoff.
Feasts. Annual famine
and rampant poverty.
Boat parties!
ALL: Three cheers for Eliot!
Hooray, hooray, hooray!
Eliot, I am so
sorry. What is it?
Tick's campaign just leaked
the transcript from your trial.
You mean the one where he called
Fillory "a malodorous shithole"?
FEN: It's already hit the posts.
Son of a Pickwick.
KADY: Julia, what the fuck...
JULIA: There's a
little boy in Syracuse.
I can feel his parents praying.
I know if I just focus enough,
I can bring down his fever.
I feel bad interrupting this.
But we need your
help with something.
Finding Reynard.
I know.
But we need to talk to a god.
I want to help you, but...
KADY: Julia.
You have all the power now.
Yeah, but he's
still a trickster.
We don't know
what he's capable of.
Look, nobody hates that
he's still alive more than me.
But if we don't do it, we're
at a complete standstill.
All you'd have to
do is locate him,
power up Penny's tattoos,
and we'll take it from there.
You can also say no.
I'm not going to
send you there alone.
Great.
All right, I'll get the
stuff for the locator.
There's no need.
I can feel him with my mind.
You guys ready?
Wait, what are you...
(WIND WHOOSHING)
This is the place.
He's nearby.
I have to say, this is
pretty disappointing.
Yeah.
We were all kind of hoping to find
Reynard showering in a Russian prison.
(GRUNTS) (ALARM BEEPING)
Oh, shit.
PENNY 23: Roxane Gay,
bell hooks, feminist lit?
What, are you saving these
for a rapist book-burning party?
I've changed.
Living amongst the
humans has given me
a whole new perspective.
You're still a liar and pathetic,
but I guess you always were.
(SIGHS)
Why are you here?
What could I have that
you could possibly want?
Let's talk about the Castle
at the End of the World.
What's inside?
How do you guys
know about that place?
Answer her question.
You're not thinking of
going there, are you?
You know there's a reason
the gods had the Architect
put it at the end of the world?
"The Architect"?
It's not for you
little guys to know.
It's funny...
'Cause from where I stand,
you're the little guy now.
(LAUGHING)
You have all my
power, and look at you.
Trying to handle something
you cannot handle.
You should have kept your mouth
shut and stayed in your place.
You've gotten yourself
into some real trouble now.
You think it's easy being a god?
You feel that?
Your tiny spark
has grown bigger in me
than it could have ever in you.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
You want the truth
about the Castle?
The Castle's where the gods
put the stuff they made before us.
The stuff that didn't work out.
Mistakes that never
should have happened.
Kinda like you. I
hope you do go.
Open that door,
see what happens!
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
No!
Recognize it?
Yeah.
I made it to kill him.
How did you get this?
Did Our Lady give it to you?
(BREATHES
HEAVILY) Of course not.
My mother left me here to rot.
My stepfather Hades was the
only one that took pity on me.
He slipped me that gun to shoot
myself in case of emergency.
I'm still a god.
Limp or not, we're hard to kill.
What are you willing to
bet this god-killing bullet
will work on the
monster in the Castle?
The fate of the world?
That's good enough for me.
Whoa, that's it?
You're just going
to leave him there?
After what he did
to the both of you?
Shoot him.
Kady, you wanted this.
I wanted him to be
punished for what he did.
And he is.
Leave him here.
I am here to deliver the
official election results.
Eliot has lost.
Shocker.
Uh...
Tick has also lost.
Um, what?
Our new High King...
Is Margo.
But I... I wasn't
even on the ballot.
You won as a write-in.
Who wrote me in?
The talking animals.
It seems you were the only
human on the campaign trail
who stopped to listen
to their concerns.
You mean that drunk bear?
Humbledrum is a highly respected
member of the community.
You see, there are certain taboo
subjects you broached with him.
Bestiality?
The talking animals believe
that if they were allowed
to inter-marry with humans,
then humans will finally
see them as equals.
None of us were brave enough to speak
out in support of the cause, until you.
You really love
that sloth, don't you?
So the human vote basically
means nothing in Fillory.
Considering there's never been
an election or census before,
we had no idea there were
only 50,000 humans in Fillory,
and upwards of a
million talking animals.
So... Yes.
On behalf of Abigail,
let me be the first
to swear loyalty to
the new administration.
El...
I'm so sorry.
And allow me to be the second.
High King Margo.
Long may you reign.
(WHIMPERS)
(CHEERING AND APPLAUDING)
(WHOOPING AND CHEERING)
Hey, Tick.
I intend to choose Death
by a Thousand Pokes.
They say you only feel
the first hundred or so.
Tick, we're not
going to execute you.
If you proved anything
during your campaign,
it's that Fillory needs
a policy wonk like you.
You're still
bitch-listed, but...
King Margo would
like you in her cabinet.
(GASPS)
With a full 24-hour security
detail watching everything you do.
We don't trust you,
but we need you.
(CHUCKLES)
Citizenship for every fairy,
full protection of the law,
and a seat in the government.
But we need the key.
And you shall have it.
Once the last fairies have
been moved to our new home.
I always saw something in you.
Even when you
didn't see it in yourself.
Now, perhaps you will.
(GASPS)
MARGO: You gave me...
I can... I can see
all sorts of things.
It's a fairy eye.
A gift you will learn
to understand in time.
But one you must
hide in plain sight.
(GASPS SOFTLY)
Could I maybe get
some fairy toes?
Hello?
MARGO: Cranky as shit.
JOSH: Just take
a little off the top.
MARGO: I just
collapsed my entire rental.
QUENTIN: Last time,
we were... Oh, my God...
JOSH: Are we
supposed to sing again?
ELIOT: Holy shit, no.
MARGO: We've got news!
Penny, is that you? PENNY: Yeah.
MARGO: We just got the
last key from the fairies.
Okay, everyone just
shut up! It's Penny.
All right, look, listen.
I don't know how
much time we have.
PENNY: Kady. But
I'm going to get you out
of the Underworld, no
matter what it takes, I promise.
PENNY 23: Kady. I love you.
This is Penny 23.
The key replaced
my Penny with you.
Look, I'm really sorry.
(CLATTERS)
(BREATH TREMBLES)
JULIA: This is it.
The end of the story.
Floodgates of magic,
ready to be opened.
Q? What's up, what's wrong?
The quest is
supposed to change us.
I've sacrificed everything
that it wanted me to
up to this point,
and I... I can't...
You thought that
when you got here,
you'd be 150% sure you
were doing the right thing.
Now, you're only
somewhere around 70%.
Because you're
worried about your dad.
Party trick.
I just feel things.
I heard you healed
Dean Fogg's eyes.
Maybe...
I could heal your dad?
Right now, he's
perfectly healthy.
There's nothing to do.
If magic comes back,
a lot of dominoes will fall
in ways that we can't predict.
I don't know if I'll be
able to help or not.
It's the deal.
Sorry it's vague.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
What if the thing that the
quest wants me to be is cold?
Being willing to sacrifice
the people I love?
Then the quest fucked up
when it chose Quentin Coldwater.
Maybe.
It's all real.
The Chatwins and Fillory.
I've been there.
I... I sat on a throne
in Whitespire, and I...
I explored the Flying Forest.
And I... Met Ember and Umber.
(CHUCKLES)
I remember reading
you those books.
Curly Q...
If all that's out there...
What are you doing here?
I'm on a quest.
TED: In New Jersey?
I have a problem.
And I don't know what to do.
No matter what choice I
make, somebody gets hurt.
Magic's gone.
Isn't it?
I'm not like you.
I'm not a Magician.
But I could feel it
when it was gone.
And I knew it
wasn't a coincidence
when I went into
remission a week later.
QUENTIN: You're right.
My friends and I
were trying to fix it.
And how's that been going?
We're getting really close.
So are you here to
ask my permission?
To...
Turn it back on?
On this quest...
I've lived a whole life.
I grew old, and I got
married. And I had a son.
Who grew old.
And what was all that
for if it's not for this?
No, I'm not here to
ask for your permission.
I wanted to look you in the eye
and tell you that I'm sorry.
I don't know what's
going to happen.
But I'm going to do this.
What was his name?
Your son.
I named him after you.