Previously on "Us"...
- What?
- Just imagine a montage.
A group of fine looking grad students
were invited to a secret school for magic
where a bunch of stuff happened
that doesn't really matter,
until they ran into a mysterious figure.
The answer to a riddle they
didn't even know to ask.
It's you.
Do you want this recap or not?
So yeah, it was me. Things were awesome.
For a minute. We became kings and queens.
Well, everybody but you.
Everyone hooked up, I had a
threesome with two harpies.
Just get to the parts about me.
You had a lot of drama with your hands.
You signed a billion-year
contract with the Library
- to help out Kady.
- Wait, who's that?
Kady Orloff-Diaz? Love of your life?
Looks like she could
crack open your balls,
because she can?
Well, it was a love for the ages.
Despite the fact that Kady
got in way over her head
with some hedge witches.
Especially her best bitch,
Julia Wicker. Their term, not mine.
I would never. Whatever went down
definitely made them ex-best...
Witches. Truthfully,
the only person Kady can stand is you.
And that pretty much cut both ways.
No, come on, Penny,
don't... don't... Come on.
And then you died. Kind of.
Meanwhile, magic got all jacked up.
You know what's weird,
that jacked up is bad,
- but jacked off is great.
- Focus, dude.
So, with magic gone,
a bunch of Fairy dicks
invaded Fillory, made Eliot
and Margo look like derps,
so the people revolted. Only ray of hope?
Julia mysteriously still has magic.
Why? Question mark!
We got sent on a dope quest
to find the Seven Keys that unlock magic.
But the fourth one got dragon gobbled
and lost in the Underworld.
The other Penny sent us the key,
but never came back.
- Then came my grand adventure.
- Hard pass.
I also saved the day
in your dumb timeline.
- And snagged up Key seven.
- Yeah, I was there for that.
And you didn't save shit.
Now wait, you skipped the Sixth Key.
This makes no goddamn sense.
No, it's intentionally confusing.
You see, Julia saved a bunch
of Fairies from slavery,
So the Fairy Queen was
like, I have the Sixth Key,
but I'm not going to give
it to you because she's...
A creamy bitch is what she is.
Meanwhile, Alice has
been acting real fishy.
Quentin was all like...
Are you working for the Library?
- And she was all...
- Yes.
And now, if you would please refer
to the hookup/murder chart.
Penny got with the other Alice.
- Interesting.
- Now that we know
who porked whom, let's
go over who murdered whom.
Penny.
You're Kady.
- What's going on?
- I'm not your Penny.
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --
Julia?
- Sorry, uh, what?
- What I'm saying is,
if there's a monster behind the door,
opening the door is probably
not the smartest plan.
But that's where magic is, like...
what, we can't exactly just
stop. Plus, this didn't come
- from the most reliable source.
- He was you.
- He was the Beast.
- Making decisions like this
without understanding the consequences
is exactly why magic is gone.
So we figure out if it's true.
We... we search the castle,
find out what's inside.
We could ask the Library.
Yeah, you're right. You should ask them.
They say they want to help.
It'd be nice if they actually did.
I'll let you know what they say.
Q...
Do you have a better plan?
Yeah, maybe don't trust the Library?
They literally snort
the bones of Fairies.
We don't have to trust them.
The Penny that you brought with you,
- The...
- Penny 23.
Yeah, look. Ask him to follow Alice
to the Library. He can Astral Project,
they'll never even know he was there.
Catching up on the news?
My timeline was post apocalyptic,
and it wasn't this fucked up.
Alice is meeting with the Library.
We need you to follow
her on the Astral Plane.
Q thinks you're more
likely to say yes if I ask,
because you and the
other me shared a thing.
But we both know that
we're total strangers.
- So...
- Go on.
Well see, this is a
chance to un-fuck magic.
And as a new citizen of Timeline 40,
that should be something
you would want to do.
Whoever asks.
I have heard of the Castle
at the End of the World.
It was built by the
gods, but its contents
are secret by design.
All we mortals know
is that we are not meant to know.
Why wouldn't they want
you to know what's inside?
Perhaps it is indeed the
lair of a horrifying monster.
Or perhaps they simply
enjoy tormenting those of us
who dedicate our lives to
cataloguing information.
Well whatever their motive,
we'd be idiots to go in totally blind.
Then ask someone who's been inside.
A god. I believe your friends
have had encounters with them.
Now, there is another matter.
That's the Siphon?
We thought it'd be bigger.
It needs to be powered, and
it requires a lot of energy.
Our intended source has not fulfilled
their end of our bargain.
Well, how are we supposed to use it?
Your friend Julia.
She's powerful enough.
If her magic were
implanted into the Siphon...
She'd never go for that
if she knew what this does.
Then you'll have to take
the power from her by force.
That could kill her.
We've all made sacrifices in
pursuit of our greater purpose.
We need the Siphon charged before...
I know.
I just need some time to
figure out another way, or...
- I'll be in touch.
- Remember.
Once magic is flowing again,
you have 30 seconds
to attach the Siphon.
If you miss that window,
our chance is gone forever.
I come bearing gifts.
This is like, 80% taco supplies.
I'm sorry, do they not
have Tuesdays in Fillory?
Feel free to do your own
grocery shopping next time.
No, no, if I have to
catch, pluck, or boil
one more pigeon, I'm going
to hurl myself off this ship.
I was gone a lot longer
than I thought it would be.
Listen, Fen.
Before you were born, you were promised
to a stranger. A king.
And I'm not one anymore.
You don't have to stay for my sake.
I'm guessing you've never thought about
where I would be if you never showed up.
I have.
Still in that same
village where I was born,
married to one of the three
obnoxious boys I lived next to.
Now those boys want to
drop you off a waterfall,
and that's them being polite.
What do you think they would do
if they got their hands on me?
That got less touching as you went.
I can't go back to my old life.
I'm stuck with you, and that
means you're stuck with me.
We've been trying to
negotiate with the Fairy Queen
for the last Key, but
this is what we got back.
- Eat my ass!
- We're not sure if...
Eat my ass!
Eat. My. Ass!
If this was the Fairy Queen's response
or this is one very kinky rabbit.
Maybe there's something we
can do to get her attention?
Eat. My. Ass.
These are on the house.
For you saving my life.
We need to talk to your Queen.
You must know how to get her to come.
- It's an emergency.
- No.
The last time I saw her,
she threatened to murder me.
Glass half full... she didn't
actually go through with it.
But you must have Fairy stepsisters
or someone you can talk to?
There were no Fairy
children in the realm.
Just humans they bargained
away from their real parents.
Like me.
Being sent to you ruined everything.
I can't go back to the Fairy Realm.
I don't fit in with
humans. Why do you think
- I work at an animal bar?
- No, really,
really, I'm not judging you.
Trust me, I'm not judging you.
Now you show up and want
to make things even worse.
Look, it's too late for me to
fix your fucked up childhood.
But what we want to offer the Queen
would mean real peace
for humans and fairies.
Maybe the distance between
us can finally start to close.
And maybe then, you won't feel so alone.
That's kind.
But just so you know, I'm not alone.
No, really.
Bye, Margo.
Bye, Humbledrum.
I love that bear.
So do I.
Yeah, hooray for bears, but we were
- kind of having a moment.
- No, honey,
she loves him.
Uh, so not bear boss. Bear boyfriend?
- Is that a thing in Fillory?
- Apparently, very taboo.
But like I told Humbledrum,
as long as it's consensual,
if I got my way, I'd say go hog wild
or bear wild or bull wild.
He's very concerned about
getting your approval.
I don't think he quite gets
that you're not even Fray's real dad.
Well, then...
I will say what I wish
my father had said to me.
I'm so happy you're dating a bear.
Thanks...
Dad.
Thanks, Fray's dad.
No problem.
That's all the Librarian knows.
We have to find somebody
who's been inside the Castle.
So...
A god. You say that like it's easy.
Our Lady Underground hasn't
answered me in months.
Yeah, the only way to track Bacchus down
was his Instagram, and it
looks like it got deleted
for terms of service violations.
Nipples, apparently.
Well, that's bullshit.
I'll ask Dean Fogg.
If I can catch him
when he's sober, maybe.
She's lying.
Not about the god stuff, that's true.
It's what she's leaving out.
They have some sort of metal thing
called a Siphon. She's
supposed to charge it up
by ripping out Julia's
power, which could kill her.
She didn't seem psyched about the idea,
but she didn't say no.
So, now what?
What's that? Truth Key?
If it was, I'd tell you to go away.
Unity.
The walkie-talkie key.
You're trying to talk
to the other Penny.
No offense... you're the other Penny.
Look.
I don't blame you. You're
just trying to survive.
It's... it's everyone else.
Acting like finding you is enough.
When our Penny, the real Penny,
is out there. Down there.
And maybe if...
we talk to him, we could help him.
- Oh, what?
- Just...
all that shit that you
did for the other me.
The only person that
would have done that for me
on my timeline is Julia.
Yeah, well...
our Julia is different.
She is not the person you loved.
You don't owe me anything.
But for what it's worth,
it'd be helpful if you explained it.
How she's different.
What about Reynard?
What happened to him
after O.L.U. took him away?
I don't know.
But it was his spark that
Our Lady gave to Julia.
And now it's not about me.
None of it ever really felt about me.
So I've, uh...
never really known how to deal
with how angry I am at all of it.
Wait, so he could be out there?
Still a god, but powerless?
I guess.
And only gods know
what's behind the door.
No.
We have to find Reynard.
Thank you for coming. I actually have
nothing to say to you.
I know what you want.
- And I can't give it to you.
- We get it.
Humans will chop you up
and snort your innards.
But not all humans are
like that, you know that.
- We aren't.
- I told Julia about our Key
to give you all a chance
to give up on your quest.
We aren't questing, we are surrendering.
We are giving you what you want...
A nice, quiet, moist as hell spot
on Fillory for you to settle.
And you give us the Key.
Or... I walk away.
And when the Lorians,
Floaters, and Western Hordes
are done with Fillory, I can take it.
All of it.
Our lifespans dwarf even the dwarves.
We can wait for what we want.
Oh, but you can't, can you?
You see, Fray, well, she told us
that there are no Fairy
children in your realm.
So... that's a prob.
That's why you planted your eggs
in the Northern Orchard, isn't it?
You can't reproduce in the Fairy Realm.
Without Fillory, you go extinct.
Fine, ignore the problem.
Your egg hole's only getting dustier.
You no longer speak for
the people of Fillory.
Tick Pickwick does.
And he has no interest in a deal.
If you want my Key,
come back with a crown.
Or an army.
I pray to you, Our Lady Underground.
Please don't be withholding for once.
- God damn it!
- Hello?
Dean Fogg?
Were you talking in here?
No, I was not, why?
I, um, I woke up this morning
with this ringing in my ears.
You should get that checked.
By someone who isn't me.
But it's not just that.
I can feel what other
people are feeling.
You were given the power of a god.
Spiritual people might say
that you're hearing prayers.
I heard you.
I felt something coming from you.
What, exactly?
Desperation.
Oh.
Look, I think that I'm
supposed to help you...
No, I do not need your help.
Yes, you do.
- Your eyes...
- Were injured magically,
and fixing them with
magic risks changing
the very core of who I
am. Do you understand?
Yes.
If you did it, or another Magician.
But that's not what I am, exactly.
If I'm hearing prayers, I'm supposed
to do something about them.
Why give me this otherwise?
You know, I put a little
leftover pigeon in my taco,
and it's really...
really bad.
We need the Key to get back magic.
We need our thrones to get the Key.
We need magic to get our thrones.
It is an ouroboros of ass.
Maybe King Idri and the Stone Queen
will back our claims.
We defeat Tick's army,
- storm the castle...
- Yes, and,
what if we replace the part
where we kill everyone with...
Oh, off the top of my head... democracy?
Like we were going to do
before magic got borked?
Tick's the only one who
can call for an election,
and he's got nothing to gain.
Oh, he'll call for it, all right.
Josh, I need you to go to Kinko's.
Election? What is this?
There are thousands of them.
They were falling from the sky.
Over villages, farms, a brothel...
I... happened to... be walking by.
Collect them all and burn them.
Of course, your grumpiness.
But as Abigail wisely reminded me,
the citizens now believe
they're getting elections.
You'd have to be the one
to announce they're not.
Given the revolutionary mood
the people have been in recently...
Your plan worked.
Tick already started putting
up his own campaign flyers.
Of course it worked.
Giving people shit is easy.
Taking it away is almost impossible.
Like Obamacare.
Or herpes. Too true, Bambi.
Speaking of difficult conversations
with a former lover,
do you have a second?
Why the fuck shouldn't
my name be on that ballot?
Because we are running for king.
We can call the job whatever
we want after we win it.
It has been a struggle
to bring this place
into the 20th century. Yes, 20th,
because when we got here,
it was straight up Dark Ages,
and we have to start somewhere.
Yeah, we're really civilizing them.
What should we teach them
next? To outlaw abortion?
Women don't want to work?
Wage gaps? Thigh gaps?
Fillory is patriarchal.
And we've got to put
our best foot forward.
And I'm sorry, but in this case,
our foot should have a dick.
What, Josh?
Do you have some patronizing
bullshit to tell me, too?
No, uh, could you drop me
off at the Earth portal tree?
- I have an idea, but I need...
- Me?
- How did you...
- Yeah, I have no idea.
Hi, Margo. I felt you needed my help.
And now I'm here. It's been a weird day.
Can't believe I did this.
This forest fed so many people.
Not for nothing,
but when I was at my lowest point,
that tiny spell you showed me,
it's what got me back in the fight.
Magic is the thing that makes
the children of Earth special.
All I'm asking is, try.
Vote Children of Earth.
Vote the Children of Earth!
Step right up, grab a poster.
We need to talk.
- Look, Quentin...
- What is a Siphon?
And why do you need Julia to power it?
- You spied on me?
- What does it do?
It's a safeguard. That's all.
The Library wants to turn magic back on.
And once it's back on,
they want to make sure
it doesn't get used for the wrong things
- by the wrong people.
- So, the Siphon diverts
magic to the Library so that
they can choose who can use it?
Look, you took a test
to get into Brakebills.
If you failed, you would
have gotten sent away,
with no memory of
magic. Happily ignorant.
But because a group of smart individuals
made a judgment call, they let you in.
Why should the Library get to choose?
They're corrupt, they're killers.
Yeah, so are we.
At least they have the information,
the perspective.
You love magic, and you're probably
the best there is at it.
You're terrified of
what you'll do with it.
- I have reason to be.
- I don't know everything
that you did as a niffin, but
I know that people make mistakes
so that they can change and do better.
But only if they're given the chance.
Taking away choice is not the answer.
There are seven Keys, and
we have eight questers.
We can do this without you, and we will.
Unless you give me the Siphon.
Just remember that when
magic was turned off,
your dad went into remission, Q.
And once you turn it back
on, his cancer comes back,
and he dies.
Straw polls are in, and
our ratings are way up.
I mean, off the charts.
Julia has done us
the solidest solid. After the trees,
she grew food for the starving peasants.
She fixed the dry wells.
She even helped this one guy's
bajanked case of head lice.
I mean, Children of
Earth are back on top!
Her Flealessness suggests
that your time as High King
has been so brief, the Fillorian people
don't yet know what you stand for.
I stand for them. I stand
for economic stability.
For a solid, well-researched strategy.
That's it.
I'm going to tell them,
in detail, my plan.
Rafe, write this down.
My fellow Fillorians, I hereby set forth
my policy to restore
economic and societal growth
to a reunified Fillory...
Blah, blah, blah, blah. So uninspiring.
Does he really think he can
win by boring them to death?
Josh!
I hereby declare all native Fillorians
shall receive ten free
sacks of grain every year.
And how exactly are we supposed to
grow that much grain, even with magic?
You're making a promise you can't keep.
Bambi, first rule of
politics on Earth...
All you have to do is say it.
It doesn't have to be true.
I hereby declare,
under my administration,
low-interest loans for
all new infrastructure.
Easy. No-interest loans.
And we're going to
build Fillory's first...
Power... plants.
Like, geraniums?
Will Tick's granular policies
keep you warm at night?
No, you know what will?
Extending the Fillorian summer.
My proposition for
growth in new sectors...
- Free healthcare for all!
- Based on rigorous
- rigorous survey research...
- Champagne fountains
- in every village.
- The abatement of dependency
- on the Golden Goose standard.
- Wealth!
Regulation of agricultural waste
to prevent environmental runoff.
- Feasts.
- Annual famine
- and rampant poverty.
- Boat parties!
Three cheers for Eliot!
Hooray, hooray, hooray!
- Eliot, I am so sorry.
- What is it?
Tick's campaign just leaked
the transcript from your trial.
You mean the one where he called Fillory
a malodorous shithole?
It's already hit the Posts.
Son of a Pickwick.
Julia, what the fuck...
There's a little boy in Syracuse.
I can feel his parents praying.
I know if I just focus enough,
I can bring down his fever.
I feel bad interrupting this.
But we need your help with something.
Finding Reynard.
I know.
But we need to talk to a god.
- I want to help you, but...
- Julia.
You have all the power now.
Yeah, but he's still a trickster.
We don't know what he's capable of.
Look, nobody hates that he's
still alive more than me.
But if we don't do it...
we're at a complete standstill.
All you'd have to do is locate him,
power up Penny's tattoos,
and we'll take it from there.
You can also say no.
I'm not going to send you there alone.
Great.
All right, I'll get the
stuff for the locater.
There's no need.
I can feel him with my mind.
- You guys ready?
- Wait, what are you...
This is the place. He's nearby.
I have to say, this is
pretty disappointing.
Yeah.
We were all kind of
hoping to find Reynard
showering in a Russian prison.
Oh, shit.
Roxanne Gay, Bell hooks, feminist lit?
What, are you saving these for
a rapist book burning party?
I've changed.
Living amongst the humans
has given me a whole new perspective.
You're still a liar and pathetic,
but I guess you always were.
Why are you here?
What could I have that
you could possibly want?
Let's talk about the Castle
at the End of the World.
What's inside?
How do you guys know about that place?
Answer her question.
You're not thinking of
going there, are you?
You know there's a reason
the gods had the Architect
- put it at the end of the world?
- The Architect?
It's not for you little guys to know.
It's funny...
'cause from where I stand,
you're the little guy now.
You have all my power, and look at you.
Trying to handle something
you cannot handle.
You should have kept your mouth
shut and stayed in your place.
You've gotten yourself
into some real trouble now.
You think it's easy being a god?
You feel that?
Your... tiny... spark
has grown bigger in me than
it could have ever in you.
You want the truth about the Castle?
The Castle's where the gods put
the stuff they made before us.
The stuff that didn't work out.
Mistakes that never
should have happened.
Kinda like you. I hope you do go.
Open that door, see what happens!
No!
Recognize it?
Yeah.
I made it to kill him.
How did you get this?
Did Our Lady give it to you?
Of course not.
My mother left me here to rot.
My stepfather Hades was the
only one that took pity on me.
He slipped me that gun to shoot
myself in case of emergency.
I'm still a god.
Limp or not, we're hard to kill.
What are you willing to
bet this god killing bullet
will work on the monster in the Castle?
The fate of the world?
That's good enough for me.
Whoa, that's it?
You're just going to leave him there?
After what he did to the both of you?
Shoot him.
Kady, you wanted this.
I wanted him to be
punished for what he did.
And he is. Leave him here.
I am here to deliver the
official election results.
Eliot has lost.
Shocker.
Uh, Tick has also lost.
Um, what?
Our new High King...
is Margo.
But I wa... I wasn't even on the ballot.
- You won as a write in.
- Who wrote me in?
The talking animals.
It seems you were the only
human on the campaign trail
who stopped to listen to their concerns.
You mean that drunk bear?
Humbledrum is a highly respected
member of the community.
You see, there are certain
taboo subjects you broached with him.
Bestiality?
The talking animals believe
that if they were allowed
to inter-marry with humans,
then humans will finally
see them as equals.
None of us were brave
enough to speak out
in support of the cause, until you.
You really love that sloth, don't you?
So the human vote basically
means nothing in Fillory.
Considering there's
never been an election
or census before, we had no idea
there were only 50,000
humans in Fillory,
and upwards of a
million talking animals.
So... yes.
On behalf of Abigail,
let me be the first
to swear loyalty to
the new administration.
El...
I'm so sorry.
And allow me to be the second.
High King Margo. Long may you reign.
Hey, Tick.
I intend to choose Death
by a Thousand Pokes.
They say you only feel
the first hundred or so.
Tick, we're not going to execute you.
If you proved anything
during your campaign,
it's that Fillory needs
a policy wonk like you.
You're still bitch listed, but...
King Margo would like
you in her cabinet.
With a full 24-hour security detail
watching everything you do.
We don't trust you, but we need you.
Citizenship for every Fairy,
full protection of the law,
and a seat in the government.
But we need the Key.
And you shall have it.
Once the last Fairies have
been moved to our new home.
I always saw something in you.
Even when you didn't see it in yourself.
Now, perhaps you will.
You gave me...
I can... I can see all sorts of things.
It's a Fairy eye. A gift you will learn
to understand in time.
But one you must hide in plain sight.
Could I maybe get some Fairy toes?
Hello?
- It's cranky as shit.
- Just take a little
- off the top.
- I just collapsed
my entire rental.
- Last time, we were...
- Oh, my God...
Are we supposed to sing again?
- Holy shit, no.
- We've got news!
- Penny, is that you?
- Yeah.
We just got the last
Key from the Fairies.
Okay, everyone just shut up! It's Penny.
All right, look, listen.
I-I don't know how much time we have.
- Kady.
- But I'm going to get you out
of the Underworld, no matter
what it takes, I promise.
- Kady.
- I love you.
This is Penny 23.
The Key replaced my Penny with you.
Look, I'm really sorry.
This is it.
The end of the story.
Floodgates of magic, ready to be opened.
Q? What's up, what's wrong?
The quest is supposed to change us.
I've sacrificed everything
that it wanted me to
up to this point, and I-I... I can't...
You thought that when you got here,
you'd be 150% sure you
were doing the right thing.
Now, you're only somewhere around 70%.
Because you're worried about your dad.
Party trick.
I just feel things.
I heard you healed Dean Fogg's eyes.
- Maybe...
- I could heal your dad?
Right now, he's perfectly healthy.
There's nothing to do.
If magic comes back,
a lot of dominoes will fall
in ways that we can't predict.
I don't know if I'll
be able to help or not.
It's the deal.
Sorry it's vague.
What if the thing that the
quest wants me to be is cold?
Being willing to sacrifice
the people I love?
Then the quest fucked up when
it chose Quentin Coldwater.
Maybe.
It's all real.
The Chatwins and Fillory.
I've been there. I
s... I sat on a throne
in Whitespire, and I...
I explored the Flying Forest.
And I... met Ember and Umber.
I remember reading you those books.
Curly Q...
if all that's out there...
- What are you doing here?
- I'm on a quest.
In New Jersey?
I have a problem.
And I don't know what to do.
No matter what choice I
make, somebody gets hurt.
Magic's gone.
Isn't it?
I'm not like you. I'm not a Magician.
But I could feel it when it was gone.
And I knew it wasn't a coincidence
when I went into remission a week later.
You're right. My friends
and I were trying to fix it.
- And how's that been going?
- We're getting really close.
So are you here to ask my permission?
To...
turn it back on?
On this quest...
I've lived a whole life.
I grew old, and I got
married. And I had a son.
Who grew old.
And what was all that
for if it's not for this?
No, I'm not here to
ask for your permission.
I wanted to look you in the eye
and tell you that I'm sorry.
I don't know what's going to happen.
But I'm going to do this.
What was his name?
Your son.
I named him after you.
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --