QUENTIN: Previously
on The Magicians...
QUENTIN: "This was Fillory,
"a land of magic."
The Chatwins, they
mostly get chased around
by this time witch,
the Watcher Woman.
She plants clocks in trees.
GUIDE: This is
where Fillory was born,
where Plover told
tales to Jane and Martin.
QUENTIN: I saw
something in there.
The poor kid, he was just
trying to get a button to Fillory,
you know, so he could
escape this monster.
SUNDERLAND: We live in a
world that is one world among many.
The Beast you saw
was from one such place.
What does Jane have
to do with The Beast?
THE BEAST: Still the same
determined little Jane Chatwin.
DEAN: Ember gave her
the ability to fuck with time,
and Jane used it to
create a time loop.
When she'd fail to stop The
Beast, she'd restart the loop.
What's different this time?
I was at Brakebills?
You were supposed to be.
I can't sit here now and
think it was anything but fate.
We summoned a goddess.
She touched all of us.
She granted every petition.
There was one time we didn't
all die. When we went to Fillory.
I'll go to Fillory
on one condition.
QUENTIN: That girl you saw in
the dungeon? We'll get her out.
We need some
serious battle magic.
KADY: Spells only work if
you channel 100% clean.
Bottling our
emotions, literally.
Shall we go fuck some shit up?
You slept with two other
people. We broke up.
QUENTIN: I was out of
my mind. I made a mistake.
My friends, I just... I can't let
them fight The Beast on their own.
You want me to come
to Fillory with you?
Yeah.
JULIA: Kind of been planning
this trip since we were nine.
QUENTIN: Fillory and
Further, Book Seven.
I will think of a
great title later.
(QUENTIN READING)
I knew it started as a blob of
crazy magic energy floating in space
that gave birth to the
gods, Ember and Umber,
that gave birth to this
amazing place, Fillory.
And I even knew that
that place was real.
What I didn't know was one day,
I would actually go there and
seek out the gods themselves.
Ember?
We need to talk to you.
Q. Come on. Put a
little conviction in it.
Ember!
Okay. Um, how did
Martin summon him?
(SIGHS) I don't know.
The books are all poetry.
It's like Martin's
blood sang to the gods.
Hmm.
Q, what if it was literal?
That's worth a shot.
(EXHALES)
Damn it.
(WINCES)
(GRUNTS)
You okay?
No, I just stabbed my own hand.
(RUMBLING) Ah!
(GROANING)
QUENTIN: We were
expecting something amazing,
and it was amazing.
Just more the shitty kind.
(COUGHING)
Smells like an outhouse in here.
Jesus. Look at all this trash.
Someone's been
holed up here a while.
It is customary to
bow, children of Earth.
Have you brought
me little cakes?
QUENTIN: You're
probably a little confused, so,
now I'm going to do
that thing I kind of hate
where the book rewinds
to fill in all the blanks.
Sorry. Let's do it.
(QUENTIN READING)
(GROANS) (PANTING)
Holy shit.
QUENTIN: Our
route to Ember started
when we traveled
back in time to 1942
to follow Jane Chatwin through a
vaguely TARDIS-looking portal to Fillory.
Here she comes.
QUENTIN: We figured
once we were actually there,
we could get to the present
and back to my friends somehow,
uh, because that's Fillory.
There's always a way.
There's Jane, and there's us,
and someone mysterious
watching us, by the way,
to follow us through.
Standing in Fillory was the
greatest moment of my life,
and not just because, as I later
found out, the air is .02% opium,
which is a pretty unfair trick
to get you to love a place,
but whatever, we loved it.
(GIGGLING)
Oh, uh, oh...
So, if you're a real fan, you'd
totally recognize this from the books.
This iconic scene, right?
Jane falls into a trap and is
saved by passing Magicians,
but what you didn't know,
is I am in that scene, bitches.
Struggle, struggle.
Tighter, tighter.
Can't you see them yet?
Nope.
But they can't be
too hard to miss.
The witch and the fool. Iconic.
JULIA: How are
the witch and the fool
supposed to see her, I mean?
BOTH: Oh!
Ooh, which one
do you think I am?
You don't look like any
witches or fools I've seen here.
Oh, wait. Don't. It's enchanted.
It'll only make it worse.
What's the point
of these, anyway?
They're everywhere.
Well, some animals can talk,
so, hunters have sort
of an ethical dilemma.
You know, you don't
want to eat something
as smart as you,
so, anything that
can answer the riddle
is set free.
So, uh, "What is no sooner
"broken than spoken?"
I have no idea.
(MOUTHING) Silence.
Silence.
How'd you know the answer?
I, uh, read it.
(SIGHS HAPPILY)
Brilliant. Thank you,
witch and fool. Ta-ta!
Okay. (CLEARS THROAT) Go.
Geek out. We're in the
books. We are in the books.
(TWIG SNAPS)
QUENTIN: So, remember how
someone followed us into Fillory?
Hey! Are you following us?
It's totally cool if you are.
Martin? He's not even
in this part of the book.
(QUENTIN READING)
Still not sure I
quite understand
why you were
following my sister.
Well, why are you
following your sister?
Because Fillory
stopped taking you?
Martin, I know
you probably think
it's your fault, but it's not.
You want to be here because
you don't feel safe at home.
And we want to help.
What do you mean?
Christopher Plover is a
very powerful Magician now.
Maybe the most.
We think we can stop him
if we find something. Um...
It's a Fillorian knife
called the "Leo blade."
Have you heard of it?
No.
But I know someone
who might have.
Nope, never heard of it.
But it's something you're
more than capable of making,
given your reputation.
Though if you think
it may be too difficult.
What in Hades is
difficult about a blade?
Well, this one...
Has to kill a Master Magician.
JULIA: And he's not
even human anymore.
Six fingers, dark spells
you've never seen before.
Lad, fetch the moonstones.
Thing like that
can only be killed with
a blade of moonstones.
I have the only two in Fillory.
You couldn't even
make a needle with that.
These aren't just
rocks. They're alive.
I can mate them and breed more.
QUENTIN: Then why haven't you?
(GRUNTS)
Expensive. Takes time.
Care. Feeding. Years.
And it's not often
I'm called upon
to forge a Master
Magician murder weapon.
But you are from a
place that likes murder.
Earth.
Am I right? Yes,
we're from Earth.
Good. Then you know what I want.
We do and we agree.
MARTIN: So, what exactly did we
promise the knife-maker last night?
JULIA: Well, he knew
we were from Earth.
QUENTIN: And the rulers of
Fillory can only be from Earth.
So, he thinks we're...
Kings and queen. He
wants a seat at court.
But years, it'll take him years.
How? (CLATTERING)
Holy shit.
Oh, my God.
Jules, it's Ember's temple.
QUENTIN: It was as
beautiful as it was in the books,
and standing there, you could
just feel that the gods were real.
(WIND WHOOSHING)
But in Fillory, with
magic comes danger.
She's coming. The Watcher Woman.
(CLOCK BELL CHIMES)
Martin. Wait. Martin!
(CLOCK BELL CHIMING)
Holy shit.
(QUENTIN READING)
In which we run into my favorite
random, scary villain from the books,
and she turns out to
be the exact opposite.
Quentin?
You know the Watcher Woman?
QUENTIN: Oh, my God. I do.
Of course, I should
have put that together.
This is my friend, Julia.
Julia, this is Jane Chatwin.
Um, all grown up.
You're not supposed
to be here yet.
Haven't even been born yet.
We know about the time
loops that you keep making.
As you should by now.
Right.
So, there have been 39 others...
And you're the volunteer tomato.
I'm sorry, what? In a
garden, you pull everything up.
Sometimes a stray vine just
keeps coming back. It volunteers.
That's really why you,
Quentin, you just keep coming.
Right. Okay.
So, okay. I'm the tomato.
And this is the last time.
Why is this the last one?
(SOFTLY) Oh.
(STAMMERING)
Well, you die this time.
Huh.
I see. Do I die doing
something brave?
Very. Right, then.
If you survive, see to it that I
get a proper temple in my honor.
Granite statue, good
likeness, mind the chin.
I'll put that at
the top of my list.
JULIA: Can I ask a question?
Why are you the Watcher
Woman? She's a villain.
Am I?
You scared the hell
out of everybody.
When I was a girl,
the Watcher Woman
inspired me to learn
magic to fight her.
Indeed, I grew up to be just a touch
stronger than that Watcher Woman.
That hurts my brain.
Apparently, it wasn't enough.
(SIGHS) At least I learned
some fun things, like this.
Wait, what did you do?
Don't want her to hear us.
There's a patch on your
friend's memory, quite crude.
Made in haste,
likely by a Hedge.
Could you remove it?
No, it's there for a reason.
Covering something
recent, something tragic.
Replacing it with something
beautiful, but false.
(INDISTINCT CHANTING)
(COINS CLINKING)
My children, you have summoned
me to shed your burdens.
And so, they shall be.
Julia.
I have a mission for you.
If you still care about her...
Of course.
Protect her.
I'm sorry I couldn't
protect you.
That was never
your job, Quentin.
Right, then.
Sorry, what were you
guys saying? So, Jane, um,
could you zoom us forward
to the present? Our present?
Goodbye, Quentin.
Godspeed.
(QUENTIN READING)
Jesus.
QUENTIN: Welcome
to Fillory 2016.
It's a lot colder. It's like
being in a fog that never lifts.
Yeah.
Ow.
"Enchanted this to find
you if you ever arrive.
"Hope you're not dead.
Margo being such a bitch.
"Follow map to find us. El."
Come on.
QUENTIN: Welcome to
the Fillory of The Beast.
And this is what
happens to a world
ruled by the worst
kind of predator.
The kind of monster
who destroys childhood.
(SNIFFS)
Cheers, B.
QUENTIN: As soon as I saw
them, I remembered, oh, uh,
we kind of all slept
with each other
and hate each other right now.
And that is largely my fault.
ELIOT: Really good
to see you again, Q,
but why am I looking at the
hedge bitch who tried to kill you?
We worked it out. I wouldn't
be here without her, so...
I'm here. You don't
have to like me.
Oh, don't you worry.
We don't.
PENNY: So, do you know where
The Beast is holding Victoria, or not?
I think the dungeon is in
the castle that isn't there.
That's the stupidest
name I've ever heard.
You didn't just do shots with
a bulldog named "Bristlycoat."
It's a kind of phosphoromancy.
Alice, you could
explain it, um, better.
How much further
to this knife maker?
These shoes weren't
cobbled for a quest.
QUENTIN: Right
over here, I think.
ALICE: Not another one.
What?
They're everywhere.
Plus headstones,
unmarked graves.
Oh, no.
QUENTIN: We'd hoped that
Martin was still out there somewhere,
that we could save
him, but we took too long.
We failed him.
All the Chatwins are dead.
Wow.
Your childhood fantasy is
a great big magical Dachau.
(QUENTIN READING)
QUENTIN: The knife maker's
house was largely the same in 2016,
but now it was
run by a stranger.
I remember you.
I must say, you've
aged well, the two of you.
Um...
I was eight.
Apprentice to my father.
Is he around?
He's out back. Six
feet under grass.
You know, he grew
a little aggravated
waiting for you
two to come back.
The Leo blade. As promised.
Payment is due.
As promised.
Here's the thing. All
the Chatwins are dead,
Fillory has no rulers, and
the only people from Earth
left here now not
locked in a dungeon...
JOSH: Oh, my God.
I'm going to be royalty.
Yeah, we all are the next wave.
So, what he wants is to become
future royalty by marriage.
Wait, he wants to
marry one of us?
No, thank God.
He wants one of us to
marry her. His daughter.
PENNY: Huh.
I mean, you know,
team player and stuff.
Hey, who says it's you, anyway?
It's not a volunteer gig,
and she doesn't get to pick.
This blade draws one
thing and one thing only.
The pure royal blood of
the High King of Fillory.
QUENTIN: I admit, I was 100%
sure that I was definitely the High King.
Hmm.
QUENTIN: I know!
Shocking, right?
You may be wondering
why they set it up
that aliens must rule Fillory,
and I'm sure there
is a great reason
and nobody has
any clue what that is.
Ember and Umber set it
up and they're not that into
explaining their big ideas
and you'd think it would be
centaurs or something, right?
I would do centaurs, but nope.
(SIGHS) So, what
exactly is supposed to...
Oh! (WINCES)
Get the fuck out.
Well, High King.
Makes certain
instinctual sense, I guess.
Your Majesty.
Oh, this'll make him
easier to live with.
(QUENTIN READING)
(SIGHS) So, there's a bump.
Bigger than marrying
a total stranger-ette?
Apparently, marriage
here is different.
Really different.
Right, but as High King, I
can get a royal annulment.
No. Never.
Once you get married, you won't
be able to be with anyone else.
Literally. For the
rest of your life.
Here, but when
I go back, I can...
I can never leave Fillory.
Jesus.
El, you don't have to do this.
(SIGHS) No, don't.
I'm doing this.
Eliot... Margo.
I am miserable.
My life, it doesn't work.
Nothing's ever fixed that.
Drugs, sex, food, booze.
Not even magic.
But maybe it all
led to this, to now.
For a reason that's actually
finally going to make my life
not just about me, and my
thoughts, and my feelings,
something... Bigger.
How wise you are,
Queen Margo the Destroyer.
(LAUGHING)
Um...
Is it okay if I hate that
you're getting married?
(LAUGHS) Shit.
I think you're the only
person that I can stand.
You know what that means?
You have to be my best man.
(LAUGHING)
(RHYTHMIC DRUMMING)
(BE MY HUSBAND BY
LISA HANNIGAN PLAYING)
Be my husband
And I'll be your wife
This is taking forever.
Be my husband
Penny.
Outside you there
is no place to go
Eliot.
Fen. Nice to meet you.
Will you marry me?
Ooh, Daddy now, now Love me good
(QUENTIN READING)
Okay, okay, where are you?
Where is this?
Please don't treat
me so doggone mean
The blade is yours.
You're the meanest
man I have ever seen
Ha!
What? That's hot.
Here, maybe it's
just for high kings.
Oh! Jesus!
Okay, father-in-law,
why is this blade 1,000 degrees?
It may only be handled
by Master Magicians.
Are none of you masters?
Okay, I found the
castle. We can...
Oh! Cool.
Fuck!
(SCREAMS)
I hate this place!
(QUENTIN READING)
JOSH: There has
to be a trick, right?
We can't trick it into
thinking we're powerful.
The trick is, we have
to be that powerful.
I gather the crowd
you usually hang with
nods like you're smart when
you say incredibly obvious shit,
but what we need is ideas.
QUENTIN: That's a good idea.
We need the power of a god.
Yeah, or gods.
Ember and Umber.
Who haven't been seen for
decades, so, good luck with that.
Okay, I have a
much less idiotic idea.
Why don't we use a Magician who's
actually been around The Beast?
The girl from his dungeon.
JOSH: So much less
idiotic, it's almost good.
I'm with Penny.
Eliot?
Yeah, according
to the fine print
not actually written down,
I have a virgin farm
girl to impregnate.
Right this second?
ELIOT: This very one.
Best of luck, all.
You're welcome.
Mrs. Me?
Mmm.
If I die while he's
balling himself limp,
I will haunt the
shit out of his ass.
MARGO: You're
fucking kidding me.
JOSH: That's why they call
it the Castle That Isn't There.
Because it's invisible.
QUENTIN: The truth is,
the castle was constructed
to be invisible primarily
for budgetary reasons.
The royals had spent their
entire seasonal allowance
and then realized they
still had a castle to build,
so, they figured builder's
grade material is just fine
if you can't see it.
You guys run,
I'll distract them.
Don't be stupid. They're men.
JOSH: My sister! Please, help!
She just fainted. Can
one of you do something?
(GASPS) Hey, hey.
(MARGO MOANS)
MARGO: I need help.
GUARD: You all right, miss?
Where am I?
(DOOR OPENS)
Victoria. (GASPING)
Hey, we're here to get you out.
We're here to get you out. Okay?
The cuffs... I can't...
They keep you from traveling.
Yeah.
We'll get them.
Can you walk?
There's someone
else in the next cell.
QUENTIN: Ember?
We need to talk to you.
QUENTIN: So, here
we are at the temple,
hoping against
hope and all that.
(RUMBLING) Ah!
(QUENTIN READING)
It is customary to
bow, children of Earth.
Have you brought
me little cakes?
No.
Uh, we didn't really know
that we were supposed to.
Oh.
And I am so tired
of eating mice.
(CHUCKLES)
No matter.
And you are?
Uh, I'm Quentin Coldwater.
And Julia Wicker. Huh.
Spank my cheeks. You're
usually dead by now.
He kills you and I'm left
here to hide like an animal
in horrid, arid,
cake-deficient Loria,
but you're here.
What happened? What
are you doing here?
He lured me into
a trap, of course.
The Beast?
As you call him, yes.
He snared me and my
dear, departed Umber.
Wait, Umber's dead?
It's unseemly, all of it.
I'm sorry.
I don't mean to disrespect,
but how could a Magician
put the drop on you?
Fillory's magic belongs
to no one, not even a god.
A Magician with
enough determination
can harness its forces
and make haggis
of any one of us.
Hmm.
So, now I just
wait till he is slain.
I'm so fucking bored,
children of Earth.
Ha!
I've had sex with every
nymph in the kingdom.
Well, we're here to help.
But you're not a nymph.
No, I'm...
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Pray pardon?
What are you doing here?
You're just going
to let The Beast
trample the shit out of Fillory?
You think that I
want to be here?
I think you're being
kind of a whiny bitch.
Q, maybe don't insult...
No, does he care, or not?
You're right.
Years trying to outwit him.
(CHUCKLES)
Greatest failure, deepest shame.
And now he is prepared
for anything I do.
It's not I who can
defeat him, not directly.
I'll do it.
I volunteer. I'll
kill The Beast.
I love Fillory. I
don't know why.
But I am supposed to be here.
I'm supposed to fight for it.
Can you be the champion
we've been waiting for?
I want to be.
I'm ready to be.
I'll do whatever it takes.
You love Fillory.
And you never stopped.
Julia stopped.
I mean, maybe in
college, but now I totally...
Yes, you see, she stopped.
But you never did.
Only the best and the purest
can face The Beast,
and that is you.
Right, okay, so
here's the thing,
I can't really touch the
knife that can kill The Beast.
Yes, you need my strength.
I will infuse you
with my essence.
I have gifted you my bestowal,
my largesse, the
seed of my power.
When you are ready
to face The Beast,
imbibe it.
JULIA: Is that semen?
Thank you.
Hmm. Thank you.
And you, daughter of Earth.
Hmm.
Your mind is encumbered.
A shroud.
No... What?
Crudely made.
Ember, no, it's okay...
I shall remove it.
JULIA: Remove what?
No, no, don't!
God. Jules!
You're welcome.
No need to thank me.
(GASPING)
Best of luck.
Oh, my God.
Jules... Please. Please, don't.
Please don't touch
me, please don't...
Okay.
Hey, Jules, come on. What
happened? Just tell me, please.
Can you take my memory?
Please, take my memory.
I don't know how.
Then we have to go.
QUENTIN: I knew Julia wouldn't
tell me until she was ready,
but that might be never.
(GASPS)
Here.
Thank you.
Any time.
Honestly, I was
getting pretty sick
of hearing your
voice in my head.
And I wanted to help
you so badly. I'm sorry I...
Don't be. You found me.
Look, is there some trick?
How do you take people along?
Any of us can.
Well, I can barely travel me.
They're a spell.
MARGO: Ugh. Literally?
QUENTIN: So, the dungeon?
Roaring success, and a twofer.
Sorry?
We should see if
he's awake by now.
QUENTIN: Oh, my God.
That's Christopher Plover.
What?
We were wrong about everything.
Plover's not The Beast.
No.
Martin Chatwin is.
I loved Martin.
But there's something black
inside him I failed to see.
Look at the
markings on his face.
Age suspension magic,
so every day he can start over.
Yeah, poor you.
ALICE: We need to find Martin.
Why? You can't stop him.
Tell us everything or
I'm going to feed you to him.
(EXHALES)
When he was still a child,
Fillory stopped taking him.
Once he found his way back,
he made it his mission to stay.
He'd heard about the Wellspring,
the most ancient
location in Fillory.
Which is what?
The source of all magic.
It's not only stronger than
Ember and Umber, it created them.
Fillory runs on it.
Martin goes every
night to drink from it,
draining it a little
more each time.
The Wellspring's
magic is so strong,
it killed every
human thing in him.
There's only The Beast now.
So, he goes to the Wellspring
every night, but it's not on any map.
(SIGHS) Guess I can
start asking around.
Or cast some kind
of locator maybe?
Or ask me.
He never could hide
his mind from me.
Our connection.
Okay, I vote we test
the knife out on him.
VICTORIA: Be careful.
Josh, come on. We've got to go.
Come on! JOSH:
I have your cloak...
QUENTIN: Yeah,
Josh and Victoria bailed.
On one hand, fuck them,
on the other hand, you
can't really blame them.
So, I was writing this down
because I didn't know much,
but I knew that I was
the hero of this story.
It all just felt like
the exact moment
that my entire life had
been building up to,
all of the reading,
and dreaming,
and loneliness, and magic.
All of it.
And then...
Well, and then this
story actually happened.
And I started to
realize the truth.
It's so insignificant.
Us being together
and falling apart,
I mean, it just doesn't matter.
I made a mistake.
I know you don't want
to hear it, but I love you.
You're right, I don't.
But I'm not going to
go in there angry at you.
Okay? I've got your
back, Quentin. We all do.
You know, my entire life,
ever since the first time I
read Fillory and Further,
I've been waiting for some
powerful being to
come down and say,
"Quentin Coldwater,
you are the one."
Every book, every movie,
it's about one special guy.
He's chosen.
In real life, for every one guy,
there are a billion
people who aren't.
(LAUGHS)
Almost none of us are the one.
Ember said...
Ember is a little
out of touch, I think.
You're a better Magician.
And you're a better person.
And I think that
if he'd met you,
he wouldn't be so
sure that it's me.
But you're the one that they say
shows up every
single time, it's you.
I want to be the one. I do.
It's just,
it's the adult part of me,
the part of me that
understands how magic works,
it just keeps
screaming that it's you.
Every time that
Jane reset the loop,
she changed something.
So, what if I change something?
What if I give the blade to you?
You're not as good as I hoped,
Quentin Coldwater.
But you're better than you know.
PENNY: Alice, you okay?
Come on, hon.
Pretend it's prom night and
you just want to shut him up.
Did you bogart the whole thing?
Alice?
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Q, uh, can I...
Can I talk to you?
(CRYING)
Jules, talk to me.
I did something.
Me and my friends.
We followed all the clues.
We thought that she
was leading us to her,
we summoned her.
You know, I actually believed
Our Lady Underground chose me.
(ALL CHANTING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Guys, stop. We should stop.
Julia. You dumb little witch.
You can't unring a bell.
(LAUGHING)
Richard.
Move! Richard, move!
(GROANS)
(ALL PANTING AND SHRIEKING)
(GASPS) Stop her!
MAN: Do something.
WOMAN: Nothing's working.
Oh, God.
Richard.
RICHARD: You'll find
I've taken away your magic,
so there's no point in trying.
(SPITS)
My thanks for opening the door.
You may address me
as Reynard the Fox,
trickster of the faithful,
the pure of heart,
the very stupid.
Richard...
(ALL SCREAMING) (SHRIEKS)
No, no!
(ALL CHOKING AND GAGGING)
Kady!
Run, run.
Kady, that was my hermit
who healed your heart.
And now, I'm going to taste it.
Don't you fucking touch her!
When you address me...
(WHISPERS) avert your gaze.
I said, "Don't you
fucking touch her."
Fine. I'll take you first.
(SCREAMING)
Kady, go!
I chose you, Julia.
From the first moment
you prayed, I felt your body.
I lifted it in my hands...
(GROWLING) (WHIMPERS)
(WHIMPERS)
(RICHARD GROWLING)
(CRYING)
I can give you the greatest
pleasure of your life.
I can make you...
Ow! (CRYING)
(RICHARD GROWLING)
(PANTING)
(SOBBING)
JULIA: I need your help.
Something happened.
(CRYING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Jesus.
Thank you for coming.
I got you. I got you.
The thing, where is it now?
Gone. It got what it wanted.
I didn't know who else to call.
You called the right person.
I'm going to help
you clean this up.
I'm going to need another favor.
And I know it'll cost
me, but I don't care.
Jesus, Julia, I want to help.
What Brakebills
did to your memory?
I need you to do it to me.
Please.
Jules. Uh...
Yeah, I know. What the
fuck were we thinking?
You were trying to do good,
and you got duped.
It's not your fault.
Jules, you saved Kady.
Yeah, but what
about everyone else?
You know, what...
Hey.
I'm going to help you.
I promise, whatever that means.
It means find him.
It means kill him.
And somehow I doubt that
that's easy, or even possible.
Well, impossible shit
is sort of our thing.
The Wellspring of all magic?
It's a truck stop shit-house.
QUENTIN: He'll be here soon.
Let's go.
The fuck?
It's Plover's writing room.
All that power,
and he can't stop thinking
about where it happened.
Fillory needs meds
way more than magic.
Okay, so, where's
the actual Wellspring?
Poor Martin.
Okay, so...
(MOTH WINGS BUZZING)
THE BEAST: Quentin.
Is it time for this already?
Hi, Martin.
We know it's you.
Mmm.
(LOCK CLICKS)
Well, you made it a good
long way this time around.
But this is it, Quentin.
QUENTIN: I know
you're still in there.
Look at this.
You still feel,
you're still hurt,
and you should be after
what happened to you.
The mediocre are
always so sentimental.
Although, must say,
most wouldn't walk to
certain death 40 times in a row.
(CHUCKLING)
You're no quitter.
Mmm.
Right.
Let's get this over with. Wait.
I have an offer.
Jane gave me a message for you.
A gift.
She said that you would want it,
that you would understand.
Your stupid bloody cards.
Your stalling tactics haven't
gotten any less pathetic.
Next time, put something
useful in your pocket.
Oh, that's right. No next time.
(CHOKING)
Shit!
You're stronger than you were.
Haven't learned to cast
while you're bleeding out?
(CHOKING AND COUGHING)
For the love of
Christ, children...
Ah!
(COUGHING)
(SHRIEKS)
(GROANING)
Quentin Coldwater.
Wait.
(CELL PHONE LINE TRILLING)
(CRYING)
I need... I need your
help. Something happened.
Ah!
(WHIMPERING)
Something's still happening.
Stronger as well, I see.
So many surprises.
So,
what do you want?
Jules.
You killed Umber.
And you trapped Ember.
You know how to deal with gods.
You know how to
fuck up their shit.
Julia. No.
I want to make a deal.
Let's.
PENNY: No.
(PENNY GROANING AND PANTING)
God.