QUENTIN: Previously on
The Magicians...
QUENTIN: "This was Fillory,
"a land of magic."
The Chatwins,
they mostly get chased around
by this time witch,
the Watcher Woman.
She plants clocks in trees.
GUIDE: This is where
Fillory was born,
where Plover told
tales to Jane and Martin.
QUENTIN: I saw
something in there.
The poor kid, he was just trying
to get a button to Fillory,
you know, so he could
escape this monster.
SUNDERLAND: We live in a world
that is one world among many.
The Beast you saw was
from one such place.
What does Jane have
to do with The Beast?
THE BEAST: Still the same
determined little Jane Chatwin.
DEAN: Ember gave her
the ability to fuck with time,
and Jane used it to
create a time loop.
When she'd fail to stop The
Beast, she'd restart the loop.
What's different this time?
I was at Brakebills?
You were supposed to be.
I can't sit here now and think
it was anything but fate.
We summoned a goddess.
She touched all of us.
She granted every petition.
There was one time we didn't all die.
When we went to Fillory.
I'll go to Fillory
on one condition.
QUENTIN: That girl you saw in the dungeon?
We'll get her out.
We need some
serious battle magic.
KADY: Spells only work if
you channel 100% clean.
Bottling our emotions,
literally.
Shall we go fuck
some shit up?
You slept with two other people.
We broke up.
QUENTIN: I was out of my mind-
I made a mistake.
My friends, I just... I can't let
them fight The Beast on their own.
You want me to come
to Fillory with you?
Yeah.
JULIA: Kind of been planning
this trip since we were nine.
QUENTIN: Fillory and Further,
Book Seven.
I will think of
a great title later.
(QUENTIN READING)
I knew it started as a blob of crazy
magic energy floating in space
that gave birth to the gods,
Ember and Umber,
that gave birth to this
amazing place, Fillory.
And I even knew that
that place was real.
What I didn't
know was one day,
I would actually go there and
seek out the gods themselves.
Ember?
We need to
talk to you.
Q. Come on. Put a little
conviction in it.
Ember!
Okay. Um, how did
Martin summon him?
(SIGHS) I don't know.
The books are all poetry.
It's like Martin's
blood sang to the gods.
Hmm.
Q, what if
it was literal?
That's worth a shot.
(EXHALES)
Damn it.
(WINCES)
(GRUNTS)
You Okay?
No, I just stabbed
my own hand.
(RUMBLING)
Ah!
(GROANING)
QUENTIN: We were expecting
something amazing,
and it was amazing.
Just more the shitty kind.
(COUGHING)
Smells like
an outhouse in here.
Jesus. Look at
all this trash.
Someone's been
holed up here a while.
It is customary to bow,
children of Earth.
Have you brought
me little cakes?
QUENTIN: You're probably
a little confused, so,
now I'm going to do
that thing I kind of hate
where the book rewinds
to fill in all the blanks.
Sorry. Let's do it.
(QUENTIN READING)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
Holy shit.
QUENTIN: Our route
to Ember started
when we traveled
back in time to 1942
to follow Jane Chatwin through a vaguely
TARDIS-looking portal to Fillory.
Here she comes.
QUENTIN: We figured once
we were actually there,
we could get to the present and
back to my friends somehow,
uh, because that's Fillory.
There's always a way.
There's Jane, and there's us,
and someone mysterious
watching us, by the way,
to follow us through.
Standing in Fillory was the
greatest moment of my life,
and not just because, as I later
found out, the air is - 02% opium,
which is a pretty unfair trick
to get you to love a place,
but whatever, we loved it.
(GIGGLING)
Oh, uh, oh...
So, if you're a real fan, you'd totally
recognize this from the books.
This iconic scene, right?
Jane falls into a trap and is
saved by passing Magicians,
but what you didn't know,
is I am in that scene,
bitches.
Struggle, struggle.
Tighter, tighter.
Can't you see them yet?
Nope.
But they can't be
too hard to miss.
The witch and the fool.
Iconic.
JULIA: How are the witch
and the fool
supposed to
see her, I mean?
BOTH: Oh!
Ooh, which one
do you think I am?
You don't look like any witches
or fools I've seen here.
Oh, wait. Don't.
It's enchanted.
It'll only make
it worse.
What's the point
of these, anyway?
They're everywhere.
Well, some
animals can talk,
so, hunters have sort
of an ethical dilemma.
You know, you don't
want to eat something
as smart as you,
so, anything that
can answer the riddle
is set free.
So, uh, "What is no sooner
"broken than spoken?"
I have no idea.
(MOUTHING) Silence.
Silence.
How'd you know the answer?
I, uh, read it.
(SIGHS HAPPILY)
Brilliant. Thank you,
witch and fool. Ta-ta!
Okay.
(CLEARS THROAT) Go.
Geek out. We're in the books.
We are in the books.
(TWIG SNAPS)
QUENTIN: So, remember how someone
followed us into Fillory?
Hey! Are you
following us?
It's totally
cool if you are.
Martin? He's not even
in this part of the book.
(QUENTIN READING)
Still not sure
I quite understand
why you were
following my sister.
Well, why are you
following your sister?
Because Fillory
stopped taking you?
Martin, I know you
probably think
it's your fault,
but it's not.
You want to be here because
you don't feel safe at home.
And we want to help.
What do you mean?
Christopher Plover is a
very powerful Magician now.
Maybe the most.
We think we can stop him if
we find something. Um...
It's a Fillorian knife
called the "Leo blade."
Have you heard of it?
No.
But I know someone
who might have.
Nope, never heard of it.
But it's something you're
more than capable of making,
given your reputation.
Though if you think it
may be too difficult.
What in Hades is
difficult about a blade?
Well, this one...
Has to kill
a Master Magician.
JULIA: And he's not
even human anymore.
Six fingers, dark spells
you've never seen before.
Lad, fetch
the moonstones.
Thing like that
can only be killed with
a blade of moonstones.
I have the only
two in Fillory.
You couldn't even
make a needle with that.
These aren't just rocks.
They're alive.
I can mate them
and breed more.
QUENTIN: Then why haven't you?
(GRUNTS)
Expensive.
Takes time.
Care. Feeding.
Years.
And it's not often
I'm called upon
to forge a Master
Magician murder weapon.
But you are from a place
that likes murder.
Earth.
Am I right?
Yes, we're from Earth.
Good. Then you
know what I want.
We do and we agree.
MARTIN: So, what exactly did we
promise the knife-maker last night?
JULIA: Well, he knew
we were from Earth.
QUENTIN: And the rulers of
Fillory can only be from Earth.
So, he thinks
we're...
Kings and queen.
He wants a seat at court.
But years,
it'll take him years.
How?
(CLATTERING)
Holy shit.
Oh, my God.
Jules, it's Ember's
temple.
QUENTIN: It was as beautiful
as it was in the books,
and standing there, you could just
feel that the gods were real.
(WIND WHOOSHING)
But in Fillory,
with magic comes danger.
She's coming.
The Watcher Woman.
(CLOCK BELL CHIMES)
Martin. Wait.
Martin!
(CLOCK BELL CHIMING)
Holy shit.
(QUENTIN READING)
In which we run into my favorite
random, scary villain from the books,
and she turns out to
be the exact opposite.
Quentin?
You know
the Watcher Woman?
QUENTIN: Oh, my God. I do.
Of course, I should
have put that together.
This is
my friend, Julia.
Julia, this is
Jane Chatwin.
Um, all grown up.
You're not supposed
to be here yet.
Haven't even
been born yet.
We know about the time loops
that you keep making.
As you should by now.
Right.
So, there have
been 39 others...
And you're
the volunteer tomato.
I'm sorry, what? In a garden,
you pull everything up.
Sometimes a stray vine just keeps
coming back. It volunteers.
That's really why you,
Quentin, you just keep coming.
Right. Okay.
So, okay.
I'm the tomato.
And this is
the last time.
Why is this
the last one?
(SOFTLY) on.
(STAMMERING)
Well, you die
this time.
Huh.
I see. Do I die doing
something brave?
Very.
Right, then.
If you survive, see to it that I
get a proper temple in my honor.
Granite statue, good
likeness, mind the chin.
I'll put that at
the top of my list.
JULIA: Can I ask a question?
Why are you the Watcher Woman?
She's a villain.
Am I?
You scared the hell
out of everybody.
When I was a girl,
the Watcher Woman
inspired me to learn
magic to fight her.
Indeed, I grew up to be just a touch
stronger than that Watcher Woman.
That hurts my brain.
Apparently,
it wasn't enough.
(SIGHS) At least I learned
some fun things, like this.
Wait, what did you do?
Don't want her
to hear us.
There's a patch on your
friend's memory, quite crude.
Made in haste,
likely by a Hedge.
Could you remove it?
No, it's there
for a reason.
Covering something recent,
something tragic.
Replacing it with something
beautiful, but false.
(INDISTINCT CHANTING)
(COINS CLINKING)
My children, you have summoned
me to shed your burdens.
And so, they shall be.
Julia.
I have a mission for you.
you still care
about her...
Of course.
...protect her.
I'm sorry I couldn't
protect you.
That was never
your job, Quentin.
Right, then.
Sorry, what were you guys saying?
So, Jane, um,
could you zoom
us forward
to the present?
Our present?
Goodbye, Quentin.
Godspeed.
(QUENTIN READING)
Jesus.
QUENTIN: Welcome
to Fillory 2016.
It's a lot colder. It's like
being in a fog that never lifts.
Yeah.
Ow.
"Enchanted this to find
you if you ever arrive.
"Hope you're not dead.
Margo being such a bitch.
"Follow map
to find us. El."
Come on.
QUENTIN: Welcome to
the Fillory of The Beast.
And this is what
happens to a world
ruled by the worst
kind of predator.
The kind of monster
who destroys childhood.
(SNIFFS)
Cheers, B.
QUENTIN: As soon as I saw
them, I remembered, Oh, uh,
we kind of all
slept with each other
and hate each other right now.
And that is largely my fault.
ELIOT: Really good
to see you again, Q,
but why am I looking at the hedge
bitch who tried to kill you?
We worked it out. I wouldn't
be here without her, so...
I'm here. You don't
have to like me.
Oh, don't you worry.
We don't.
PENNY: So, do you know where The
Beast is holding Victoria, or not?
I think the dungeon is in the
castle that isn't there.
That's the stupidest
name I've ever heard.
You didn't just
do shots with
a bulldog named
"Bristlycoat."
It's a kind of
phosphoromancy.
Alice, you could
explain it, um, better.
How much further
to this knife maker?
These shoes weren't
cobbled for a quest.
QUENTIN: Right over here,
I think.
ALICE: Not another one.
What?
They're everywhere.
Plus headstones,
unmarked graves.
Oh, no.
QUENTIN: We'd hoped that Martin
was still out there somewhere,
that we could save him,
but we took too long.
We failed him.
All the Chatwins
are dead.
Wow.
Your childhood fantasy is a
great big magical Dachau.
(QUENTIN READING)
QUENTIN: The knife maker's house
was largely the same in 2016,
but now it was
run by a stranger.
I remember you.
I must say, you've aged
well, the two of you.
Um...
I was eight. Apprentice
to my father.
Is he around?
He's out back.
Six feet under grass.
You know, he grew
a little aggravated
waiting for you
two to come back.
The Leo blade.
As promised.
Payment is due.
Here's the thing. All
the Chatwins are dead,
Fillory has no rulers, and
the only people from Earth
left here now not
locked in a dungeon...
JOSH: Oh, my God.
I'm going
to be royalty.
Yeah, we all are
the next wave.
So, what he wants is to become
future royalty by marriage.
Wait, he wants to
marry one of us?
No, thank God.
He wants one of us to marry her.
His daughter.
PENNY; Huh.
I mean, you know,
team player and stuff.
Hey, who says
it's you, anyway?
It's not
a volunteer gig,
and she doesn't
get to pick.
This blade draws one thing
and one thing only.
The pure royal blood of
the High King of Fillory.
QUENTIN: I admit, I was 100% sure
that I was definitely the High King.
Hmm.
QUENTIN: I know!
Shocking, right?
You may be wondering
why they set it up
that aliens must rule Fillory,
and I'm sure there
is a great reason
and nobody has any
clue what that is.
Ember and Umber set it up
and they're not that into
explaining their big ideas
and you'd think it would be
centaurs or something, right?
I would do centaurs, but nope.
(SIGHS) So, what
exactly is supposed to...
on! (WINCES)
Get the fuck out.
Well, High King.
Makes certain instinctual
sense, I guess.
Your Majesty.
Oh, this'll make him
easier to live with.
(QUENTIN READING)
(SIGHS)
So, there's a bump.
Bigger than marrying
a total stranger-ette?
Apparently, marriage
here is different.
Really different.
Right, but as High King, I
can get a royal annulment.
No. Never.
Once you get married, you won't
be able to be with anyone else.
Literally. For
the rest of your life.
Here, but when
I go back, I can...
I can never
leave Fillory.
Jesus.
El, you don't
have to do this.
(SIGHS) No, don't.
I'm doing this.
Eliot...
Margo.
lam miserable.
My life,
it doesn't work.
Nothing's ever
fixed that.
Drugs, sex,
food, booze.
Not even magic.
But maybe it all
led to this, to now.
For a reason
that's actually
finally going
to make my life
not just about me, and my
thoughts, and my feelings,
something...
Bigger.
How wise you are,
Queen Margo
the Destroyer.
(LAUGHING)
Um...
ls it okay if I hate
that you're getting married?
(LAUGHS) Shit.
I think you're the only
person that I can stand.
You know what that means?
You have to be
my best man.
(LAUGHING)
(RHYTHMIC DRUMMING)
(BE MY HUSBAND
BY LISA HANNIGAN PLAYING)
Be my husband
And I'll be your wife
This is taking forever.
Be my husband
Penny.
Outside you there
is no place to go
Eliot.
Fen.
Nice to meet you.
Will you marry me?
Ooh, Daddy now, now
Love me good
(QUENTIN READING)
Okay, okay,
where are you?
Where is this?
Please don't treat
me so doggone mean
The blade is yours.
You're the meanest
man I have ever seen
Ha!
What?
That's hot.
Here, maybe it's
just for high kings.
Oh! Jesus!
Okay, father-in-law,
why is this blade
1,000 degrees?
It may only be handled
by Master Magicians.
Are none of
you masters?
Okay, I found the castle.
We can...
Oh! Cool.
Fuck!
(SCREAMS)
I hate this place!
(QUENTIN READING)
JOSH: There has to
be a trick, right?
We can't trick it into
thinking we're powerful.
The trick is, we have
to be that powerful.
I gather the crowd
you usually hang with
nods like you're smart when you
say incredibly obvious shit,
but what we need is ideas.
QUENTIN: That's a good idea.
We need
the power of a god.
Yeah, or gods.
Ember and Umber.
Who haven't been seen for
decades, so, good luck with that.
Okay, I have a much
less idiotic idea.
Why don't we use a Magician who's
actually been around The Beast?
The girl from
his dungeon.
JOSH: So much less
idiotic, it's almost good.
I'm with Penny.
Eliot?
Yeah, according
to the fine print
not actually
written down,
I have a virgin farm
girl to impregnate.
Right this second?
ELIOT: This very one.
Best of luck, all.
You're welcome.
Mrs. Me?
Mmm.
If I die while he's
balling himself limp,
I will haunt the shit
out of his ass.
MARGO: You're
fucking kidding me.
JOSH: That's why they call it
the Castle That Isn't There.
Because it's invisible.
QUENTIN: The truth is,
the castle was constructed
to be invisible primarily
for budgetary reasons.
The royals had spent their
entire seasonal allowance
and then realized they still
had a castle to build,
so, they figured builder's
grade material is just fine
if you can't see it.
You guys run,
I'll distract them.
Don't be stupid.
They're men.
JOSH: My sister! Please, help!
She just fainted. Can one
of you do something?
(GASPS) Hey, hey.
(MARGO MOANS)
MARGO: I need help.
GUARD: You all right, miss?
Where am I?
(DOOR OPENS)
Victoria.
(GASPING)
Hey, we're here
to get you out.
We're here to get
you out. Okay?
The cuffs...
I can't...
They keep you
from traveling.
Yeah.
We'll get them.
Can you walk?
There's someone
else in the next cell.
QUENTIN: Ember?
We need to talk to you.
QUENTIN: So, here
we are at the temple,
hoping against hope
and all that.
(RUMBLING)
Ah!
(QUENTIN READING)
lt is customary to bow,
children of Earth.
Have you brought
me little cakes?
No.
Uh, we didn't really know
that we were supposed to.
Oh.
And I am so tired
of eating mice.
(CHUCKLES)
No matter.
And you are?
Uh, I'm Quentin Coldwater.
And Julia Wicker.
Huh.
Spank my cheeks. You're
usually dead by now.
He kills you and I'm left
here to hide like an animal
in horrid, arid,
cake-deficient Loria,
but you're here.
What happened?
What are you doing here?
He lured me into
a trap, of course.
The Beast?
As you call him, yes.
He snared me and
my dear, departed Umber.
Wait, Umber's dead?
It's unseemly,
all of it.
I'm sorry.
I don't mean
to disrespect,
but how could a Magician
put the drop on you?
Fillory's magic belongs to
no one, not even a god.
A Magician with
enough determination
can harness its forces
and make haggis
of any one of us.
Hmm.
So, now I just wait
till he is slain.
I'm so fucking bored,
children of Earth.
Ha!
I've had sex with every
nymph in the kingdom.
Well, we're
here to help.
But you're not a nymph.
No, I'm...
What the fuck is
wrong with you?
Pray pardon?
What are you
doing here?
You're just going
to let The Beast
trample the shit
out of Fillory?
You think that I
want to be here?
I think you're being
kind of a whiny bitch.
Q, maybe don't insult...
No, does he care,
or not?
You're right.
Years trying to
outwit him.
(CHUCKLES)
Greatest failure,
deepest shame.
And now he is prepared
for anything I do.
It's not I who can
defeat him, not directly.
I'll do it.
I volunteer.
I'll kill The Beast.
I love Fillory.
I don't know why.
But I am supposed
to be here.
I'm supposed
to fight for it.
Can you be the champion
we've been waiting for?
I want to be.
I'm ready to be.
I'll do whatever
it takes.
You love Fillory.
And you never stopped.
Julia stopped.
I mean, maybe in college,
but now I totally...
Yes, you see,
she stopped.
But you never did.
Only the best
and the purest
can face The Beast,
and that is you.
Right, okay,
so here's the thing,
I can't really touch the knife
that can kill The Beast.
Yes, you need
my strength.
I will infuse you
with my essence.
I have gifted you
my bestowal,
my largesse,
the seed of my power.
When you are ready
to face The Beast,
imbibe it.
JULIA: ls that semen?
Thank you.
Hmm. Thank you.
And you,
daughter of Earth.
Hmm.
Your mind
is encumbered.
A shroud.
No...
What?
Crudely made.
Ember, no,
it's okay...
I shall remove it.
JULIA: Remove what?
No, no, don't!
God. Jules!
You're welcome.
No need to thank me.
(GASPING)
Best of luck.
Oh, my God.
Jules...
Please. Please, don't.
Please don't touch me,
please don't...
Okay.)'-
Hey, Jules, come on. What happened?
Just tell me, please.
Can you take my memory?
Please, take my memory.
I don't know how.
Then we have to go.
QUENTIN: I knew Julia wouldn't
tell me until she was ready,
but that might be never.
(GASPS)
Here.
Thank you.
Any time.
Honestly, I was
getting pretty sick
of hearing your
voice in my head.
And I wanted to help you so badly.
I'm sorry I...
Don't be.
You found me.
Look, is there
some trick?
How do you take
people along?
Any of us can.
Well, I can barely
travel me.
They're a spell.
MARGO: Ugh. Literally?
QUENTIN: So, the dungeon?
Roaring success,
and a twofer.
Sorry?
We should see if
he's awake by now.
QUENTIN: on, my God.
That's Christopher
Plover.
What?
We were wrong
about everything.
Plover's not The Beast.
No.
Martin Chatwin is.
I loved Martin.
But there's something black
inside him I failed to see.
Look at the markings
on his face.
Age suspension magic,
so every day
he can start over.
Yeah, poor you.
ALICE: We need to find Martin.
Why? You can't stop him.
Tell us everything or
I'm going to feed
you to him.
(EXHALES)
When he was still a child,
Fillory stopped taking him.
Once he found his way back, he
made it his mission to stay.
He'd heard about
the Wellspring,
the most ancient
location in Fillory.
Which is what?
The source of all magic.
It's not only stronger than Ember
and Umber, it created them.
Fillory runs on it.
Martin goes every
night to drink from it,
draining it a little
more each time.
The Wellspring's
magic is so strong,
it killed every
human thing in him.
There's only The Beast now.
So, he goes to the Wellspring every
night, but it's not on any map.
(SIGHS) Guess I can
start asking around.
Or cast some kind
of locator maybe?
Or ask me.
He never could
hide his mind from me.
Our connection.
Okay, I vote we test
the knife out on him.
VICTORIA: Be careful.
Josh, come on.
We've got to go.
Come on!
JOSH: I have your cloak...
QUENTIN: Yeah,
Josh and Victoria bailed.
On one hand, fuck them,
on the other hand,
you can't really blame them.
So, I was writing this down
because I didn't know much,
but I knew that I was
the hero of this story.
lt all just felt
like the exact moment
that my entire life
had been building up to,
all of the reading,
and dreaming,
and loneliness, and magic.
All of it.
And then...
Well, and then this
story actually happened.
And I started to
realize the truth.
It's so insignificant.
Us being together
and falling apart,
I mean, it just
doesn't matter.
I made a mistake.
I know you don't want to
hear it, but I love you.
You're right,
I don't.
But I'm not going to go
in there angry at you.
Okay? I've got your back, Quentin.
We all do.
You know,
my entire life,
ever since the first time I
read Fillory and Further,
I've been waiting
for some
powerful being to
come down and say,
"Quentin Coldwater,
you are the one."
Every book, every movie,
it's about one special guy.
He's chosen.
In real life,
for every one guy,
there are a billion
people who aren't.
(LAUGHS)
Almost none of us
are the one.
Ember said...
Ember is a little
out of touch, I think.
You're a better Magician.
And you're a better person.
And I think that
if he'd met you,
he wouldn't be so
sure that it's me.
But you're the one
that they say
shows up every
single time, it's you.
I want to be
the one. I do.
It's just,
it's the adult
part of me,
the part of me that
understands how magic works,
it just keeps screaming
that it's you.
Every time that
Jane reset the loop,
she changed something.
So, what if I change
something?
What if I give
the blade to you?
You're not as good as I hoped,
Quentin Coldwater.
But you're better
than you know.
PENNY: Alice, you okay?
Come on, hon.
Pretend it's prom night and
you just want to shut him up.
Did you bogart
the whole thing?
Alice?
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Q, uh, can I...
Can I talk to you?
(CRYING)
Jules, talk to me.
I did something.
Me and my friends.
We followed
all the clues.
We thought that she
was leading us to her,
we summoned her.
You know,
I actually believed
Our Lady Underground
chose me.
(ALL CHANTING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Guys, stop.
We should stop.
Julia. You dumb
little witch.
You can't
unring a bell.
(LAUGHING)
Richard.
Move! Richard, move!
(GROANS)
(ALL PANTING AND SHRIEKING)
(GASPS) Stop her!
MAN: Do something.
WOMAN: Nothing's working.
Oh, God.
Richard.
RICHARD: You'll find I've
taken away your magic,
so there's no point
in trying.
(SPITS)
My thanks for
opening the door.
You may address me
as Reynard the Fox,
trickster of the faithful,
the pure of heart,
the very stupid.
Richard...
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SHRIEKS)
No, no!
(ALL CHOKING AND GAGGING)
Kady!
Run, run.
Kady, that was my hermit
who healed your heart.
And now,
I'm going to taste it.
Don't you fucking
touch her!
When you address me...
(WHISPERS)
...avert your gaze.
I said, "Don't you
fucking touch her."
Fine. I'll take
you first.
(SCREAMING)
Kady,go!
I chose you, Julia.
From the first moment you
prayed, I felt your body.
I lifted it in my hands...
(GROWLING)
(WHIMPERS)
(RICHARD GROWLING)
(CRYING)
I can give you the greatest
pleasure of your life.
I can make you...
Ow! (CRYING)
(RICHARD GROWLING)
(PANTING)
(SOBBING)
JULIA: I need your help.
Something happened.
(CRYING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Jesus.
Thank you for coming.
I got you.
The thing,
where is it now?
Gone. lt got
what it wanted.
I didn't know
who else to call.
You called
the right person.
I'm going to help
you clean this up.
I'm going to
need another favor.
And I know it'll cost me,
but I don't care.
Jesus,Julia,
I want to help.
What Brakebills
did to your memory?
I need you to do it to me.
Please.
Jules. Uh...
Yeah, I know. What
the fuck were we thinking?
You were trying
to do good,
and you got duped.
It's not your fault.
Jules, you saved Kady.
Yeah, but what about
everyone else?
You know, what...
Hey.
I'm going to help you.
I promise,
whatever that means.
It means find him.
It means kill him.
And somehow I doubt that
that's easy, or even possible.
Well, impossible shit
is sort of our thing.
The Wellspring
of all magic?
It's a truck stop
shit-house.
QUENTIN: He'll be here soon.
Let's go.
The fuck?
It's Plover's
writing room.
All that power,
and he can't stop thinking
about where it happened.
Fillory needs meds
way more than magic.
Okay, so, where's
the actual Wellspring?
Poor Martin.
Okay, so...
(MOTH WINGS BUZZING)
THE BEAST: Quentin.
Is it time for
this already?
Hi, Martin.
We know it's you.
Mmm.
(LOCK CLICKS)
Well, you made it a good
long way this time around.
But this is it,
Quentin.
QUENTIN: I know
you're still in there.
Look at this.
You still feel,
you're still hurt,
and you should be after
what happened to you.
The mediocre are
always so sentimental.
Although, must say,
most wouldn't walk to certain
death 40 times in a row.
(CHUCKLING)
You're no quitter.
Mmm.
Right.
Let's get this over with.
Wait.
I have an offer.
Jane gave me
a message for you.
A gift.
She said that
you would want it,
that you would
understand.
Your stupid
bloody cards.
Your stalling tactics haven't
gotten any less pathetic.
Next time, put something
useful in your pocket.
Oh, that's right.
No next time.
(CHOKING)
Shit!
You're stronger
than you were.
Haven't learned to cast
while you're bleeding out?
(CHOKING AND COUGHING)
For the love of Christ,
children...
Ah!
(COUGHING)
(SHRIEKS)
(GROANING)
Quentin Coldwater.
Wait.
(CELL PHONE LINE TRILLING)
(CRYING)
I need... I need your help.
Something happened.
Ah!
(WHIMPERING)
Something's
still happening.
Stronger as well,
I see.
So many surprises.
So,
what do you want?
Jules.
You killed Umber.
And you trapped Ember.
You know how to
deal with gods.
fuck up their shit.
Julia. No.
I want to make a deal.
Let's.
PENNY: No.
(PENNY GROANING AND PANTING)
God.