MARGO: Previously on
The Magicians...
My mother was
a hedge witch, too.
I didn't know
you were a hedge.
Oh, yes. My mentor,
Everett, found me.
The Foremost saved them
with special weapons
that expel possession.
They call them ice axes,
and I'm assuming that's poetic license.
So, we might have
a chance to save Eliot.
Overthrow me right
the fuck now, Fen.
- I never should have...
- Or I will never forgive you.
And neither will Eliot,
if you keep me from getting
the one thing that can save him.
(GROANS)
When the going gets tough,
tough listens
to pop anthems from the '80s.
(DOOR OPENS)
Hi. It's me. It's the real me.
It's Eliot.
This is a mind palace situation
and we don't have a lot of time,
and I have some extremely
major shit to tell you.
THE MONSTER:
Some god of war.
He only liked them
when they were too weak to fight.
He's not trying
to rebuild his body.
That's not what
the stones are.
That's not what they're for.
It's so much worse than that.
- Just breathe.
- If the stones aren't for building a body,
what does
he want with them?
No, he's building a body.
His sister's.
He's trying to bring her
back to life.
Oh, my God.
That's the girl he thought was a sacrifice
to summon Enyalius, but she wasn't.
Enyalius and the other gods
killed her.
They chopped her up and turned
her into four stone organs.
- Jesus. There's two of them.
- Yeah.
And if he got prison
and she got the death penalty,
I'm guessing
she's the bad one.
Till he remembers,
he won't know
to go look for Enyalius.
THE MONSTER: Hi.
If you want to talk to me,
the price is a drink.
You're fun.
One drink.
- BARTENDER: What are you having, ma'am?
- Vodka ice.
THE MONSTER: Vodka ice.
BARTENDER: There you go.
- I have a question.
- No, I don't come here often.
You haven't
seen me anywhere.
And, yes, I do
have plans this weekend.
Still have a question?
Yes.
Why does this place
smell like death?
(LAUGHING)
It is weird, right?
Bar next to a hospital.
Doctors need happy hour,
too, I guess.
So that's what you are?
A doctor?
No.
I'm sick.
But I got good news today.
I'll only be sick
for another two months.
Three, maybe.
Sometimes my friend says
one thing but means another thing.
Is that what you're doing?
- Keep 'em coming.
MAN: (SINGING OVER EARPHONES)
Meet me in a restaurant
Meet me on the top
of the world
Meet me
And we'll talk the language of love
I'll meet you
anywhere you want
on a ballroom floor
Well, I'm definitely hitting
my step goals today, huh?
Meet me and we'll float to
the level above
I wish you'd drop
what you're doing
- (PANTING)
- (MUSIC STOPS)
Jesus, fuck,
a wise man's donkey.
Just give me a sign.
Come on. Where's water?
Anything.
(WIND HOWLING)
(MUSIC RESUMES)
Wait.
(SINGING) Don't get me wrong
If I'm looking kind of dazzled
El?
I see neon lights
Whenever you walk by
Eliot?
Don't get me wrong
Oh, my God.
If you say hello
and I take a ride
Upon a sea
where the mystic moon
Is playing havoc
with the tide
Hey! It's you, right?
Don't get me wrong
It can't be The Monster.
He doesn't have the moves.
Hey, what are you
doing here?
Turn down the music
and talk to me, will you?
Wait a sec.
Whoa.
Oh, my God.
I'm tripping on lizard.
Don't get me wrong
If I'm acting so distracted
I'm thinking
about the fireworks
Oh, come on.
That go off when you smile
Don't get me wrong
If I split
like light refracted
I'm only off to wander
Across a moonlit mile
Once in a while,
two people meet
Seemingly for no reason
Theyjust pass on the street
Suddenly thundershowers
everywhere
Who can explain
the thunder and rain?
MARGO: Don't get me wrong.
I'm happy to see you.
Where are you taking me, Eliot?
I'm so thirsty.
Don't get me wrong
If I come
and go like fashion
I might be great tomorrow
But hopeless yesterday
Don't get me wrong
If I fall
in the mode of passion
It might be unbelievable
But let's not say so long
It might be just fantastic
(GROANS)
Don't get me wrong
MAN: Woman, hello.
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
Oh, hey.
Hi.
Can't believe that psychotropic
douche got me here.
Can I get some water?
Who wants
the honor of killing her?
Hey, if water's a dealio,
I'm good.
Oh, we have water.
What we don't have
are strangers
- wandering into our camp.
- Her wrist.
Our enemy's enemy
is our ally.
Well, how about that?
(THUD)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
You're in pain,
aren't you?
Come with me.
I can take it away.
Sorry,
but I got to get home
and tell my parents
all the medical debt was for nothing.
Thanks for the drinks.
Wait.
Do that again.
My face.
Touch my face.
Are you okay?
Whenever you touch my face,
I remember something.
Again.
You remind me of someone
I had forgotten...
My sister.
I'm gonna leave.
No, you have to
come with me now.
No, I'm...
What's up?
This was
in the Mirror World.
And I heard you were looking
for the binder, so...
(GASPS) Holy shit.
It's in some language
I've never seen before. I...
Well, I'll get on this just as soon
as we find Enyalius.
Hopefully before
The Monster does.
I thought we wanted him
to find Enyalius.
Yeah, we did,
but we were wrong.
He's building his sister.
What are y'all doing?
Tracking the Library's entire
magic infrastructure
to find weak points
and start a rebellion.
But, um, good luck
with yours.
Yeah. Thanks. You, too.
Yeah, I can tell you
what he looks like,
the food the dude
likes to eat,
but shit-all
for anything useful.
One thing is bugging me.
In the memory,
I could swear he was
wearing a ring, emerald.
Guy is described up and down,
but nothing about the ring.
Wait a minute.
Did you say emerald?
Yeah.
When I did research
with the Free Traders,
there was this god.
What was his name? Uh...
He... He always
worked in disguise,
but he was known for always
wearing an emerald ring.
So Enyalius is a front.
JULIA: Here.
Aengus.
Celtic god.
- Jules, it says here he's a trickster.
- It's fine.
And we...
It wouldn't be a summoning.
We can only get to him
through a magical creature.
Apparently there's
a whole species
that exists to entertain him
and protect him.
And they're
really annoying and...
What I'm getting at is,
we need to find a leprechaun.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
- Don't!
- I'm sorry.
Listen, I... I just saw
this red sand out there.
It was following me.
I thought it was
'cause I was tripping balls.
Our desert is alive.
It's filled with demon spirits
that attack our women.
Okay.
Speaking of D-spirits,
I'm looking for something
- I think you guys have.
- MAN: You know what can happen.
- A pair of black...
- WOMAN: You're angry with me?
How dare you?
You lay with my sister,
and I'm the one you scream at?
I'm the one you threaten?
- Zal, calm yourself.
- Pig!
You want my sister?
She's yours.
Wow.
Desert Dynasty.
Think we're gonna
get a girl fight?
Jesus, how long
does one lick last?
Take her. You two
deserve each other.
- You must be silent! Now.
- (WHOOSHING)
(GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
- (GRUNTS)
- (MAN SCREAMS)
Gross.
But cool, but gross.
(GROANING)
(GRUNTS)
So, anytime a woman gets
a teensy bit emotional,
one of those things rises up
out of the sand, and what?
Possesses her.
Eventually causing paralysis,
even death.
Men save us because they alone
have the strength to survive.
And the spirit zoo
you got going?
They can't be killed,
so I've learned
how to imprison them.
Some brave dudes.
And some awfully
compliant women.
You're not seeing or hearing this,
are you?
Seeing or hearing...
I thought so.
Man, this lizard's got
a half-life like uranium.
So the guy with the axes,
which tent's he hang his thong in?
Have we identified the leader
of the Serpent group yet?
Not yet, but we're looking.
Where?
Phyllis is in charge
of that investigation.
I could join her.
Perhaps there are places
she doesn't know to look
that I would,
considering my past.
That's a very generous offer.
But it seems that you have
enough on your plate already.
Hmm.
Very well.
MARGO: I was just
sitting in a bar
when a bear named Humbledrum
started talking to me.
What can I tell you?
Fillory's a weird place.
So I hear.
- But you...
- Mmm-hmm.
- A woman...
- As king?
- Talking animals.
I'm gonna go
get some more.
ELIOT: Wow.
Light speed, Bambi.
Okay, can you just tell me?
What the hell are you?
Pieces of you.
Your spirit guide.
Your memories.
Your Eliot.
Your conscience.
- Speaking of conscience...
- Wait, what?
You're really gonna
pass lycanthropy
to a guy who lives
on a planet with two moons?
I'll tell them I'm surfing
the red breakers,
and we got to get creative.
And this is just
to get the axes.
- Out, now.
- (MUSIC PLAYING)
And this is
guiding me how?
It's the song you think to yourself
whenever you're working a guy, remember?
High school,
junior year?
- Ray Latanza.
- Yeah.
This song came out
on the car radio.
I wanted to ride in his Porsche,
so I gave him a hand job.
In your own driveway,
which is sad,
'cause then your dad
walked out.
Okay, road closure
on Memory Lane.
(SINGING) I don't know
where I'm going
But I sure know
where I've been
BOTH: Hanging on the promises
in the songs of yesterday
'Cause I've made up my mind
I ain't wasting no more time
ALL:
Here I go again
Hey, Margo.
Thanks for inviting me.
I invited her?
(SINGING) Though I keep searching
for an answer
I never seem to find
what I'm looking for
O Lord, I pray
You give me the strength to carry on
ELIOT AND FEN:
'Cause I know what it means
To walk along the lonely
street of dreams
Here I go again on my own
Going down the only road
I've ever known
JOSH AND FEN: Like a drifter,
I was born to walk alone
And I made up my mind
I ain't wasting no more time
The Library says that they have
sufficient levels of ambient magic.
Magic output reports
are published weekly.
Yeah, well, we didn't trust
them, and guess what.
Look.
This is how much magic the Library says is
being distributed as ambient.
And this is the level
in the pipes right now.
It's nothing close to the amount
of magic they say there is.
So long as Library members
get their Deweys, who cares?
Beside hedges.
- That can't be right.
- It is.
We bugged the pipes.
A beetle
with McCormick's tracer.
Were you mapping
the pipe system?
Trying to.
Until our beetle disintegrated
somewhere outside Earth.
But the spell
shows magic levels.
And when we saw this,
we thought we should show you,
because I don't think
you signed up
to work for an organization
that lies, right?
- I'm sure there's an explanation.
- There is.
Harriet told you and me.
Everett's trying
to squeeze out hedges.
This is just
more of the same.
Look, you are on the inside.
You can find out where
the extra magic is going
and why they're hoarding it
and why the Library is lying.
Mmm.
MARGO: Yeah, sweetie.
Just let me borrow them.
I'll have them back in a day,
two at the most.
- No one else can use them but me.
- Mmm!
They're enchanted.
As I'm sure you can understand
better than most.
I, uh... (CHUCKLES)
I loved it last night
when you did that thing to me.
(SIGHS) What are you,
some kind of witch?
Magician.
So can I get ones
that work for me?
You'll have to make your own.
Swell. How?
Mostly white, no?
But every hundredth
grain or so...
Is black.
Mmm.
A warrior goes
alone into the desert,
picks out only the black ones,
enough to fill a large bag,
which is then forged.
Thanks.
- You're gonna try?
- I'm gonna do.
(CHUCKLES) If you get the least bit emotional,
the spirits will possess you.
Clear on that.
And there'll be
no man to protect you.
- Story of my life.
- And you can't use magic.
- It renders the grains...
- Impotent?
- I don't know that word.
- You sure don't, Marathon Man.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) I'm just another heart
in need of rescue
Waiting on
love's sweet charity
And I'm gonna hold on
for the rest of my days
What is she doing here?
- Four-octave range, bitch.
- Seriously?
I got my id,
my lost innocence,
my guilt,
and now my inadequacy?
(SINGING) 'Cause I know
what it means
To walk along the lonely
street of dreams
And here I go again
on my own
ALL: Going down the only road
I've ever known
Like a drifter, I was born
to walk alone
And I've made up my mind
I ain't wasting no more time
But here I go again
Okay, this is too much.
Your subconscious thought
you needed some wisdom.
You do whiskey,
not wisdom.
Okay. Fine.
(SINGING) And I
made up my mind
I ain't wasting
no more time
Show-off.
ALL: (SINGING)
Here I go again
Here I go!
Ah, morning.
What can I do you for?
Uh, we were hoping that you could
help us find somebody.
Well, I'm not sure about that,
but, uh, I can fix your shoes.
- Uh, this is Berry's, right?
- Yeah.
I'm Berry, so...
We're looking
for a leprechaun.
(LAUGHING)
Right. So are you looking for, like,
a pot-of-gold leprechaun,
or is this a breakfast-cereal
situation, or...
We're looking
for a god named Aengus,
but to find him we have to talk
to a leprechaun first,
and I know this is
a bat-shit thing to say
with a straight face,
but if you could help us...
(SIGHS)
Well, all right,
since you're desperate.
Are you the leprechaun?
What do you expect some short
little bearded child in overalls
with a buckle on me hat?
Why didn't you just tell us?
Because you're hysterical
when you're desperate.
- (ARCADE MUSIC PLAYING)
- Want to see Aengus?
He's right through there.
QUENTIN: Great. No knob.
Someone's trying
to kill your boss,
and we need to warn him,
so, please, just let us through.
No.
Aengus is pretty strict on that.
Keeps out the riffraff.
Don't worry.
Everything you need to open
the door is in here.
It's fun.
It's an escape room,
like for kids' parties.
Not ours.
(BERRY LAUGHS)
ELIOT: (SINGING)
Beautiful dreamer
Wake unto me
Starlight and dew drops
Are waiting for thee
Enough.
You loved this song when you were little
and your father sang it.
You're me, right?
I run me, so shut it.
(SIGHS)
Yes.
- It's okay. I think I can get it.
- Whoa, whoa, wait, wait.
Lets the knob down,
but if you stick your arm up there,
you'll just get sliced up.
(CHUCKLES)
We have no idea how close The Monster is.
So, if I get cut, I get cut.
We don't have time
to argue about this.
Stupid, 'cause one of us here
is indestructible.
(SIGHS)
(CHEERS)
It's you. Julia.
Aengus has been
very interested in you.
What's that
supposed to mean?
No, no, nothing to worry.
We've all been interested in the girl
who became the goddess who became...
QUENTIN:
Shit. We still need a key.
Well, then maybe Aengus
would appreciate if you let us through.
Aw...
I can't.
- (GIGGLES)
- (SIGHS)
I quit.
I can't do this anymore.
That goddamn lullaby.
He'd sing it
every night to me.
Even away on business,
he'd sing it over the phone.
He called me
his little princess.
He was better
than other dads.
And he thought I was better
than other daughters.
- Until...
- You had the audacity to grow up.
Fuckin' apologies
for the surprise, Dad.
He saw what he raised...
A woman
he couldn't control.
Who didn't need
anyone else's approval.
Nothing deadlier
to the fragile male ego.
He was the one who told me
I could be anything.
And I believed him.
But he didn't tell you
that the world makes you choose.
You can be
one of the smart ones
or one of the pretty ones
or even a strong one.
- But...
- Try to be all three...
You better learn to smile
and shut up...
'Cause the second
you're you,
the second...
Out loud, pissed off,
it's, "What a bitch."
"What a slut."
"Who the fuck
does she think she is?"
So you never
give them a chance.
You hit first.
And anyone dumb enough to hit back soon
finds that there's no hurting you,
sheathed in all that
hard, glossy armor.
Then why does it
hurt so much?
Why does it feel like
I'm losing my mind, Eliot?
Wind and sand
reduce mountains
into rubble.
Are you stronger
than a mountain?
I'm a king.
Not a goddamn princess.
A king.
You were.
I'm still a king.
King of manipulation.
King of pointless rage.
King of "I can't do this."
King of "He was right."
King of "I eventually
fuck up everything."
- That's not true.
- That's what Eliot would say.
But you're not Eliot,
are you?
You're me.
And we know.
Margo. Don't...
Get angry?
I'm angry
every second.
Every second my eyes are open
because I know who I am.
Not what I pretend to be.
Can't do anything
except pose and judge.
Margo, you have to stop.
The only thing I ever did right
was be your best friend.
That's the only thing
I ever got right.
And I can't even do that,
or else this fucking bag
would be fucking full!
(SCREAMING)
(SOBBING)
Wait.
You're a girl?
Sorry, woman. Female?
And how am I hearing you?
You're in my thoughts.
Who isn't?
- Are you getting this?
- Yeah, of course.
Of course.
So then maybe you can tell me
if you're a womanish thing,
why do you do such shitty things
to other women?
What?
- Fuck.
- QUENTIN: Last one.
- PENNY: It doesn't work.
God damn it.
(GIGGLES)
Come on.
(BERRY CHUCKLES)
You may enter.
Aengus. Or, Enyalius.
Whatever your name is.
Do we... We're too late.
Shit. Shit.
(LAUGHING)
Oh, your face.
- What the hell, dude?
- We were trying to warn you.
Yeah, yeah,
I got you good.
Your anxieties
are glowing.
- This one especially.
- The Monster is coming for you.
The one that you
locked up in Blackspire.
You care for a snack? Something to drink?
I mean, you've certainly earned it.
No. No. We...
We want you to leave.
I have a place to hide.
I just refuse
to let your panic infect me.
Happiness is a choice,
you know.
Yeah, well,
you should turn the panic up.
We wasted so much time
in your escape-room shit,
The Monster could be here
any second.
(LAUGHING)
You mortals are always
so precious about time.
(MOCKING) "There's never
enough of it."
(IN AMERICAN ACCENT) "Ahh! Every second,
I'm closer to death. Ahh!"
(IN NORMAL ACCENT)
Well, yes, but...
How can you enjoy life if you're
in constant fear of its end?
Think on it.
Except you, of course, Julia.
It's a fascinating
pleasure.
We're trying to save you.
You need to hide now.
(GASPS) Hide?
Yes, it took me a while
to shake the mortal fear, too.
You'll get there.
So that's a no
on the snacks?
(CLEARS THROAT) I did hope that the decoy
and alias would keep him at bay,
but just in case...
Fallout shelter of sorts.
No one, not even
The Monster, can get in.
It's gonna be so very boring,
but, uh...
Since you insist.
- Thank God.
- You're most welcome.
- But before I, um...
- Jesus Christ.
Julia, come with me.
What?
I know a thing or two
about god powers.
I'm sure I can fix
whatever's wrong with you.
We're more alike
than you know.
Think it over.
Whilst I remember
my password.
(AENGUS CLEARS THROAT)
(AENGUS SIGHS)
(PRESSING BUTTONS)
MARGO: So, can we do
this thing or what?
- I don't mean to be brusque.
- Do what?
Turn my black sand into axes.
(LAUGHING)
Uh-oh.
Guys, whatever
the joke is, skip it.
- It's just so...
- Richly enjoyable.
Not to mention a first.
You should feel good
at least.
No other woman has ever gone alone
out there and come back
with all of that.
- Most give up.
- Or die.
Yeah, hilarious.
I can't believe
your kingdom exiled you.
You're strong, smart...
And a very adequate whore.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, yeah, it's a big uh-oh.
You know, a funny thing
happened out there.
I met one of them,
a demon spirit.
And I got the whole download on
how this place really rolls.
See, I lost my shit,
in a big way.
And she came up
out of the sand.
Only, I didn't see
shifty, scary smoke.
I saw her.
Maybe it's this weirdo
fairy eye I have.
It's a long
and very bizarre story
for another day
and another quest.
But I also heard her.
She didn't attack me.
That's not what they do.
But you guys already
know that, don't know?
You and your whole ruling council of
pussy-phobic chuckle-dicks.
'Cause those spirits,
when they hear a woman
who's sad
or scared or upset...
Or angry...
They rise up
out of the sand to help.
And they help by possessing
whatever man is causing the distress.
They're protectors.
And if the problem
isn't a man,
they do whatever it takes
to help women.
(GASPS)
If your intent is to tell
our people those lies,
then I'm sorry,
but that's not gonna happen.
If your intent
was to double-cross me,
you missed a key
plot point, shit-crisp.
I'm a fuckin' magician.
- (GROANS)
- (MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING) There's a storm
on the way
All right
There's a storm on the way
And it's coming
no matter what I say
(VOCALIZING)
BOTH:
There's truth in the thunder
There's love in the lightning
The feeling is frightening
But isn't it exciting?
I'm something
like stormy weather
If I weren't, we'd never
huddle together
Do I have to tell you
That I'm also the sunlight
that shines shortly after?
I just rain 'cause I have to
On to another chapter,
I wish you lots of laughter
Till the next time you see me
Just remember you need me,
I'm the storm coming
Just remember you need me
So here I come,
I come, I come
No...
I'm the storm coming
Just remember you need me
I wish you lots of laughter
Till the next time
you see me
Just remember you need me
I'm the storm coming
- (BONES SNAPPING)
- (GASPS)
Just remember you need me
I'm the storm coming
So here I come,
I come, I come
I'm the storm coming
Come on
Here I come, I come, I come
Don't ask why
Just live
And die
Aren't you gonna
use the axes?
No.
Tell the spirits
to exit your husband.
They serve you...
All of you.
Come on, ladies.
It's time to get your head
out of the sand... Literally.
Close your eyes.
Think the thought,
"Leave my husband."
(GASPS)
She's talking to me.
From now on, if a demon
possesses a man or a woman,
you can just
tell them to leave.
Or stay and finish them off.
Or help with the laundry.
They're pretty handy.
Hey.
(SIGHS)
This isn't over.
Yes, it is.
No, it's not.
I'm gonna figure out whatever
the hell this, uh, binder's all about
and become a goddess again.
Okay, that's not
gonna make a difference.
Well, yeah, there's a ton
of reasons it won't,
but when has
that stopped us?
Look, once I finally get this
goddess shit straight...
I need you...
To help remind me
what it's like to give a shit
about other people,
to want to risk
your life to save them.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
I got it.
May I come in?
MARGO: Look who's up.
Trump and Aunt Lydia.
Welcome to the
New Desert Order.
It's gonna suck for you.
(SINGING) Beautiful dreamer
Queen of my song
List' while I woo thee
With soft melody
Gone are the cares of
Life's busy throng
Nice song, asshole.
Beautiful dreamer
Awake unto me
Look, I know you're just
a reptilian hallucination.
But I miss you...
So much.
And I promise you...
I'm gonna get you back.
(BREATHES SHARPLY)
(SINGING)
Sound of the rude world
Heard in the day
Led by the moonlight
Have all passed away
ELIOT AND MARGO: (SINGING)
Beautiful dreamer
Queen of my song
List' while I woo thee