Previously on The Magicians...
Have you ever
heard of Brakebills?
No. JULIA: It's
like this secret Yale,
and you have to be able
to do magic to even get in.
Well, I can do magic.
JULIA: Yeah, so can I.
Sorry, I just got your e-mail.
My fifth e-mail.
Just tell me what
you meant by...
I mean not herself. I
mean barely talks to me.
She looks like a goddamn
ghost. She's not Julia.
I need you to tell them
they were wrong about me.
Tell them to test me again.
I'm sorry, but they would know.
It's really okay if
this is not your thing.
So you were... Top
bitch in New York.
I am willing to teach the
right people everything I know.
Who are we trying to contact?
- Charlie.
And who's Charlie?
My brother. He died.
Jesus, we could not have
screwed up that spell worse,
and we can't take it back.
Now that you're in, it's
time to learn some magic.
Just don't get too excited.
Start slow.
Yeah, I don't really do slow.
Hmm.
Being a Magician
has always been,
in part,
about accruing power.
Power over yourself,
the elements.
Power over the
future. He's back.
The very world that
exists around you.
He said he had an announcement.
But power, as you all know,
does not come cheaply.
There are reasons
we teach this curriculum
precisely the way that we do.
Skipping around,
focusing on all
the wrong things,
lack of guidance.
These are all
extremely dangerous.
There are certain
energies, certain spells,
which are far too powerful
for one Magician alone.
If you lose control,
they will turn against you.
They will kill you.
They will consume you.
Change you
into something else.
Now that I have your attention,
we test to discern
your discipline.
Your area of concentration.
It is what you are, and
with the right guidance,
you may safely rise
to unknowable heights.
You will find your scheduled
times and invitations
inside your bags.
Hey, babe, it's me. Um,
just got your message.
I'm so sorry, I got stuck.
Be there as soon as I can.
Love you.
Never gets old, does it?
Having a secret.
You have magic.
They don't.
Better than money.
Better than sex.
Well, I guess that one depends.
James is cool, really.
He barely notices.
We've both been
so busy with school.
Look,
we all juggle.
You're kicking ass.
Just don't forget to
manage your shit.
Don't want boyfriend getting worried,
following you to the safe house door.
Got it covered, okay?
I know you do.
Just saying.
Yes, these are promising.
I get a strong sense of blues
and pinks.
Is that Alice Quinn?
Alice, please sit,
if there's a seat.
Bit of a transition.
I find that I prefer an
office that I can reach
without falling down three
flights of steps that I cannot see.
This'll be quick, Alice.
Show Professor
March what you can do.
Like I said, I used to do a
lot of coin and card tricks,
and I guess sometimes I
would actually use real magic.
Predictions could mean psychic.
Vanishing could mean
illusions or physical magic.
Hmm. Curious.
What? What's curious?
Now, try holding these.
Think the alphabet in Greek.
No.
Just lovely, Miss Quinn.
So clean. Very advanced.
Physical magic. Hmm.
Definitely.
Just stare at it.
Well, you're not an herbalist.
Undetermined? Can they do that?
Yeah, Sunderland
said it happens,
so I guess they'll
try again next year.
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Your time has come
What is your discipline?
Phosphoromancy.
I bend light.
Holy shit!
There are much cooler areas.
Are you kidding me? You
have light bending power.
I'm a nothing-mancer.
I'm a squat-mancer.
Well, if you're undetermined, then
why are you assigned to the Cottage?
Literally, they
have extra space.
Well, at least they have that allegedly
mind-blowing signature cocktail.
Can't be all bad.
Uh, is there a doorbell
I missed or something?
No.
"Let yourselves in," as in
we have to figure out how.
Right.
What a bunch of dicks.
Ow!
This might actually be hard.
Hey, what about
your light-bendy thing?
Like, yeah, we could use,
like, a magnifying glass.
You know, like,
you ever burn ants
when you were a kid?
No, that's horrifying.
Take all your medicine
Phosphoromancy, bitches.
What took you so
long? I'm starving.
Welcome to our gracious abode.
You're unable to
tell You know it's over
Shit.
You and your first year boys.
What's your obsession
with the flavor of the month?
Aww! Come on.
He's a high-strung super nerd.
We love those.
I'm not an experienced
drinker, Quentin.
I couldn't tell.
You know, it should've worked.
That spell we did
to reach my brother.
I mean, I went over
it, like, a million times.
"Should've"? You
say that like you
wanna do it again.
Wait, you don't wanna
try it again, do you?
I need to know
the truth, that's all.
You know, the spell
we did was, like...
I don't know, it was
like a phone call.
We made contact,
but he didn't pick up,
so then The Beast picked up.
But that still leaves the
question, "Where's Charlie?"
Well, the last time we asked
that question, somebody died.
Never mind. What do you care?
No.
I do. I care. I wanna help.
I just... I don't...
Hmm...
Oh! Yeah.
Um...
Have you read,
uh, Teukolsky yet?
So apparently, you can find deceased
spirits with a simple locator spell.
If they wanna be found.
That's stupid.
You're stupid. You
have a stupid face.
Anyone have a match?
It's not working.
Just keep walking.
Okay.
Finally.
Guess it's Woof Fountain.
Ugh! I never liked this thing.
Eliot says it's
enchanted as shit.
Supposedly it's bottomless,
so you know the psychics love it.
Suicide fountain.
You don't think your brother...
No.
He wasn't that kind of guy.
He was the kind of guy who always wanted
to fix things for everyone around him.
He was really, really good.
You know that spell I did
on the first day of class?
With the Glass Horse?
He taught me that.
Come on, let's go.
Nothing's happening.
The whole thing
is fucking pointless.
Psychic?
I wanna punch
Sunderland in the throat.
You know, as a psychic, you'd
think you'd have seen all this coming.
Woman, please. Ahh!
Hold on.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Are we actually
doing this again?
Do you know how to close your
mind? 'Cause I will show you right now.
I thought I was.
Eliot gave me a...
Seriously, man?
Taylor Swift?
I am not singing
Taylor Swift in my head.
Okay, I'll work on it.
So, it's got lots of
space. Lots of light.
It looks really great.
I'm sorry, I guess I thought you were still
considering Yale for the fall with me.
What?
Okay, can we just
talk about this now?
Where is your head?
Why do I feel like
I'm talking to myself?
I've just been
busy with class...
Are you seeing someone else?
No! Why would you ask that?
Because you're different.
You stand me up. You
don't answer your phone.
I'm just... I'm starting
to feel like the asshole.
You're not.
Hey...
I love you.
You know that.
Look, I know I've been
moody lately, but...
I feel a lot better.
James, come on.
Hey.
Mmm.
Okay, go on. Someone killed
themselves in the fountain?
Yeah, try 15 students
and one dean.
Van Pelt. Fountain's
named after him.
It does feel a little bit off
here though, doesn't it?
Brief announcement.
The Van Pelt fountain
is temporarily off limits.
There's been an incursion.
We believe it's a
garden variety haunting.
Redrawing the wards
may have released it
much like a mouse caught
in the walls of a building.
No one was seriously hurt.
Both students involved are
recuperating in the infirmary.
Regardless,
stay away until we lock it down.
I mean, what if it was Charlie?
I don't know. Maybe.
If not, it's a pretty
big coincidence.
But if it was Charlie, don't you think
that he would have reached out to you,
directly?
Maybe he just did.
It's definitely Charlie.
Okay.
So, why would he try and
drown a bunch of psychics?
Uh... Have you met them?
Are you two talking about
what happened at Woof?
That was a private
conversation. You know.
Well... Meow!
What was that?
I Just... I don't trust her.
Okay, look. I just...
I think trying to drown
people seems a little violent.
He may not have even
known what he was doing.
I mean, spirits, they
can get confused.
Okay, then how do we talk to
him without him trying to drown us?
I don't know.
But first thing's
first. I found a spell...
Well, five actually, but they
all have their own down side.
Like, we don't know
how Charlie died exactly
and the moon is in the
wrong spot right now.
Look, I know you
don't trust her,
but maybe Margo could...
Or there's a Maori spell.
I'd have to cut off a finger,
but they might be preferable.
Quentin, I need your
help. Highest priority.
Let's go. Okay.
Hey, look, you said it yourself,
you don't have all the facts,
so maybe you don't need a spell.
Maybe you need information, and
Margo's discipline is gossip, so...
What do you need?
We have a real problem.
Is it in the box?
Professor Sunderland
came looking for a book
from the Physical
Cottage Library,
and it's missing.
I diverted her attention, but...
What does that have
to do with the box?
Books at Brakebills,
Quentin, are not just books.
One goes missing, it's not just a
library fine we're talking about here.
What're we talking about?
We're talking about...
We have
occasional parties.
During one, someone took a
book, and if we don't find that book
the faculty are going to take
a harder look at our parties,
and that cannot happen, Quentin.
So you gonna tell me
what's in the box, or...
Hmm...
What the hell is that?
The missing book is Volume One.
That...
is Volume Two.
She's going to
lead us to her mate.
Oh.
Shit.
Uh... Let me try it again.
Should be easy.
You're distracted.
I know, I just... I
have a lot going on.
No, you don't. You
have this spell. That's it.
So how do you manage it all?
Juggling magic and your life?
I don't understand the question.
I'm not judging you.
I started out like you
and you have a good life.
Boyfriend.
Probably think he
keeps you centered.
Kind of.
Or, you know, you're keeping
him around in case you fail here
and need to fall back.
All I know, you have to
mean it for magic to work.
Something clicks
when you're all-in,
and the real big stuff,
you can't do it
till you're doing
it without a net.
I need your help.
That wasn't so hard, was it?
Look, I'm just trying to find out
what happened to my brother.
He was a student
here five years ago.
Okay.
He was a physical kid.
His name was Charlie,
and then he died.
Know what? I did
hear about that.
At Woof, right?
Five, six years back?
It's all making sense now.
What is? You.
The awkward thing.
The anger underneath
the ineffable air of tragedy
you wear like a perfume.
Look, can you just tell me what
you know about Charlie? Please?
Loathe as I am to admit it, I
don't actually know anything.
Although, there was a girl
from Charlie's year who might.
Emily Greenstreet.
Who was she?
Just a girl.
When he died,
apparently she took it hard.
Dropped out. Gave up
magic. The full muggle.
It was a bit of a scandal.
Where is she now?
The city.
Fogg set her up with a job
which is how you know
they're hiding something big.
I know how to find her.
Come on, I'll show you.
I'd actually prefer to go alone.
Oh. I know you would, but...
What choice do you really have?
Penny.
Welcome.
Knew you were coming.
I know you've been dreading
this, but you're gonna like it.
The coves are for meditation
while the enclosed
"Consciousness Areas"
are reserved as a
place to cry, and process.
Hmm...
We call it, "The Amplifier."
So basically, it's like turning
your psychic powers up to 11.
Why would you wanna do that?
Oh, I get it.
You're one of those guys
who's trying to shut it out.
You wanna get control of it
or it will mess up
your shit big time,
and this is the best
place to practice.
So...
I do what? Sit.
Relax.
Let your mind wander.
It's pretty simple.
But you gotta start by
letting go, tough guy.
Less talking.
No touching.
Help!
Please! Help me! Please!
I think that's her.
Emily?
No, don't run.
These shoes are insane.
You're from
Brakebills, aren't you?
That part of my life is
behind me. I'm sorry.
Charlie was my brother.
I just wanna know
what happened to him.
Your brother saved my life.
Well, he tried to at least.
So, I fell for this professor.
I know how it sounds,
but I was young and...
And he loved me.
But then, well, he was married.
You know how it is
when you're that age.
You get terrible ideas.
Hmm...
Like what?
I thought I could make
him love me again.
Oh! Some kind of love spell?
No.
I thought if I could
make myself prettier...
Oh, God.
No one warned you
how dangerous that was?
I knew, but I'd convinced myself
that it was the only way.
It took me weeks to
figure out how to do it, and
when I did, well, you...
You can imagine how that went.
No!
I was gonna kill myself.
Emily! Wait!
What happened?
What did you do?
Please.
I just wanna help.
Don't tell anyone, please.
Course not.
Wait here. I'll be
back. I'm gonna fix this.
He mashed a
bunch of stuff together.
It was...
It was totally untested.
I really believed
he might actually be
able to undo what I did.
He was a good Magician.
You know, he would
have done anything for me.
It was a lot. It was...
It was too much.
I begged him to
stop, but he wouldn't,
and that's when it went
totally out of control.
It burned right through him...
Until he wasn't there
anymore. He was...
Do you know what a Niffin is?
No.
Yes.
It's when too much
runs through you.
Consumes you.
Only the magic is left,
but you're not
you anymore. You're...
Lost.
Where did Charlie go?
I don't know. He was just gone.
I never saw him again.
Who did all this then?
My professor.
Well, I guess you got
his attention after all.
I quit school.
Gave up magic, and
never looked back.
I'm so sorry about Charlie.
Hear that? She's
getting excited.
I think we're close.
Hold this, will you?
This bodega is
warded up the ass.
Hedge witches.
Amateurs. Magical D-leaguers.
Sad and desperate people.
Once one of 'em offered
to blow me for a spell.
It was barely worth it.
Let me do the talking.
These are witches?
Hmm. Pathetic. No?
Ugh!
This kid's trying
Popper number four.
It's painful.
Hear you're selling something.
Quentin?
Oh, hey.
What the hell are
you doing here?
You know these guys?
Yeah, they're from Brakebills.
We're friends. That's right.
We're from Brakebills.
We're classically trained
and we want our book.
We don't have your stupid book.
Are they...
Yep.
Love wins.
Hey! So, that's it?
That's all you're
gonna say to me?
Don't talk to her. Keep going.
I don't know what
you're doing here, Jules.
You're better than this.
You say that like
I had a choice.
Of course you have a choice.
No, because guess what?
Magic wasn't just handed to me.
I told you to please
tell them about me.
At first, you know, I thought
maybe they'd actually test me again,
and then I figured
someone would at least come
and try to take my
memory again, and then...
Just waiting.
It took me weeks to realize you
never even told them about me at all.
Look, Jules, I... You
were my best friend.
Yeah, and so I let it go.
What does that
mean, "You let it go?"
No, that's crazy, I
can actually do...
The people at Brakebills,
Jules, they can bend light.
They can read
minds. They can fly.
You can do a party trick.
So this is it, huh?
The real you.
Do you ever stop to think about
how maybe you treated me?
What?
I was always there...
What? You were so nice
and you were so sweet
to poor little Q who
couldn't get his shit together.
Between you and James
I was Don't put that on me.
A two-for-one charity case.
That's your interpretation.
Why are you saying this?
Because that is true, Julia!
No, that's not true. I... You
know how I felt about you.
I don't know what...
Admit it. Just admit it.
Admit it.
So, you're gonna
punish me for that?
I don't know what else to say.
You can't blame me.
Does James even
know that you're here?
You're hanging out
with a bunch of tweakers
who are turning
tricks for spells.
Are you kidding me?
These people wanna...
Stop slumming because you're pissed
that you lost, for once in your life.
I'm sorry, but I mean it.
You could really get hurt
doing this shit, and for what?
Grow up.
Do you love magic?
Is it in your soul?
Is it like the secret heart
of what you always were?
Yeah.
So you know how I feel.
Get in.
Penny, how's your head?
How do you think?
So, what's wrong with me?
Nothing's wrong.
I made the mistake of thinking
you were just psychic, but it...
It's more complicated.
You are a Traveler.
A what now?
The rarest
and most difficult discipline.
Travelers can, with
a little bit of training,
go anywhere on Earth, instantly,
just as you did.
But you can, with a
great deal of training,
actually move between worlds.
Go to other worlds? DEAN: Yes.
If the gift does
not kill you first.
Great. Just fucking great.
Do you know why I'm here?
To say this.
You've been a thin
layer of insouciance over
an open pit of
self-pity your entire life.
This is not a joke.
You do not have the luxury to mess
around now that this is out of the bottle.
You will study this. You will
master this. Do you understand?
Ain't you a bucket of
empathy, blind man.
Please say yes.
I cannot see you nod.
Fine.
Yes.
So, are we just gonna drive
all the way back to Brakebills?
We're already there.
Penny.
I've learned a great deal
about Traveling over the years.
We'll start one-on-one tutorials to
help you get a handle on your ability.
Yes,
before you accidentally
transport yourself inside a volcano.
She's right.
We were best friends.
Should we help? No.
Let me in, you assholes!
I don't know what happened.
I don't know how it got so bad.
You found out who you are
and she found out who she's not.
Life.
Tell you what.
Let's not talk.
How long were you two douchebags
gonna leave me out there?
Never mind that.
Now you're with your people.
Cheers to that.
Good God.
Cheers.
So this is a Niffin box?
This have a lid?
There isn't one.
The Niffin becomes fused with
the wood. It's unable to escape.
How do you activate
it? There's a short chant.
You just basically repeat, "I
bind you," in Turkish and English.
That sounds a little easy.
Well, that and the month
long incantation it took
to enchant the thing
in the first place.
So, this is the
enchantment research?
We're not gonna use the box.
What?
We're gonna bring Charlie back.
Okay, Alice this is the point
where I look at you like you're nuts.
Okay, look.
I've been doing some
research on Niffins.
Look, they're not even
alive. They're something else.
Look, I can't explain it,
but I know that he's out
there. He's somewhere.
Is there anything in the
literature that says that
going Niffin is reversible?
Nothing says that it isn't.
Exactly.
So I found this spell.
It can transmutate
certain meta-quantum
energies into matter, in theory.
And I combined it with an
advanced transformation ritual...
Alice, this is Major Arcana.
What? Just because
you couldn't do it?
Nobody could do it. You're
making it up as you go along.
Look, I...
You are an amazing
Magician... Don't patronize me.
I'm not patronizing you. I'm telling
you that this is not a good idea.
What do you know, hmm?
You only learned about magic,
what? Three months ago?
Okay, sure. But even I
can tell that this is crazy.
I don't understand
why you can't see that.
Fine. Stay behind.
I'm here, and I'm only here, to
find out what happened to Charlie,
and now that I know I
can help him, I'm going to.
Thanks for coming so quick.
I was kind of
surprised you called.
Thought you disappeared again.
You okay?
You wanna talk about it?
Please?
Last call, Julia.
I don't know how
to talk about it.
I got involved with something.
Made me wanna
give up everything.
Life, school. All of it.
It got under my skin,
and it...
And?
Jules, just tell me.
It's Adderall.
I started taking it when I
was applying to grad school,
and then I was
taking more and more.
I know I've been a bitch,
but lately I've been
going to meetings.
Wow!
Can I...
I don't know, can I hug you?
I wish you would.
It's okay, Jules.
I really love you, you know.
I know. I'm amazing.
Okay, so, we're here, and...
Arrive at the place of his
transformation. Present yourself.
There's a third step.
What's the third step?
I have to call in to him with
something personal between us,
um,
so Charlie used to sing
to me my favorite song
when I was feeling bad
which is kind of all the time.
Won't you come see about me
Is that The Breakfast Club?
I'll be alone dancing
You know it, baby
Tell me your troubles and doubts
Giving me everything
inside and out
Don't you forget about me
Don't, don't, don't, don't
Alice, look.
Charlie.
Charlie?
Charlie, is that you? Alice.
Oh, my God, Charlie,
I can't believe it's you.
I missed you so much. I
don't even know what to say.
Charlie, what are you doing?
Charlie, you're hurting
me. Charlie, that hurts.
You're just confused,
Charlie, it's me.
Charlie, why are you doing this?
Why?
Alice, I don't think... I
don't think that we should...
I know you're in there,
Charlie. I know it's you.
Alice!
Ha!
Charlie, stop! I can help you.
Alice, stop!
Alice, he's gonna kill
us. It's not gonna work.
You have to stop.
Shut up, I can do this.
Alice, it's not Charlie.
You are bound and held fast.
No!
I bind you!
No! I bind you!
You brought the box.
Yeah.
Alice, he was gonna kill you.
Why did you think
you had to save me?
Fuck you, Quentin.
You had no idea
what I was doing.
I was so close,
and now he's gone.
Where you going, kitty cat?
I'm done here. For good.
You should be happy.
Less competition.
Alice.
I like competition.