Previously on The Magicians...
Have you ever
heard of Brakebills?
- No.
- It's, like, this secret Yale,
and you have to be able
to do magic to even get in.
- Well, I can do magic.
- Yeah, so can I.
Sorry, I just got
your e-mail.
My fifth e-mail.
Just tell me
what you meant by--
I mean not herself.
I mean barely talks to me.
She looks like a goddamn ghost.
She's not Julia.
I need you to tell them
they were wrong about me.
Tell them to test me again.
I'm sorry, but they would know.
It's really okay
if this is not your thing.
- So you are--
- Top bitch in New York.
I'm willing to teach the right
people everything I know.
- Who are we trying to contact?
- Charlie.
- And who's Charlie?
- My brother. He died.
Jesus, we could not have
screwed up that spell worse,
and we can't take it back.
Now that you're in,
it's time to learn some magic.
Just don't get too excited.
Start slow.
Yeah, I don't really do slow.
Hmm...
Being a magician
has always been,
in part,
about accruing power.
Power over yourself,
the elements.
- Power over the future.
- He's back.
The very world
that exists around you...
He said he had an announcement.
But power, as you all know,
does not come cheaply.
There are reasons
we teach this curriculum
precisely the way that we do.
Skipping around,
focusing on
all the wrong things,
lack of guidance...
these are all
extremely dangerous.
There are certain energies,
certain spells,
which are far too powerful
for one magician alone.
If you lose control,
they will turn against you.
They will kill you.
They will consume you.
Change you...
into something else.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Now that I have your attention.
We test
to discern your discipline.
Your area of concentration.
It is what you are,
and with the right guidance,
you may safely rise
to unknowable heights.
You will find
your scheduled times
and invitations
inside your bags.
Hey, babe, it's me.
Um, ahem, just got your message.
I'm so sorry, I got stuck.
Be there as soon as I can.
Love you.
Never gets old, does it?
Having a secret.
You have magic.
They don't.
Better than money.
Better than sex.
Well, I guess that one depends.
James is cool, really.
He barely notices.
We've both been
so busy with school.
Look...
we all juggle.
You're kicking ass.
Just don't forget
to manage your shit.
Don't want boyfriend
getting worried,
following you
to the safe house door.
Got it covered, okay.
I know you do.
Just saying.
Yes, these are promising.
I get a strong sense of blues
and...and pinks.
Is that Alice Quinn?
Alice, please sit,
if there's a seat.
Bit of a transition.
I find that I prefer an office
that I can reach
without falling down
three flights of steps
that I cannot see.
This'll be quick, Alice.
Show Professor March
what you can do.
Like I said, I used to do
a lot of coin and card tricks,
and I guess sometimes
I, like, actually used
real magic.
Predictions could mean psychic.
Vanishing could mean illusions
or physical magic.
Curious.
What? What's curious?
Now, try holding these.
Think the alphabet in Greek.
No.
Just lovely, Miss Quinn.
So clean.
Very advanced.
- Physical magic.
- Hm.
Definitely.
Just stare at it.
Well, you're not an herbalist.
Undetermined?
Can they do that?
Yeah, Sunderland said
it happens,
so I guess they'll
try again next year.
♪ Yeah yeah yeah ♪
♪ You're time has come ♪
What's your discipline?
Phosphoromancy.
I bend light.
Holy shit!
There are much cooler areas.
Are you kidding me?
You have light bending power.
I'm a nothing-mancer.
I'm a squat-mancer.
Well, if you're undetermined,
then why are you
assigned to the Cottage?
Literally,
they have extra space.
Well, at least they have that
allegedly mind-blowing
signature cocktail.
Can't be all bad.
♪ Show you the ropes ♪
Uh, is there a doorbell
I missed or something?
No.
"Let yourselves in"
as in we have to figure out how.
Right.
What a bunch of dicks.
♪ Daft Punk
is playing at my house ♪
♪ My house ♪
Ow!
♪ You got to set them up kid ♪
This might actually be hard.
Hey, what about
your light-bendy thing?
Like...yeah, we could use,
like, a magnifying glass.
You know, like,
you ever burn ants
- when you were a kid?
- No, that's horrifying.
♪ Too hard to do nothing ♪
♪ Ooh ooh ♪
♪ Take all your medicine ♪
Phosphoromancy, bitches.
Whoo!
What took you so long?
I'm starving.
Welcome to our gracious abode.
♪ You're unable to tell ♪
♪ You know it's over ♪
Shit.
You and your first year boys.
What is your obsession
with the flavor of the month?
Oh, come on.
He's a high-strung super nerd.
We love those.
I'm not an experienced
drinker, Quentin.
I couldn't tell.
You know, it should have worked.
That spell we did
to reach my brother.
I mean, I went over it,
like, a million times.
Should have?
You saying that like you...
wanna do it again.
Wait, you don't wanna
try it again, do you?
I need to know the truth,
that's all.
You know, the spell
we did was, like...
I don't know,
it was like a phone call.
We made contact,
but he didn't pick up,
so then The Beast picked up.
But that still leaves
the question,
"Where's Charlie?"
Well, the last time we asked
that question, somebody died.
Never mind.
What do you care?
No.
I do. I care.
I wanna help.
I just--I don't--
Ooh, oh. Yeah.
Um...
have you read Teukolsky yet?
Uh, so apparently
you can find deceased spirits
with a simple locator spell.
If they wanna be found.
That's stupid.
You're stupid.
You have a stupid face.
Uh, anyone have a match?
Uh, it's not working.
Just keep walking.
Okay.
Finally.
Guess it's Woof Fountain.
Ugh. I never liked
this thing.
Eliot says
it's enchanted as shit.
Supposedly it's bottomless,
so you know
the psychics love it.
Suicide fountain.
You don't think
your brother--
No.
He wasn't that kinda guy.
He was the kinda guy
who always wanted
to fix things
for everyone around him.
He was really, really good.
You know that spell I did
on the first day of class?
The Glass Horse?
He taught me that.
Come on, let's go.
Nothing's happening.
The whole thing is fucking pointless.
Psychic?
I wanna punch Sunderland
in the throat.
You know, as a psychic,
you'd think
- you'd have seen all this coming.
- Oh, woman, please.
Ah!
Hold on.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa whoa.
Are we actually
doing this again?
Do you know how
to close your mind?
'Cause I will show you
right now.
I thought I was.
Eliot gave me a--
Seriously, man?
Taylor Swift?
I am not singing Taylor Swift
in my head.
Okay, I'll work on it.
Jeez.
So, it's got lots of space.
Lots of light.
It looks really great.
I'm sorry, I guess
I thought you were still
considering Yale
for the fall with me.
What?
Okay, can we just
talk about this now?
Where is your head?
Why do I feel like
I'm talking to myself?
I'm--I've just been busy
with class--
Are you seeing someone else?
No! Why would you
ask that?
Because you're different.
You stand me up.
You don't answer your phone.
I'm just--I'm starting
to feel like the asshole.
You're not.
Hey...
I love you.
You know that.
Look, I know
I've been moody lately,
but...
I feel a lot better.
James, come on.
Hey.
Mm.
Okay, go on.
Someone killed themselves
in the fountain?
Try 15 students and one dean.
Van Pelt.
Fountain's named after him.
It does feel a little bit off
here though, doesn't it?
Brief announcement.
The Van Pelt fountain is
temporarily off limits.
There's been an incursion.
We believe it's
a garden variety haunting.
Redrawing the wards
may have released it
much like a mouse caught
in the walls of a building.
Help!
No one was seriously hurt.
Both students involved
are recuperating
in the infirmary.
Regardless,
stay away until we lock it down.
Ow. I mean,
what if it was Charlie?
I don't know.
Maybe.
If not, it's
a pretty big coincidence.
But if it was Charlie,
don't you think
that he would have
reached out to you
directly...
Maybe he just did.
It's definitely Charlie.
Okay.
So, why would he try
and drown a bunch of psychics.
Uh, have you met them?
Are you two talking about
what happened at Woof?
I--that was
a private conversation.
= You know.
Well, meow.
What was that?
I just--I don't trust her.
Okay, look.
I just--
I think trying to drown people
seems a little violent.
He may not have even
known what he was doing.
I mean, spirits,
they can get confused.
Okay, then how do we talk to him
without him trying to drown us?
I don't know.
But first thing's first.
I found a spell--
well, five actually, but they
all have their own down side.
Like, we don't know
how Charlie died exactly
and the moon is
in the wrong spot right now.
Look, I know
you don't trust her,
- but maybe Margo could--
- Or there's a Maori spell.
I'd have to cut off a finger,
but they might be preferable.
To talking to Margo?
Quentin, I need your help.
Highest priority.
- Let's go.
- Okay.
I--hey, look,
you said it yourself,
you don't have all the facts,
so maybe you don't need a spell.
Maybe you need information,
and Margo's Discipline
is gossip, so...
We have a real problem.
Is it in the box?
Professor Sunderland
came looking for a book
from the Physical
Cottage Library,
and it's missing.
I diverted
her attention, but--
What does that have to do with the box?
Books at Brakebills, Quentin,
are not just books.
One goes missing, it's not just
a library fine
we're talking about here.
- What're we talking about?
- We're talking about--
we have...
occasional parties.
During one, someone took a book,
and if we don't find that book
the faculty are going to take
a harder look at our parties,
and that cannot happen, Quentin.
So you gonna tell me
what's in the box or...
What the hell is that?
The missing book is Volume One.
That...is Volume Two.
She's going to lead us
to her mate.
Oh.
Odemknout.
Shit.
Uh, let me--
let me try it again.
Should be easy.
You're distracted.
I know I have a lot going on.
No, you don't.
You have this spell.
That's it.
So how do you manage it all?
Juggling magic and your life?
I don't understand the question.
I'm not judging you.
I started out like you
and you have a good life.
Boyfriend.
Probably think
he keeps you centered.
- Right?
- Kinda.
Or, you know, you're keeping
him around in case you fail here
and need to fall back.
All I know...
you have to mean it
for magic to work.
Something clicks
when you're all-in,
and the real big stuff,
you can't do it
till you're doing it
without a net.
I...
I need your help.
That wasn't so hard, was it?
Look, I'm just trying
to find out what happened
to my brother.
He was a student here
five years ago.
Okay.
He was a physical kid.
His name was Charlie,
and he died.
Know what?
I did hear about that.
At Woof, right?
Five, six years back?
It's all making sense now.
- What is?
- You.
The awkward thing.
The anger underneath
the ineffable air of tragedy
you wear like a perfume.
Look, can you just tell me
what you know about Charlie?
- Please?
- Loathe as I am to admit it,
I don't actually know anything.
Although, there was a girl
from Charlie's year who might.
Emily Greenstreet.
Who was she?
Just a girl.
When he died,
apparently she took it hard.
Dropped out.
Gave up magic.
The Full Muggle.
It was a bit of a scandal.
Where is she now?
The city.
Fogg set her up with a job
which is how you know
they're hiding something big.
I know how to find her.
Come on, I'll show you.
I'd actually prefer to go alone.
Oh, I know you would, but...
what choice do you really have?
Penny.
Welcome.
Knew you were coming.
I know you've been
dreading this,
but you're gonna like it.
The coves are for meditation
while the enclosed
"Consciousness Areas"
are reserved as a place
to cry, and process.
Hm.
We call it "The Amplifier."
So basically, it's like turning
your psychic powers up to 11.
Why would you wanna do that?
Oh, I get it.
You're one of those guys
who's trying to shut it out.
You wanna get control of it
or it will mess up your shit
big time,
and this is the best place
to practice.
So...
I do what?
Sit.
Relax.
Let your mind wander.
It's pretty simple.
But you gotta start
by letting go, tough guy.
Less talking.
No touching.
Help!
Please!
Help me!
Emily?
No, don't run.
These shoes are insane.
You're from Brakebills,
aren't you?
That part of my life
is behind me.
- I'm sorry.
- Charlie was my brother.
I just wanna know
what happened to him.
Your brother saved my life.
Well, he tried to at least.
So, I fell for this professor.
I know how it sounds,
but I was young and...
and he loved me.
But then, well, he was married.
You know how it is
when you're that age.
You get...terrible ideas.
Hmm.
Like what?
I thought I could
make him love me again.
Oh, some kind of love spell?
No.
I thought if I could
make myself prettier.
Oh...God.
No one warned you
how dangerous that was?
I knew, but I'd convinced myself
that it was the only way.
It took me weeks
to figure out how to do it,
and...
when I did, well, you--
you can imagine how that went.
No...
I was gonna--I was
gonna kill myself.
Emily!
Wait!
What happened?
What did you do?
Please.
I just wanna help.
Don't tell anyone, please.
Course not.
Wait here.
I'll be back.
I'm gonna fix this.
He mashed a...
bunch of stuff together.
It was--
It was totally untested.
I really believed
he might actually
be able to undo what I did.
He was a good magician.
You know, he--
he woulda done anything for me.
It was a lot.
It was--it was--
It was too much.
I begged him to stop,
but he wouldn't,
and that's when it went
totally out of control.
It burned...
right through him...
until he wasn't there anymore.
He was--
Do you know what a Niffin is?
- No.
- Yes.
It's when too much
runs through you.
Consumes you.
Only the magic is left,
but you're not
you anymore.
You're...
lost.
Where did Charlie go?
I don't know.
He was just gone.
I never saw him again.
Um, who did all this then?
My professor.
Well, I guess you got
his attention after all.
I quit school.
Gave up magic,
and never looked back.
I'm so sorry about Charlie.
Hear that?
She's getting excited.
I think we're close.
Hold this, will you?
This bodega is warded
up the ass.
Hedge witches.
Amateurs.
Magical D-leaguers.
Sad and desperate people.
Once one of 'em offered
to blow me for a spell.
It was fairly worth it.
Let me do the talking.
These are witches?
Hm. Pathetic. No?
Ugh, this kid's trying
Popper number four.
It's painful.
Hear you're selling something.
Quentin?
Oh, hey.
- What the hell are you doing here?
You know these guys?
Yeah, they're from Brakebills.
- We're friends.
- That's right.
We're from Brakebills.
We're classically trained
and we want our book.
We don't have your stupid book.
Are they?
Yep.
Love wins.
Hey!
So, that's it?
That's all you're
gonna say to me?
Don't talk to her.
Keep going.
I don't know what
you're doing here, Jules.
You're better than this.
You say that
like I had a choice.
- Of course you have a choice.
- No, because guess what?
Magic wasn't just handed to me.
I told you to please
tell them about me.
At first, you know,
I thought maybe
they'd actually test me again,
and then I figured someone
would at least come
and try to take my memory
again, and then...
just waiting.
It took me weeks to realize
you never even
told them about me at all.
- Look, Jules, I--
- You were my best friend.
Yeah, and so I let it go.
What does that mean,
"you let it go?"
No, that's crazy,
I can actually do--
The people at Brakebills,
Jules, they can bend light.
They can read minds.
They can fly.
You can do a party trick.
So this is it, huh?
The real you.
Do you ever stop to think
about how maybe you treated me?
What?
I was always there--
What? You were so nice
and you were so sweet
to poor little Q who couldn't
get his shit together.
- Don't put that on me.
- Between you and James it was
- a two for one charity case.
- That's your interpretation.
- Why are you saying this?
- Because that is true, Julia!
- No, that's not true. I--
- You know how I felt about you.
- I don't know what--
- Admit it. Just admit it.
Admit it.
So, you're gonna
punish me for that?
I don't know what else to say.
You can't blame me.
Does James even
know that you're here?
You're hanging out
with a bunch of tweakers
who are turning tricks
for spells.
Are you kidding me?
These people wanna--
Stop slumming
because you're pissed
that you lost
for once in your life.
I'm sorry, but I mean it.
You could really get hurt
doing this shit,
and for what?
Grow up.
Do you love magic?
Is it in your soul?
Is it like the secret heart
of what you always were?
Yeah.
So you know how I feel.
Get in.
Penny, how's your head?
How you think?
So, what's wrong with me?
Nothing's wrong.
I made the mistake of thinking
you were just psychic,
but it...
it's more complicated.
You are a Traveller.
A what now?
The rarest
and most difficult Discipline.
Travellers can,
with a little bit of training,
go anywhere on Earth instantly
just as you did.
But you can, with a great
deal of training,
actually move between worlds.
- Go to other worlds?
- Yes.
If the gift
does not kill you first.
Great. Just fucking great.
Do you know why I'm here?
To say this.
You've been a thin layer
of insouciance
over an open pit of self-pity
your entire life.
This is not a joke.
You do not have the luxury
to mess around
now that this is
out of the bottle.
You will study this.
You will master this.
Do you understand?
Ain't you a bucket of empathy,
blind man.
Please say yes.
I cannot see you nod.
Fine.
Yes.
So, are we just gonna drive
all the way back to Brakebills?
We're already there.
Penny.
I've learned a great deal
about Travelling over the years.
We'll start one-on-one tutorials
to help you get
a handle on your ability.
Yes,
before you accidentally
transport yourself
inside a volcano.
She's right.
We were best friends.
- Should we help?
- No.
Let me in, you assholes!
I don't know what happened.
I don't know how it got so bad.
You found out who you are
and she found out who she's not.
Life.
Tell you what.
Let's not talk.
Shit!
How long were you to douchebags
gonna leave me out there?
Oh, never mind that.
Now you're with your people.
Cheers to that.
Good God.
Cheers.
So, this Niffin box?
- This have a lid?
- There isn't one.
The Niffin becomes
fused with the wood.
It's unable to escape.
- How do you activate it?
- There's a short chant.
You just basically repeat
"I bind you"
in Turkish and English.
That sounds a little easy.
Well, that and the
month long incantation it took
to enchant the thing
in the first place.
So, this is
the enchantment research?
We're not gonna use the box.
What?
We're gonna bring Charlie back.
Okay, Alice this is the point
where I look at you
like you're nuts.
I--okay, look.
I've been doing some research,
um, on Niffins.
Look, they're not even alive.
Th--they're...
something else.
Look, I can't explain it,
but I know that he's out there.
He's somewhere.
Is there anything
in the literature that says
that going Niffin is reversible?
Nothing says that it isn't.
Exactly.
So I found this spell
that can transmutate
certain meta-quantum energies
into matter...in theory.
And I combined it with an
advanced transformation ritual--
Alice, this is Major Arcana--
What? Just because
you couldn't do it?
Nobody could do it.
You're making it up
as you go along.
Look, I--
- You are an amazing magician--
- Don't patronize me.
I'm not patronizing you.
I'm telling you that
- this is not a good idea.
- What do you know?
Hmm?
You only learned
about magic, what?
- Three months ago?
- Okay, sure.
I--but even I can tell
that this is crazy.
I don't understand
why you can't see that.
Fine. Stay behind.
I'm here, and I'm only here,
to find out
what happened to Charlie,
and now that I know
I can help him
I'm going to.
Thanks for coming so quick.
I was kinda surprised
you called.
Thought you disappeared again.
You okay?
You wanna talk about it?
Please?
- Last call, Julia.
- I--
I don't know
how to talk about it.
I got involved with something.
Made me wanna
give up everything.
Life, school...
all of it.
It got under my skin,
and it--
And?
Jules, just tell me.
It's Adderall.
I started taking it
when I was applying
to grad school,
and then I was taking
more and more.
I know I've been a bitch,
but lately I've been
going to meetings.
Wow.
I--
Can I--
I don't know, can I hug you?
I wish you would.
It's okay, Jules.
I really love you, you know.
I know.
I'm amazing.
Okay, so, we're here, and...
Arrive at the place
of his transformation.
Present yourself.
There's a third step.
What's the third step?
I have to call in to him with
something personal between us,
um...
so Charlie used to sing to me
my favorite song
when I was feeling bad
which is kind of all the time.
♪ Won't you come see about me ♪
Is that "The Breakfast Club"?
♪ I'll be alone dancing ♪
♪ You know it, baby ♪
♪ Tell me your troubles
and doubts ♪
♪ Giving me everything
inside and out ♪
♪ Don't you forget about me ♪
♪ Don't, don't, don't, don't ♪
Alice, look.
Charlie, Charlie?
- Charlie, is that you?
- Alice.
Oh, my God, Charlie,
I can't believe it's you.
I missed you so much.
I don't even know what to say.
Charlie, what are you doing?
Charlie, you're hurting me.
Charlie, that hurts.
You're just confused,
Charlie, it's me.
Charlie--Charlie,
why are you doing this?
Why?
Alice, I don't think--
I don't think that we should--
I know you're in there, Charlie.
- I know it's you.
- Alice!
Hah!
Charlie, stop!
I can help you.
Alice, stop!
Alice, he's gonna kill us.
It's not gonna work.
- You have to stop.
- Shut up, I can do this.
Alice, it's not Charlie.
Oh, shit.
Shit.
Emrediyorum!
Alice, stop!
You're gonna kill yourself.
You are bound and held fast.
Seni baglamak!
No!
I bind you!
Seni baglamak.
- No!
- I bind you!
Seni baglamak.
You--you brought the box.
Yeah.
Alice, he was gonna kill you.
Why did you think
you had to save me?
Fuck you, Quentin.
You had no idea
what I was doing.
I was so close,
and now he's gone.
Where you going, kitty cat?
I'm done here.
For good.
You should be happy.
Less competition.
Alice.
I like competition.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com