ALICE: Previously on
The Magicians...
Have you ever
heard of Brakebills?
MARINA: NO- JULIA: It's
like this secret Yale,
and you have to be able
to do magic to even get in.
MARINA: Well, I can do magic-
JULIA: Yeah, so can I-
QUENTIN: Sorry,
I just got your e-mail.
JAMES: My fifth e-mail.
QUENTIN: Just tell me
what you meant by...
JAMES: I mean not herself.
I mean barely talks to me.
JAMES: She looks like a goddamn ghost.
She's not Julia.
I need you to tell them
they were wrong about me.
Tell them to test me again.
QUENTIN: I'm sorry,
but they would know.
It's really okay
if this is not your thing.
JULIA: So you were...
Top bitch in New York.
lam willing to teach the right
people everything I know.
Who are we trying to contact?
ALICE: Charlie.
And who's Charlie?
My brother. He died.
QUENTIN: Jesus, we could not have
screwed up that spell worse,
and we can't take it back.
PETE: Now that you're in,
it's time to learn some magic.
Just don't get too excited.
Start slow.
(SCOFFS)
Yeah, I don't really do slow.
Hmm.
DEAN: Being a Magician
has always been,
in part,
about accruing power.
DEAN: Power over yourself,
the elements.
Power over the future.
(WHISPERS) He's back.
DEAN: The very world
that exists around you.
(WHISPERING) He said
he had an announcement.
But power,
as you all know,
does not come cheaply.
DEAN: There are reasons
we teach this curriculum
precisely the way that we do.
Skipping around,
focusing on
all the wrong things,
lack of guidance.
These are all
extremely dangerous.
There are certain energies,
certain spells,
which are far too powerful
for one Magician alone.
If you lose control,
they will turn against you.
They will kill you.
They will consume you.
Change you
into something else.
Now that I have
your attention,
we test to discern
your discipline.
Your area of concentration.
It is what you are,
and with the right guidance,
you may safely rise
to unknowable heights.
You will find your scheduled
times and invitations
inside your bags.
Hey, babe, it's me. Um,
just got your message.
I'm so sorry, I got stuck.
Be there as soon as I can.
Love you.
Never gets old, does it?
Having a secret.
You have magic.
They don't.
Better than money.
Better than sex.
Well,I guess
that one depends.
James is cool, really.
He barely notices.
We've both been
so busy with school.
Look,
we all juggle.
You're kicking ass.
Just don't forget to
manage your shit.
Don't want boyfriend getting worried,
following you to the safe house door.
Got it covered, okay?
I know you do.
Just saying.
DEAN: Yes,
these are promising.
I get a strong sense
of blues
and pinks.
Is that Alice Quinn?
Alice, please sit,
if there's a seat.
Bit of a transition.
I find that I prefer
an office that I can reach
without falling down three
flights of steps that l cannot see.
This'll be quick, Alice.
Show Professor March
what you can do.
Like I said, I used to do
a lot of coin and card tricks,
and I guess sometimes I would
actually use real magic.
Predictions could mean
psychic.
Vanishing could mean
illusions or physical magic.
Hmm. Curious.
What? What's curious?
Now, try holding these.
Think the alphabet in Greek.
No.
Just lovely, Miss Quinn.
So clean. Very advanced.
Physical magic.
Hmm.
MARCH: Definitely.
Just stare at it.
Well, you're not an herbalist.
ALICE: Undetermined?
Can they do that?
Yeah, Sunderland
said it happens,
so I guess they'll
try again next year.
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Your time has come
What is your discipline?
Phosphoromancy.
I bend light.
Holy shit!
There are much cooler areas.
Are you kidding me?
You have light bending power.
I'm a nothing-mancer.
I'm a squat-manner.
Well, if you're undetermined, then
why are you assigned to the Cottage?
Literally, they have
extra space.
Well, at least they have that allegedly
mind-blowing signature cocktail.
Can't be all bad.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(CLAMORING)
Uh, is there a doorbell
I missed or something?
No.
"Let yourselves in," as in
we have to figure out how.
Right.
What a bunch of dicks.
(DOOR CLICKS)
(CRACKLES)
This might actually be hard.
(MUFFLED MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey, what about your
light-bendy thing?
Like, yeah, we could use,
like, a magnifying glass.
You know, like,
you ever burn ants
when you were a kid?
No, that's horrifying.
Take all your medicine
Phosphoromancy, bitches.
(APPLAUSE AND CHEERING)
What took you so long?
I'm starving.
Welcome to our gracious abode.
You're unable to tell
You know it's over
(READING HALTINGLY)
Shit.
MARGO: You and your
first year boys.
What's your obsession
with the flavor of the month?
ELIOT: (CLICKS TONGUE)
Aww! Come on.
He's a high-strung
super nerd.
We love those.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
I'm not an experienced
drinker, Quentin.
I couldn't tell.
You know,
it should've worked.
That spell we did
to reach my brother.
I mean, I went over it,
like, a million times.
"Should've"? You say
that like you
wanna do it again.
Wait, you don't wanna
try it again, do you?
I need to know
the truth, that's all.
You know, the spell
we did was, like...
I don't know, it was
like a phone call.
We made contact,
but he didn't pick up,
so then The Beast picked up.
But that still leaves the
question, "Where's Charlie?"
Well, the last time we asked
that question, somebody died.
(SIGHS) Never mind.
What do you care?
(GROANS) No.
I do. I care. I wanna help.
I just... l don’t...
(SIGHING) Hmm...
Oh! Yeah.
Um...
Have you read, uh,
Teukolsky yet?
So apparently, you can find deceased
spirits with a simple locator spell.
If they wanna be found.
(CHUCKLING) That's stupid.
You're stupid.
You have a stupid face.
(STUTTERS)
Anyone have a match?
QUENTIN: (SIGHS)
It's networking.
ALICE: Just keep walking.
Okay.)'-
Finally.
QUENTIN: Guess it's
Woof Fountain.
ALICE: Ugh!
I never liked this thing.
Eliot says it's
enchanted as shit.
Supposedly it's bottomless, so
you know the psychics love it.
Suicide fountain.
You don't think
your brother...
No.
He wasn't that kind of guy.
He was the kind of guy who always wanted
to fix things for everyone around him.
He was really, really good.
You know that spell I did
on the first day of class?
With the Glass Horse?
He taught me that.
(SIGHS)
Come on, let's go.
Nothing's happening.
The whole thing
is fucking pointless.
Psychic?
I wanna punch
Sunderland in the throat.
You know, as a psychic, you'd think
you'd have seen all this coming.
Woman, please. Ahh!
(LAUGHS)
PENNY: Hold On.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Are we actually
doing this again?
Do you know how to close your mind?
'Cause I will show you right now.
I thought I was.
Eliot gave me a...
Seriously, man?
Taylor Swift?
l am not singing
Taylor Swift in my head.
(SIGHS)
(SOFTLY) Okay,
I'll work on it.
JAMES: So, it's got lots
of space. Lots of light.
It looks really great.
I'm sorry, I guess I thought you were still
considering Yale for the fall with me.
What?
Okay, can we just
talk about this now?
Where is your head?
Why do I feel like
I'm talking to myself?
I've just been
busy with class...
Are you seeing someone else?
No! Why would you ask that?
Because you're different.
You stand me up.
You don't answer your phone.
I'm just... I'm starting
to feel like the asshole.
You're not.
Hey...
I love you.
You know that.
Look, I know I've been
moody lately, but...
I feel a lot better.
James, come on.
Hey.
Mmm.
Okay, go on. Someone killed
themselves in the fountain?
Yeah, try 15 students
and one dean.
Van Pelt.
Fountain's named after him.
It does feel a little bit off
here though, doesn't it?
Brief announcement.
The Van Pelt fountain is
temporarily off limits.
There's been an incursion.
We believe it's a garden
variety haunting.
Redrawing the wards
may have released it
much like a mouse caught
in the walls of a building.
No one was seriously hurt.
Both students involved are
recuperating in the infirmary.
Regardless,
stay away
until we lock it down.
I mean, what if
it was Charlie?
I don't know. Maybe.
ALICE: If not, it's a
pretty big coincidence.
But if it was Charlie, don't you think
that he would have reached out to you,
directly?
Maybe he just did.
ALICE:
It's definitely Charlie.
Okay.
So, why would he try and
drown a bunch of psychics?
MARGO: Uh...
Have you met them?
Are you two talking about
what happened at Woof?
That was a private
conversation. You know.
Well... Meow!
What was that?
(WHISPERS) I just...
I don't trust her.
Okay, look. I just...
I think trying to drown people
seems a little violent.
He may not have even
known what he was doing.
I mean, spirits,
they can get confused.
Okay, then how do we talk to him
without him trying to drown us?
I don't know.
But first thing's first.
I found a spell...
Well, five actually, but they
all have their own down side.
Like, we don't know how
Charlie died exactly
and the moon is in
the wrong spot right now.
Look, I know you don't
trust her,
but maybe Margo could...
Or there's a Maori spell.
I'd have to cut off a finger,
but they might be preferable.
Quentin, I need your help.
Highest priority.
Let's go.
Okay.
Hey, look, you said it yourself,
you don't have all the facts,
so maybe you don't
need a spell.
Maybe you need information, and
Margo's discipline is gossip, so...
What do you need?
(CLATTERING)
ELIOT: We have a real problem.
Is it in the box?
Professor Sunderland
came looking for a book
from the Physical
Cottage Library,
and it's missing.
I diverted her attention,
but...
What does that have to do
with the box?
Books at Brakebills, Quentin,
are not just books.
One goes missing, it's not just a
library fine we're talking about here.
What're we talking about?
We're talking about...
We have
occasional parties.
During one, someone took a book,
and if we don't find that book
the faculty are going to take
a harder look at our parties,
and that cannot happen,
Quentin.
(CLATTERING)
So you gonna tell me
what's in the box, or...
Hmm...
(EXCLAIMS)
What the hell is that?
The missing book
is Volume One.
That...
...is Volume Two.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
She's going to lead us
to her mate.
Oh.
(CHANTING)
(CLATTERS)
Shit.
Uh... Let me try it again.
Should be easy.
You're distracted.
I know, I just... I have
a lot going on.
No, you don't. You have this spell.
That's it.
So how do you manage it all?
Juggling magic and your life?
I don't understand
the question.
I'm not judging you.
I started out like you
and you have a good life.
Boyfriend.
Probably think he keeps
you centered.
Kind of.
Or, you know, you're keeping him
around in case you fail here
and need to fall back.
All I know, you have to
mean it for magic to work.
Something clicks
when you're all-in,
and the real big stuff,
you can't do it
till you're doing it
without a net.
I...
I need your help.
That wasn't so hard,
was it?
Look, I'm just trying to find out
what happened to my brother.
He was a student here
five years ago.
Okay.)'-
He was a physical kid.
His name was Charlie,
and then he died.
Know what?
I did hear about that.
At Woof, right?
Five, six years back?
It's all making sense now.
What is?
You.
The awkward thing.
The anger underneath
the ineffable air of tragedy
you wear like a perfume.
Look, can you just tell me what
you know about Charlie? Please?
Loathe as I am to admit it, I
don't actually know anything.
Although, there was a girl
from Charlie's year who might.
Emily Greenstreet.
Who was she?
Just a girl.
When he died,
apparently she took it hard.
Dropped out. Gave up magic.
The full muggle.
It was a bit of a scandal.
ALICE: Where is she now?
MARGO: The city.
Fogg set her up with a job
which is how you know
they're hiding something big.
I know how to find her.
Come on, I'll show you.
I'd actually prefer
to go alone.
Oh. I know you would, but...
What choice
do you really have?
(DINGING)
CAMILLE: Penny.
Welcome.
Knew you were coming.
I know you've been dreading
this, but you're gonna like it.
The coves are for meditation
while the enclosed
"Consciousness Areas"
are reserved as a place
to cry, and process.
Hmm...
We call it,
"The Amplifier."
Sc basically, it's like turning
your psychic powers up to 11.
Why would you wanna do that?
Oh, I get it.
You're one of those guys
who's trying to shut it out.
You wanna get control of it
or it will mess up
your shit big time,
and this is the best place
to practice.
So...
I do what?
Sit.
Relax.
Let your mind wander.
It's pretty simple.
But you gotta start by
letting go, tough guy.
(CHUCKLES)
Less talking.
No touching.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS
ECHOING)
WOMAN: Help!
Please! Help me! Please!
MARGO: I think that's her.
Emily?
MARGO: No, don't run.
These shoes are insane.
You're from Brakebills,
aren't you?
That part of my life
is behind me. I'm sorry.
Charlie was my brother.
I just wanna know
what happened to him.
Your brother saved my life.
Well, he tried to at least.
So, I fell for this
professor.
I know how it sounds,
but I was young and...
And he loved me.
But then, well,
he was married.
You know how it is
when you're that age.
You get terrible ideas.
Hmm...
Like what?
I thought I could make him
love me again.
Oh! Some kind of love spell?
No.
(CHUCKLES) No.
I thought if I could
make myself prettier...
(SIGHS) on, God.
No one warned you
how dangerous that was?
I knew, but I'd
convinced myself
that it was the only way.
It took me weeks to
figure out how to do it, and
when I did, well, you...
You can imagine
how that went.
(EXPLOSION)
(EMILY GROANING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GASPING) No!
(SCREAMING)
(CRYING)
I was gonna kill myself.
Emily! Wait!
(CRYING)
What happened?
What did you do?
(SNIFFLING)
(WAILING)
Please.
I just wanna help.
Don't tell anyone, please.
Course not.
Wait here. I'll be back.
I'm gonna fix this.
(SOBBING)
He mashed a
bunch of stuff together.
EMILY: It was...
It was totally untested.
I really believed
he might actually be able
to undo what I did.
He was a good Magician.
You know, he would have
done anything for me.
It was a lot. It was...
It was too much.
I begged him to stop,
but he wouldn't,
and that's when it went
totally out of control.
(LIGHTNING CRACKLES)
(INAUDIBLE SCREAMING)
lt burned
right through him...
Until he wasn't there
anymore. He was...
Do you know what
a Niffin is?
No.
Yes.
It's when too much
runs through you.
Consumes you.
Only the magic is left,
but you're not
you anymore. You're...
Lost.
Where did Charlie go?
I don't know.
He was just gone.
I never saw him again.
Who did all this then?
My professor.
Well, I guess you got
his attention after all.
I quit school.
Gave up magic,
and never looked back.
I'm so sorry about Charlie.
Hear that?
She's getting excited.
I think we're close.
Hold this, Will you?
This bodega is
warded up the ass.
Hedge witches.
Amateurs. Magical D-leaguers.
Sad and desperate people.
Once one of 'em offered
to blow me for a spell.
It was barely worth it.
Let me do the talking.
(BELL DINGS)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(DOOR BUZZING)
These are witches?
Hmm. Pathetic. No?
Ugh!
This kid's trying
Popper number four.
It's painful.
Hear you're
selling something.
Quentin?
Oh, hey.
JULIA: What the hell
are you doing here?
What the hell
You know these guys?
Yeah, they're from
Brakebills.
We're friends.
That's right.
We're from Brakebills.
We're classically trained
and we want our book.
We don't have
your stupid book.
(CLATTERING)
Are they...
Yep-
Love wins.
Hey! So, that's it?
That's all you're gonna
say to me?
Don't talk to her.
Keep going.
I don't know what you're
doing here, Jules.
You're better than this.
You say that
like I had a choice.
Of course you have a choice.
No, because guess what?
Magic wasn't just
handed to me.
I told you to please
tell them about me.
At first, you know, I thought maybe
they'd actually test me again,
and then I figured someone
would at least come
and try to take my
memory again, and then...
Just waiting.
It took me weeks to realize you never
even told them about me at all.
Look, Jules, I...
You were my best friend.
Yeah, and so I let it go.
What does that mean,
"You let it go?"
No, that's crazy,
I can actually do...
The people at Brakebills,
Jules, they can bend light.
They can read minds.
They can fly.
You can do a party trick.
JULIA: So this is it, huh?
The real you.
Do you ever stop to think about
how maybe you treated me?
What?
I was always there...
What? You were so nice
and you were so sweet
to poor little Q who couldn't
get his shit together.
Between you and James I was
Don't put that on me.
A two-for-one charity case.
That's your interpretation.
Why are you saying this?
Because that is true, Julia!
No, that's not true. I... You
know how I felt about you.
I don't know what...
Admit it. Just admit it.
Admit it.
So, you're gonna
punish me for that?
I don't know
what else to say.
(STUTTERS)
You can't blame me.
Does James even know
that you're here?
You're hanging out
with a bunch of tweakers
who are turning tricks
for spells.
Are you kidding me?
These people wanna...
Stop slumming because you're pissed
that you lost, for once in your life.
I'm sorry, but I mean it.
You could really get hurt doing
this shit, and for what?
Grow up.
Do you love magic?
Is it in your soul?
Is it like the secret heart
of what you always were?
Yeah.
So you know how I feel.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(HONKING)
SUNDERLAND: Get in.
DEAN: Penny, how's your head?
PENNY: How do you think?
So, what's wrong with me?
Nothing's wrong.
I made the mistake of thinking
you were just psychic, but it...
It's more complicated.
You are a Traveler.
A what now?
The rarest
and most difficult discipline.
Travelers can,
with a little bit of training,
go anywhere on Earth,
instantly,
just as you did.
But you can, with a great
deal of training,
actually move between worlds.
Go to other worlds?
DEAN: Yes.
If the gift does not
kill you first.
Great. Just fucking great.
DEAN: Do you know
why I'm here?
To say this.
You've been a thin layer of insouciance over
an open pit of self-pity your entire life.
This is not a joke.
You do not have the luxury to mess around
now that this is out of the bottle.
You will study this. You will master this.
Do you understand?
Ain't you a bucket of
empathy, blind man.
DEAN: Please say yes.
I cannot see you nod.
Fine.
Yes.
So, are we just gonna drive all
the way back to Brakebills?
We're already there.
SUNDERLAND'. Penny.
I've learned a great deal about
Traveling over the years.
We'll start one-on-one tutorials to
help you get a handle on your ability.
DEAN: Yes,
before you accidentally transport
yourself inside a volcano.
(CHUCKLES)
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
She's right.
We were best friends.
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
Should we help?
No.
KADY: Let me in,
you assholes!
I don't know what happened. I
don't know how it got so bad.
You found out who you are and
she found out who she's not.
Life.
(POUNDING CONTINUES)
(GROANS) Tell you what.
Let's not talk.
(EXPLOSION)
(GASPS)
How long were you two douohebags
gonna leave me out there?
(ELIOT SIGHS)
ELIOT: Never mind that.
Now you're with your people.
Cheers to that.
Good God.
(EXHALES)
Cheers.
(GLASSES CLINK)
QUENTIN: So this is
a Niffin box?
This have a lid?
There isn't one.
ALICE: The Niffin becomes fused with
the wood. It's unable to escape.
How do you activate it?
There's a short chant.
You just basically repeat, "I bind
you," in Turkish and English.
That sounds a little easy.
Well, that and the month long
incantation it took
to enchant the thing
in the first place.
So, this is the enchantment
research?
We're not gonna use the box.
What?
We're gonna bring
Charlie back.
Okay, Alice this is the point where
I look at you like you're nuts.
Okay, look.
I've been doing some
research on Niffins.
Look, they're not even alive.
They're something else.
Look, I can't explain it,
but I know that he's out there.
He's somewhere.
Is there anything in the
literature that says that
going Niffin is reversible?
Nothing says that it isn't.
Exactly.
So I found this spell.
It can transmutate
certain meta-quantum energies
into matter, in theory.
And I combined it with an
advanced transformation ritual...
Alice, this is Major Arcana.
What? Just because
you couldn't do it?
Nobody could do it. You're
making it up as you go along.
Look,I...
You are an amazing Magician...
Don't patronize me.
I'm not patronizing you. I'm telling
you that this is not a good idea.
What do you know, hmm?
You only learned about magic,
what? Three months ago?
Okay, sure. But even I can
tell that this is crazy.
I don't understand why
you can't see that.
Fine. Stay behind.
I'm here, and I'm only here, to
find out what happened to Charlie,
and now that I know I can
help him, I'm going to.
(SIGHING) Thanks for
coming so quick.
I was kind of surprised
you called.
Thought you disappeared
again.
You Okay?
You wanna talk about it?
Please?
Last call, Julia.
I...
I don't know
how to talk about it.
I got involved
with something.
Made me wanna
give up everything.
Life, school. All of it.
It got under my skin,
and it...
And?
Jules, just tell me.
It's Adderall.
I started taking it when I
was applying to grad school,
and then I was taking
more and more.
I know I've been a bitch,
but lately I've been
going to meetings.
Wow!
(STAMMERS)
Can I...
I don't know, can I hug you?
I wish you would.
It's okay, Jules.
I really love you,
you know.
I know. I'm amazing.
(CHUCKLES)
(PHONE BUZZING)
Okay, so, we're here, and...
Arrive at the place of his transformation.
Present yourself.
There's a third step.
What's the third step?
I have to call in to him with
something personal between us,
um,
so Charlie used to sing
to me my favorite song
when I was feeling bad
which is kind of all the time.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(SINGING) Won't you
come see about me
ls that The Breakfast Club?
I'll be alone dancing
You know it, baby
Tell me your troubles
and doubts
Giving me everything
inside and out
Don't you forget about me
Don't, don't, don't, don't
Alice, look.
(WHISPERS) Charlie.
Charlie?
Charlie, is that you?
Alice.
Oh, my God, Charlie,
I can't believe it's you.
I missed you so much. I don't
even know what to say.
(LAUGHS)
Charlie, what are you doing?
Charlie, you're hurting me.
Charlie, that hurts.
(CACKLING)
You're just confused,
Charlie, it's me.
(SHRIEKS)
Charlie, why are you
doing this?
Why?
Alice, I don't think... I
don't think that we should...
ALICE: I know you're in there, Charlie.
I know it's you.
Alice!
Ha!
(GASPS)
ALICE: Charlie, stop! I can help you.
(CHOKING)
(ALICE CHANTING)
(CONTINUES CHANTING)
Alice, stop!
(RESUMES CHANTING)
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
QUENTIN: Alice, he's gonna kill us.
It's not gonna work.
QUENTIN: You have to stop.
Shut up, I can do this.
Alice, it's not Charlie.
(QUENTIN GRUNTS)
(CHANTING)
You are bound and held fast.
No!
I bind you!
(CHANTING)
No!
I bind you!
(CHANTING)
(GRUNTS)
(STAMMERING)
You brought the box.
Yeah.
Alice, he was gonna
kill you.
Why did you think
you had to save me?
Fuck you, Quentin.
You had no idea
what I was doing.
I was so close,
and now he's gone.
(PANTING)
Where you going, kitty cat?
I'm done here. For good.
You should be happy.
Less competition.
Alice.
I like competition.