ELIOT: Previously
on The Magicians...
Are you Santa Claus?
Well, I'm not, not that.
Magic's gone.
I'm not a magician,
but I could feel it
when it was gone,
and I knew it
wasn't a coincidence
when I went into
remission a week later.
What timeline are you from?
The one where you
owe me child support.
I'm kidding.
Okay, then if you want
me to help these students,
can you tell me who they are?
Their lives were
in grave danger.
I cast a spell that erased their
identities and gave them new ones.
I mean, isn't there
anything you can do?
If I reveal that the
spell can be reversed,
then someone would
reverse the spell.
(ENERGY SPARKS)
(GASPING)
(MANY VOICES SCREAMING)
MARGO: Bacchus,
what are you doing here?
Why do you want everyone
thinking you're Ember?
Thanks for popping in.
Oh, my God.
Mis hermanos.
Where were you?
We looked everywhere.
Stay back. Why?
Because I'm not here to play.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
MARGO: Marina.
Why do you look like
you're fleeing something?
It's me, Margo,
previously known as Janet.
Look, I'm gonna do you a solid.
Don't go up there. Why?
Because there's an uninvited
guest in my apartment
who's probably killing
your friends right about now.
Look, I don't know what he
is, and I'm assuming it's a "he"
because this is some
toxically masculine behavior,
but he walked through
every ward and shield I had,
set off every alarm.
So, instead of going inside,
I'm gonna get a
breakfast burrito.
You wanna join?
We have to help them.
Oh. You're one of those.
Fine, you wanna
stick your neck out?
There's something
inside that can help you.
Do tell.
No traveling. (GRUNTS)
Where to start?
Order is important
with these things.
Who goes first? Who goes last?
Oh, you keep looking at him.
Because you don't
want him to die?
Which means he has to go
before you. (INHALES DEEPLY)
You care about all of them.
So, you're last.
Thank Christ.
Wait, wait, wait.
Not Eliot.
MARINA 23: This thing
has god-level power,
and I have a bad
history with gods,
since apparently one killed me.
No, it's fine.
Different me, but I didn't want
to get caught off guard again,
so I called in every favor I had
to build a defense system.
All you have to do is get
him to sit in the gold chair.
Why the gold chair?
Because it had to be something,
and everybody wants
to sit in the gold chair.
It's a total power move.
I'm so glad you came.
Saves me having
to hunt you down.
(SIGHS) I've got so much
of that ahead of me already.
What is he talking about?
He's, uh, hunting gods.
It's vengeance for
locking you in the castle.
They did more than that,
and so did you.
You tried to kill me.
(CHUCKLING)
You were all part of it.
MARGO: Then what?
There's a bell on the table.
Ring it.
And he explodes?
He gets a face full
of distilled ambrosia.
It's basically meth for gods.
It gets them high,
but an overdose
will knock them on their asses.
(SIGHS)
Tell me Eliot is still
in there somewhere.
Not that I've seen.
Your round, innocent face
will make your death
particularly upsetting,
so, I've decided
to start with you.
(GROANING)
I can give you Bacchus.
(JOSH COUGHING)
You're hunting gods,
and I found him hiding
someplace far away.
Hiding from you, right?
I can take you there
if you let them live.
All of them.
Perhaps we can
be friends after all.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
So, where is everyone else?
I don't know.
(CHUCKLES) You were
supposed to remain hidden.
I meant to protect you.
Doesn't really seem
like I need protection.
I mean, nothing
your spell threw at me
even left a scratch.
Reynard did say, even
without their powers,
gods are hard to kill.
I wouldn't underestimate
the will of Irene McAllistair.
Ah.
Tell a few people that
you're leaving forever,
and look what the
ungrateful bastards do.
Ah, yes.
You know, if the deal is broken
and the McAllistairs are coming,
I'm gonna have to warn everyone.
Contacting your friends will
put a target on their backs.
To be clear,
you put the target on our backs.
You betrayed us.
Hmm.
I sacrificed everything
to bring back magic.
You know what I sacrificed,
and look what you do with it.
Yes, Ms. Wicker,
I made a deal
with the goddamn Library,
and in doing so, I
saved your lives.
Yeah, well, you're pretty
fucking quick to compromise,
you know that?
Now, I need to find my friends,
but I can't do magic,
so you're going to cast
the locator spell for me.
(SIGHS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Dean Fogg. Finally.
I only have a moment.
You know how the Library
contains the books of
everyone who ever lived?
Yeah.
The Great Blank Spot is over.
The Library can update
their books again.
So, if your friends were
to get their memories back,
the Library would know.
They'd try to find them
to keep them safe
from the Monster that
you warned us about.
NICK: You're telling me
they have books that describe
every damn thing everyone
does or ever will do,
when you're sleeping,
when you're awake,
naughty or nice?
You know how much time
that would have saved me?
Can we please not with
the Santa stuff right now?
Well, could you please not
with the angsty, nerdy stuff, huh?
No, 'cause that's who you are,
and I don't judge you for it.
Dean Fogg was trying
to give me a message.
Look, if we escape,
they'll just read our books,
find out where we
are, and come after us.
So, we just take
the books with us,
or destroy 'em.
But first we have
to actually escape.
I can get us to the fireplace.
Just be ready.
All I'm offering is a location.
The rest is on you.
Knowing where Bacchus is
doesn't help me if he runs away,
which he'll do the
second I show up.
You see my problem,
and how maybe it is
just easier to kill you all.
Do you know what this is?
Where did you get that?
I didn't,
but I know that enough of it
will mess up a god long enough
for you to do whatever
you need to do.
Excuse me, Margo?
Quick talk?
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Could you stop volunteering?
I know Bacchus. He's a friend.
Great.
Then you'll poison him.
He'll never suspect a friend.
I could always kill you.
Awesome.
Great choices.
Well, let's get going, then.
Guys, in case it
even needs to be said,
I know Marina.
She is not a helpful person.
So, just act accordingly.
(SIGHS)
Of course I'm getting paid.
The McAllistairs have
a bounty on your heads,
dead or alive.
The real yous,
not the witness-protection
identities.
So, you can see how
it'd be profitable for me
to get you back to normal.
What are they offering?
Three Deweys. What
the hell's a Dewey?
As in Melvil Dewey,
the most famous
librarian of all time.
He has his own decimal system.
Well, I think you're being
generous with the word "famous."
Okay, so in the New World Order,
there is just enough
magic in the air
to keep the boring
masses fat and happy,
but you got an itch to
do something bigger,
you have to file a
request with the Library.
They decide if you're
trustworthy, and they give you
a cute little battery
in the shape of a coin.
They put the faces of
famous librarians on there,
but Dewey's the only
one people can remember.
Well, and Laura Bush,
but Bushes just never stuck.
All right, well, we'll pay
the bounty ourselves.
How are you gonna get Deweys?
I don't know.
We'll figure it out.
We always... Sometimes.
Most of the time, we do.
Five Deweys to make
it worth the delay,
and know that I have
trackers on all of you,
so if you try to run,
it won't go your way.
(EXHALES)
Don't drink all my beer.
Seems like this is the place.
It is. (SIGHS)
Those are Maenads,
Bacchus followers.
Get to it, then.
Oh, and if they have
pizza, bring me some.
(SIGHS)
We can still find a way out.
We already did. This is
it. We're doing it right now.
You have a weapon that
could have stopped him,
and instead of using
it, you gave it to him.
We tried that already with
Julia's god-killing bullet.
All it did was kill
The Monster's host,
which in this case is Eliot.
Who, for all we know, is dead.
(SCOFFS)
Or he's trapped in there,
forced to watch everything
The Monster does,
just waiting for us to
find a way to help him.
What are you gonna
slip the ambrosia into?
I guess I'll make a Fillorian
version of his favorite drink,
margarita, but instead of
salt on the rim, it will be...
God meth. Perfect.
Now go poison his ass so we
can get out of this malarial swamp.
You know what's incredible?
How you can be
such a good friend
and such a terrible friend
at the exact same time.
THE MONSTER: There's not a lot
that I can relate
to in this world.
People here are, (SIGHS)
well, people, generally,
and me, not so much.
But I relate to you.
I hate being alone.
I don't like being left
with my own thoughts,
such as they are.
I need friends.
One way of making friends
is not murdering
everyone you meet.
Yes, you get my dilemma,
but you're like me.
Josh said so.
A bad friend and a good
friend at the same time.
How do you do it?
I have no choice.
You were friends with Eliot.
Very best friends.
Now you can be friends with me.
It'll be the same.
You can show me
how to be more like him.
No.
I love Eliot.
I would do anything
for him, even help you,
but you and I, we
won't ever be friends.
Unless you let me talk to him.
Prove he's still alive in there.
I can't do that.
But you could let him go.
You could choose a new body.
(CHUCKLES) But I like this one.
I like the way
people look at me,
and you and your friends
care so deeply about
what happens to it.
Why would I ever leave it?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Hi. I'm here to see Bacchus.
Um...
Yeah, I don't know what
you're talking about. Um...
It's Ember's.
"Bacchanal" is the
word you're looking for.
Cut the crap, Shoshana.
It's me, Josh, from
the Bed-Stuy party.
Uh, oh, I...
I didn't think you'd
remember me. (CHUCKLES)
Well, it's actually, you know...
It's really good
that you're here,
'cause he's been darker
the last few weeks.
I think a friendly
face could really help.
Great.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Hey, Q?
BOTH: Oh, my God.
Hey.
Where have you been?
We couldn't find you.
"Enrolled at
Brakebills," she said,
fully aware of the irony.
I just, um...
I don't know
where to start. Uh...
Have you heard
anything about Alice?
No.
No, I mean, not
since she completely
screwed us over
at Blackspire, why?
Where is everyone else?
JULIA: If the Library's
going to arrest us on sight,
how do we get one of
these coins, much less five?
I asked around, so there
might be another way.
The Library's official story
is that the McAllistair family
heroically turned magic back on.
So, they gave them a free pass
to as many coins as they want.
They give them
these special cards
with no limits, no
questions asked.
Only a few of them
exist, and hedges
are calling them Black Cards.
We could steal one.
If you steal a credit card,
it only works until
it's reported stolen.
With something this valuable,
that's gonna happen
pretty damn quick.
Forgery, maybe?
Good enough to fool the Library?
I used to know a guy,
a master counterfeiter.
The Beast killed him, but...
But that was in your timeline.
I did know Frankie
since before Brakebills,
so hopefully your
Penny did, too.
And hopefully he
has the same number.
Damn it. (CHUCKLES)
I still have the DJ's phone.
Well, the good
news is your Penny
has the same password as me,
so, I'm downloading
his contacts right now.
Ugh. So many
Insta notifications.
Okay, I got his
number. I'll try him.
QUENTIN: I can't log in.
It wants to send a text message
to my old phone to confirm,
but if I had my old phone,
why the hell would
I be doing this?
Have you talked
to your dad lately?
I called him from Brian's phone,
but nobody picked up.
Nobody answers their phone
when they don't recognize
the number, right?
You're probably right.
Guys, he picked up.
Oh, I don't think
you can park there.
Yeah, I don't think he cares.
Shit just always seems
to work out for Frankie.
Another timeline?
That's wild.
I thought you were dead.
PENNY 23: Likewise.
So, the Frankie I knew
was a counterfeiter.
So am I, but for most jobs,
my skills are overkill.
Duping objects to fool
regular dopes is simple.
99% of the art you
see in museums is fake,
because, why
waste the real thing
on people who can't tell
the difference anyway?
Fooling magicians, though,
that's where the
special sauce comes in.
So, what's the MacGuffin?
A Library Black Card.
That's gonna
take a lot of sauce.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
You know what? Let me get that.
That's probably for me.
Congratulations! Not now, guys.
You know what?
Actually, I'm gonna grab...
Thank you. Thanks.
Have a good one.
Are you gonna
explain that, or...
Is it in your size?
They're always my size.
Anyway, uh...
Library Black Card.
That's tricky, but I can do it.
Yeah, what'll it cost us?
Whatever you're
withdrawing from the Library,
double it.
Ten Dewey coins?
That's like "raise an army
of the dead" level magic.
That is a big ask. Yeah.
If my forgery works,
it won't matter.
Now, I'm gonna need some stuff.
I'm gonna need at least two
minutes with a real Black Card
to use as a mold, two
Philly cheese steaks,
four liters of cherry soda,
not store brand.
(PENNY 23 LAUGHS)
That's a deal breaker.
I know, I know.
And at least a third of a
Dewey coin to get us started.
You need a battery
to get more batteries?
Yeah. Call it, uh, seed magic.
Oh, uh...
We can't exactly
walk into the Library
and just ask for one.
Well, there's a game of
Push happening tonight.
What's Push?
It's a card game.
High rollers play for Deweys,
but you can buy in for less.
Any of you good at cards?
(SIGHS)
QUENTIN: A magic card game is
hard under normal circumstances,
but right now the Library's
only putting out enough magic
for small-scale spells.
I mean, one big transformation,
and I'm gonna black
out the entire room.
Yeah, it's about efficiency.
Some magicians are semi-trucks,
guzzling magic to
do a simple spell.
Some of us are Priuses.
What are you?
A sensible, mid-sized...
What was the one that
would always explode?
Yeah, that.
Hey, can we back him up?
(KADY CLEARS THROAT)
No, no, not, not me.
I can't even make a spark.
Well, I'm persona non grata
at Push games
in this city, so...
I just don't want to.
It's a one-on-one game,
anyway, so no backup.
But, uh, good luck.
MAN: What do you have to wager?
(CLEARS THROAT)
It's a protection amulet.
It's sort of
all-purpose. (CAWING)
(CONTINUES CAWING)
It's not good enough.
If you can't buy in, make
room for somebody who can.
Uh, wait, um, he's a Traveler.
I'll wager his exclusive
services for 48 hours.
A year. A month.
Whoa. Hold on. I won't lose.
But you're a loser.
A month. No questions asked.
Welcome to the game.
Okay, the rules
of Push are simple.
It's like the game War.
Two players.
Each draws a card.
High card wins the hand.
When the deck is
gone, the game's over.
But the real art of the game
is knowing how to cheat.
See, a shuffled deck of cards
is not a fixed thing.
It's a cloud of possibilities.
And you can change
the odds if you know how.
Put the right card
into your hand,
or the wrong card
into your opponent's.
Wait, what is that?
Rules of poker.
FRANKIE: You'll have
to beat three opponents
to win the whole thing.
Shall we?
The more probability
spells that you throw around,
the more improbable
things can get.
Be careful of those.
They killed Bobby Darin.
The final round is when
you play for the Dewey.
(BIRD CAWING)
(BLOWS)
Breaking a tie is complicated.
Get the hats.
You throw cards into a hat,
and whichever ones you sink,
you score like a poker hand.
Straight flush.
(BIRD CAWS)
I'm just saying,
what if he loses?
I'm a Traveler. I'll grab
the coin and blip away.
Yeah, and then the
people you just robbed
hunt you down and torture you.
So, why don't we
save that for plan B?
Listen, if you lose
this last hand, it's over.
I think we need to be ready
for plan B. (MOUTHS) No.
(BIRD CAWS)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
What is the point
of this display?
(THUNDER CRASHES)
You've used up all the
ambient magic in the room.
I guess we'll just have
to play an honest game.
(BIRD CAWING)
Got it. Perfect.
Now the easy part.
Borrow a Black Card
to use as a template.
Anything? No.
Why are we going
along with this?
Marina killed my mother.
That was a different Marina.
How different?
And we're just gonna
hand her a nuclear bomb?
What's the alternative?
We use it against her.
Where does that end?
I came here to get away
from that kind of shit.
You know, I'm getting
really sick of being the voice
in the back of the room
that everyone ignores.
The other me, Sam,
did whatever she
thought was right,
regardless of what
anybody else thought.
I get it.
Because where I came from,
everyone I cared about is dead.
No other voice to
listen to but mine.
But maybe Sam didn't care
what anyone else thought
because she's alone.
You aren't.
Whoa.
I got something here.
There's huge energy
coming off her purse.
It's gotta be the
Black Card in there.
Showtime.
Oh, excuse me, I'm...
I'm sorry.
Do I know you from somewhere?
I mean, I dabbled in acting.
What have I seen you in?
Let's just say some
provocative films of the 1970s.
PENNY 23: Interesting.
All finished.
Great. Let's go.
Uh, there is one little thing.
That special sauce I
was talking about before.
Most forgers use
complicated illusion work.
That's not quite my thing.
(TAPPING ON WINDOW)
(DOOR OPENS)
Did a bird just bring
you a sandwich?
Yeah, I guess she did.
You want it?
Well, I mean, yeah, but...
But what the fuck, Frankie?
This is what I'm talking about.
Luck is my discipline.
The forgeries I make give whoever's
holding them insanely good luck.
So, nobody even bothers
to check if the thing is fake.
I've done the spellwork so many
times, I'm just sort of encrusted with it.
Luck is zero-sum, so all that
bad luck has got to go somewhere.
It goes into a bear?
Somebody, not
me, has to hold that
while the others bring the
Black Card to the Library.
And whoever's holding it
is gonna have a bad day.
I'll do it. No, Jules.
You don't have to. He...
It's okay.
It's hard to explain, but
I'm kind of bulletproof.
If anybody should have
terrible luck, it should be me.
Why are you bulletproof?
That's none of your business.
Pick it up.
No, no, no, no, no,
no, something's wrong.
Uh, whatever "none of my
business" shit is going on with you,
it's interfering with the
fortune spell, so set it down.
Set it down! All right.
Ahh...
Looks like you just volunteered.
You awake?
Nope.
It's time.
(SPITS)
(BLOWING)
(CRACKLING)
(LOCK CLINKS)
Anti-magic paint
on a magic lock.
Wish I had thought of that before those
book-sniffing bastards ruined Christmas.
(SHUSHES)
(WHISPERING) Which way now?
I don't know.
Something isn't right.
This should continue straight.
Well, you made this map by
mind-controlling a cockroach.
Shouldn't we trust our eyes
rather than some shit-eating bug?
(DOOR OPENS)
No, I think it's an illusion.
There's spellwork on this wall.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
Or it's a wall.
This is it.
The Books of Everyone.
You look for yours, and
I'll go look for my friends'.
BACCHUS: I gotta tell you,
it is such a relief to take
off that Ember disguise.
So, what have I been
missing down on Earth?
It must be bad. Your
chakras are all fucked up.
Oh! (CHUCKLES) Yeah.
Uh, we got magic
turned back on. Hey!
And, you know, one of
our friends just betrayed us.
Which is crazy, right?
(CHUCKLING) Like,
who would do that?
Yeah. I got mind wiped.
Yeah, I was living as this other
dude named Isaac for months.
Um, that is exactly kind
of close to my situation.
So, I'm being hunted by
this douchebag Monster,
and, like, I need a
place to crash, right?
That's when I remember,
that squirrelly little
human friend of yours
said that he killed Ember,
and I'm like, "I could
take that guy's place."
Live to fuck another
day, you know?
It's kind of nice, you know?
Freeing to live as
someone else for a little bit.
Yeah, I guess.
You know, a famous
cocksman once told me,
"Once you've had quantity,
the only thing left is strange."
And, boy, is this
place full of strange.
I mean, Isaac's life was great.
Lot of friends, big family.
But eventually, it all ends,
and your old life,
your old problems,
they catch up to you.
Or your problems
never find you and the
party goes on forever.
(CHUCKLES) Oh!
Look at that, I'm dry.
Is that... Did you make for me?
Yes. Josh special?
Uh, yes, I made it for you.
You and me, Joshy,
we're the same.
We're born to be
the perfect hosts.
We want everyone around us to
have a good time, we make sure of it.
Nobody does the same for us.
Mmm-mmm.
This is to Josh, not to Isaac.
This is to the real you.
(GOBLET CLATTERS)
I'm sorry.
I pee-peed in it,
and you don't...
You don't drink that.
So...
This is the dumbest plan.
Frankie says the
disguises won't matter.
If the Black Card works,
nobody will question them.
I feel like an idiot.
Excuse me, sir.
You have a fresh look.
Have you considered modeling?
(LAUGHING)
Okay, it's just soup.
Can't choke, it's not
scalding. It's totally safe.
KADY: Ugh! Look at that
line. This is gonna take forever.
I've been thinking,
while we're here,
we should get a bit extra.
Five for Marina, five
for Frankie, 10 for us.
We'd have to be insanely
lucky to get that much.
The more luck we get,
the more bad luck Quentin gets.
When this is over, the
McAllistairs will still be after us.
We'll need to do some
major cloaking spell.
It could kill him.
Hey! There's a truck outside
giving out free ice cream!
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
I mean, two extra
coins can't hurt.
It's all good. Soup
spills all the time.
Thanks. (GROANS)
Damn it.
How the hell do you get a
paper cut from a paper towel?
Welcome. Hi.
So, how can I help you today?
We need 12
contained current coins.
Here. No, God.
Keep it away.
(SNAKE HISSING)
Everything looks in order.
Just need to check
one little thing.
(CANDY CLATTERING) Oh, shoot.
(WHIRRING)
Did you hear something?
(HISSING) (QUENTIN GRUNTING)
Where did it come from?
Out of the toilet.
All right, then, I'll
send this requisition
to the home office, and
they'll return your coins.
(VIBRATING)
I thought you said your
phone wasn't working.
(VIBRATING CONTINUES) (PANTING)
It's a voicemail from my mom.
Do you think...
Q?
It's got to be about
my dad. I'm not gonna...
No, Q, the bear.
BRANCH MANAGER:
Okay. (CLEARS THROAT)
Oh.
Your request has been flagged
for follow-up with a supervisor.
Wait here, please.
A requisition follow-up for you.
SUPERVISOR: Christ, can it wait?
Fine.
Sorry, I can't see for shit.
(GRUNTS)
Bloody thing's making
me crazy. Do you mind?
No, do your thing.
What do I do? Just,
please, don't listen to it
until we hear back
from Penny and Kady.
Oh, shit!
Oh, Jesus Christ, now
I've got it in backwards.
About those coins...
Listen,
the truth is, the red
tape, the paperwork,
it's, in my mind,
all just a wank.
You guys gonna
blow yourselves up?
No. No?
Great.
Request approved.
Sorry about the inconvenience.
Thank you very much.
You have a good day.
Jesus, shit!
Okay, they did
it. Drop the bear!
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
It really came out of the...
I don't want to talk about it.
Thank you, brother.
I had a feeling things would
work out, because they always do.
By the way, I'd
destroy those ASAP.
They'll be out of juice soon, but
you don't want to take any chances.
I'm on it.
You nutsacked out, didn't you?
Oh, well, "pussied out"
makes perfect sense here?
Well, if you mean that I
couldn't go through with it,
then, yes, you're right.
Josh, we don't
have a choice here.
Now, where is the
rest of the ambrosia?
(SIGHS)
Fine.
But just know that Bacchus will
never drink anything you give him.
Oh, I'm not gonna
give it to Bacchus.
Yeah, I'm gonna
dump it in there.
Everyone will drink it.
Are you nuts? There
are over 100 people here.
You have no idea
what that will do to them.
Well, I'm pretty sure
it'll fucking kill them.
And I'll do it, unless you
start acting like a real pussy
and take one for
the fucking team.
Hey, uh, I'm sorry about...
We've all peed in
things we regret.
I know gods are supposed
to be distant and unknowable,
but you're a good guy.
I wanna tell you a secret.
(EXHALES)
What did you put in this?
(GOBLET CLATTERS) (PEOPLE GASP)
I found my book. Now
let's get the hell out of here.
I can't find my friends' books.
"The following books have been
removed from circulation for revisions.
"Q. Coldwater, A. Quinn."
They're filling in the
endings of our books...
The pages that were missing
because of the Great Blank Spot.
(CART RATTLING)
Nick?
Hey, I'm sorry about your friends'
books, but this is our chance.
Come with me. I can't.
I can't leave
without their books.
Well, I want to do the...
Look, just go while you
still have the chance, okay?
I can find the Revision
Room on my own.
For what it's worth,
you're still on my Nice List.
(GRUNTS)
(MUFFLED GASP)
(SLEIGH BELLS RINGING)
The fuck?
(BACCHUS GROANING)
Do you remember me?
Because I don't.
I don't remember my name
or where I came from.
But I remember you.
You took something from
me, something important,
and then you threw me
in a cage,
and I would like
for you to explain.
You remember all that,
but you don't remember
what you are, what you did.
The word "monster"
has been thrown around.
That's right.
We put you with
the rest of your kind.
And I ate them.
You're kind of making
my case for me here.
We have the same parents.
Why am I a monster
and you're a god?
If you don't want to be a
monster, then let me go.
Give me back what you took
from me, and maybe I will.
I can't ever.
I'm sorry.
It was a part of me,
and now it's a part of you,
burning in your body.
Wait. Wait.
This world needs me.
Its god is dead.
You don't have to do this.
There's others.
There's still time.
We can figure something out.
It doesn't have to be me.
It doesn't have to...
(SCREAMING)
(CHOKING)
(RETCHES)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
JOSH: What the fuck
did he just rip out of him?
Whatever it is, to a fairy eye,
it's like staring
straight at the sun.
They're real.
Well, it's been a pleasure.
The trackers on us?
Not actually a thing.
You guys are too
lawful good to bitch out.
MAN: Marina.
I've been looking for you.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Excuse me, miss. These
are free to a good home.
Are you interested?
(PUPPIES WHIMPERING)
Hey, are you sure Marina's apartment's
the safest place for us to meet?
It's not Marina's.
It's mine.
What did you do?
I handled the problem.
Now, can we do
this cloaking spell
before the McAllistairs
show up and kill all of us?
Hey.
You haven't listened?
You know, your bad luck's gone.
Safe as it'll ever be.
But that's not what's
really stopping you.
The other me,
Brian...
His dad died when he was a kid.
He was too little
to even understand.
All of his problems
were like that.
No sharp edges.
Yeah.
Look at us.
We paid a hell
of a fucking price.
You gave up being a goddess.
I gave up my father.
What did we get in return?
Magic is back.
(CHUCKLING BITTERLY)
Mmm-mmm. Not in
the way that we wanted.
How are you not furious?
Because, for almost everyone,
the world is a little brighter.
Even if they never know why.
I hate the Library
for what they did.
But my part in it...
I knew what it cost.
And I'd do it again.
But you wouldn't.
Will you sit here for a minute?
Yeah.
LAURA: (ON MESSAGE) Hi, Quentin.
Sorry to leave a
message with bad news.
I need to talk to you
about your father.