Previously on The Magicians...
Quentin Coldwater for
the grad school interview?
Well, he's dead.
I think he left
something for you.
You may address me as Dean.
Your only job is to pass
the examination before you.
Regrettably, you
failed the written exam.
Do magic!
Stop it!
Ah...
I need you to tell them
they were wrong about me.
I can do whatever I want to you.
Awesome.
You thought the school is
the only place to track the gift?
We've been watching
you for quite a while now.
What does that mean?
Okay, for some reason
you're involved, so be involved.
It says we need four people.
Look, I gather you guys need
some extra hands or something.
Let us know if
shit gets exciting.
Quentin Coldwater.
There you are.
Mr. Coldwater.
Quentin.
Quentin?
Quentin!
Describe The Beast
that attacked you.
Uh...
How did it get in here?
Mr. Coldwater, what
did The Beast say to you?
How did it know your name?
So what is this place exactly,
besides a health hazard?
Time was, the finest
meat packing plant in town.
Yeah, it's a winner.
Hey, that star on
your arm... I earned it.
You will too, with effort,
whole sleeve of 'em.
So what does it mean?
Does it mean that...
You ask a lot of questions.
Yeah, I sure do.
Oh, my God, these are
real? Every one of them?
Guys, this is Julia.
Julia, my associates.
Holy shit, it's...
And that is...
I'm sorry, what's
your name, sweetie?
I'm Marina. I'm new.
Yeah, no kidding.
Everything up and running?
Yeah.
Julia, Marina. Grand tour.
Wait, so who were
those people exactly?
You seriously don't know?
What are you even doing here?
I don't know. I'm waiting for
something interesting to happen. You?
Magic is what I'm doing here.
They're hedge witches.
We're hedge witches.
Jesus, how are you even...
Girls, play nice.
So here is where we keep
all our ingredients and such.
Keeps them safe.
It's a... Meat locker,
or it was, anyway.
Now it is so well-stocked,
it's like the end
of the rainbow.
After you.
Hey!
Come on, open the door.
Hey, don't be an asshole.
Open the door! Dude!
We were frozen.
Some kind of paralysis spell.
Took over the whole room.
Let's just nip
this all in the bud.
I already told you, the Dean
had something in his hand.
I don't know where
it went after that.
You can materialize objects?
I've been doing card
tricks half my life.
I guess some of them
were disappearing.
Quentin...
Take this.
Is he dead?
The Dean?
How did you know that spell?
Look, I know we're not supposed
to fire off battle magic, but...
I mean, come on.
Can we just get out
of this room soon?
Please?
I know you want to
understand what happened.
Here's what I can say.
We live in a world that is
one world among many.
The Beast you saw
was from one such place.
We do not know the
exact nature of this entity,
only that it was
powerful and malevolent.
Stop it!
And we know that it is gone now.
Wards and shields
protect Brakebills.
They are encoded to each authorized
person on campus and no one else.
We are investigating
how this Beast got through
and resetting everyone.
If someone is
responsible for this attack,
rest assured, they
will be expelled.
Classes are canceled tomorrow.
They will resume Wednesday.
There will be a quiz.
Alice.
Okay...
Um... Don't.
Hey, we did that spell.
You don't get to
say, "Don't," okay?
If they find out...
There they are.
Glad to see you, kid.
Oh, you poor thing.
Nurse? Are you okay?
No, it's okay, we're just
gonna get you a nice drink.
Jesus, you didn't tell
me you were dangerous.
Damn it.
And damn it.
Pretty sure my boyfriend's
starting to get curious where I am.
Oh, Jesus Christ, it's cold.
We're stuck, and they're
trying to kill us, so...
They're not trying
to kill us, okay?
These people are not
murderers. Trust me.
How do you know that?
Because, they don't
have the balls for it.
It's like some sort of
hazing ritual, a test.
I'm sick of flunking
tests right now.
I'm gonna figure it out.
Nothing to see, you
louche little degenerates.
Avada Kedavra.
Whatever, Eliot.
Welcome to the
Physical Kids' Cottage.
It's the single best
place on campus
for a number of reasons
that will become clear
as soon as you taste
our signature cocktail.
I've got to...
Try on this dress I have.
It's perfect. It's made
exactly for those assets
you're hiding underneath
that pilgrim tent.
Yes, you must. Trust me.
Après moi.
On purpose?
Like, you guys
cast it, thinking,
"Oh, monster from another world.
"By all means, come on in."
So you messed up.
It's a little bit bigger
than messing up.
Than what? Than whatever
blew up the entire third year class?
There's a bad story every
few years around here.
I'm not sure that's avoidable.
Okay.
And if you confess...
Then I'm done. Yeah.
Argh...
Before I got here, I
was in the hospital.
I have... Or I had...
I don't know, uh, this thing that
I couldn't shake where I felt like
because nothing was ever not
gonna be pointless and empty, then,
uh, why go on?
And then I got here, and...
It's amazing I survived
as long as I did
not knowing that
I was a Magician.
I can't go back.
So, okay.
There is a spell, uh, if they question
you, so they can't read your minds.
I'll write it down.
It's bulletproof.
Thank you.
Now, can you just help
me live with myself?
Okay, I'm gonna
tell you something
deep and dark and personal now.
Ready? Good. I killed someone.
What?
I was 14. He was this...
He beat me up.
So I'm walking on the
street eating a candy bar,
'cause by then I already ate my
feelings at a professional level,
and I saw him crossing over.
And there was this bus coming.
I barely thought the thought.
Bam.
I knew immediately what
I'd done, that it was me.
My nose literally
started bleeding.
Logan Kinear died instantly and
I ruined my favorite button-down.
And that is the story of how I
discovered I was telekinetic.
If you're trying to tell
me that it gets better...
Oh, God, no. No, it doesn't.
I'm trying to tell you,
you are not alone here.
Funny little irony
they don't tell you,
magic doesn't come from talent.
It comes from pain.
So, do you know what it was,
the thing that attacked you?
No, I have no idea. Oh.
I thought you might be familiar
with some pretty crazy
shit since your family.
Yeah, no, my family's not...
Right. Yeah.
I get it.
Mine too.
Pointless and toxic.
I didn't really learn
magic formally as a kid.
I heard you never got invited to
take the Brakebills entrance exam.
How'd you even find
it? You walked right in.
It's not that hard.
We're in the Bermuda
Triangle of upstate New York.
How'd you get through though?
The wards around the
school are fingerprinted.
You're a stranger.
My parents have alumni keys.
Which are supposed to be charmed
with McNaughton's Unstealable.
I stole one.
Hmm.
Um...
I just wanted to go to school.
Why do you care?
Curious.
Just 'cause...
I don't know.
I want to be your
friend, I guess.
I don't feel like you do.
I'm sorry, I should
go. Thank you.
There has to be something here.
Maybe the phone numbers
are, like, a code or...
That's too easy.
Come on.
Chop-chop.
There has to be
something. I mean...
Oh!
Is it...
Dead? Mmm-hmm, yeah.
But it was already
dead, so I don't know.
Oh, my God.
Jesus Christ,
they're gonna kill us.
Why did I sign up
for this? This is...
Stop it, stop, okay? Okay, okay.
It's dead dead now, I think.
I don't know.
Calm down. Jesus, guys, it's me.
Pete, is that you?
Howdy.
Oh, Pete, that's definitely a
good look for you, an improvement.
Why don't you join us in
here? I think Marina misses you.
Just let us out.
Don't be stupid. You
have to find your way out.
So this is a test, another test.
Look, if you can't
get through this,
you definitely can't deal with
what it takes to do what we do.
Do you want magic or not, Julia?
Did you look everywhere?
Fast, frostbite's gonna set in.
Asshole. Shit.
What did that mean?
Uh, where didn't we look?
Wait.
"Une chaleur temporaire."
Temporary warmth.
I was just researching.
Reading a kids' book?
What do you want from me, huh?
Jesus, we could
not have screwed up
that spell worse, and
we can't take it back,
and you don't even like me.
I don't know you.
I don't know you either,
except that we summoned some kind
of killer mothman from another world.
Yeah, there is that.
You should hate me right
now. I dragged you into this.
It's just you showed up
with that sigil on your hand,
and it was the same one that
was on the book that I needed,
and my brother,
his spirit, I mean,
sent you to help me contact him.
So, I'm not really sure
that that's what happened.
The thing on my hand, the sigil,
uh, it appeared when I
was dreaming of Fillory.
Okay.
In my dream, the
sigil on my hand,
it came from Jane.
Chatwin. From Fillory.
Look, honestly,
Quentin, growing up,
the last thing I wanted
to do was read fantasy.
Okay. What if, um...
What if Fillory is real?
And I know that you think
that this is just about Charlie,
but I think maybe it's bigger,
because what came through
that mirror instead of Charlie,
it didn't exactly grow
up in the neighborhood.
Okay.
So what if it came
from, like, actual Fillory?
That's a leap, Quentin.
I mean, there are other worlds
out there, but Fillory is just fiction.
Oh, no, the uh,
Chatwins, they're real.
They lived next
door to the author.
He based the characters on them.
Jesus, how do you
not know any of this?
Is there, um, someplace on campus
we can to go to watch a video?
Yeah. Good.
After living next door
to the Chatwins for years
and writing stories for
young Jane and Martin,
when Martin Chatwin disappeared,
Christopher Plover
was devastated.
This was just one of a series of painful
events that haunted Christopher Plover.
It suffused his work with a
sense of melancholy and loss.
And the mystery of Martin
Chatwin's disappearance
was never solved.
Even more mysterious,
Martin's sister Jane disappeared
the following year.
That's a lot of disappearing.
Yeah, I mean, that's kind of why
people are obsessed with the books,
'cause you have these kids walking
into clocks, uh, into other worlds,
and they're based on real kids,
and the real kids, uh, vanished.
You're saying that
Charlie vanished too...
No, no, no, no,
no. I don't know.
I don't know what happened
to Charlie or anyone.
I don't, uh, know.
I mean look, we called
something from another world.
I don't know, can that
really be a coincidence?
So what do we do?
Don't get caught. I
can't get kicked out.
I mean, I have to find
out what happened to him.
Yeah, I know, but...
What if Fillory is real?
Jesus, you don't understand how
mind-blowing that is. It's just like...
Do you want to
stay at Brakebills?
Yes. Okay, so do I.
So let's just hide the evidence
and get our story straight.
Okay?
What, you're leaving?
I'm gone. Come on.
Look, I know I don't
know you that well,
but I know you're not
the type to scare easy.
You want the truth? No sweat.
Hearing people's thoughts
is the least of my problems.
Couple lines, right mix of meds.
But you heard Quentin
and Alice in the lab.
No, I didn't.
There's this voice.
Everyone else comes
with a lot of static,
but him, he's clear
as a fucking bell.
Says he's a Magician. That's...
That's all I know about him.
That and everything that he
taught me is real and it works.
Holy shit.
Let's just say life wasn't
exactly non-stop fun growing up.
That's why I love that voice.
Saved my ass so many times,
he's basically my only friend.
Yeah, right up until he
sent me to a lab to help,
and then that thing
walked in through the mirror.
You were hearing The
Beast? I was getting duped.
But, do they know? I
mean, Sunderland, anyone?
No, there's no point now.
But don't... Penny, don't go.
Come on. It's not your fault.
He tricked you.
Come on, don't be stupid.
Why would you leave
the only place with experts
that might actually be
able to help you with this?
Why do you care?
Look, I did the
spell too, Penny.
If you're guilty, I'm guilty.
You're guilty.
Okay, great, let's
jump off a bridge.
Kady.
I can't stand it.
Okay.
Go.
But...
Hey, since you're out anyway,
come do something stupid
with me before you go.
Come on.
Yeah, 'cause crushed rocks,
you see that in spells that have
a concentrated area of effect.
I'm sorry, you knew this and
you didn't want to say anything?
Okay, well, I don't
know what I know.
Years reading Internet crap and
accidentally poisoning myself twice,
and now I'm stuck in a
freezer with some bitch.
Well, you are.
What, did you figure you wanted
magic at your blow dry last week?
This is serious for some of us.
Okay, you know what? I'm not
interested in your personal issues.
Hey.
There was sand
in that paint can.
Yeah, and I'm gonna
need a knife and a bowl.
Okay.
And...
"Graisse de l'animal...
De préférence de mouton."
Animal fat. Mutton.
Maybe there's meat?
Come on, let's go before
we freeze our tits off.
This isn't just some
lark to me, so you know.
No offense, okay, you just
smell a little Ivy League to me.
Yeah, well, it's 'cause I am.
I was.
Have you ever
heard of Brakebills?
Well, it's like this secret
Yale, but for magic.
What?
And you have to be able
to do magic to even get in.
Well, I can do magic.
Yeah, so can I.
And yet, somehow, I
flunked the entrance exam.
That doesn't seem right.
Either you can or you can't.
No, it's not right, and yet
they just left me behind.
I mean, seriously, what
do they expect, you know?
Magic is real and that's the thing,
and once you know that, you can't...
Nothing else matters.
Exactly.
It's like...
I know it's there.
It's everywhere, all around me,
a whole world of
power and beauty.
You can't unsee it.
You wake up for the first time.
Yeah.
Who are we kidding?
There's no meat in here.
We've checked everything.
No, no way, I cannot do that.
Mmm-mmm. No, please do that.
I let my old life
tie me to the tracks
I heard my best friend tell me
You can never go back
I spent my long years
Learning to get out of the way
I have been taught
to turn the other cheek
I get my back stabbed,
buddy to the end of the week
I only try to make it
to the end of the day
I've seen it break
so many before
I don't wanna stick around
here and watch anymore
Mmm. Oh...
Yo, this one looks bunk.
Well, it's not. It's
Emerson's Alloy.
Uh, alloy's rusting.
How do you know?
'Cause I know things.
Like this place...
What? It's a gold mine.
Look, you can't
run away from you.
And, well, I'm here, and
I'm amazing, so I mean...
I'll take it under
advisement, okay?
Hey.
No, leave us alone.
Gladly, we've got
to discuss, um...
There you are, Quentin and
Alice, and Penny and Kady.
You're exactly who
I was looking for.
I found the most interesting
thing buried in our woods.
Follow me.
We never got near
the mirror, I swear.
We were studying, that's all.
What language even is this?
Yes, I mean, sure, I touched it.
We all touched it.
I mean, I touched...
We were studying, so...
Look, I'm just trying
to make sense of this.
There's residue
all over this book,
including a summoning
we believe opened
the door to The Beast.
What did you say?
Nothing, I...
Don't look at me.
Look, I know
they're your friends.
Okay, at this point, I just have
to assume it was all of you.
Yeah, well, it wasn't.
Shut up and I'll
tell you, happily.
It's fine, let's go.
You're welcome, by the way.
What does that mean?
Quentin, can I see you, please?
Alice, you're free to go.
There's nothing I
can do in this moment
to stop the comet from
crashing into the earth, is there?
Hold on.
Uh...
What is this?
My books. I'm headed to return
them. You've heard, I assume.
Word travels fast
when your life's over.
Don't say that.
They're bringing
in a specialist.
Yeah, thanks. Ominous.
I'm sorry.
I don't know, I keep trying to
tell myself this is somehow better,
you know, not to know.
'Cause who would want
to know that magic exists
if there's nothing you
can do about it, you know,
if there's no one to
teach you or help you.
I don't know what to say.
Of course you don't, because
nobody would rather not know.
You don't see color and want
to go back to black and white.
You do not have to
make me feel better really,
we basically just
met each other.
Well, I bond fast.
Time is an illusion.
Look, don't go out
there and be the old you.
How, Eliot?
I go back there, and I'm...
I'm a depressed super nerd.
How about I find you, and
I don't say magic is real,
but I do seduce you,
and so lift your spirits
that life retains its
sparkle for decades.
Yeah, that sounds
nice. Thank you.
Okay.
Is there any way
not to get wiped?
I don't know.
I've heard of the specialist,
and all I can say is,
I hear they're very good.
This is Julia, little
busy. Leave a message.
Hey, it's Q.
Look, I know when
we last met that, uh...
I'm sorry, Jules. I am.
I didn't know what it
must be like for you,
and I, um, I hope that
you are doing better.
Oh, my God, you're
just going for it.
So, I got expelled, and they
are sending in a specialist
because the local brain wipe
guy is dead, and long story.
Um...
So if you remember or you
figured out why it didn't work on you,
I'd like to know
that, about now,
because I need you to
remind me that magic is real.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
You know, without
Brakebills, it's just...
I'm lost and you're not.
Magic.
Okay.
Let's find a way
out of this shit hole.
You can't help
and I can't help you,
and it's just...
To send your message, press one.
To erase, press two.
Deleted.
Hey!
You little piece of shit.
You ratted me
out. I told the truth.
Not all of it. Oh, am I a fool?
Apparently not.
Get off! Yeah,
that's what I thought.
What the hell was
that, you maniac?
Hey! Step back, both of
you! Who shot off that spell?
He did! I did.
Infirmary, both of you, now.
Figured it out.
The spell, or, you know, the
whole point, that there isn't one.
Not to get out of the room, not
to keep the door locked, nada.
Cute, Pete.
Oh, and scissors make a
shitty screwdriver, by the way.
Good for you.
Now you get why
it was so important.
Uh, to almost die for no reason?
To figure out that not
everything gets solved by magic.
Key fact if you want
to last the month.
You're not still debating letting
me into your club, are you?
Hey, I invited you.
No, you attacked me in a bar,
in a bathroom, on my birthday.
I'm done trying to
prove myself to you.
You weren't.
You were trying to
prove yourself to me.
That means level 50.
Um...
Uh...
Wait, so you were...
Top bitch in New
York, for starters.
Um, and this was...
Me discovering
how much I like you.
You are smart. You're
passionate. You question things.
You messed with my head!
Think about how much you
learned about how to do that
for when you're level 50.
Hey, don't be mad. Don't be mad.
How am I supposed to trust you?
Why would you ever trust anyone?
I am willing to teach the
right people everything I know,
and I know a lot,
because I have certain
connections in certain places,
just like, for
instance, Brakebills.
Brakebills.
You want a drink?
Let's get a drink.
Might burn a little.
This is why you're not supposed
to throw this kind of magic around.
If you're lucky, I can fix this.
You're lucky
you're not expelled.
That's actually...
Hold still, please.
Pussy. Nobody asked you.
Me, the guy you
threw battle magic at?
Hey, have you heard of karma?
Well, sometimes it's instant.
You're welcome.
What is that? How did you...
Real Magicians
protect themselves.
Would somebody please
sign him out of here?
She's late.
She's coming.
Or she's just
done with your shit.
She doesn't have the option.
Finally.
Hey, look, that thing you wanted,
that charm or crystal or whatever?
The Emerson's Alloy Repellant?
Yeah, this guy I was
with, he grabbed it.
Look, I'll find you
another one, okay?
And more.
Here.
There's a ton of
good shit in there.
Listen to all that backpedaling.
I'll get it, okay?
Whatever you want.
I'll find you another one.
Great. You're a
sweet girl, Kady.
You're a heartless bitch.
I'm generous with
you, considering.
Get me everything
on this list, this week.
Thanks so much.
You better get back to bed, hon.
I'm sure you got
class in the morning.
Hi. Oh...
Caught me where I'm not
meant to be, a terminal snooper.
How are you, Quentin?
I heard about the attack.
You were there the day
of the alumni interview.
You were a paramedic.
Call me Eliza.
I was there that day to
make sure that you got here.
Oh...
Well, uh, thank you,
but I kind of screwed that up.
Uh...
They're calling in a specialist.
He's supposed to, um, wipe it
all away like it never happened.
Mmm. That sounds...
Hmm...
You know, I'm the
specialist? Sorry.
Shall we sit?
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Um, just before, um, can I...
Um, why did you
give me that book?
Fillory and Further, book six.
I thought you'd appreciate it.
I lost it.
Guess I was wrong.
No, you're not, I...
I need to read it. I
just, I can't find it.
Things with Fillory
are funny that way.
Is Fillory real?
Why even ask if you'll
just forget it again?
The books, they're just...
They always felt
realer than anything.
Then it's real.
That's not a real answer.
Shall we begin?
Okay, do it.
Oh, Quentin, I am pleased!
What? Why?
You're a much better liar
than I expected you to be.
Can I level with you?
I wish you would.
You're not very remarkable.
You're smart, but no genius.
You do magic,
but nothing special.
And the worst is, you're
so eager to belong,
you even forget why you're here.
Why am I here?
You dreamed of it, didn't you?
Fillory, before the
attack, like a warning?
Yeah, how did you...
Because I've dreamed of it too.
And I've looked into
that Beast's eyes.
What?
Do you think you have a destiny?
Um, yes.
Yeah.
I used to believe that
crap too when I was young.
There is no destiny,
no born heroes.
I can't tell you why The
Beast came sniffing for you.
There's no reason
it should be you.
You can either step up
to it or not, it's up to you.
We'll just hope for the best.
Who are you?
Just another inadequate
Magician who's lost people.
So will you if you
don't get strong.
Learn fast, any means necessary.
Which is why I'm so pleased
to see you sitting there
like you don't have an
Emerson's in your pocket
to repel any spell
to wipe your mind.
Uh, you stole that.
Who stole it?
Relax, nobody's
taking your mind today.
We'll make something of you yet.
I'll tell the school one
more chance, probation.
They'll respect my call.
Don't make me regret it.
Don't hop back on the garden
path like some little lemming,
or I'll erase everything
and start you over entirely,
for your own good.
The garden path?
Everything's connected.
Don't over-think it.
All of Bobby's flowers
going to stand up straight
Congratulations, Julia. Big day.
First star. First of many.
Yeah.
Bobby put the flowers
in his mama's car
This is just the beginning.
And he knew that they
wouldn't have to drive too far
Hope your bits are covered.
Coming in.
How are you, Henry?
I'm sorry.
I knew he'd come, but I
swear I didn't know so soon.
No one is ready.
We need more time,
and a teacher with
full use of his hands.
There's that new wrinkle.
I'll find a way to help you.
We'll heal your
hands and your eyes.
It wouldn't help us. It
wouldn't help them, would it?
This is your problem,
that you should solve!
Quentin, Penny,
they're not built for this.
I know, and I've tried.
Go back there.
You say that like
I could hop a bus.
Find a way back.
Find The Beast. Kill him.
If I could manage that, we'd
be sharing a drink right now,
not a care in the world and
four good eyes between us.
I'm sorry.
Just tell me what else I can do.
All we can do is
make them Magicians.
That's not enough.
I know.
Gonna just keep this
BBQ poppin', my love.
Quentin!
Get over here. Quentin.
Come on! Come on!
Join the party,
sad sack. Hurry up.
Oh, my God, it's not
like we have all day.
We're so drunk.
Okay, we have all day.