QUENTIN: Previously on The Magicians...
(BELL RINGS)
QUENTIN: Quentin Goldwater
for the grad school interview?
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
Well, he's dead.
I think he left
something for you.
(AIR WHOOSHING)
You may address me as Dean.
Your only job is to pass
the examination before you.
Regrettably, you failed
the written exam.
Do magic!
Stop it!
Ah...
I need you to tell them
they were wrong about me.
I can do whatever
I want to you.
(GRUNTS)
Awesome.
You thought the school is the
only place to track the gift?
We've been watching you
for quite a while now.
What does that mean?
Okay, for some reason you're
involved, so be involved.
It says we need four people.
Look, I gather you guys need
some extra hands or something.
Let us know
if shit gets exciting.
(GRUNTS)
THE BEAST: Quentin Coldwater.
There you are.
SUNDERLAND: Mr. Coldwater.
Quentin.
Quentin?
(GASPS)
Quentin!
Describe The Beast
that attacked you.
Uh...
How did it get in here?
Mr. Goldwater,
what did The Beast say to you?
How did it know your name?
So what is this place exactly,
besides a health hazard?
Time was, the finest meat
packing plant in town.
Yeah, it's a winner.
Hey, that star on your arm...
I earned it.
You will too, with effort,
whole sleeve of 'em.
So what does it mean?
Does it mean that...
You ask a lot of questions.
Yeah, I sure do.
Oh, my God, these are real?
Every one of them?
Guys, this is Julia.
Julia, my associates.
Holy shit, it's...
And that is...
I'm sorry,
what's your name, sweetie?
I'm Marina. I'm new.
Yeah, no kidding.
Everything up and running?
Yeah.
Julia, Marina. Grand tour.
JULIA: Wait, so who were
those people exactly?
You seriously don't know?
What are you even doing here?
I don't know. I'm waiting for
something interesting to happen. You?
Magic is what I'm doing here.
They're hedge witches.
We're hedge witches.
Jesus, how are you even...
Girls, play nice.
So here is where we keep
all our ingredients and such.
Keeps them safe.
It's a...
Meat locker, or it was, anyway.
Now it is so well-stocked,
it's like the end
of the rainbow.
After you.
Hey!
(DOOR LOCKS)
Come on, open the door.
Hey!
Hey, don't be an asshole.
Open the door! Dude!
We were frozen.
Some kind of paralysis spell.
Took over the whole room.
THE BEAST: Let's just nip
this all in the bud.
I already told you, the Dean
had something in his hand.
I don't know where
it went after that.
You can materialize objects?
I've been doing card
tricks half my life.
I guess some of them
were disappearing.
DEAN'. Quentin...
Take this.
(CLICKS)
ls he dead?
The Dean?
(CLAMORING)
How did you know that spell?
Look, I know we're not supposed
to fire off battle magic, but...
I mean, come on.
(GRUNTS)
Can we just get out
of this room soon?
Please?
(GRUNTS)
SUNDERLAND: I know you want
to understand what happened.
Here's what I can say.
We live in a world
that is one world among many.
The Beast you saw was
from one such place.
We do not know the exact
nature of this entity,
only that it was
powerful and malevolent.
THE BEAST: Stop it!
And we know that
it is gone now.
(GRUNTS)
Wards and shields
protect Brakebills.
They are encoded to each authorized
person on campus and no one else.
We are investigating
how this Beast got through
and resetting everyone.
If someone is responsible
for this attack,
rest assured,
they will be expelled.
Classes are canceled tomorrow.
They will resume Wednesday.
There will be a quiz.
QUENTIN: Alice.
Okay...
Um...
Don't.
Hey, we did that spell.
You don't get to say,
"Don't," okay?
If they find out...
MARGO: There they are.
Glad to see you, kid.
Oh, you poor thing.
Nurse?
Are you okay?
No, it's okay, we're just
gonna get you a nice drink.
Jesus, you didn't tell me
you were dangerous.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Damn it.
And damn it.
Pretty sure my boyfriend's starting
to get curious where I am.
(SHIVERING) Oh, Jesus Christ,
it's cold.
We're stuck, and they're
trying to kill us, so...
They're not trying
to kill us, okay?
These people are not
murderers. Trust me.
How do you know that?
Because, they don't
have the balls for it.
It's like some sort
of hazing ritual, a test.
I'm sick of flunking
tests right now.
I'm gonna figure it out.
(BLOWS)
(SCREAMS)
(GASPING)
(SHRIEKS)
Nothing to see,
you louche little degenerates.
Avada Kedavra. (SNAPS FINGERS)
Whatever, Eliot.
(CHUCKLES)
Welcome to the Physical
Kids' Cottage.
It's the single best
place on campus
for a number of reasons
that will become clear
as soon as you taste
our signature cocktail.
I've got to...
Try on this dress I have.
It's perfect. It's made
exactly for those assets
you're hiding underneath
that pilgrim tent.
Yes, you must. Trust me.
Aprés moi.
On purpose?
Like, you guys
cast it, thinking,
"Oh, monster from
another world.
"By all means, come on in."
So you messed up.
It's a little bit
bigger than messing up.
Than what? Than whatever blew
up the entire third year class?
There's a bad story
every few years around here.
I'm not sure that's avoidable.
Okay.
And if you confess...
Then I'm done.
Yeah.
(STAMMERING) Argh...
Before I got here,
I was in the hospital.
I have... Or I had...
I don't know, uh, this thing that I
couldn't shake where I felt like
because nothing was ever not gonna
be pointless and empty, then,
Uh, Why go on?
And then I got here, and...
It's amazing I survived
as long as I did
not knowing that
I was a Magician.
I can't go back.
So, okay.
There is a spell, uh, if they question
you, so they can't read your minds.
I'll write it down.
It's bulletproof.
Thank you.
Now, can you just
help me live with myself?
Okay, (CLEARS THROAT)
I'm gonna tell you something
deep and dark
and personal now.
Ready? Good.
I killed someone.
What?
I was 14. He was this...
He beat me up.
So I'm walking on the street
eating a candy bar,
'cause by then I already ate my
feelings at a professional level,
and I saw him crossing over.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
And there was this bus coming.
I barely thought the thought.
Barn.
I knew immediately
what I'd done, that it was me.
My nose literally
started bleeding.
Logan Kinear died instantly and I
ruined my favorite button-down.
And that is the story of how I
discovered I was telekinetic.
If you're trying to tell
me that it gets better...
Oh, God, no. No, it doesn't.
I'm trying to tell you,
you are not alone here.
Funny little irony
they don't tell you,
magic doesn't
come from talent.
It comes from pain.
(ELECTRONIC MUSIC
PLAYING FAINTLY)
So, do you know what it was,
the thing that attacked you?
No, I have no idea.
Oh.
I thought you might
be familiar
with some pretty crazy shit
since your family.
Yeah, no, my family's not...
Right.
Yeah.
I get it.
Mine too.
Pointless and toxic.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
I didn't really learn
magic formally as a kid.
I heard you never got invited to
take the Brakebills entrance exam.
How'd you even find it?
You walked right in.
It's not that hard.
(SCOFFS)
We're in the Bermuda Triangle
of upstate New York.
How'd you get through though?
The wards around the school
are fingerprinted.
You're a stranger.
My parents have alumni keys.
Which are supposed
to be charmed
with McNaughton's
Unstealable.
I stole one.
Hmm.
Um...
I just wanted to go to school.
Why do you care?
Curious.
Just 'cause...
I don't know.
I want to be
your friend, I guess.
I don't feel like you do.
(SCOFFS)
I'm sorry, I should go.
Thank you.
There has to be
something here.
Maybe the phone numbers
are, like, a code or...
That's too easy.
Come on.
Chop-chop.
There has to be something.
I mean...
Oh!
(BOTH PANTING)
ls it...
Dead? Mmm-hmm, yeah.
But it was already dead,
so I don't know.
Oh, my God.
Jesus Christ,
they're gonna kill us.
Why did I sign up for this?
This is... (SHUSHING)
Stop it, stop, okay?
Okay, okay.
It's dead dead now, I think.
I don't know.
(GASPS AND SHRIEKS)
Calm down.
Jesus, guys, it's me.
Pete, is that you?
Howdy.
Oh, Pete, that's definitely a good
look for you, an improvement.
Why don't you join us in here?
I think Marina misses you.
Just let us out.
Don't be stupid.
You have to find your way out.
So this is a test,
another test.
Look, if you can't
get through this,
you definitely can't deal with
what it takes to do what we do.
Do you want
magic or not, Julia?
Did you look everywhere?
Fast, frostbite's
gonna set in.
Asshole. Shit.
What did that mean?
Uh, where didn't we look?
Wait.
"Une chaleur temporaire."
Temporary warmth.
(FAINT POP MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHS) I was
just researching.
Reading a kids' book?
What do you want from me, huh?
Jesus, we could not
have screwed up
that spell worse,
and we can't take it back,
and you don't even like me.
I don't know you.
I don't know you either,
except that we summoned some kind of
killer mothman from another world.
Yeah, there is that.
You should hate me right now.
I dragged you into this.
It's just you showed up
with that sigil on your hand,
and it was the same one that
was on the book that l needed,
and my brother,
his spirit, I mean,
sent you to help
me contact him.
So, I'm not really sure
that that's what happened.
The thing on my hand,
(STAMMERS) the sigil,
uh, it appeared when
I was dreaming of Fillory.
Okay.
In my dream,
the sigil on my hand,
it came from Jane.
Chatwin. From Fillory.
Look, honestly, Quentin,
growing up,
the last thing I wanted
to do was read fantasy.
(SIGHS)
Okay. What if, um...
What if Fillory is real?
And I know that you think that
this is just about Charlie,
but I think maybe it's bigger,
because what came through that
mirror instead of Charlie,
it didn't exactly grow up
in the neighborhood.
Okay.)'-
So what if it came from,
like, actual Fillory?
That's a leap, Quentin.
I mean, there are other worlds out
there, but Fillory is just fiction.
Oh, no, the uh,
Chatwins, they're real.
They lived next door
to the author.
He based
the characters on them.
Jesus, how do you
not know any of this?
Is there, um, someplace on campus
we can to go to watch a video?
Yeah.
Good.
NARRATOR: (ON TV) After living next
door to the Chatwins for years
and writing stories
for young Jane and Martin,
when Martin Chatwin
disappeared,
Christopher Plover
was devastated.
This was just one of a series of painful
events that haunted Christopher Plover.
It suffused his work with a
sense of melancholy and loss.
And the mystery of
Martin Chatwin's disappearance
was never solved.
NARRATOR:
Even more mysterious,
Martin's sister Jane
disappeared
the following year.
That's a lot of disappearing.
Yeah, I mean, that's kind of why
people are obsessed with the books,
'cause you have these kids walking
into clocks, uh, into other worlds,
and they're based
on real kids,
and the real kids,
uh, vanished.
You're saying that
Charlie vanished too...
No,no,no,no,no.
I don't know.
I don't know what happened
to Charlie or anyone.
I don't, uh, know.
I mean look, we called
something from another world.
I don't know, can that
really be a coincidence?
So what do we do?
Don't get caught.
I can't get kicked out.
I mean, I have to find out
what happened to him.
Yeah, I know, but...
What if Fillory is real?
Jesus, you don't understand how
mind-blowing that is. It's just like...
Do you want to
stay at Brakebills?
(SCOFFS) Yes.
Okay, so do I.
So let's just hide the evidence
and get our story straight.
Okay?
What, you're leaving?
I'm gone.
Come on.
Look, I know I don't
know you that well,
but I know you're not
the type to scare easy.
You want the truth? No sweat.
Hearing people's thoughts
is the least of my problems.
Couple lines,
right mix of meds.
But you heard Quentin
and Alice in the lab.
No, I didn't.
There's this voice.
Everyone else comes
with a lot of static,
but him, he's clear
as a fucking bell.
Says he's a Magician.
That's...
That's all I know about him.
That and everything that he
taught me is real and it works.
Holy shit.
Let's just say life wasn't
exactly non-stop fun growing up.
That's why I love that voice.
Saved my ass so many times,
he's basically my only friend.
Yeah, right up until
he sent me to a lab to help,
and then that thing
walked in through the mirror.
You were hearing The Beast?
I was getting duped.
But, do they know?
I mean, Sunderland, anyone?
No, there's no point now.
But don't... Penny, don't go.
Come on. It's not your fault.
He tricked you.
Come on, don't be stupid.
Why would you leave
the only place with experts
that might actually
be able to help you with this?
Why do you care?
Look, I did
the spell too, Penny.
If you're guilty, I'm guilty.
You're guilty.
Okay, great,
let's jump off a bridge.
Kady.
I can't stand it.
Okay.
Go.
But...
Hey, since you're out anyway,
come do something stupid
with me before you go.
Come on.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Yeah, 'cause crushed rocks,
you see that in spells that have
a concentrated area of effect.
I'm sorry, you knew this and you
didn't want to say anything?
Okay, well,
I don't know what I know.
Years reading Internet crap and
accidentally poisoning myself twice,
and now I'm stuck
in a freezer with some bitch.
Well, you are.
What, did you figure you wanted
magic at your blow dry last week?
This is serious
for some of us.
Okay, you know what? I'm not
interested in your personal issues.
(SHIVERING)
Hey.
There was sand
in that paint can.
Yeah, and I'm gonna
need a knife and a bowl.
Okay.
And...
"Graisse de I'animal...
De préférence de mouton."
Animal fat. Mutton.
Maybe there's meat?
Come on, let's go before
we freeze our tits off.
(BLOWING)
This isn't just some
lark to me, so you know.
No offense, okay, you just smell
a little Ivy League to me.
Yeah, well, it's 'cause I am.
I was.
Have you ever
heard of Brakebills?
(EXHALES) Well, it's like this
secret Yale, but for magic.
What?
And you have to be able
to do magic to even get in.
Well, I can do magic.
Yeah, so can l.
And yet, somehow,
I flunked the entrance exam.
That doesn't seem right.
Either you can or you can't.
No, it's not right, and yet
they just left me behind.
I mean, seriously,
what do they expect, you know?
Magic is real and that's the thing,
and once you know that, you can't...
Nothing else matters.
Exactly.
It's like...
I know it's there.
It's everywhere,
all around me,
a whole world
of power and beauty.
(CHUCKLES)
You can't unsee it.
You wake up for
the first time.
Yeah.
(SCOFFS)
Who are we kidding?
There's no meat in here.
We've checked everything.
No, no way, I cannot do that.
Mmm-mmm.
No, please do that.
(SOBS)
I let my old life
tie me to the tracks
I heard my best friend tell me
You can never go back
I spent my long years
Learning to get out of the way
I have been taught
to turn the other cheek
I get my back stabbed, buddy
to the end of the week
I only try to make it
to the end of the day
I've seen it break
so many before
I don't wanna stick
around here and watch anymore
Mmm.
Oh...
(CHUCKLES)
Yo, this one looks bunk.
Well, it's not.
It's Emerson's Alloy.
Uh, alloy's rusting.
How do you know?
'Cause I know things.
Like this place...
What? It's a gold mine.
Look, you can't
run away from you.
And, well, I'm here,
and I'm amazing, so I mean...
(CHUCKLES)
I'll take it under
advisement, okay?
HEY-
No, leave us alone.
Gladly, we've got
to discuss, um...
There you are, Quentin and
Alice, and Penny and Kady.
You're exactly who
I was looking for.
I found the most interesting
thing buried in our woods.
Follow me.
We never got near
the mirror, I swear.
We were studying, that's all.
What language even is this?
Yes, I mean,
sure, I touched it.
(STAMMERING) We all touched it.
I mean, I touched...
We were studying, so...
Look, I'm just trying
to make sense of this.
There's residue
all over this book,
including a summoning
we believe opened
the door to The Beast.
What did you say?
Nothing, I...
(SIGHS)
Don't look at me.
Look, I know
they're your friends.
(SCOFFS)
Okay, at this point, I just have
to assume it was all of you.
Yeah, well, it wasn't.
Shut up and I'll
tell you, happily.
It's fine, let's go.
You're welcome, by the way.
What does that mean?
Quentin, can I
see you, please?
Alice, you're free to go.
There's nothing I
can do in this moment
to stop the comet from crashing
into the earth, is there?
Hold On. (CLEARS THROAT)
Uh...
What is this?
My books. I'm headed to return them.
You've heard, I assume.
Word travels fast
when your life's over.
Don't say that.
They're bringing
in a specialist.
Yeah, thanks. Ominous.
I'm sorry.
I don't know, I keep trying to tell
myself this is somehow better,
you know, not to know.
'Cause who would want
to know that magic exists
if there's nothing you can do
about it, you know,
if there's no one
to teach you or help you.
I don't know what to say.
Of course you don't, because
nobody would rather not know.
You don't see color and want
to go back to black and white.
(SIGHS)
You do not have to make
me feel better really,
we basically
just met each other.
Well, I bond fast.
Time is an illusion.
Look, don't go out
there and be the old you.
How, Eliot?
I go back there, and I'm...
I'm a depressed super nerd.
How about I find you,
and I don't say magic is real,
but I do seduce you,
and so lift your spirits
that life retains
its sparkle for decades.
Yeah, that sounds nice.
Thank you.
Okay.
ls there any way
not to get wiped?
I don't know.
I've heard of the specialist,
and all I can say is,
I hear they're very good.
(PHONE BEEPING)
(LINE RINGING)
JULIA: (OVER RECORDING) This is
Julia, little busy. Leave a message.
(RECORDING BEEPS)
(SNIFFLES) Hey, it's Q.
Look, I know when
we last met that, uh...
I'm sorry, Jules. I am.
I didn't know what it
must be like for you,
and I, um, I hope that
you are doing better.
(GRUNTS)
Oh, my God,
you're just going for it.
So, I got expelled,
and they are
sending in a specialist
because the local
brain wipe guy is dead,
and long story.
QUENTIN: Um...
So if you remember or you figured
out why it didn't work on you,
I'd like to know that,
about now,
because I need you to remind
me that magic is real.
(CHUCKLING) Oh, yeah. Yeah.
You know, without Brakebills,
it's just...
I'm lost and you're not.
Magic. (CHUCKLES)
Okay.
Let's find a way
out of this shit hole.
You can't help and
I can't help you,
and it's just...
(BEEPS)
MAN: (OVER RECORDING) TO send
your message, press one.
To erase, press two.
(BEEPS)
Deleted.
Hey!
(EXCLAIMS)
You little piece of shit.
You ratted me out.
I told the truth.
Not all of it.
Oh, am I a fool?
(GROANS)
Apparently not.
Get off!
Yeah, that's what I thought.
(QUENTIN GROANING)
What the hell was that,
you maniac?
Hey! Step back, both of you!
Who shot off that spell?
He did!
I did.
SUNDERLAND: Infirmary, both of you, now.
(PANTING)
Figured it out.
The spell, or, you know, the whole
point, that there isn't one.
Not to get out of the room, not
to keep the door locked, nada.
Cute, Pete.
Oh, and scissors make a shitty
screwdriver, by the way.
(APPLAUDING)
Good for you.
Now you get why it
was so important.
Uh, to almost die
for no reason?
To figure out that not
everything gets solved by magic.
Key fact if you
want to last the month.
You're not still debating letting
me into your club, are you?
Hey, I invited you.
No, you attacked me in a bar,
in a bathroom, on my birthday.
I'm done trying
to prove myself to you.
You weren't.
You were trying
to prove yourself to me.
That means level 50.
Um...
Uh...
Wait, so you were...
Top bitch in New York,
for starters.
Um, and this was...
Me discovering
how much I like you.
You are smart. You're passionate.
You question things.
You messed with my head!
Think about how much you
learned about how to do that
for when you're level 50.
(SCOFFS)
Hey, don't be mad.
Don't be mad.
How am I supposed
to trust you?
Why would you
ever trust anyone?
lam willing to teach the right
people everything I know,
and I know a lot,
because I have certain
connections in certain places,
just like,
for instance, Brakebills.
Brakebills.
You want a drink?
Let's get a drink.
Might burn a little.
This is why you're not supposed to
throw this kind of magic around.
If you’re lucky,
I can fix this.
You're lucky
you're not expelled.
(GROANS)
That's actually...
(CRACKING)
(INHALES SHARPLY AND SCREAMS)
Hold still, please.
(LAUGHING)
Pussy.
Nobody asked you.
Me, the guy you
threw battle magic at?
Hey, have you heard of karma?
Well, sometimes it's instant.
You're welcome.
What is that? HOW did you...
Real Magicians
protect themselves.
Would somebody please
sign him out of here?
(LAUGHING)
(PETE SIGHS)
PETE: She's late.
MARINA: She's coming.
Or she's just
done with your shit.
She doesn't have the option.
PETE: Finally.
Hey, look, that thing you wanted,
that charm or crystal or whatever?
The Emerson's Alloy Repellant?
Yeah, this guy I was with,
he grabbed it.
Look, I'll find you
another one, okay?
And more.
Here.
There's a ton
of good shit in there.
Listen to all
that backpedaling.
I'll get it, okay?
Whatever you want.
I'll find you another one.
Great. You're
a sweet girl, Kady.
You're a heartless bitch.
I'm generous with you,
considering.
Get me everything on
this list, this week.
Thanks so much.
You better get
back to bed, hon.
I'm sure you got
class in the morning.
Hi.
Oh...
Caught me where I'm not meant
to be, a terminal snooper.
How are you, Quentin?
I heard about the attack.
You were there the day
of the alumni interview.
You were a paramedic.
Call me Eliza.
I was there that day to make
sure that you got here.
Oh...
Well, uh, thank you,
but I kind of screwed that up.
Uh...
They're calling
in a specialist.
He's supposed to, um,
wipe it all away
like it never happened.
Mmm. That sounds...
Hmm... (SMACKS LIPS)
You know,
I'm the specialist? Sorry.
Shall we sit?
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
Um, just before,
um, can I...
Um, why did you
give me that book?
Fillory and Further, book six.
I thought you'd appreciate it.
I lost it.
Guess I was wrong.
No, you're not, I...
I need to read it.
I just, I can't find it.
Things with Fillory
are funny that way.
Is Fillory real?
Why even ask if you'll
just forget it again?
The books, they're just...
They always felt
realer than anything.
Then it's real.
That's not a real answer.
Shall we begin?
Okay, do it.
(CHUCKLES) Oh, Quentin,
lam pleased!
(SIGHS) What? Why?
You're a much better liar
than I expected you to be.
Can I level with you?
I wish you would.
You're not very remarkable.
You're smart, but no genius.
You do magic,
but nothing special.
And the worst is,
you're so eager to belong,
you even forget
why you're here.
Why am I here?
You dreamed of it, didn't you?
Fillory, before the attack,
like a warning?
Yeah, how did you...
Because I've
dreamed of it too.
And I've looked
into that Beast's eyes.
What?
Do you think you
have a destiny?
Um, yes.
Yeah.
I used to believe that
crap too when I was young.
There is no destiny,
no born heroes.
I can't tell you why The Beast
came sniffing for you.
There's no reason
it should be you.
(SCOFFS) You can either step up
to it or not, it's up to you.
We'll just hope
for the best.
Who are you?
Just another inadequate
Magician who's lost people.
So will you if you
don't get strong.
Learn fast,
any means necessary.
Which is why I'm so pleased
to see you sitting there
like you don't have
an Emerson's in your pocket
to repel any spell
to wipe your mind.
Uh, you stole that.
Who stole it?
Relax, nobody's
taking your mind today.
We'll make
something of you yet.
I'll tell the school
one more chance, probation.
They'll respect my call.
Don't make me regret it.
Don't hop back on the garden
path like some little lemming,
or I'll erase everything
and start you over entirely,
for your own good.
The garden path?
Everything's connected.
Don't over-think it.
(DOOR BUZZING)
All of Bobby's flowers
going to stand up straight
(TATTOO MACHINE WHIRRING)
All of Bobby's flowers
going to stand up straight
Congratulations, Julia.
Big day.
First star. First of many.
Yeah.
Bobby put the flowers in his mama's car
This is just the beginning.
And he knew that they
wouldn't have to drive too far
Hope your bits are covered.
Coming in.
(AIR PUMP HISSING)
How are you, Henry?
I'm sorry.
I knew he'd come, but I swear
I didn't know so soon.
No one is ready.
We need more time,
and a teacher with
full use of his hands.
There's that new wrinkle.
I'll find a way to help you.
We'll heal your
hands and your eyes.
It wouldn't help us. It
wouldn't help them, would it?
This is your problem,
that you should solve!
Quentin, Penny,
they're not built for this.
I know, and I've tried.
Go back there.
You say that like
I could hop a bus.
Find a way back.
Find The Beast. Kill him.
(SCOFFS) If I could manage that,
we'd be sharing a drink right now,
not a care in the world
and four good eyes between us.
I'm sorry.
Just tell me
what else I can do.
All we can do is
make them Magicians.
That's not enough.
I know.
ELIOT: Gonna just keep this
BBQ poppin', my love.
(MARGO CHUCKLING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
(LAUGHING)
Quentin!
Get over here.
Quentin.
Come on!
Join the party, sad sack.
Hurry up.
Oh, my God, it's not
like we have all day.
We're so drunk.
Okay, we have all day.
(ELIOT AND MARGO LAUGHING)