QUENTIN: Previously
on The Magicians...
ALICE: I hesitated with The
Beast. I should've... It's my fault.
QUENTIN: No, it's not.
MARGO: It's Julia's fault.
You know how to deal with gods.
You know how
to... up their shit.
Julia. No.
I want to make a deal.
No! Guys! She
was... She's not sane.
MARGO: One small consolation is
the bitch is with The Beast right now,
and I can't really see
that going her way.
Word As Bond.
I assume the extra
bits enchant the blade
to kill me instantly
in the event I break it.
JOSH: You guys
are from Brakebills?
Dude, Josh
Hoberman, class of '16.
Come with me if
you want to live.
QUENTIN: Yeah,
Josh and Victoria bailed.
On one hand... them,
on the other hand, you
can't really blame them.
I'm Marina. JULIA:
So you were...
MARINA: Top bitch in
New York, for starters.
MARINA: Welcome
back to Brakebills.
JULIA: Wait, you went here?
MARINA: Kicked out three
months before graduation.
Let's go steal their shit.
(SIGHS) So, there's a bump.
Bigger than marrying
a total stranger-ette?
MARGO: Once you get married, you
won't be able to be with anyone else.
Literally. But when I go back...
I can never leave Fillory.
Please fix my hands.
MAN: Let's see, how do I put this
in a way that you will understand?
Ah. Go fuck yourself.
ELIOT: According to the
best and only magic we have,
The Beast will kill
us. End of story.
Okay. A zillion bucks says The
Beast comes back any minute.
So what's the plan?
We lost the blade. So
we need a new something.
Especially while Alice is
still... ALICE: Juiced up?
ALICE: Wait, this is something.
It's a workbook on
spells. Serious ones.
But the actual
spells aren't here.
I know where we need to go.
Brakebills?
PENNY: I don't get it.
How come nobody in the
'hood is trying to kill us?
Okay, that's just weird.
You wanna stop and
figure it out, be my guest.
You're alive. What
a lovely surprise.
QUENTIN: Okay, so...
The castle armory was
basically empty, except for this.
This is a Brakebills
student workbook.
I'm not blind,
Quentin. Technically.
From 1893.
So, I guess that means that a
Brakebills student was in Fillory,
uh, over 100 years ago.
And the only humans that had
access to the Armory were...
Own it, pumpkin. The Monarchy.
So, we're not the first
Brakebills students
to get into Fillory or
to assume the throne.
It's a great question
for history class,
but if The Beast gets to
the Wellspring right now
and sucks it bone dry,
magic dies in
Fillory. It dies there...
It dies here. On Earth.
My God.
So, the battle magic that
this student learned here,
he learned from a
professor named Bigby.
Have you heard of him? Her.
Well, there is a note in here.
There's a spell that seems strong
enough, called the Rhinemann Ultra.
Right. But the spell
isn't actually here.
Because why should
anything be easy?
Shit. Shit! Duck!
Who? PENNY: Everybody!
(GRUNTING)
What the hell is that about?
MARGO: Uh...
It's semi-not-related to any of
this, but I think I know a temp fix.
DEAN: All right.
I'll get back to you.
(SIREN WAILING)
MARTIN: (SINGING) Hey-ho
If love were all
I should be lonely
(PIANO MUSIC STARTS PLAYING)
I believe
The more you love a girl
The more you give your trust
The more you're bound to lose
Okay, is that an actual song
or are you trying to get me to
stab a knife into my eardrums?
(CONTINUES SINGING) Although
Of course.
When shadows fall
I think if only
Somebody splendid
really needed me
You mind? I'm working.
It's still too similar to the
first sigil that summoned him.
He'll know it's you. And a trap.
You're welcome to
have an actual idea.
Oh, no. I'd ruin
your primitive purity.
That's part of
what attracts him.
You're an absolute
savage, Julia.
Look, I know you're
basically stoned on sugar,
but if you could just
dial down the chipper.
(LAUGHING) All I do
is accept what you fight.
(SIGHS) Well...
Which is? Life is pointless.
The afterlife even more so.
Which is why we invent these
games to fill the void of existence.
Who diddled whom?
Who'll get revenge for it?
Who takes the throne?
Mmm. Yeah, well, that would
be me, actually, and my friends.
Oh, well, I doubt they're
your friends anymore.
And they won't be royals long.
(CHUCKLES)
Why?
Oh, maybe you could use a bit
of help with the Binding Principle.
Did you put some kind
of curse on the castle?
Did I?
It was so long ago.
I hardly remember.
The Throne Room, sire.
MAN: Oh, God!
Can't be that hard
to find dead rats.
(SCREAMS)
MARTIN: Wait, wait, wait. Yes.
I believe I did work
up a little welcome.
Yes, since Ember made it
impossible for me to retake the throne,
and the Children of Earth
kept coming and coming,
drunk on self-love
and power-lust.
Yes, I thought of it
as a kind of royal test.
That no one ever passed.
Sadly.
What kind of test?
Ah, that's something for each new
despot to puzzle out themselves.
Anyway, you're on the right
track. Now we just need the bait.
As soon as I'm finished
with this, I'm ready.
He knows you. A
bit too intimately.
No, I have the perfect,
fresh candidate.
She's young, beautiful, female
and a very powerful witch.
No.
Julia... Let's skip
the discussion.
You do as I say or this...
Does its job, per the bond.
Well, technically, the
Leo Blade cuts my throat
if I attempt to harm you,
your beloveds or
undermine your efforts.
And my dear, I assure you...
(PIANO MUSIC STARTS PLAYING)
(SINGING) I believe
That since my life began
The most I've had is just
A talent to amuse
Hey-ho
If love were all
QUENTIN: Uh...
Wait, the cottage
was here, right?
ALICE: Hmm...
It's not invisible,
it's just not.
Aw, shit! Right.
End of semester prank to
ditch the first-year losers.
I should've remembered,
it was my idea.
Are you...
I hate all of you.
QUENTIN: Could we just
find the cottage, please?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Mmm!
Promising.
To the first bottle of
Fillorian champagne.
Which I know technically
isn't champagne.
Except I'm renaming the Royal
Gardens "Champagne Nouveau" so...
Ugh.
"Champagne No-No-No." Jesus!
That makes no sense.
I used the go-to
fermenting enchantment.
No fretting. We'll get
it right. Trial and error.
I'm your wife. I
want to be obedient.
(LAUGHS)
Sit down.
Nobody wants to be obedient.
I do want to serve
you and Fillory.
But...
But?
Look, I'm okay being a king,
but I don't want to run a cult.
If anyone has the right
to speak up, it's you.
There hasn't been
a truly inspiring,
caring ruler since
Rupert Chatwin,
and that was so long ago,
most barely remember.
Look, I'm cleaning the place up.
I'm trying to get some
decent wine going.
(SCOFFS) What else is there?
The people are starving.
Seriously?
Oh. Okay. We should
probably get on that.
(SIGHS)
And I'm guessing magic
probably won't do the trick.
Magic is the problem.
Oh, boy.
(SIGHS)
(UPBEAT MUSIC
PLAYING ON SPEAKERS)
(ALL SHOUTING EXCITEDLY)
Yep. We're alive. Deal.
Can you keep your shit
tight for a few more minutes?
Couple minutes is all I need.
Drink! Now!
You deserting,
chickenshit motherfucker!
Wait! Wait, wait!
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
No! No! Goddamn it!
Like Lando and Han. Right on.
(GROANING)
Still got my legs.
So, is it true what Josh is
saying? Fillory's real, right? Right?
DEAN: Fillory is
very real. Okay.
And this is going to be on
the syllabus next semester?
We shall see.
But for now, Quentin, Alice,
Penny and Margo need battle magic.
We're going to teach
battle magic now?
It was once a required course.
Till it was outlawed.
For good reason, I hear.
Yes, well, it was a
very messy situation.
At the time, I
thought it was right.
But the professor
who taught it disagreed.
Strongly.
She was fired and as she was
escorted off campus, she said that...
I'm sorry, Henry,
this is fascinating
but why are you telling me this?
The professor, Bigby,
hinted that she hid
all the battle magic spells
somewhere on campus.
"You'll need them
someday," she said.
"And me."
Again, why?
All the battle magic spells
are hidden in the library.
No one knows the
library better than you.
(UPBEAT MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
Look, I'm sorry, okay? We
both are. Seriously sorry.
So where is Victoria? Traveling.
I don't even know if she's
on this planet anymore.
PENNY: Can't blame her.
Spit in it. What is it?
The hangover cure El and I
used when we got the shakes.
I amped it up with Nightshade
and a couple Ativans.
Might make you a little
woozy but it could do the trick.
Temporarily. So
keep a stash on you.
It is good to see
you guys, though.
Hey, fuck off. Okay.
(SIGHING)
Oh!
This one...
Is sheer, hellcat perfection.
(HORN HONKING)
I don't give a shit
about getting him.
You should. Look, I
didn't summon him.
I didn't get raped by him.
I have no skin in this
except that I
wanna kick your ass
and kill him.
(SINGING) Fate may
often treat me meanly
But I keenly pursue
A little mirage in the blue
Did you scrape him
off the cabaret floor?
Reynard is targeting
Hedges. Right,
so the answer is to
hire Michael Bublé
to kidnap me and then
use me as your bait.
If I'm wrong, raise your hand.
Look, you're right.
It was wrong grabbing
you the way that we did.
But sooner or later
he was gonna find you.
We need someone... Else, Julia.
Or we have a problem.
Do you want a problem with me?
Forget it. Great.
(DOOR OPENS)
I told you untying
her was a mistake.
(DOOR SLAMS SHUT)
ALICE: (WINCES) Ow!
What? It's starting
to burn a little.
Take it off. No,
I can't. I need it.
The more it burns,
the less time we have.
If it hurts then...
Not everything
that hurts is bad.
I hate that all
of this is on you.
You'd tell me if there
was something I could do?
To shift the weight off?
Yeah, I'd tell you.
MARINA: (ON PHONE) Look, she's a bitch
on three wheels, probably batshit crazy,
but she's not wrong.
Did you find it?
I did. And?
Look, I know we made a pact,
I stick to my coast,
you stick to yours,
but this might take all
the top hedge witches
to coven up and
take this asshole out.
Your coast or mine?
I'm already on my way.
ELIOT: So, if I'm
understanding this,
things here grow magically.
Until recently, yes.
Everything always
took care of itself.
We used to grow all the
nuts in the southern region.
Until The Beast
drained the magic.
Now what's required
is actual farm work,
which no one in
Fillory knows how to do.
Uh... (CHUCKLES)
I think I'm getting one
of those migraines where
everything gets all bendy.
Please, God, let me pass out.
No? All right.
Fen.
(SIGHS)
I have a secret.
It's fairly difficult
for me to confess.
And it brings me nothing but
waves of aching nausea, but...
(ELIOT INHALES DEEPLY)
I grew up on a farm.
That's your secret?
I've spent years
blocking it all out.
The smell of wet hay.
That feel of an udder.
The taste of fresh...
(GAGS) Goat milk.
And the worst humans in
the known universe, my family.
It's coming back,
and if it all comes back
I'm pretty sure I'll
know exactly what to do.
That's wonderful! (SIGHS)
On a planet with no Zoloft.
Now you sound like my King.
(ELIOT CHUCKLES)
And, so if I just needed
one little thing from you to,
to ease my agony...
Anything. (CHUCKLES)
There's my girl.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
(LOCK TURNING)
Professor Bigby was
brilliant. Impatient. Stubborn.
And mercurial.
And a 500-year-old pixie,
who more-or-less saw humans
as children to be toyed with.
If she's as good as her word,
and one thing she
certainly wasn't was a liar,
then her book of battle
magic will be found here.
In this room. Why?
She told me. "The battle magic will
be where the knowledge always is.
"The day you need it, I
promise, it will be your last hope."
Er, those are her exact
words? "Last hope"?
Yes.
Well, that's the name of one of the
more powerful texts on battle magic.
The Last Hope Options.
Yes! Of course. (CHUCKLES)
Pixies love puzzles and riddles.
Especially those that
make humans look stupid.
She gave me the title of the
book that we're searching for,
but I'm afraid that it
will be very hard to find.
Let's get to it.
Rhinemann.
The Rhinemann Exchange.
A spy novel by Robert Ludlum.
What's next?
(SIGHS) "Last Hope
Options" is an anagram for?
"Pane Hotspot Silo"?
(SIGHS) All right.
Let's try assigning a different
number structure to the letters.
For instance, "A"
is 11, "B" is 22,
"C" is 44 and so on.
Okay. (CLEARS THROAT)
ALICE: "Tat Loosens Hippo".
"Opine Path Stools".
(CLAPS)
Pixie puzzles?
Ah...
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
Penny.
What's... What's
happened to your hands?
What hasn't?
Well, tell me. Why?
Maybe I can help.
MARGO: Nada.
(SIGHS) Professor?
I can safely say that
none of the number codes we
came up with led to anything.
We found about 300
anagram phrases.
Anything promising?
Uh... Well, uh,
"hospital nose top"
mean anything? What about,
"latte shop poison"? No?
(EXHALES) That's surprising.
Uh... Oh, this one's good.
This one's my favorite
because it's absurd.
"Hotel Spa Potions."
Wait. That's a book. In here.
Yes!
ALICE: Last Hope
Options. DEAN: Ah.
A chapter's been ripped out.
Wait, there's a note.
"Hello, Henry.
"If you're reading
this, I was right
"and everyone at
Brakebills was wrong.
"How delightful.
"It also means I'll see
you quick as 1, 2, 9,
"where middle
leads and last is fine.
"Summer's here
and ne'er retreats,
"a pretty island
made of streets."
Another riddle. Awesome.
Oh, well, if it's, like,
where to find her,
"island made of
streets" is Rhode Island.
What? Duh.
(SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
Sorry, could you spell
your last name again?
I would but...
You're asleep.
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
You said "anything."
But this is... This is...
Am I not enough for you?
(SIGHS)
You're great.
For who you are. It's just...
I already told you, my
life was different before.
Yeah, and I'll help
you make a new life.
Well, this is new.
And right inside
the lines of marriage.
We just do what we do in bed
and they do what they do.
I only picked people
already doing each other.
And we get to watch.
(SIGHS)
You guys are all
cool with this, right?
ALL: Mmm-hmm.
ELIOT: See?
You're their King.
They'll do as you
wish, no matter how...
Fun? Debased.
(CHUCKLING) Debased?
Honey-love, I've been
doing this shit since I was 12.
Except on a computer.
I don't know what that means.
But, if it's what you desire...
(SIGHS)
All right, goodnight, everyone.
Thanks. You all look
really good naked.
MAN: Thank you, sire.
Well, I guess life is about
new experiences and...
I've never been
pussy-whipped, so.
MARTIN: You're doomed.
Which I might find amusing,
except it's likely to get me killed.
And for what?
Because no matter what,
I'm going to hold onto my...
If you say
"humanity" you'll learn
I can vomit nonstop
for two hours.
(SIGHS)
You know, I'm about to
make an enemy of a god
who I have no quarrel with.
And without decent bait,
you're literally asking
me to do it blindfolded,
shackled and hopping on one leg.
If I took just a
smidgen of your Shade,
not only would your
trauma drop away,
you'd have no issue
with using Marina.
You'd be free of
these useless feelings
and this idiotic moral quagmire.
Come near me, and
the knife won't kill you.
'Cause you can still
live without a dick.
(PIANO MUSIC STARTS PLAYING)
(SINGING) Life is
very rough and tumble...
Or a tongue.
MARGO: So, Rhode Island
was just beginner's luck.
QUENTIN: Okay, uh, okay.
"Summer's here and ne'er retreats."
So "ne'er retreats."
It's set. Summer is set.
Summer... Summer set. Somerset.
"Somerset." And the numbers
could be a street address?
Right.
"Quick as 1, 2, 9.
Middle is first, last is fine."
219.
So, it's 219-something Somerset.
Come on!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GRUNTS)
I think I can help.
(SIGHS)
Sorry, sir? Yes?
But we've had a security breach.
Marina. Please.
I need asylum.
DEAN: Marina, what else
can you tell me about this...
Situation?
Well, for starters,
it's not a "situation."
It's a raping, killing, omniscient
god with a pretty specific type.
Me and mine.
What the fuck else
do you need to know?
I see you still don't expend
much on good manners.
What, this is a
charm school now?
No, but it is my school.
Not a safe house.
I was the best student
you ever had here.
You said that. I confused
talent with character.
You need both to be a
true Magician, Marina.
Kicking you out wasn't a choice.
I couldn't have you
infecting my students then,
and I certainly won't now.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
You fucking prick.
Where am I supposed to go?
You can keep your memories.
I hope that whatever you've
learned here will help keep you safe.
What I learned here
will get me killed.
(DOOR SLAMS)
Remember, pixies are tricky.
Keep all questions and
answers short, and to the point.
You understand? BIGBY: Henry!
DEAN: Ah, yes.
Henry! You look awful!
What's happened to your
eyes? Are you blind? And your...
Your hair! Henry,
you look ancient!
Very nice of you
to say so, dear.
Oh, no wonder you sought me out.
I mean, you've been
positively mauled by something.
Bigby, let me introduce...
Mmm...
(CHUCKLING)
Some things haven't changed.
You still are the
most wonderful kisser.
Do you have time
to go to bed with me?
We are a bit on the clock,
darling. And these are my students.
They are in need of
the Rhinemann Ultra.
(LAUGHS) Are they now? Oh, yes.
Well, if the stuffed shirts
and ninny naysayers
hadn't outlawed battle
magic 38 years ago,
then they would have it.
Which you well know, Henry.
You look hungry.
QUENTIN: So, why was
battle magic outlawed?
Ugh. Humans' least
attractive qualities.
Panic and paranoia.
And there were several
student deaths that semester.
BIGBY: Far fewer than the 1870s,
or the 1920s, or the '60s.
Another human
failing. Short memory.
Mmm.
Hmm.
You'd be the one casting? Good.
It'd burn anyone
else to a crisp.
I can feel your
power. It's almost...
(LAUGHS) It's almost godlike.
Did you fuck one of them?
I mean, they are
wonderful, aren't they?
Or at least mine was. I
glowed for weeks. No, literally.
I actually got mine
a little differently.
Yes, and it's
waning. Quite quickly.
So, Bigby, if you could
just please give us the spell.
I don't give anything, Henry.
You of all people know that.
So, well, convince me.
(SIGHS)
Where the hell is
the burned river?
Apologies for last
night, dear wife.
None required, My Lord.
I will need to find some
way to blow off steam.
Somehow, someday, but
in the meantime, I get to
stroll the wondrous memory
fields of my agrarian childhood.
Sprinkling shit.
"Sprinkling shit"?
Shoveling, mixing,
drying, hauling.
Sorry, sprinkling it on what?
Crops.
Oh...
Fertilizer?
Your farmers don't fertilize?
ALICE: So, it's the only thing we've
found that might stop The Beast.
I mean, it was
amazing reading about
how you used the
Rhinemann at Gettysburg
to help win the war for
the Union. QUENTIN: Right.
And it was you who
slipped it to Rupert Chatwin
for the Battle of the Bulge.
I mean, you changed history.
I did. Yes. Many times.
Henry, is that
juniper tree still there?
You know, the one
by the infirmary?
Oh, yes. Oh! It has
the softest grass.
It feels delicious on your ass.
I mean, we used to sneak out at
night and, oh, for hours, we would...
Bigby. Please.
BIGBY: Are you telling me you
don't even remember that tree?
Of course I do, darling.
Of course. But it's private.
(LAUGHING)
Well, not anymore!
Plus, these two
fuck like jackrabbits!
I mean, you can just smell
it. (DEAN CLEARS THROAT)
And it is delicious, darling.
Bigby, we really are in a
time crunch. Mmm-hmm.
There's a lot at stake.
Which I told you would be
the case someday. Hmm?
Well, welcome to someday.
(SIGHS)
(CLEARS THROAT)
No one but you can be
within 20 feet of the blast.
It will kill anyone,
including your Beast.
As strong as he
is, you're stronger.
But not for long. Hmm? So,
stop prattling and get to it!
Boys? The shit.
Um, sire, I do not wish
to appear ungrateful...
You're just going to have
to trust your King on this one.
Come on, lads,
many a farm to grace...
With our royal dung!
Hyah!
Shit!
ELECTRONIC VOICE:
The time is 10:58 p.m.
Alice, you're getting it. But...
It's taking too long. I'm
not as strong as I was.
By the time I'm
fully powered up,
The Beast will have
eaten all of our faces off.
DEAN: You all are going to need
something strong to hit him with.
Bigby isn't the only one who
tucked away a few secrets.
PENNY: Ow!
Sorry, spell says
it has to be tight.
Do they have to be behind
me? I feel like I'm getting busted.
You can't look at your
hands for 12 hours.
Okay, what is that? I
can't pronounce the name.
It's from China.
It'll keep the blood circulating
but take away a
lot of the discomfort.
Wait, that feels... Ahh!
Okay.
I'm wondering if maybe you
could rub a little into my shoulder.
Yeah, I got a cramp.
Which one?
Both, actually.
I feel guilty.
Why?
Letting you do all the work.
I don't mind.
Still.
If there's anything I can
do for you, let me know.
I don't think you're in
a position to do much.
(WHISPERING) Try me.
I might.
After you graduate.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
QUENTIN: Jules!
Q. Hey. Hey.
Hey, um...
I got your message
in my bathroom mirror.
So freaky.
Look, I'm not supposed to
tell you what I'm gonna tell you.
Okay, fine. Don't.
It's just... I have
to warn you. Uh...
You could die if you don't
get clear of The Beast.
You think I don't know
how dangerous he is?
No. Not him. Us.
We're going to kill him.
Yeah, do what you want with
him, but not until I get Reynard.
No, we can't wait.
You won't. No! Jules, we can't.
I know that you're
hurting. I just, I...
I need you to see that
this is bigger than you.
The Beast, he is killing
magic everywhere.
And Reynard is killing
people everywhere.
You think that
that's less important?
No, I just think that what you
want here is revenge and...
And you don't?
Just don't be within
20 feet of The Beast
when we make our move, okay?
Do it before I get Reynard,
you better not be
within 20 miles of me.
I came here to warn you,
and you're threatening me.
Look, I did what I had to do.
(SIGHS) Just make
up your own mind.
There's something.
About the castle.
He made some kind of a
joke. He put a curse on it.
Anyone who assumes the throne.
What kind of curse?
He wouldn't say.
But I'm pretty
sure it's no joke.
Okay, vague.
Mildly helpful. I guess.
It's all I got.
Thank you.
Sure.
This is... (MOUTHING INAUDIBLY)
I know.
Okay, I'll see you
when I see you.
See you.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(GASPS SOFTLY)
(SIGHS) Wow.
I owe you for real.
Good.
Alice is going to take just a
few minutes to fully power up.
You all are going to need
something strong to hold off The Beast.
Step one
is for all of you
to get very, very drunk.
Why? You'll see. Chug-a-lug.
(SCREAMING)
DEAN: As you grow, your name
will become an important part of you.
Even the shape of the letters
will connect with your will,
your unique abilities.
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
Well, I can never get
buried in a Jewish cemetery.
ALICE: Are you even Jewish?
No. Options.
How much do I
have to drink so that
I never have to hear
your voice again?
DEAN: Good. Now,
for the painful part.
That wasn't the
painful part? Oh, no.
Professor Li?
(METAL CLANGING)
(CREATURE SQUEALING)
This is a cacodemon.
Jesus. DEAN: They'll
grow much bigger.
Unleash these and, believe me,
they'll keep The Beast plenty busy.
Each of you will be
given a special word
to command your
cacodemon to attack.
They are a one-shot weapon.
So, pick your moment with care.
What are you, uh,
gonna do with it?
Lift your shirt, Quentin,
and turn around.
Oh!
Those words never
led to anything good.
Well, almost never.
(SQUEALING) (SCREAMING)
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
DEAN: Right. Next.
Sire, it's working.
Oh, great.
Mmm, thank you.
Thank you, My King.
No, no, thank the hell
that was my childhood.
(WHOOSHING)
Oh, well. (CLEARS THROAT)
Perfect timing. For once.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Your High King has
agricultural tales to tell.
I give you the reign of...
King Shit.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
I figured you'd pretty much
be dead without me. So...
MARTIN: (SINGING)
Is it an earthquake?
Or simply a shock?
Is it the good turtle soup
Or merely the mock?
Jesus Christ.
(CONTINUES
SINGING) Is it a cocktail?
This feeling of joy?
He has to stop.
Or is what I feel
The real McCoy? (PIANO
MUSIC STARTS PLAYING)
Ah, don't make me wait, ladies.
Are we three
going to kill a god?
Yeah, for starters. Good one.
(CONTINUES SINGING)
Is it Granada I see?
Or only Asbury Park?
Is it a fancy
You lose like a glove
Or is it at long
Last love?