Previously on The Magicians...
My hands won't cast.
We can help you, Penny.
What's the catch?
Bound in service to the
Library up to and after my death?
That isn't just any door.
PENNY: Then what is it?
The Poison Room.
There is knowledge
behind that door
that could destroy
more than just people.
It could destroy worlds.
The Ars Deicidium?
The art of killing gods.
King Idri is our honored guest.
We're getting married.
One big royal
polyamorous family.
The Fairies can bring
back the Wellspring?
They can.
And in return?
The child that grows in the
womb of the High King's wife.
Some friends and I
summoned a goddess.
You may address me as Reynard
the Fox, trickster of the very stupid.
Reynard's son is John Gaines?
My son.
Jules, I talked to your Shade.
She's not gone.
So where is she?
Shades go to the Underworld.
The living can access the Underworld
with the help of a Gatekeeper.
An Ancient One.
I think I figured out
what an Ancient One is.
Look, Q, you don't
have to come with me.
In fact, I don't think
that you should.
Noted, but I'm coming.
You feel the energy
coming off that?
Yeah, also the stink.
I don't know. My ancient
Greek is a little rusty.
"The old reveals itself to the
new at the fall of milk teeth."
Milk teeth?
Oh, uh, baby teeth.
You think we have to
stick one in to open it up?
I mean, I could write a spell.
Uh, we could find the
nearest child's house
expecting the
tooth fairy, and...
Break in and steal their teeth?
I'd leave money.
I hate to bring this
up, but I actually...
I still have one.
A molar that never came in.
Oh! I know an extraction spell.
Ah!
Fuck. Sorry.
This dragon better
be fucking cool.
Hmm...
Or not?
I wouldn't have
guessed baby teeth.
Why would a dragon
want baby teeth?
Shit.
I collect baby teeth, as I collect
many things, little mammal.
Greetings, Your Ladyship.
"Your Ladyship"? I am a
Queen of the Great Worms.
Of course you are.
That's awesome. I wasn't
suggesting that you weren't.
Your manner does not
endear me to you, human.
We seek passage to the
Underworld, O Ancient One.
Hmm, you seek to die?
Uh, no, actually we were
hoping to come back after.
Suit yourself.
I require a gift.
A gift? Um...
Yeah. I mean, name it,
and we'll get it for you.
You already have it.
It's in your pocket.
No. Pick something else.
If this gets you your
Shade back... No.
Fillory is your home.
And what about your friends?
What if they need you? We can't.
Queen of the Great Worms,
what if I needed to
borrow it in the future?
Just super briefly.
No. If you wish to return home,
you must find other means.
The first door remains
open, little mammal.
Great, um, I super love riddles.
Are you giving me
the button or not?
Your bodies will stay here,
and your souls will travel.
You have 24 hours
to return to the portal.
Or...
I sit patiently, waiting
for you to come back.
No, I eat you. I'm a fucking
dragon. What'd you expect?
Great. Good to know.
Then it's settled.
Jesus! A little
warning next time.
Really.
Q, look.
Time to go.
Fucking millennials.
Welcome to the Underworld.
Please take a number.
The fuck...
Idri is almost here. And does
anyone know where Fen is?
I present King Idri of Loria.
My life is perfect.
Hello.
Josh. Wine, canapés.
I said have it ready.
We have a lovely blend of...
Okay.
Where are the fire dancers?
I don't know.
I'm sorry. I had
a whole thing...
Your Majesty, this
presentation is beautiful, but...
It would be so much better
with fire dancers. I know.
I hope my arrival isn't
causing undue stress.
Stress? I'm not stressed.
Eliot, I don't care
about ceremony.
You don't? But...
But I came here for you.
Oh...
Well, the feeling's mutual.
Take me somewhere we can
become a bit better acquainted.
Alone.
Congratulations, you're dead!
You've passed through
the veil, to the Underworld.
Is this your final
destination? No.
It's the first leg
of your journey.
We designed this part
of the Underworld for you,
based on your life and
personal expectations
to facilitate a
comfortable transition.
You've been grouped with others
who have similar expectations.
Perfect, right?
This is your time
to process... Ow.
What?
And settle into this next
stage of your existence.
In the unlikely event
you're missing your Shade,
please report to a
bellhop immediately.
Enjoy your wait.
I guess we need
to find bellhops.
Security! We have
a Shadeless patron.
What? BELLHOP: Take him away.
Why? Where are you taking
me? Thank you. Thank you.
Read me my rights.
Let go. Wait... Ow!
Or, you know, we take a beat.
173.
Place your hands on the
counter for identification, please.
Hey, do you know where they
were taking that guy just now?
Oh, his soul is
missing a little piece.
They just took him somewhere
where he would be more comfortable.
So he could be reunited with it?
I doubt it. That's
very difficult to do,
especially after a
prolonged separation.
Yeah, but you can't just take...
I assure you, all
the Shades are safe
and well protected
for their eternity.
Nothing to worry over.
Ah, here we are.
Wicker and Coldwater.
Oh.
Oh, my...
What?
You've both died 39 times?
No. A-ha!
Time loop. Thought so. Our
computers do not handle these well.
This will take
a bit to sort out.
Once you're in the
system, we'll reunite you
with your immediate
karmic circle,
but until then, I'll need to stick
you somewhere. Do you like skiing?
Look, I thought this was just a
way station? We're kind of in a hurry.
Oh, it is, but souls
do stay a while
until they're ready to
move on.
Snorkeling? Art museums?
Actually, is it possible to
check on a few names?
I think I might have a
karmic circle we could visit.
You're making progress.
Am I? Nothing's happening.
It's an exceedingly
difficult way to do magic,
trying to isolate muscles not
generally associated with...
Call it what it is.
Sphincter magic.
Gets me there? No shame.
And if it doesn't, we all
need a healthy pelvic floor.
Now, I'm afraid study time
is over. I have your next job.
Re-shelving books.
Great.
Any questions, direct them to...
Where'd she go? Sylvia!
What? Shh!
Penny, Sylvia. Sylvia, Penny.
So what, I'm babysitting now?
Oh, no, Sylvia is
your supervisor.
Good luck! I'll check back.
Nice scarf.
Anyway, I married
Fen because I had to.
I didn't know her at all.
And now,
I don't know you.
My wife used to say there's one
way to learn to be with another person.
The hard way?
Actually, yes.
Stand up.
Would you mind removing this?
Buttons, too, please.
What are you doing? Shh.
This is a lesson.
All of them.
Please.
I really hate to bring this up,
but you do realize
there's nothing
we can actually do.
Oh, I know.
And yet there's so
much we can do.
I can't touch you.
You can't touch me.
But I can tell you how
I want to touch you.
And you can show me
how you like to be touched.
I admire your
commitment to education.
If you're waiting for
my permission, don't.
What the fuck?
Eliot, Heloise just
turned into a rat!
What was that?
I'm not getting
laid tonight, am I?
This is all of them?
We can't be sure.
So many people have vanished,
and there are so many
rats in the castle already.
Well, one of them has to be Fen.
Okay, bottom-line it for me,
what the fuck is going on?
I'm sorry, Your Highness, but,
this magic, I've never seen it before.
Abigail? If you can
hear me, squeak.
Let me know you're okay.
Why didn't I study how
to speak rat in school?
Okay. Search the
castle. Find every rat.
And then council meeting,
or what's left of the council.
What do we call that? Mmm.
In-sex-tion?
Inter-cepti-course?
Incepti-sex?
"Incepti-sex."
I like that.
That said, I like
real life better.
Mmm.
But at least, this way, we
don't have to get up for beers.
Thank you.
So no pressure,
but any word on the Poison Room?
Believe me, I wanna get in
there. It's above my pay grade.
I need a code to get in.
Well, what about that Librarian?
Oh, man, if she has the code, it is
locked down tighter than a nun's pussy.
Right, of course it is.
Hey, does she
have a book of her?
Everyone has a book.
You're thinking...
I mean, if the room
is that important...
It's in her book.
Okay.
I can work on that.
Hey, what's up with the senator?
He went back to work.
He made up some bullshit
excuse about the kidnapping.
All the news outlets bought it.
But hey, get this.
I saw Reynard in the
back of a press photo
in a suit, like an
advisor or something.
Are you kidding me?
He's a trickster.
Guess that includes his own son.
Jesus Christ.
We can't get one more vote?
We're in touch with
Matthews, Bauer, Wheeler.
Just give them a couple days.
They'll come to their senses.
Call in Senator Cowden.
Why bother? He won't budge.
We can change his mind.
Trust me. How?
Everyone, give us a minute.
So they're taking
your orders now?
Have been for a while.
I controlled their minds,
just like you have
many, many times.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You know you have that power.
You've been using
it your whole life.
I always thought I had some
kind of god-level good luck.
True, you've only used it
instinctively, but I'm here now.
I can teach you how
to use it at will. Easy.
And once you've mastered it,
that's how you
get Cowden's vote.
I don't know that I wanna
do that. It feels like cheating.
They all don't cheat?
Everyone uses whatever
they've got, John,
and the bad ones don't hesitate.
So someone like you,
someone who wants to do
some actual good in the world,
how can you not?
Here's all you have to do.
Look at me.
You look him straight in
the eye, and you tell him,
plainly, directly.
That's it?
It's that simple.
Good luck with the
meeting, Senator.
Why would anyone
want their afterlife
to look like a terrible
middle-school birthday party?
Is this about your incident?
I've moved on. Have you?
Julia? Julia!
Julia! Oh, my God! Welcome!
Julia! Welcome!
Where's Bender? Is he okay?
He's great. He moved on.
Uh, who's your friend,
and what's his shoe size?
We're not really here to bowl.
Kid, the first rule of being
dead. If you're here, you bowl.
We're actually not dead, either.
Uh, we're here because
we need your help.
Julia?
What?
Nothing. It's good to see
you, Richard. The real you.
The real me? What happened?
I need your help. I
need to find my Shade.
Okay.
The Underworld is massive.
There's every ecosystem.
Nearest we can tell,
about 2,000 islands
built to look like Hawaii.
And you went with
the bowling alley?
And the powers that
be are into whatever
helps us settle in, so
that we can move on.
Yeah!
Yes! JULIA: Powers that be?
Yeah, gods. We were
right about them being real.
Hades created the Underworld,
runs it with his wife, Persephone.
They live in a big
house way over here.
It's a beautiful
area called Elysium.
Apparently, they used to
come and go like clockwork,
every fall and spring,
but, a while back,
they just disappeared.
Wait. Why are you
doing all this, Richard?
I know you. This is a project.
I'm trying to find my son.
I don't know where he
is, if he's even still here,
but he's got to be somewhere,
and they won't tell
me a damn thing.
Why not?
I'm flagged as
culpable in his death.
There are rules.
And friends to
help me break them.
Okay, so wait. So where
do they keep the Shades?
Sorry, we don't know that yet.
So we're flying blind?
Hon, you're gonna have to bowl.
No, look, I had an incident when I
was a kid. My fingers got stuck and...
Oh, get over it.
Your girl would.
She's not my girl.
No shit. She's tough as granite,
and you're afraid to bowl.
Fine.
How long before the
dragon eats you and Quentin?
Tomorrow morning.
Always the one to tell the
impossible to go fuck itself, huh?
Yeah, well, it
doesn't always listen.
They'll know where the
Shades are kept at reception.
I don't know. They
didn't seem too keen
on helping out a person
who looked like this.
Shit.
It seems to be closing
up much faster down here.
Okay, so we hurry, but
just... Not for nothing,
reception isn't keen to
help much of anyone.
I can't count the number of
times I've been kicked out of there,
trying to find my little boy.
Whoo! I have an idea.
Oh, my God.
Julia! I got a strike.
Yeah, Q!
The thing about the
Underworld is, the first week,
it's always a strike.
Let him have this one.
Whoo! Go, Q!
You wanted to talk?
You lying son of a bitch.
You turned Fen into a rat
along with half the castle.
Fen is in her human
form in the Fairy Realm,
and she was taken because you
tried to get clever with our deal.
So you turn half my
staff into snake food?
That wasn't the Fairies. Huh.
Well, it sure smells like
their whimsical bullshit.
"Whimsical"?
It's the mark of the
stupid and the arrogant
to attack what you
can't comprehend.
Fine.
Get it out of your system.
Then, if you know what's
going on, just tell me.
I take it back. You're
not entirely simpleminded.
There's another power which you've
made the mistake of overlooking.
You wanna be specific or not?
A power without logic.
A power that acts, not for
gain but solely because it can.
That's the true danger.
Face that, or face the
end of your kingdom.
Uh, hey!
I got a question for you.
Of course. How can I help?
You know, I never got your name.
You may call me Head Librarian.
And, uh, what do I get to
call you outside of work?
I see what you're getting at.
But intra-office courtship
is expressly prohibited.
I'm flattered, but
rules are rules.
Are they?
Always?
Penny, please don't take it
personally, but you're not my type.
You're a touch
emotionally insecure,
for which you compensate heavily
with boisterousness
and foul language.
I'm here if you
need anything else.
Hey, guys!
Mr. Corrigan. Mr. Corrigan,
you have no need to be in here.
Just a couple of questions.
I'm gonna take a number.
Please, sir.
You know what? I'm gonna
take a couple of numbers
just in case I don't
hear the first number.
Yeah, wow, you guys
got a lot of numbers.
Now, Mr. Corrigan,
I beseech you.
No. Does this thing
run out of numbers?
There we go. Play time
is over, Mr. Corrigan.
I'm not playing. I
really have questions.
Quite the jokester, you are.
That is it. Look, security!
Don't call security, Thomas.
Security! Oh, no! Security.
They're on their way.
No, no, no. I'm just
getting a number here.
Ha-ha. Very funny, Mr. Corrigan.
Does this thing
run out of numbers?
It's locked.
"Disconnected Shade." Where?
It doesn't say. Just says, "E."
Here's another one.
"Disconnected Shade, E."
"E." They all say "E."
Elysium. Yes.
Okay, great, the complete
opposite end of the Underworld.
Guys, I'm just... Take him
away for disciplinary processing.
Thank you. There's
no need, guys.
Okay, you got me.
Hope you had some fun to
make your confinement worthwhile.
Aw, what's a few
weeks out of eternity?
This is books, for school kids.
If it's so important, finding
me that $5 mil can't be too hard.
I'm not adding
another amendment.
You invited me in. You knew
what you were getting into.
Right.
You're going to
support this bill.
In fact, your "yes" will
be the first vote cast.
John, this bill should have
been passed a long time ago.
And I'm sorry for trying to
drag you into the ditch on this.
You have my vote.
And I thank you for your help.
You all right?
Let me get you some water.
I must've stood up too fast.
Here you go.
I need a minute.
Becca. Becca! Get the
doctor. Get the doctor, now!
John, I'm sorry,
but I think you're
overestimating yourself here.
No, honey, I am
being 100% literal.
I am not human, Cindy.
And I know it sounds
ridiculous, but it is true.
Okay. I think that you have
been working too hard...
No, I haven't. I haven't.
I am telling you the truth
because you are the one I trust.
You are the only one, really.
And I really just need your
support right now, babe.
Of course, honey.
I apologize.
I know that you
always find a way
to do the right thing,
and I am here for you,
whatever you need.
Now, come on, let's go home.
It's like a Shade orphanage.
We should hurry. We're running
out of time. We should split up.
I kind of have a thing about splitting
up in houses full of creepy kids.
Hey, can we ask you a question?
Sure.
What was that that you
just did with the money?
For the little boy?
What little boy? The little
boy with the shitty dad.
He ran away, and now
he's cold and hungry.
He'll find it on the
sidewalk any minute.
And that's...
She's in a hospital room.
She's making them bloom.
It's a really obvious
miracle, but that's okay.
The girl in the room
is gonna die anyways.
So you're all making miracles?
Just little tiny ones, though.
Cool. Um...
We were looking for a
Shade. Her name's Julia.
Yeah. She looks
like her, kind of.
And... Well, she's
a... She's a mess.
We all were when we got here.
Anything else? Um...
She's brave and funny,
and she probably made
friends with some of the
most shy, maladjusted Shades.
She's curious, and she
won't take "no" for an answer.
Are you looking for
the kind of new one
who's always getting in trouble
and sneaking into Ms.
Persephone's room?
Because, you know, we're never
supposed to go in there.
Yeah. Yeah, that
does sound like her.
I just saw her. This way.
Up those stairs, last door.
Eugene? Yeah?
Who's that?
That's Ms. Persephone.
She hasn't been here for a really long
time, and no one knows where she is.
Thank you so much
for all your help.
That's Our Lady Underground.
What? The one that you...
So you were real all along, huh?
Just completely AWOL.
Self-centered bitch.
We were so stupid to love you.
Jules, I'm sorry.
For what?
Look, I'm glad I know.
It's always better to
know, Q. You keep watch.
I'm gonna sneak in and find the
part of me that already snuck in.
Hmm.
We're under attack.
The Rattening. Now
reports of upside down rain?
Correct. As well as
anthills turning to volcanoes,
the Balmy Sea turning to acid,
and the mysterious disappearance
of all blondes in the
province of Crickety Cove.
The talking-animals report.
This includes palomino horses.
Also, every chicken
in Fillory has laryngitis.
Is there a pattern
to any of this?
None that we can tell. Only
that whatever it is, it is increasing.
Idri's turned into a rat,
so it isn't the Lorians.
We've incapacitated
the FU Fighters.
That leaves the
people in this room.
Your Highness?
If anyone has anything to say...
I'm embezzling funds
from the royal treasury.
Why did I just say that? Ha!
Because there's truth
serum in this wine.
I've truthied you.
Anyone else?
Abigail and I have been using the
castle guards to run an escort service.
Gross.
Clever.
Doesn't help us.
Should have made this stronger.
It was me.
I made a deal with the Fairies,
and I know where Fen is.
You've got to be kidding me.
It's not your break.
So, what, you, uh,
gonna report me?
Answer a question,
maybe I'll forget to.
What's your question?
You trying to fuck
that Librarian?
No.
I saw you.
You wanna fuck her. You
wanna lick her butthole, huh?
Oh, Jesus, no!
Then why are you scamming
her so hard that I nearly blew you?
I just need her name. Okay?
Oh, why didn't you ask? Here.
The "S" stands for "Shot,"
or maybe it's "Schiff."
Let me know if you find
anything gross in her book.
I have a feeling she's
a total freak in the sack.
Okay, what's your deal?
I have no deal. You're a child.
Okay, grandpa,
that's a little bit...
What are you even
doing stuck here?
What do they have on you?
Nothing.
Okay, fine. They're
protecting me.
Protecting you from what?
My dad is a businessman,
and sometimes, his
competition can get a little rough,
so he sent me here.
Like, he's a...
Legitimate businessman.
Can we please not talk about it?
My God, you're like that whiny
little kid in The Sopranos. Willow.
Jesus Christ! You
are so lame. Please.
And her name was Meadow.
You truthied me.
I can't lie.
Eliot, I did this for you.
There was no other way.
Don't.
You started this when
you declared war.
Now, my wife and child are gone.
I need to deal with the rats.
I can't risk having to
clean up your next mess.
Guards.
No, Eliot, what are you doing?
I don't know what else to do.
Take her to the dungeon. No!
Eliot.
I'll fix this.
Make sure she
gets the best room.
And see that she
gets her coconut oil.
Goodbye, Margo.
Oh, shit!
I know you're in there.
Come out.
It's okay.
It's me.
Oh, my God.
Julia, I found her. She's...
Quentin.
I missed you so much.
Oh, my God.
Hi.
Are you okay?
Yeah. Are you?
Not really,
without you.
Did you get Reynard yet?
I'm trying.
I missed you, too. I can't...
She talks about
him all the time.
Says he's a good guy.
Stupid sometimes, but good.
Is there any way we
can take her with us, too?
I know you told
security to keep me out,
but then I suggested
they let me in.
Stalemate, I guess.
Is this about Cowden?
I think you just
overwhelmed him a little.
I know it's a lot,
but it's worth it.
My wife.
Is anything about
our relationship real?
I've been controlling her
from the day we met, right?
Yes. Lucky her.
How is that?
She's a person.
Yes, and you're not.
The sooner you wrap
your head around that...
No. No.
I don't want it.
You want to be President
of this entire idiotic country.
You have always
sensed your place.
Julia and Kady,
they said you
did terrible things.
I should have looked
you up on the spot.
You didn't because I
gently suggested you don't.
It's for your own good, kid.
So it's all true.
Those poor women...
Those women were hardly victims.
They said they were
just trying to summon
a little help from
some kind of goddess.
They were summoning
an evil bitch.
You looked me up?
Says "Trickster"?
See, that's honest.
Yes, I fuck with the weak.
You know what that
does? Improves the herd.
I help the same little
creatures you want to help.
It's not surprising. You're
my son. How else could it be?
But her, the benevolent
Our Lady Underground?
Oh, it is all about her.
Power, attention,
grinding men and gods
into the fucking dirt,
and then she leaves.
You loved her.
Guess there are some
things you can't control after all.
I can see you're upset,
but I need you
to move past that.
Stop worrying about
humans. They're beneath you.
This is your birthright, son.
We're gonna do so much together.
How'd you do it? You
know, turn me back?
A special Fillorian mint.
About 50 straight
minutes of casting,
so I'm gonna need
a minute to recharge.
You're sure you don't
want any clothes or... Mmm.
Can't you get Margo to help,
you know, give you a break?
I kind of threw
her in the dungeon.
Got you.
Well, you'll run yourself dead
doing everything on your own.
Believe me, I know.
Pass some shit down the chain,
to the governors or
the dukes or whatever.
You don't have any governors?
No dukes?
Get you some delegates, son!
Right. Really good idea.
Select governors.
Yet another task
for the High King.
Or you just hold an election.
Let the people pick
their own. You do nada.
That's... Stupid? Is
it stupid? I'm sorry.
Brilliant. Josh, I think you
just invented democracy,
and it's going to save Fillory.
Well, high five, brother!
Eliot?
What the hell?
Dude,
I thought you were off being,
like, the High King of Fillory.
I am.
I was.
I think I just got kicked out.
Of course. Her book is
relocated to the Poison Room.
Okay.
So what's our next move?
Admit I'm fucking cursed?
Is this all you guys do?
You talk about your fee-fees?
I was kind of hoping
you'd get to fucking.
What?
How did you...
Oh, I hopped into your mind
when you hopped into hers.
It's a little trick my
dad's friends taught me.
Your dad's friends are perverts?
Thugs. Magic mobsters.
No, they're not. Jesus.
Which is why I'm
leaving. So's Willow.
Meadow, doofus.
Fine, kick me out,
if you really don't
need my help.
Help with what?
Trying to break into
the Poison Room.
I've been in your
crappy Nolan movie
for, like, 20 minutes.
I heard everything.
I've been trying to
get in there myself
'cause, you know, I'm
curious about a few things.
So either you start from
square one on your own,
or you can hop
the line and join...
The pervy mob
girl has a point. No.
It's dangerous. You
know what's safe?
Nothing.
You're not responsible
for me, okay?
Free will. I exercise that shit.
I'm gonna hate this.
You hate everything.
It's why I like you.
Kady. Kady. Kady, wake up.
Kady. Hey.
What?
Hey, you got a guest.
Professor Lipson told
me to bring him here.
If you're still after
Reynard, I want in.
Eliot?
Oh, you.
I shouldn't be here, but...
Please, Your
Majesty, be careful.
So not a nice Scotch, then.
It will transport you
to the Fairy Realm.
I must warn you, few return.
But if there's a chance
to save Fen, the baby...
I would go, but...
You're a pussy, who's in love
with a sloth who's currently a rat,
and, end of the day,
it's my mess to clean up.
Tell Eliot that.
Q, it's time.
This is it. It's why I couldn't
make the math work.
What math? The spell
to bring Alice back.
I knew something was
missing. I just didn't know...
It was me.
You have to go now.
There's a portal in
there, back to reception.
And I'm glad we
got to say goodbye.
I'm gonna be back
here for good one day,
and I am going to find you.
Okay.
You first.
Jules, what the hell?
This isn't up for debate.
We came here
so that you could...
Yeah. So? Things change.
If you do this... I know.
This is my one shot, and
this is what I want to do with it.
I found them! Stop!
Come on, or we'll lose her, too.
You can't take that Shade.
You, stop!
It's all going to
be okay, Quentin.