QUENTIN: Previously
on The Magicians...
JULIA: Q, I think this is it.
The Tale of the Seven Keys.
Jules, this is our quest.
Was there always a
keyhole right there?
The eye can never be fixed.
But you can't spy on me anymore.
You have a week's
sail back to Whitespire
to think about what you've done.
Alice!
I'm sorry. You
called me too late.
No, no, no, no,
no, no, no. He can't.
No, come on, Pen.
Don't, don't, come on.
(SOBS) No. Shit.
What the fuck is happening?
We have to do something.
Do something!
Kady.
Kady, he's gone.
KADY: No.
Kady. Kady, I'm right...
You need to hear me.
I was astral projecting.
I wasn't in my body
when I died... It died.
Damn it!
Damn it.
(YELLS)
(THUDS) Damn it!
JULIA: Q. Hey.
Hey, I... What's wrong?
Um... It's... It's Penny.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, come on.
I'm sorry. Do you
ever have, like,
an inappropriate emotional
response that you just can't...
Um...
Why is nobody crying?
I saved all your
asses so many times.
Appreciate me!
Well, I suppose someone
should say some words.
Yes?
QUENTIN: Okay, um, yeah.
We're here today
to remember the life
of a friend and student.
William Penny Adi...
Adi, uh...
I don't really know how to
pronounce his last name.
It's Adiyodi. Idiot.
QUENTIN: Penny was complicated.
And I think he
probably hated me.
But, um...
None of us really knew him.
Not even me.
That's how he wanted it.
So, uh...
All I can really say is, uh...
I am so screwed.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Okay, come on.
Damn it.
Yo.
SHEP: Bodi, you down there?
Shep!
I found one of them
soft ones you like.
Don't burn it.
Oh. The vellum
feels nice on my ass.
No, no, no, no, no. I need that.
I got a surprise for you, too.
Fresh meat upstairs.
What's it been?
Two weeks since we
caught the librarian?
Not much left but gristle.
You ate a librarian?
Hi, there.
Eliot? Hello, kind strangers.
We were hoping to warm
ourselves by your fire.
That's a bad move, Eliot.
What brought you
to the Neitherlands?
Family vacation.
No, I mean...
We got here using magic beans.
We used a magic
key. ELIOT: Right.
But there's no magic
now, so, um, we're stuck.
Like you? That's right.
Fountains are all frozen over.
We haven't eaten in days.
ELIOT: Right. Um...
If you had an extra
sandwich or something...
No. No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Have a seat. (SIGHS) Thank you.
No, no, no. No, Eliot, don't!
They're cannibals!
Oh, God.
Thank you. PENNY:
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
No, that's... Don't eat that.
No, don't eat that, please.
You're eating a dude!
Mmm. It's not bad.
Man, seriously, fuck this place!
I can't believe that he's gone.
I mean, we were
never really that close.
But I don't know, I...
I loved him, I think.
It's just... How come
you never really know
how much you care about
somebody until they're gone?
I remember he used to let me
ride around on his shoulders.
What?
I loved that.
Were you close with your dad?
Oh.
For fuck's sake.
QUENTIN: I saw
him a few weeks ago.
It's crazy. Um...
The cancer that
he had was sort of
inherently magical,
so magic went away, and...
He's, like, in remission.
Sorry. I didn't mean to, uh...
No, it's good. It's good.
It's the one good thing
to come out of this.
I didn't know when I
was gonna see you again.
I had nowhere else to go.
After the burial, I can't be in
the same room as my mom.
I mean, we could use your help.
Finding these keys,
bringing magic back...
Honestly, I don't
think we should.
Okay, I don't really know
where to begin with that.
But, I mean, for
starters, I mean,
this is... This is our quest.
I sort of feel like
we were elected.
It's magic. Jesus, Alice, I...
You turn it back on, what
happens to your dad?
(EXHALES) Sometimes
I want magic back
more than anything.
And sometimes I just...
I look around and see
what a mess we made with it.
Right now I just wanna be 23,
and not know what I want,
and not know what I'm doing.
Yeah.
Oh, God.
I just remembered,
I have to tell
Eliot and Margo about Penny.
How? Aren't they in Fillory?
(MOUTHING)
What are you doing?
That was super weird.
PICKWICK: Your
Majesty, if you would prefer,
we can put into harbor
at Broken Bay instead.
When did you get
this sweet boat?
Man.
I miss all the cool shit.
MARGO: We don't have a choice.
If we sail anywhere
other than Whitespire,
the Fairy Queen will fly in
on the back of some
whimsical animal,
and she'll slit our
throats, or worse.
A messenger bunny, Your Majesty.
Penny's dead. Sorry.
Penny's dead?
Was he not already?
What?
I can't believe it.
PENNY: Thank you.
Finally!
He was my best friend.
Okay, I mean, all right.
I guess I always thought
someday we were gonna bang.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
Me, too, girl. Me, too.
You know, I... I thought
we'd have normal problems.
Like, I'd look at other
girls, and you'd get mad.
Or you'd tell me a
story for the third time,
and we'd realize we
have nothing left to say.
But we don't get
normal problems.
I know what you're
looking for. Don't.
This is stupid.
What do you think
this is gonna solve?
You can't hear a word I say.
There is no point in me staying
here and watching you suffer
if I can't do a damn
thing about it, so...
I'm gonna go.
Try and find some
way to fix this.
Goodbye, Kady.
Julia. (GASPS)
Help her. Now.
What? The hell?
You're the only one who can.
What? What happened?
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Oh, fuck.
Jesus. Kady!
Kady, come on!
Um...
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
Kady...
Come on!
Come on. Please, Kady.
Wake up. (GASPS)
Okay. Okay.
Okay, baby.
Okay.
Holy shit, that was gross.
What?
You can see me?
Hey, what's your deal?
(CHUCKLES) Sorry.
It's just, you're talking to me,
and not through me,
and that's kind of huge, Penny.
How do you know my name?
Well, I've been watching you
and your friends
since you got here.
I'm Hyman. Cooper.
Hyman? Mmm-hmm.
Did that mean something
different when you were born?
Wait, you haven't heard of me?
The Pervert Ghost of Brakebills?
I was a student
here in the 1920s.
A Traveler, like you.
I would practice astral
projection around the campus.
You know, pop into
lectures, the dormitories,
showers, you know how it is.
Uh... No. And as a prank,
someone moved
my body while I was...
Being a fucking pervert.
And, yes, in their defense, I
was given several warnings.
But I never found my body.
You can't cast a locator spell
without actual fingers, so...
It must have died
without me in it.
That's a bummer.
Well, joke's on them.
'Cause now I'm a ghost.
So it's all peeping,
all the time.
You know you're
not a ghost, right?
Wha... I'm not?
You were on the astral
plane when you died.
So was I.
Our minds were traveling.
Now they have no
place to go back to.
Look, ghosts have some
unresolved shit in this world,
so they relive their
death over and over.
Are you doing that?
People can see ghosts.
Ghosts can touch things.
I know, 'cause I've been
touched by a ghost, Hyman,
and it wasn't great.
We can't do that.
Okay, Professor, then how come
I can sit in a chair?
Why am I not
just falling forever?
I don't know. I
don't make the rules.
Your ass just knows.
Look, didn't you
figure all this shit out
100 years ago when you died?
I mean, haven't you
communicated with anyone?
I mean, tried to get a message
out that you're alive-ish?
Believe me, I tried everything.
For years.
It did not end well.
(DOOR OPENS)
What do you
mean, it didn't end...
Shh. Shut up.
Shut up.
JULIA: Hey. Hey.
How's Kady?
Sleeping it off
in the infirmary.
How did you know to
knock down her door?
Just a feeling. Okay.
They're my favorite pairing.
The tension between them.
Friends for years, but
he's always loved her.
You're in a bit of a
research K-Hole here.
Yeah. It's cool.
It just reminds me of me.
QUENTIN: So, the second
key... So, the knight's daughter,
she found it in a sentient cave
that just kept
asking her riddles,
and wouldn't let her in
until it deemed her worthy.
It was very patronizing. Wait.
Why does that sound familiar?
Because Rupert Chatwin
found the same cave
in the first Fillory book,
The World in the Walls.
He was being chased by
a belligerent cassowary.
I remember. Right. Um...
So he finds this
mountain of treasure,
but only takes one item.
A golden key.
To bring to his friend.
Right, that he
met during the war.
So, look, if this story is real,
and he actually
did give him the key,
then I... I...
Jules, I think the
key is here on Earth.
(CHUCKLES)
Seriously?
These two?
You and Kady are great.
I totally ship that.
Alice is okay.
She's a bit of a Mrs. Grundy.
You know? I don't
get that reference.
Oh, Josh is my idol.
That man is a Vagician.
But Quentin, I mean,
the outsider let into the inner
sanctum of secret knowledge.
As someone born in 1902,
I find a heterosexual white
male hero very relatable.
Anyway, Quentin
is the duck's nuts.
No, that cannot be a
real thing people said.
So we should send
a message to Eliot.
Shit. Eliot.
Oh, my God.
(PANTING)
Cannibals! They're cannibals!
I told you!
Oh, my God.
They made me
eat a person.
We should make a deal with them.
No.
You can't negotiate
with cannibals.
You can't give
them what they want.
Well, can't we? No!
You're grounded.
We need to find
a way out of here.
On the Muntjac, the
key created the door
out of nowhere
when we needed it.
I don't see any doors or
places a door could be.
Downstairs in the Library!
You lied about the key.
They lied first.
I couldn't risk them
taking the key from us.
No, you lied to me.
You were never collecting taxes.
Uh, can we have this talk
when we're not being hunted
by cannibals?
What is the key for?
Fray! What does it really do?
It doesn't fucking matter
if we can't find a door.
Wait, there are doors all over
the downstairs of the Library.
No shit!
I think, there are cannibals
sitting on the only entry point.
Wait, they're coming!
Run, run, run!
Slow down! I have wooden toes!
Go, go, go, go, go, go.
Hyman, where have you been?
I went with them
to solve the mystery
of Rupert's golden key.
Who cares?
If they find all
seven keys, Penny,
then...
Something good happens?
I missed a bit.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
So the seven keys
from the story unlock magic?
Oh, that's...
We think that Rupert Chatwin
brought one back to Earth
and gave it to an American
soldier that he served with
in World War II.
His name was Lance Morrison.
And it turns out
that after the war,
Lance went to a magic school.
Brakebills. JULIA: Right.
So if there are any
records from the late 1940s,
maybe that can
help us find the key.
My assistant's file
cabinet, bottom drawer.
Thank you.
Pardon the interruption.
Can I help you?
Wait a minute. I know that guy.
I certainly hope you can.
I'm here on behalf of The Order.
At the Library formerly
headquartered in the Neitherlands?
We need to talk about Penny.
Sorry to be blunt,
but did Penny die
a traumatic death?
Dean Fogg said you
were the one to ask.
Yes, it was traumatic.
That explains it.
Penny signed a
contract with The Order,
guaranteeing his
services in this life
and, well, beyond.
Curiously, his soul
never reported for service
to our Underworld branch.
Then where is he?
I'm right here.
Likely in the process of
becoming a vengeful spirit.
Best to nip that in the
bud before his time is up.
What do you mean?
The soul is tethered to the body
for seven days after death.
We can use that tether to yank
Penny's soul out from wherever
and send him on his way.
How? Eat him, naturally.
(CHUCKLES) Sweetheart,
I'm not gonna eat him.
I'm a pescatarian.
The Order has retained
the services of a corpse eater
for situations such as this.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, no
one is eating my body, okay?
I'm not fucking
done with it yet.
Kind of a ticking clock on this.
If the tether goes before
Penny's soul passes on,
he's right fucked.
The corpse eater
needs a tick to prepare.
She'll be here
tomorrow at sundown.
Oh, and you're welcome.
The ghost children at the
Plover house couldn't be saved.
But Penny still has his tether.
I'm not a ghost!
KADY: If he's a
ghost, shouldn't he be,
I don't... I don't
know, haunting us?
What if something else happened?
Yes, something else did happen!
ALICE: It can take decades
for a spirit to become malevolent.
Corpse eaters
are a rare creature.
If the Librarians
actually have one,
not just some sicko
who wants a free meal,
you should use it.
But what if there's
a way to fix him?
To bring him back?
ALICE: Without magic?
Julia has magic.
Okay, not much, but I...
It's just, I... I... I can't
wrap my head around
sending him to work for
the Library for a billion years.
I don't trust them.
There you go. Come on, Kady.
The Underworld's not so bad.
Quentin says there's
a bowling alley.
And a billion years surrounded
by books sounds like Heaven.
PENNY: Damn it, Alice.
I thought we were bros.
Ah. Let go, let go, let go!
My God!
I was only trying
to follow the story.
No, what Julia does
in the bath is not story!
It is revealing of character.
Listen, I need to talk
to Kady somehow today.
Okay?
Now, I don't give a
shit if it didn't end well
for you in the past. You
are going to help me.
Or I will cock block
you for the rest of time.
Okay.
When I first got stuck
in the Astral Plane,
I spent months
trying to push things.
I never got anywhere.
Until I tried being the thing.
Uh...
(EXHALES)
Okay, focus on a penny.
(LAUGHS)
Get it? 'Cause of
your name? You get it.
Now, you're not gonna
try to move the penny.
You're gonna try to be it.
So pour yourself into its shape.
Inhabit it with
your whole being.
Hmm?
Go ahead.
Be the penny. Okay.
I got this.
Be the penny.
Just be the goddamn penny!
Penny, just be it! (STUTTERS)
What does that even mean?
You're getting confused
by the whole Penny thing.
Maybe we should have
started with a nickel.
Wha... Huh? Be the nickel!
Maybe you shouldn't
say the same dumb shit
over and over!
Oh, I'm sorry, but
you're a dullard!
A real dunce, I say!
You are worth less than a penny,
and a penny is worthless!
(SCREAMS)
Um...
PENNY: This is weird.
(GASPS) You are the penny.
What do I do now? I can't move.
Well, how could you?
You don't have any feet.
(PENNY GRUNTS)
What are you...
What are you doing?
It sounds like you're pooping.
Holy zerts! You
did it! (CHUCKLES)
(GAGGING) Oh.
I still have the taste of
pennies in my mouth.
Wait, why... Why don't I...
Why don't I just project
myself into my own body?
I know how to be that.
The only reason
you're still alive
is because you were astral
projecting when you died.
So if you go back
into your corpse,
you'll just be dead.
I need something bigger.
I need something that can talk.
Yeah, hey, be careful.
Controlling things with
brains is much harder.
PENNY: Be the bunny.
(EXHALES) Be the bunny.
Be the bunny.
MARGO: It won't work.
Fairy Queen bitch
thinks she can break me
with a few days' time
out on Eliot's party boat?
Your Majesty, upon
our return to Whitespire,
might I suggest a hot
bath to relax yourself?
I can't, because that chalky
twat won't get out of my tub.
I keep waiting for
Eliot to come back.
But maybe he never will.
That bunny I sent him
was returned to sender.
For all I know, he's dead.
And him and Penny are
blowing each other in Heaven.
Now, when I get back...
I'm gonna fix this.
Benedict, you're gonna
round up the guards.
Tick, you're gonna go to
that fairy-repelling hallway
and you're gonna grind
one of those bricks to dust.
You're gonna put it in
the Fairy Queen's bath
and when that
knocks her on her ass,
I'm gonna cut out
her heart and eat it
in front of every goddamn
fairy asshole in the kingdom.
Damn. Girl, you get shit done.
(GROANS)
And I thought Hyman was a perv.
Be the Margolem.
Uh, um... Um, announcement.
You guys remember the Margolem?
Margo's doppelganger
made of living clay?
Since Margo's been
gone, I've been storing it.
You know, for safekeeping?
Ew. That's problematic.
TODD: It's not like that.
I just dress her up and
pretend she respects me.
Anyways, she's been out of
commission since magic died,
only... (MARGOLEM GROANS)
She woke up.
Fuck.
(GROWLS)
(QUENTIN YELLS)
(GROANS)
(BOTH YELLING)
I told you it wouldn't end well.
You know, I wish
you weren't dead
so I could kill you.
DEAN: So, this
Margolem must've had
some residual magic left in her.
Or the living clay she was
made of was a magical creature?
Uh, anyway, while
we have you here,
we found Lance
Morrison's Brakebill records.
Um... It says that he was
only a student for a semester.
But it also says in
this file that he left
because of a "code seven."
Student suicide.
Or he magically exploded.
I don't know why they use
the same damn code for both.
Okay, either way,
he died on campus.
So the key might
still be here, right?
But it says he was
living in the West Dorm,
and there is no
such thing, so...
That's because it's buried.
Oh, no. No, no, no, no.
DEAN: In the late 1940s,
there was a haunting
in the West Dorm.
At the time, it was
considered bad form
to have a ghost on campus.
Unlike today, where we put
it in the goddamn brochure.
"That ghost" is gonna kill them.
To death, Penny.
So, the Dean buried
the whole dorm.
Magically protected
the entrances
so that students
couldn't find it.
But magic is gone.
So we can walk right in.
Right?
What are you gonna do?
Nothing.
It's not my problem.
They're your friends.
Who I can't help in any way.
You go figure some shit out.
(SCOFFS) I'm not
going down there.
What are you scared of?
You're dead already.
You're so dumb, Penny.
Ghosts can hurt
whatever it is we are.
That one in the West dorm?
Terrorized me for a week.
Wait a minute.
If they can hurt us, then...
Then they can see us.
Hey. Q.
(DOOR CREAKS)
All right.
Um... Excuse me.
Lance Morrison?
Who are you?
Did my father send you?
You can tell him I am not
coming home for winter.
PENNY: Hey, ghost boy.
We need to talk.
You need to tell them that
Penny is in the room with them.
What are you talking about?
No, I am not a bitch!
Well, we don't think
that. Right, no, of course.
Do you know anything
about a golden key
that maybe your friend
Rupert Chatwin gave you?
Rupert?
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
This place is quite something.
Nothing compared
to where you've been.
He's in a ghost loop.
He's not even listening to us.
I brought you something.
From Fillory. Here.
Take it.
It won't hurt.
It just reveals the
honest truth of things.
Shows them as they truly are.
I see.
(CHUCKLES) Damn it, Hyman.
This isn't terrifying. It's
just two dudes kissing.
You homophobic pussy.
Lance Morrison.
You've been speaking out of turn
about your mother's family.
You have sullied
the McAllistair name.
LANCE: All I did
was tell the truth.
Truth can bury us.
It's the key.
It's ruined everything.
Hi, I'm sorry to interrupt
this little father-son moment,
but could someone
please just say the words,
"Penny is in the room"?
Say it isn't true. Okay.
You can't control yourself.
Don't blame the key
for your perversion.
Whoa, dude!
Whoa!
(CHOKES)
(SOFTLY) The key's
in the dad's pocket.
I think he just...
Oh, shit.
(GRUNTS)
I tried being nice.
You will say my name.
You say my name, you ghost dick!
What is your name?
That's not a name!
No, it isn't!
Uh, Q?
I think we might
have broken this ride.
No!
(SIGNING)
The Library has a corpse eater
that can help take
him to the Underworld.
What's she saying?
What... What...
Fuck, stop signing!
(OUT LOUD) Burn his
body. KADY: Burn his body?
Oh, hell no.
Then he'll be stuck
there for eternity,
turning into a ghost, or worse.
KADY: She says,
"Better than a slave
"to the people who killed him.
"For a billion years."
Am I the only one
that knows that eternity
is a lot longer
than a billion years?
(GROANS)
Lance said his mom
was a McAllistair.
Well, that would explain
how he got into Brakebills.
The McAllistairs are
on the board of trustees.
They're one of the oldest
magical families in America.
Lance's father held the key.
I mean, he knew
how powerful it was.
That it would reveal truth.
It would show things
that were hidden.
So, he would have kept it.
Except that he would
have died by now, so...
Wait, could you get
us into that house?
Maybe.
Irene McAllistair's been
calling me every day
looking for a lead on the magic.
Perhaps if we could
give her something
that she really wants...
Hey, have you been paying
attention to Quentin's stupid key thing?
Have I? Yeah, great, shut up.
The ghost said it has
the power to reveal things
that are hidden.
I'm a hidden thing.
(GASPS) Twist.
Okay, tonight it'll be
seven days since I died.
If I don't contact Kady today,
she is either gonna
burn my corpse,
or worse, give
it to the Library.
I'm not getting eaten.
You know, Q said Eliot
already found one of those keys.
Okay, simple plan.
We use the key to make a
Shadow Bat monster illusion
like that priest
did on that island.
We scare away the bad
men, we get to a book chute,
we find a door, and
we get the hell out.
Okay. Okay.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
Please tell me you can see me.
Jesus.
Holy moly.
What have I done?
Eliot, what the hell
are you wearing?
Hi, Dad.
This is your
father? Hi, Grandpa.
What is with everyone and
their daddy issues today?
Dressed like that,
everyone's gonna know
you haven't worked
a day in your life.
It's just an illusion.
I didn't think you could make
a sailor's uniform look gayer.
My God. It's just an illusion.
Eliot, you might be the
only person in the multiverse
more fucked than me.
You're just an illusion.
I wish I could help.
Henry. DEAN: How are you?
(CHUCKLES)
It is so good to see you!
I was so happy when you called.
Yeah. Irene, these
are my students.
Nice to meet you.
It's a pleasure.
Come on in.
Okay, there's some
real Beauty and the Beast
kind of stuff happening here.
I don't understand.
How is that possible?
Well, the house's
enchantments run
on a reserve of energy that
my father built up over decades.
When he was a child,
there was a blackout
that lasted for months.
So he wanted to be prepared.
Please, come. Follow me.
Unfortunately, they won't last.
Most of the enchantments
have failed already.
Which is why I was so
intrigued by your call, Henry.
Would you like a martini?
Martini! (ICE CUBES RATTLE)
Can I get an olive
in mine, please?
Thank you.
So, which one of
you can do magic?
Um...
Well, I, um...
So, before I knew
about magic, real magic,
I... I used to do a lot
of sleight of hand tricks.
So, it turns out that I
wasn't very good at it.
I was cheating, by
using translocation spells
without really knowing it.
I don't know why, but,
um, those tricks still work.
Or you have a squished
olive in your pocket.
(CHUCKLES)
Fascinating.
Not at all useful, but, uh...
I can do more.
Um... Do you have
a deck of cards?
(CLEARS THROAT) Uh, excuse me.
Where's your restroom?
Holy shit.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
I'm sorry, Penny.
It's been six and a half days.
Time's up.
Come on.
Come on, find it!
Come on!
Damn it.
PENNY: Kady, wait.
I just need more time.
ALICE: It's not too late.
Corpse eater will
be here any minute.
Honestly, why do you care?
He was my friend.
He wasn't one of you.
You're right. I
barely knew Penny.
I don't know where he was from,
I don't know about his family,
I don't know... I don't
know how he found magic.
But I know what
it's like to be trapped
and to totally lose control
of yourself and your life.
But in the Underworld,
he still gets to be Penny.
Dammit, Alice, I'm still me.
It took everything I had
to try to save his life.
And then
he died anyway.
And then, I... And
then I was relieved.
To be done.
If Penny was here...
If he could tell us
what he wanted...
But he's not.
Okay, look, they're
both terrible options,
but if I had to choose,
please don't send
me to the Underworld.
I know you don't
want the responsibility.
So don't take it.
Let me.
No, Kady, please.
Be the candle.
I'll go get the corpse eater.
Penny...
That's uncomfortable to hold.
It makes me feel like...
I don't know, like
I'm not really myself.
Okay, then I will
pass on touching it.
Oh, uh... I checked the book.
So, you unlocked chapter three.
Um... And it looks
like the... The next key
might be in Fillory, maybe.
(DOOR OPENS) Um...
(CLEARS THROAT)
Dean Fogg.
Good morning.
Yeah. It is the morning.
Irene sent her apologies.
Our little show did not
convince her last night.
We're out of time.
As of this morning,
the board of directors
put Brakebills up for sale.
The school will be closed.
I'm out of a job.
And I'd say you're evicted,
but I have no idea who
actually owns this building.
Quentin, is this scotch or rye?
Rum. Excellent.
Well, carry on.
I'm going to go lie down.
Well, look at it this way.
Now we've both been
kicked out of Brakebills, so...
We've got that in common.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Holy shit. (BREATHES HEAVILY)
(SIGHS)
Thank Christ. Eliot?
Hey. How did you...
Hey.
ELIOT: Can I please
have some water?
Yeah, sure. Sparkling, please.
Gather 'round.
Story time with Uncle Eliot.
This story is called,
"Eliot did nothing wrong
but was chased by cannibals
"through the befucked
Neitherlands anyway."
Sorry, who's this?
Oh, right, yeah. Meet Fray.
Our daughter.
I'm sorr... Your...
Wait, your daughter?
Please, hold your
questions till the end.
So, the cannibals blocked
our only point of egress.
Naturally, I resolved
to use the key,
which, in Fillory,
created illusions
of a terrifying monster.
He made his father instead.
No spoilers.
But, yeah. What she said.
Turns out the key
creates illusions
of what you most fear.
Hence...
My dad.
I told my father that
the guys in the tent
didn't know the difference
between a tractor
and a backhoe.
So he went to set them straight.
You saying you...
You fed your...
Your dad to cannibals?
An illusion of him. But, yes.
It was very cathartic.
There was lots of
screaming on both sides.
But we snuck right past them.
We found a key, too. Uh...
We've been... We've
been calling it the truth key
'cause it... Well,
it reveals truths.
JULIA: Truths. I can
handle a little truth.
I don't know.
I don't see anything.
Maybe it doesn't work on me.
Oh, hey, Penny.
Wait.