ELIOT: Previously
on The Magicians...
You're not right, El,
and we both know why.
You said you don't
remember what happened
when you were
possessed, but Julia does.
And I don't.
I don't know why you're
accusing me of lying.
MAN: Eliot. Let me out.
We're looking for Stoppard.
Mom? Mom? What's wrong?
Moms die every
day. Circle of life.
We know you're trying
to look out for your mom.
Are you saying you'll leave?
Sorry, man. I'm
not going anywhere.
The Harmonic Convergence.
Mmm. A.K.A. the
end of the world.
The Convergence will only
occur during this perfect alignment.
If we move the
moon out of position...
No Convergence, no
circumstance, no apocalypse.
If you have moon brain,
then you will see her aura.
If it is green,
she is listening.
Only then may you
ask her to move.
You will need a piece of her.
ALICE: Like a moon rock?
In here, boss.
Ladies.
You're moving the
moon? ELIOT: Yeah.
(BOTH SCREAMING)
Uh... Guys.
I think we broke the moon.
NEWS ANCHOR:
NASA estimates just hours
before the first pieces
reach our atmosphere.
In a tweet, the President
stressed the need for calm,
saying, "We will fix
the moon decisively.
"The American people have
absolutely nothing to fear."
(TIMER DINGS)
(MUFFLED HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
I know we are dealing with
the lunapocalypse problem,
but I have to insist
that we all take a minute
for a little
self-care/pizza, okay?
Okay.
Cautioning everyone
that though the world
appears to be coming to an end,
everyone's behavior will still be counted
when the time comes for judgement.
Feeling the wrong
kind of boned right now.
At least the Harmonic Convergence
isn't happening anymore.
I just have this bad feeling.
Hey.
We'll figure out
how to stop this.
(MUFFLED SIREN WAILING)
I mean, on the off-chance
the President doesn't.
Let's review.
Emergency code words
if this all goes shit-shaped.
Um...
Really?
Kidding. Okay.
(CLEARS THROAT)
As follows. Credenza,
no questions asked.
Inglenook, tie those fools up,
toss them through
the Fillory portal.
Chifforobe, flee to Canada.
Armoire, shield up, stat.
Kimono, all hell's broken
loose. All hell's broken loose.
Time and hope are quickly
running out, though rumors about...
Everything I'm seeing says the first
chunk's gonna hit around 10:00 p.m.
We have 12 hours.
Uh, look, what if we created a
massive portal in the atmosphere?
We'd need a specialist, and
the metamath is just... It's too...
This is really bad, Julia.
Uh-uh.
Don't you dare give up.
(SNEEZES)
ALICE: This math is
so damn frustrating.
JULIA: Yeah, but you'll get it.
Jesus. What
happened to your shoe?
Have you been out there? It's
the literal end of the actual world.
No, it's not. We're
gonna stop it.
Tell that to the rioters,
and prayer circles,
and people fucking
in the streets.
I can't believe
this is happening.
I'm just numb.
Try the truffled
prosciutto. It's incredible.
I did have one idea, after my
very bad idea to take the subway.
Okay, do you know Richard's
Reverse Entropy spell?
We already talked about it.
Unfortunately, it's just way too small.
True, but I reworked it.
And check my math.
Mmm... This is fantastic,
but I don't think we have
enough cooperative power.
Chances are high for a surge in
the next 12 hours. We could use it.
And we have enough Hedges around the
world on standby to do it with us. So...
It might not be enough.
Well, we make it enough.
Today, we are saving the world.
And this time, it's gonna stick.
Damn right we are.
Okay.
But just in case...
Anything I need to say to you?
Jules, we're good.
REPORTER: Scientists around the world
have been sending out their predictions
for what we should
expect in the coming hours.
Though the tides remain
mysteriously intact,
expect volcanic
activity, tectonic shifts,
disrupted weather patterns, and
strange behavior from animal life.
And to Sharon Cappanelli
from ninth grade, I lied.
It was my tampon, and
that was your girlfriend.
I'm not sorry. But I want...
Thanks for spreading
the word, Pete.
Stand by.
Everyone's set. We're
just waiting for the surge.
(FAINT HIGH-PITCHED RINGING)
You guys feel that?
It's the surge.
It's cresting. We should...
Go. Pete, now.
(AIR-RAID SIREN WAILING)
Did it work?
(AIR-RAID SIREN
CONTINUES WAILING)
It didn't work.
We failed.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(TIMER DINGS)
(MUFFLED HELICOPTER
WHIRRING) (SIGHS)
Feeling the wrong
kind of boned right now.
At least the Harmonic Convergence
isn't happening anymore.
REPORTER: And though the world's greatest
minds are locked in a desperate race
to save humanity from
this sudden lunar cataclysm,
time and hope are
quickly running out.
Everything I'm seeing says the first
chunk's gonna hit around 10:00 p.m.
We have 12 hours.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
JULIA: Uh, look, what if we created
a massive portal in the atmosphere?
We'd need a specialist, and
the metamath is just... It's too...
This is really bad.
Am I crazy or...
This already happened, right?
(JOSH SNEEZES)
ALICE: This math is
so damn frustrating.
This did. This did
already happen.
Ow!
Not a dream.
Hey. Am I on something, or
did we try this plan yesterday?
Wha... At Westbrook's estate?
(FOOTSTEPS RUNNING)
Jesus.
What happened to
your shoe? (CHUCKLES)
Have you been out there?
It's the literal end
of the actual world.
JULIA: No, it's not.
We're stopping it. Oh.
KADY: Tell that to the
rioters, and prayer circles,
and people fucking in
the streets. (GASPS)
BOTH: We're in a time loop.
Excuse us while
we briefly sidebar.
Why exactly is this happening?
"Why is anything?" he asked,
still freaked, because the last thing
he remembers is all of Earth ending.
It felt so inevitable. I know.
But why us, now, time loop?
Of course we're the
chosen ones. We're us.
Okay, everybody.
What is going on with you two?
Quick recap. Kady's
plan won't work.
We tried it, and the moon
still crashed into the Earth.
Okay. What do
you mean, tried it?
We suspect we're in a time loop.
How?
Obviously, the moon's a wily
cunt who doesn't wanna die.
Okay.
All right, so not
Reverse Entropy.
What do you guys suggest?
We cast Vinnola's
Oxygen Saver on Penny 23.
Then he travels to the moon.
It's easier to do a portal there.
Oh, GPS is kinda broken.
I might end up in a wall.
It's the apocalypse.
Gonna need you to try.
Fuck all of you. Fine.
(BREATHING SHARPLY)
JOSH: You got this, man.
(SNIFFS)
(SQUELCHING) Oh!
Oh, no! No, no, no!
(BOTH SCREAMING)
(SIGHS)
(EXPLOSIONS)
(TIMER DINGS)
(SIGHS)
Okay, forget the moon.
Let's move the Earth.
Kady, get your hedge
witches on the horn.
We got cooperating
to do. I'm on it.
(EXPLOSIONS)
Okay. I found a spell that
can hold (TIMER DINGS)
the pieces in
suspension. We just...
Right. Good to assume we
can all do sphincter magic?
(EXPLOSIONS)
(TIMER DINGS)
Can we make this very big?
(EXPLOSIONS)
(TIMER DINGS) Mother shit.
You... You okay?
No, Julia, I'm not
okay. Bless you.
(SNEEZES)
Whoa.
Allow me to explain.
So, here we are, eight loops in.
Ten.
If these loops sent us
back even a little earlier,
we could stop Marina
from bad-touching this
whole situation, but we can't.
So we need time magic.
I know a horomancer who builds
machines. Maybe he has something.
Fantastic. Vámonos.
One problem. I kind of let his
mom die last time I saw him.
Oh.
Oh, come on. Like
you guys are all saints?
You're in a time loop?
But why you two?
'Cause we're the best-looking.
Here. This is Penny's address.
Margo, what are you doing? Shh.
Favorite coffee shop,
hipster club where we
suspect he DJs on the weekend,
and it's your lucky day.
His traveling's borked, so
he's a sitting duck in a scarf.
Margo, we can't just kill Penny.
We don't, he dies anyway,
along with everyone.
This is basic
trolley problem shit.
Ovary up. Okay.
If I wanted revenge on Penny, I
would've gotten that a long time ago.
You've got
particles all over you.
Were you spritzed
with something?
Spritzed, like, with what?
Something that nebulized a cloud
of temporal permanence around you?
(SMACKS LIPS) Mmm.
BOTH: (CHICLY) Permanence.
For men and women.
Yeah, I may have accidentally
stolen a weird perfume bottle
from a time witch in Fillory.
Okay, whatever you really did,
it's created a field around you both.
That would explain
why you're in a time loop.
Ah. And here we
thought we were special.
What are you doing? Helping.
You said it's the end
of the world, right?
That is right.
I think I can hop you guys back a
full 48 hours so you can prevent this.
Oh, really? Just like that?
Well, really
goddamn complicated,
but I'm a genius.
Oh. Oh!
Here we go.
(CLICKING)
Are we time traveling right now?
The hell? What's wrong?
Nothing's working. At all.
Are you saying your
shit's broken? I hope so.
The alternative is all time
magic's in some kind of lockdown.
What could even do that? (SIGHS)
Something powerful and ancient.
You mean like the moon?
Maybe if I just fix this, and
bypass the oscillations...
Hey, no rush, but in 30
seconds, we're all gonna die.
This will get you there.
Not in one piece, but...
Wait. What?
Shit. I'm sorry. Oh, well.
(EXPLOSIONS)
(TIMER DINGS)
MARGO: I cannot believe we didn't
consider going to Jane Chatwin first.
ELIOT: Well, she is a person
that may be upset with us.
MARGO: Fuck this.
No. Huh.
Time magic's locked down
and portal to Fillory's blocked?
This smacks of a
not-so-random coincidence.
Okay, we can still get
there. Penny can't do shit.
What about that other
Traveler dick-bucket?
(GROANS) Gavin? What's his name?
Everything I'm seeing says the first
chunk's gonna hit around 10:00 p.m.
BOTH: We know! Twelve hours.
ELIOT: We're seeing this
wrong. We're missing something.
Uh, maybe we need
to take a step back,
start thinking outside the box.
What do you suggest?
Remember Professor Soto?
(SCOFFS) The one with the pants.
Yeah. He had that ridiculous test
everyone thought was impossible.
That we solved, because
we rule. Solved how?
You want me to remember a
solution I came up with at a rager,
doing upside-down
shots in a fur bikini?
You say "rager," I say
"problem-solving session."
That's how we do.
We put our minds on
something different,
we catch the solution out
of the corner of our eye.
Is this actually a plan or do
you just wanna blow off steam?
Two birds, Bambi.
Besides, we're stuck in a
game that keeps hitting reset.
Infinite time, zero
consequences.
Just you and me, saving the
world through unbridled hedonism.
Mmm, fine. Let's do it.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
MAN: (WHISPERS) Eliot.
MARGO: Hey. Uh, hey.
Did someone just
knock on the door?
No. We going?
Yeah.
(DOOR OPENS)
(CLEARS THROAT) Okay,
miscreants, it's Armageddon.
So, die as you lived. Boring.
Or join us in an end-of-the-world
soiree, and die legends. Your choice.
You heard the man.
(UPBEAT INDIE POP MUSIC BLARING)
Come on!
It's a tie!
Anything?
Not yet.
(LAUGHING)
(CROWD EXCLAIMS)
Come on!
(PEOPLE YELLING)
(LAUGHTER)
(TIMER DINGS)
(ELECTRO-POP MUSIC PLAYING)
Gimme your control
MARGO: Mmm. MAN:
(WHISPERS) Eliot.
El. El. You look
like you saw a ghost.
Hey, ask it how
we stop the moon.
Actually, I think
I might... Wait.
Oh, my God. I think
I got something.
An idea. Hit me.
(LAUGHING)
Cock and balls. I forgot.
(CHUCKLES DRYLY) (LAUGHS LOUDLY)
(TIMER DINGS)
(DUBSTEP MUSIC PLAYING)
This isn't working.
No offense, Rajit.
It's Todd.
(CHUCKLES)
No. Come back when you're Rajit.
(CLEARS THROAT)
You know, I've been thinking.
Clearly, we need
something a little bit stronger.
No, we need an idea.
You know what?
I'm gonna go hydrate,
and, I dunno, stare at moon
chunks hurling straight for Earth.
Can't be worse than
discovering I just jacked Todd off
for three time loops in a row.
(CHUCKLES)
MAN: (WHISPERS) Eliot.
ELIOT: (IN SINGSONG VOICE) No.
It's never happening.
Leave me alone.
(TIMER DINGS)
(INDIE POP MUSIC PLAYING)
I never, never,
never get so close
It's under control
I'm reachin' the
end of a hallway
I never, never, never
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Been so out of my body...
I can walk away from you
all fucking day!
(TIMER DINGS)
Pardon me, Brenda.
Get this... (RATTLING)
(MUFFLED MUSIC PLAYING)
(SNIFFS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
I got a lead.
I've been talking to this
weird oceanographer guy,
who, no joke, has
a dolphin harem,
but he also knows
some real shit about...
Hey, what's up with you?
(GROGGILY) What's up is, hmm,
my brain is a
snake eating its tail,
and the tail is another
snake eating its tail.
Jesus. Okay, you stay here.
I'll report back
with some research.
(TIMER DINGS)
(MUFFLED HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(MUFFLED) I figured it out, El.
From talking to
that dolphin-fucker.
Everything he said checked out.
(NEWS REPORT PLAYING)
We need to go to Fisher Beach.
It's kinda out of the
way. Lifeguard station 17.
PENNY: Everything I'm
seeing says the first chunk's...
MARGO: Eliot.
PENNY: We have 12
hours. MARGO: Hey.
I got the answer. You
can take a breather.
Not right now, Margo.
Okay, Leaving Las Vegas.
I was happy to give you space to tell
your Monster secrets in your own time,
but we're stuck in this
Jean-Paul Sartre bullshit,
and you're getting worse fast.
I told you this isn't
important right now, okay?
Whatever it is you remember,
it's not your fault, okay?
ALICE: This math
is so damn hard.
Can we just stop the
moon first, please?
Not if your liver falls out of
your twat first. Let's talk about it.
No.
Seems like we have to. It's me.
Don't be a coward. Stop.
(BREATH TREMBLING)
It's still in me, okay?
(INHALES DEEPLY)
I am seeing what I am seeing.
Some pieces of
it must've held on.
The Monster's gone.
I exorcised it, and Q
threw it into the Seam.
The only thing here
is, you medicating
instead of facing your
memories and your feelings.
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
And I empathize, I do,
but I think you're forgetting
you can tell me anything.
I just told you and
you didn't believe me.
I love you, even
when you're nuts.
But our window's 12
hours to stop the moon
or it's game over again,
and I need it to be fixed
before I go as nuts as you.
So just sit this round out.
No. And I'll go alone.
No, no, no. Please,
please. I can...
You can't. I can
keep it together.
See you yesterday. I
can keep it together.
Please, no, Margo.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
(DUBSTEP MUSIC BLARING)
(TIMER DINGS)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(MUFFLED HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
I'm feeling the wrong
kind of boned right now.
Okay. I'm sorry.
What you said yesterday...
Yesterday? At Westbrook's house?
(NEWS REPORT PLAYING ON LAPTOP)
Yesterday, before you
went to Fisher Beach.
I didn't go to Fisher Beach.
You don't...
You don't remember.
Remember that tit-chafe Marina showed
up and broke the moon? How could I forget?
(SOFT SNEEZE)
Did Josh just
sneeze on the pizza?
(SIGHS)
(TIMER DINGS)
WOMAN: So, let's release
that ache, that desire for control.
Understand the moment we're in.
Accept our state of being.
Take a breath, send a prayer up
to the god of your understanding.
Send a prayer and accept.
Amen. ALL: Amen.
Thank you.
You've momentarily
lessened my existential dread.
(DOOR SHUTS)
MAN: (ON LAPTOP)
This may be the end.
MAN 2: No, I'm not reading this.
Okay, asshole. Bring it.
MAN: (ON LAPTOP)
I just want to say...
This world is flawed.
We each have
good in us, and bad.
Every day, we fight
to let the good win.
This is the last day.
Think about those who you love.
Turn off the TV
and be with them.
Thank you, and...
(BUTTON CLICKS)
I'm sorry. Were
you listening to that?
It was so depressing.
Not really.
Hey. You okay?
Not really. Me neither.
Cookie?
Yeah.
I have to admit, I don't
think their spell will work.
(SCOFFS)
It won't.
I can't believe
I'm about to die.
You are. But then, you'll
just start all over again.
We're in a time loop.
Shut up. Seriously?
That's a relief. Like,
uh, Groundhog Day?
Or Russian Doll? Or Happy Death
Day? Or Happy Death Day 2U?
Or Source Code?
Oh, that X-Files.
The Star Trek, Edge of Tomorrow,
but really All You Need is Kill,
and it's like, why change
the title like that, right?
Wow.
You really love time
loop stories, don't you?
And you're awake in the loop.
You're the hero. I am totally jealous.
Hey, you wanna get out of here?
I've got this place
on my bucket list,
and, well, uh,
it's gotta be now.
And to Sharon Cappanelli
from ninth grade, I lied.
JOSH: Man.
REPORTER: It was my tampon,
and that was your girlfriend.
JOSH: Time loops.
REPORTER: I'm not
sorry. But I want you...
Gnarly. They're
extremely gnarly.
So, you're talking
to me about it.
(DROWSILY) Yeah.
As opposed to
Alice, Julia or Kady,
or, to state the obvious, Margo.
I kinda blew it beyond
repair with Margo.
How is anything beyond repair
when you're stuck in a time loop?
(CRUNCHING LOUDLY)
Well, she was awake
with me for a while,
and then she got kicked out
somehow, and now I am utterly alone.
Well, if I'm learning anything
from these squishy pierogi tacos,
it's that not everything
belongs together.
(SIGHS)
How can we help?
Help save the world?
(SCOFFS)
Honestly, I don't know.
It might not be possible.
This might be it.
Me, alone,
in this particular
12 hours, eternally.
Okay. That sounds
like a lot for you.
So, uh, anything I
can do to help you?
(GROANS) I wish, because
the longer this goes on,
the more certain I am that The Monster
is inside of me and trying to get out.
Good metaphor.
I'm being literal.
Oh.
Shit.
(SIGHS)
It's worse every loop.
I hear its voice. I see
blood on the walls.
I... I see this door.
It wants out.
Have you tried letting it out?
Why in God's name
would I do that?
Uh, I'm just spit-balling.
A lot of the time,
in these movies,
the solution to the problem
is facing the thing
you're most afraid of.
What if I die?
What if you do?
(MUFFLED SQUEALING)
(MUFFLED CRASHING)
(MAN SCREAMING)
(CRUNCHING)
MAN: (MUFFLED) Why?
(AIR-RAID SIREN WAILING)
Anyway...
You're not upset
you're about to die?
(CHUCKLES QUIETLY)
I don't love it.
But you'll figure
out a way to fix this.
(TIMER DINGS)
REPORTER: (MUFFLED) Though
the world's greatest minds are locked
in a desperate race
to save humanity...
(MUFFLED) Everything I'm seeing
says the first chunk's
gonna hit around 10:00 p.m.
We have 12 hours.
What if we create a massive
portal in the atmosphere?
ALICE: We'd need
a specialist and...
(SNEEZES)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
Charlton?
Well, fuck.
How the hell are you here?
I was trapped wandering
your remembrances,
when, mercifully, you decided not to
sleep for five days and broke your brain.
That gave me an
opening to contact you.
That voice? That was you?
Yes, of course. (CHUCKLES)
When all the scary
creatures were pulled out,
I held on tight as I could
in your Happy Place,
and, well, here we are.
This place was so
vivid in your mind,
but there is nothing like
the real thing, is there?
The sights, the sounds.
(SNIFFS)
The smells. Oh!
I forgot about smells, Eliot. They
are overwhelmingly unpleasant.
Those messages?
That was you, too?
"I'm still here." "Let me out."
Yes. I wanted you to
know that I was still here,
and I wanted to be let out.
In red paint?
Right, like strawberries
and Santa Claus.
And blood, Charlton.
Perhaps it was a touch ominous.
As was the creepy whisper.
I was trying to be polite.
Well...
It is nice to have a
non-imaginary imaginary friend
for the end of
the world, I guess.
Half-imaginary.
I was a passenger
in your unconscious.
Now, I'm still in your head.
But the conscious part.
I can't tell you how much
of an improvement this is.
Your Happy Place is nice,
and I was able to see everything
you were doing here, but...
Well, there's no
substitute for being heard.
Especially since I often
disagree with your choices,
and I'd like to
share my opinions.
That's peachy.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Well, let's start now.
(SIGHS)
Opinion on what to do next?
Oh, well, I think
that's obvious.
(SCOFFS) Is it? In
case you didn't notice,
Margo was sort of driving
the bus on this whole thing,
before I screwed
up and lost her.
But you didn't lose her, Eliot.
She's out of the
loops, Charlton.
No, I simply mean, I
don't think that's about you.
I think she got too
close to the answer.
Perhaps that's why she was thrown
from your shared loop experience.
That does have
the ring of logic to it.
(WHISPERING) Margo
mentioned a beach, did she not?
Fisher Beach.
Okay.
Let's go.
CHARLTON: Why
is there no one here?
ELIOT: I think it's a "cancel
your beach trip" kinda day today.
Just keep your eyes peeled for anyone
or anything that might not want us here.
Is that phone wire?
Are phones generally
used underwater?
ELIOT: I think we got a lead.
Lifeguard Station 17. It's
the same track Margo was on.
This didn't go well for her,
so perhaps we should discuss
before going in there, okay?
Ovary up, Charlton.
Um...
I guess... "Off" and "Whales."
DISTORTED MALE AND FEMALE VOICES:
What is the purpose of this distraction?
With whom are we speaking?
We are the whales.
Like, all of them?
Of course.
Why do you speak through a TV?
Why do you? What is
the nature of your query?
Okay, I don't really
know how to explain this.
Um... (CLICKS TONGUE)
Okay, so you probably don't
know this, but we are in a time loop.
We are aware of the disturbance.
Oh. Huh.
Whales grok time loops.
So, do you happen to remember if a
woman named Margo came to see you?
Uh, brilliant, about yea
high, maybe a little brusque.
A contemptuous creature.
We were compelled to wash
away her temporal immunity.
You took her Permanence off?
Why?
Her manner was appalling.
That does sound like Margo.
Okay. I apologize for
her bedside manner.
And I just... I humbly
and I respectfully ask,
do you...
do you have any insight
into this loop that we're in?
Our magic caused it.
(GASPS)
You're Magicians?
Pay attention. We
will explain. Once.
Our ancestors made a
pact with the Old Gods.
And so we spend our lives
tracing sigils into the ocean floor.
This task is crucial.
Why?
To ensure the
Kraken stays dormant.
Like "the Kraken" Kraken?
What's a Kraken Kraken?
Should the Kraken ever awaken,
it would soon consume the world.
Okay. Got it.
So, the loops... Why?
The moon collided with Earth,
obliterated our protective sigils,
causing the Kraken to rise.
Kinda seems like a hat on a hat
when you've already
got a moon apocalypse.
A bit flippant for a creature
who caused said apocalypse.
Fortunately, our ancestors
implemented a failsafe.
If the Kraken awakens, it
sends Earth back 12 hours,
to allow another chance
to avert catastrophe.
Whereupon it will all
just keep happening,
because the fucking
moon is broken.
So it would seem.
Well, uh, if you're Magicians, then
maybe you can help fix the moon?
We cannot. We must
maintain our sigils.
Okay.
If you don't fix the moon, the
Kraken's just gonna keep krakening.
This distraction has
gone on too long.
Wait. No, no, no.
We must attend to the
sigils. ELIOT: Hold on.
Do not contact us
again. No, no, no.
(STATIC HISSING) No.
Uh...
(SIGHS) Shit.
(TIMER DINGS)
(SIGHS) Feeling the wrong
kind of boned right now.
Oh, okay. Bye, I guess.
(MUFFLED HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(PEOPLE SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
What am I supposed to do?
I can't fix the moon.
That won't work.
You can't help.
You're a non-corporeal.
True.
But...
(WHISPERS) You are not alone.
ALICE: So, whales really
are powerful Magicians.
I knew they did weird
stuff on the ocean floor.
I didn't realize it was... Wait.
Yes. Alice. Tell me what
else you know about whales.
Um...
Their closest
cousin is the hippo.
Mmm... Mating
season is in the fall.
That is so sad for them.
What if they never
get to make love again?
Though I am one to talk.
It's been over 1,000 years.
It's not exactly what I needed.
Well, you asked me what I knew.
Is there any info about the Kraken
that might point us in a direction?
Oh-ho-ho-whoa. Okay, well, you
have your Lovecraftian god krakens,
uh, and then there's the D&D
kraken, which is sort of six-of-one,
and then, of course,
there's Clash of the Titans,
both the original and
the remake. Thank you.
With the very famous line...
Thank you, Josh.
Every time the Kraken awakens,
time jumps back 12 hours.
Which would be great if it took
us back to before the moon broke.
If we get the time loop spell
to trigger a couple hours early...
Why don't we just kill
all the damn whales?
That's clearly what you tried to do
when they took away your Permanence.
But she's right.
Maybe we need to let out
the thing that scares us.
Maybe we need to, uh...
"Release the Kraken!" Exactly.
Yeah. Uh, but earlier.
Early enough, uh, to
a time before the heist.
Shit. We're almost out of time.
(AIR-RAID SIREN WAILING)
Look, if the whales have the power
to take away your Permanence,
this could be your last shot.
No presh, but
you're our only hope.
I will do my very best.
(MUFFLED EXPLOSION)
(TIMER DINGS)
(GASPS)
WHALES: Surely you jest.
I know, I know.
It goes against everything you've
ever believed in and I fully respect that.
But the only way to fix this
is to release the
Kraken right now.
I don't think they
liked that. What? No.
God damn it.
Eliot? Eliot?
Please be careful. Uh, you
don't know what they will do.
Hey!
You know I'm right.
I know you're listening.
You know, I have
it on good authority
that mating
season is in the fall.
Do you never want to fuck again?
Eliot, that was
too personal. Uh...
Okay, uh, sorry.
Look, I get it.
Look, I get it. Your
ancestors made a deal.
But special circumstances, okay?
Just let it out for 30
seconds. I will fix this.
And then, you know,
uh, the Kraken will be
back in its safe little seabed,
and, uh, you can maintain
your sigils for all of eternity.
You gotta trust me.
Just release the goddamn Kraken.
Please, please, please.
(WATER BUBBLING) Look.
Hi there.
Uh...
Are you the Kraken?
The who?
(ROARING)
JULIA: Josh, Margo, Penny,
you guys go inside,
loop all the cameras,
open the side door for Natasha.
I'll be outside waiting
with Eliot and Alice.
Holy shit. Holy shit.
(CHUCKLING) Holy shit.
This is before the
moon broke. (LAUGHS)
It worked.
Okay, break. ELIOT: Sorry.
Um, could you
just... Could you...
You're freaking
out, aren't you? No.
Look, you can pull the ripcord
now. Get out. We'll handle this.
Margo. Credenza.
Don't ask questions,
just do what you say?
Mmm-hmm.
Fine.
Okay, slight change of plans.
We are so close
to saving everyone.
You can't take that
away from us now.
Look, whatever
it is you're after,
what's the point if
there's no world left?
There'll still be a world.
Just not as many people.
Have you met people?
I've met people. Many people.
How many people have you met?
Because I bet I've met more people.
What the fuck is wrong
with you? MARGO: Hi.
What the hell...
Hell yes.
What? What the... How did you...
Julia, now.
(SEARING)
(CHUCKLES)
(TIMER DINGS)
(LAUGHTER) Hey, hot pizza.
That's one pizza
without gluten in it. Whoo.
All right. Oh, nice pour.
(LAUGHTER)
To us.
KADY: Yes. Cheers. Cheers. Yes.
JOSH: Bam! Yes, no prob.
(LAUGHTER) JULIA:
All right, Emeril.
KADY: Yes. Cheers.
Cheers. JULIA: Whoo.
KADY: Ooh. Get me.
You don't want a drink?
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
Actually, I desperately do not.
That's concerning.
Those time loops must've
really done a number on you.
So...
You're right. I have
been pushing you away.
Yeah, no shit.
It's just...
(INHALES DEEPLY)
I do remember The Monster.
It was bad and bloody.
And, um, those memories
are right here, and, um...
(CLICKS TONGUE) Maybe
I really do need that drink.
I don't get why you feel
like you have to go it alone.
(GROANS QUIETLY)
I don't either.
My logical brain knows without
a doubt that I am better with you.
Yes. And same.
(SIGHS)
Tell your coping
mechanisms to back off,
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
or I'll punch them in the dick.
During the loops,
we were in it together.
And then you were gone.
And shocking revelation,
I am utterly miserable
when you're not around.
(LAUGHS) Yeah. I know.
I don't know if
that's fair to you.
What are you talking about?
The other thing I learned being
in the loops with you for so long...
You're not exactly
who you used to be.
You...
Please don't say "aged."
You've evolved, Margo Hanson.
You've become more of
your true self. (CHUCKLES)
(CHUCKLES) You've earned it.
I don't want to ask
you to take a step back,
just so I can try and catch up.
El.
I was a mess you had to untangle
in there, just so you could soldier on.
And once you did, you
figured out how to fix all of this.
Then you picked up the
baton and actually did the thing.
I got lucky. No.
It's 'cause you understand
me better than anyone.
Mmm-hmm.
So quit acting like
you're a screw-up
and get on my level, El.
You did it.
You did it when the
world was on the line.
Now do it for yourself.
I don't know if I wanna get on your
level, knowing that you jacked off Todd.
I did not.
Yeah, you did.
(URGENT KNOCKING ON DOOR)
What the hell? Coming.
Oh, thank God.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I've tried every other magical
penthouse in the city, and...
Todd, what... Why are you here?
I need your help.
Something just happened that
feels way above my pay grade,
and you were the first person I
thought of who could help me handle it.
Okay, it's a weird one.
Just hear me out, okay?
So, this pig dude,
who kinda looked like that
one guy Paul Giamatti played
in that one show with all the wigs,
told me I'm supposed to do a quest.
Seriously? That
asshole went to you?
Wow. (SCOFFS)
Ah, he's extremely
committed to finding a dude.
Yeah, it's fine,
Todd. We fixed it.
Are you sure?
Yeah. Yes. I'm sure.
The Harmonic Convergence
isn't happening anymore.
The who now?
The end of the world.
Uh, no. He did say the end
of something, but not that.
He was talking about Fillory.
Remind me. Is Fillory real?
The end of Fillory?
So...
So, we saved the wrong world?
So we're not done.
Of course.