Previously on "The Magicians"...
You're not right, El,
and we both know why.
You said you don't remember
what happened
when you were possessed,
but Julia does.
And I don't.
I don't know why
you're accusing me of lying.
Eliot, let me out.
We're looking for Stoppard.
Mom? Mom, what's wrong?
Moms die every day.
Circle of life.
We know you're trying
to look out for your mom.
You're saying you'll leave?
- Sorry, man.
- I'm not going anywhere.
The Harmonic Convergence.
AKA the end of the world.
The convergence will only occur
during this perfect alignment.
If we move the moon
out of position...
No Convergence,
no Circumstance, no apocalypse.
If you have moon brain,
then you will see her aura.
If it is green,
she is listening.
Only then may you ask her
to move.
You will need a piece of her.
- Like a moon rock?
In here, boss.
Ladies.
You're moving the moon?
Yeah.
Uh, guys?
I think we broke the moon.
NASA estimates just hours
before the first pieces
reach our atmosphere.
In a tweet, the president
stressed the need for calm,
saying, "We will fix
the moon decisively.
The American people have
absolutely nothing to fear."
I know we are dealing
with the lunapocalypse problem,
but I have to insist
that we all take a minute
for a little
self-care/pizza, okay?
Okay.
Cautioning everyone that
though the world appears
to be coming to an end,
everyone's behavior
will still be counted
when the time comes
for judgment.
Feeling the wrong kind
of boned right now.
At least
the Harmonic Convergence
isn't happening anymore.
I just have this bad feeling.
Hey.
We'll figure out
how to stop this.
I mean, on the off-chance
the president doesn't.
Let's review.
Emergency code words
if this all goes shit-shaped?
Um...
Really?
Kidding. Okay.
As follows.
"Credenza," no questions asked.
"Inglenook," tie those fools up,
toss 'em through
the Fillory portal.
"Chifforobe," flee to Canada.
"Armoire," shield up, stat.
"Kimono"...
both:
All hell has broken loose.
Time and hope
are quickly running out.
Everything I'm seeing says
the first chunk's gonna hit
around 10:00 p.m.
We have 12 hours.
Uh, look.
What if we created
a massive portal
in the atmosphere?
No, we need a specialist,
and the meta-math is just...
it's too...
this is really bad, Julia.
Nuh-uh.
Don't you dare give up.
This math
is so damn frustrating.
Yeah, but you'll get it.
Jesus.
What happened to your shoe?
Have you been out there?
It is the literal end
of the actual world.
No, it's not.
We're gonna stop it.
Yeah, tell that to the
rioters and the prayer circles
and people fucking
in the streets.
I can't believe
this is happening.
I'm just numb.
Try the truffled prosciutto,
it's incredible.
I did have one idea
after my very bad idea
to take the subway.
Okay, do you know Richard's
Reverse Entropy spell?
We already talked about it.
Unfortunately, it's just
way too small.
True, but I reworked it.
And check my math.
This is fantastic, but...
I don't think we have
enough cooperative power.
Chances are high for a surge
in the next 12 hours.
We could use it.
And we have enough hedges
around the world on standby
to do it with us, so...
That might not be enough.
We make it enough.
Today we are saving the world,
and this time it's gonna stick.
Damn right, we are.
Okay.
But just in case...
Anything I need to say to you?
Jules, we're good.
Scientists around the world
have been sending out
their predictions
for what we should expect
in the coming hours.
Though the tides remain
mysteriously intact,
expect volcanic activity,
tectonic shifts,
disrupted weather patterns,
and strange behavior
from animal life.
And to Sharon Cappanelli
from ninth grade:
I lied.
It was my tampon,
and that was your girlfriend.
I'm not sorry.
Thanks for spreading
the word, Pete.
Stand by.
Everyone's set.
We're just waiting
for the surge.
You guys feel that?
It's the surge.
- It's cresting.
- We should...
- Go.
- Pete, now!
Did it work?
It didn't work.
We failed.
Feeling the wrong kind
of boned...
right now.
At least the Harmonic
Convergence
isn't happening anymore.
Although the world's
greatest minds
are locked in a desperate race
to save humanity
from this sudden
lunar cataclysm,
time and hope
are quickly running out.
Everything I'm seeing
says the first chunk's
gonna hit around 10:00 p.m.
We have 12 hours.
Uh, look, what if we created
a massive portal
in the atmosphere?
We need a specialist,
and the meta-math is just...
it's too... this
is really bad, Julia.
Am I crazy, or...
This already happened, right?
This math is so damn
frustrating.
This did.
This did already happen.
Ow!
Not a dream.
Hey, am I on something,
or did we try this plan
yesterday?
We're...
At Westbrook's estate?
Jesus.
What happened to your shoe?
Have you been out there?
It's the literal end
of the actual world.
- No, it's not.
- We're stopping it.
Tell that to the rioters,
prayer circles,
and people fucking
in the streets.
Both:
We're in a time loop.
Excuse us
while we briefly sidebar.
Why exactly is this happening?
- "Why is anything?"
- he asked,
still freaked, 'cause
the last thing he remembers
is all of Earth ending.
It felt so inevitable.
I know.
But why us, now?
Time loop?
Of course we're the chosen ones.
We're us.
Okay, everybody.
What is going on with you two?
Quick recap,
Kady's plan won't work.
We tried it, and the moon
still crashed into the Earth.
- Uh, okay.
- What do you mean, "tried it"?
We suspect we're in a time loop.
How?
Obviously...
the moon's a wily cunt
who doesn't wanna die.
Okay.
All right,
so no reverse entropy.
What do you guys suggest?
We cast Vinnola's
Oxygen Saver on Penny 23,
then he travels to the moon.
It's easier
to do a portal there.
Look, GPS is kinda broken.
I might end up in a wall.
- It's the apocalypse.
- Gonna need you to try.
Fuck all of you.
Fine.
You got this, man.
- Oh... oh, no!
- No!
Okay, forget the moon.
Let's move the Earth.
Kady, get your hedge bitches
on the horn.
We got cooperating to do.
I'm on it.
Okay.
I found a spell that can hold
the pieces in suspension,
we just...
right, good to assume
we can all do sphincter magic?
Could we make this very big?
Mother-shit!
You... you okay?
- No, Julia.
- I'm not okay.
Bless you.
Whoa.
Allow me to explain.
So here we are, eight loops in.
Ten.
If these loops sent us back
even a little earlier,
we could stop Marina
from bad-touching
this whole situation,
but we can't.
Okay, so we need time magic.
I know a horomancer
who builds machines.
Maybe he has something.
Fantastic, vámanos.
One problem...
I kind of let his mom die
last time I saw him.
Oh.
Oh, come on.
Like you guys are all saints?
You're in a time loop?
Well, why you two?
'Cause we're the best-looking.
Here.
This is Penny's address.
Margo, what are you doing?
Favorite coffee shop,
hipster club where we suspect
he DJ's on the weekend,
and it's your lucky day...
his Travelling's borked,
so he's a sitting duck
in a scarf.
Margo, we can't just kill Penny.
We don't; he dies anyway,
along with everyone.
This is basic
trolley problem shit.
Ovary up.
Okay.
If I wanted revenge on Penny,
I would've gotten that
a long time ago.
You've got particles
all over you.
Were you spritzed
with something?
Spritzed, like with what?
Something that nebulized
a cloud of temporal permanence
around you?
Mm.
Both: "Permanence."
For men and women.
Yeah, I may have
accidentally stolen
a weird perfume bottle
from a time witch in Fillory.
Okay, whatever you really did,
it's created a field
around you both
that would explain why you're...
in a time loop.
Ah.
And here we thought
we were special.
- What are you doing?
- Helping.
You said it's the end
of the world, right?
That is right.
I think I can hop you guys back
a full 48 hours so you can
prevent this.
Oh, really? Just like that?
Well, it's really
goddamn complicated,
but I'm a genius.
- Oh.
Here we go.
Are we time traveling right now?
The hell?
What's wrong?
Nothing's working... at all.
Are you saying
your shit's broken?
I hope so.
The alternative is...
all time magic's
in some kind of lockdown.
What could even do that?
Something powerful...
and ancient.
You mean like the moon?
Maybe if I just fix this
and bypass the oscillation...
Hey, no rush, but in 30 seconds,
we're all gonna die.
This'll get you there.
Not in one piece, but...
Wait, what?
- Shit.
- I'm sorry.
Oh, well.
I cannot believe
we didn't consider
going to Jane Chatwin first.
Well, she is a person
that may be upset with us.
Yes.
- No.
- Huh.
Time magic's locked down,
and the portal
to Fillory's blocked.
This smacks of
a not-so-random coincidence.
Okay.
We can still get there.
Penny can't do shit.
What about that other
Traveller dickbucket,
- Gavin what's-his-name?
- Everything I'm seeing
says the first chunk's
gonna hit around 10:00 p.m...
We know!
12 hours.
- We're seeing this wrong.
- We're missing something.
Uh, maybe we need
to take a step back.
Start thinking outside the box.
- What do you suggest?
- Remember Professor Soto?
- Oh, the one with the pants?
- Yeah.
He had that ridiculous test
everyone thought was impossible.
That we solved because we rule.
- Solved how?
- You want me to remember
a solution I came up with
at a rager
doing upside-down shots
in a fur bikini?
You say rager,
I say problem-solving session.
That's how we do: we put our
minds on something different
and we catch the solution out
of the corner of our eye.
So is this actually a plan
or do you just wanna
blow off steam?
Two birds, Bambi.
Besides, we're stuck in a game
that keeps hitting reset.
Infinite time,
zero consequences.
Just you and me saving the world
through unbridled hedonism.
Mm, fun.
Let's do it.
Eliot.
Hey.
Uh, hey.
Did someone just knock
on the door?
We going?
Yeah.
Okay, miscreants.
It's Armageddon.
So die as you lived...
Boring.
Or join us in an
end-of-the-world soiree
and die legends.
Your choice.
You heard the man.
Come on!
It's a tie!
Anything?
Not yet!
Oh!
♪ Gimme your control
Mmm.
Eliot!
- El, El.
- You look like you saw a ghost.
Hey, ask it
how we stop the moon.
- Actually, I think I might...
- Wait!
Oh, my God,
I think I got something.
An idea.
Hit me.
Cock and balls, I forgot.
This isn't working.
No offense, Rajit.
It's Todd.
No.
Come back when you're Rajit.
Okay.
You know, I've been thinking...
clearly we need something
a little bit stronger.
No, we need an idea.
You know what?
I'm gonna go hydrate
and, I don't know...
stare at moon chunks hurtling
straight for Earth.
Can't be worse than discovering
I just jacked Todd off
for three time loops in a row.
Eliot.
No...
It's never happening.
Leave me alone.
♪ I never, never, never,
get so close ♪
♪ It's under control
♪ I'm reachin'
the end of a hallway ♪
♪ I never, never, never
♪ Been so out my body
I can walk away
from you all fucking day!
Pardon me, Brenda.
I'm gonna get this.
I got a lead.
I've been talking
to this weird oceanographer guy
who no joke has a dolphin harem,
but he also knows
some real shit about...
Hey, what's up with you?
What's up?
Is...
my brain is a snake
eating its tail,
and the tail is another snake
eating its tail.
- Jesus.
- Okay, you stay here.
I'll report back
with some research.
I figured it out, El.
From talking
to that dolphin fucker.
Everything he said checked out.
We need to go to Fisher Beach.
It's kind of out of the way.
Lifeguard station 17.
Everything I'm seeing says
the first chunk's
gonna hit around 10:00 p.m...
Eliot.
- We have 12 hours.
- Hey.
I got the answer.
You can take a breather.
Not right now, Margo.
Okay, "Leaving Las Vegas."
I was happy to give you space
to tell your Monster secrets
in your own time,
but we're stuck
in the Jean Paul Sarte bullshit
and you're getting worse fast.
I told you, this isn't
important right now, okay?
Whatever it is,
you remember
it's not your fault, okay?
This math is
so damn frustrating.
Can we just stop
the moon first, please?
Not if your liver
falls out of your twat first.
Let's talk about it.
No.
- Seems like we have to.
- It's me.
Don't be a coward.
Stop.
It's still in me, okay?
I am seeing what I am seeing.
Some pieces of him
must've held on.
The Monster is gone.
I exorcised it
and Q threw it into the Seam.
The only thing here
is you medicating
instead of facing
your memories and your feelings
and I empathize, I do.
But I think you're forgetting
you can tell me anything.
I just told you,
and you didn't believe me.
I love you.
Even when you're nuts.
But our window's 12 hours
to stop the moon
or it's game over again,
and I need it to be fixed
before I go as nuts as you,
so just sit this round out...
- No.
- And I'll go alone.
- No, no, no.
- Please, please.
I can...
You can't.
Keep it together,
I can keep it together.
- See you yesterday.
- I can keep it together.
Please.
No, Margo.
I'm feeling the wrong kind
of boned right now.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
What you said yesterday...
Yesterday at Westbrook's house?
Yesterday before you went
to Fisher Beach.
I didn't go to Fisher Beach.
- You don't...
- At around 10 p.m.
- We have 12 hours.
- You don't remember.
Remember that tit-chafe Marina
showed up and broke the moon?
How could I forget?
Did Josh just sneeze
on the pizza?
So let's release that ache,
that desire for control.
Understand the moment we're in.
Accept our state of being.
Take a breath.
Send a prayer up to the god
of your understanding.
Send a prayer and accept.
Amen.
- Amen,
- Thank you.
You've momentarily lessened
my existential dread.
This may be the end.
No, I'm not reading this.
Okay, asshole.
Bring it.
I just wanna say...
This world is flawed.
We each have good in us...
and bad.
Every day we fight
to let the good win.
This... this is the last day.
Think about those who you love.
Turn off the TV
and be with them.
Thank you and good...
I'm sorry.
Were you listening to that?
It was so depressing.
Not really.
Hey, you okay?
Me neither.
Cookie?
Yeah.
I have to admit...
I don't think their spell
will work.
It won't.
Can't believe I'm about to die.
You are, but...
then you'll just
start all over again.
We're in a time loop.
Shut up.
Seriously?
That's a relief.
Like, uh, "Groundhog Day"?
Or "Russian Doll"?
Or "Happy Death Day"
or "Happy Death Day 2U"?
Or "Source Code"?
Oh, that "X-Files".
The "Star Trek".
"Edge of Tomorrow" but really
"All You Need Is Kill"
and it's, like, why change
the title like that, right?
Wow.
You really love
time loop stories, don't you?
And you're awake in the loop.
You're the hero.
I am totally jealous.
Hey, you wanna get out of here?
I've got this place
on my bucket list
and well, uh...
it's gotta be now.
- And to Sharon Cappanelli
from ninth grade: I lied.
- Man.
- It was my tampon,
- and that was your girlfriend.
- Time loops.
Gnarly.
Extremely gnarly.
So you're talking
to me about it.
Yeah.
As opposed
to Alice, Julia, or Kady.
Or, to state the obvious,
Margo.
I kind of blew it
beyond repair with Margo.
How is anything beyond repair
when you're stuck
in a time loop?
Well,
she was awake with me
for a while and then
she got kicked out somehow,
and now I am utterly alone.
Well, if I'm learning anything
from these squishy pierogi tacos
is that not everything
belongs together.
How can we help?
Help save the world?
Honestly, I don't know.
It might not be possible.
This might be it.
Me, alone,
in this particular 12 hours.
Eternally.
Okay.
Sounds like a lot for you.
So, uh, anything I can do
to help you?
I wish.
Because the longer this goes
on, the more certain I am
that the Monster is inside
of me and trying to get out.
Good metaphor.
I'm being literal.
Oh.
Shit.
It's worse every loop.
I hear its voice,
I see blood on the walls,
I... I see this door.
It wants out.
Have you tried letting it out?
Why in God's name
would I do that?
I... I... I'm just spitballing.
A lot of the time
in these movies
the solution of the problem
is facing the thing
you're most afraid of.
What if I die?
What if you do?
Why?!
Anyway.
You're not upset
you're about to die?
I don't love it.
But you'll figure out a way
to fix this.
The world's greatest minds
are locked in a desperate race
to save humanity.
Everything I'm seeing says
the first chunk's gotta hit
around 10 p.m.
We have 12 hours.
What if we create a massive
portal in the atmosphere?
We'd need a specialist.
Charlton?
Well, fuck!
How the hell are you here?
I was trapped
wandering your Remembrances
when mercifully you decided
not to sleep for five days
and broke your brain.
That gave me an opening
to contact you.
That voice?
That was you?
Yes, of course.
When all the scary creatures
were pulled out,
I held on tight as I could
in your Happy Place,
and, well... here we are.
This place was so vivid
in your mind,
but there is nothing
like the real thing, is there?
The sights, the sounds, the...
smells!
Oh, I forgot about smells,
Eliot.
They're overwhelmingly
unpleasant.
- Those messages?
- That was you, too?
"I'm still here"?
"Let me out"?
Yes.
I wanted you to know
that I was still here
and I wanted to be let out.
In red paint?
Right, like strawberries
and Santa Claus.
And blood, Charlton.
Well, perhaps
it was a touch ominous.
As was the creepy whisper.
I was trying to be polite.
Well...
It is nice to have a
non-imaginary imaginary friend
for the end of the world,
I guess.
Half-imaginary.
I was passenger
in your unconscious.
Now, I'm still in your head.
But the conscious part?
I can't tell you how much
of an improvement this is.
Your Happy Place is nice
and I was able to see
everything you were doing here,
but...
well, there's no substitute
for being heard.
Especially since I often
disagree with your choices,
and I'd like
to share my opinions.
Oh, that's peachy.
Well, let's start now.
Opinion on what to do next?
Oh, well, I'd think
that's obvious.
Is it?
In case you didn't notice,
Margo was sort of driving
the bus on this whole thing
before I screwed up
and lost her.
You didn't lose her, Eliot.
She's out of the loops,
Charlton.
No, I simply mean
I don't think that's about you.
I think she got too close
to the answer.
Perhaps that's why
she was thrown from
your shared loop experience.
That does have
the ring of logic to it.
Margo mentioned a beach,
did she not?
Fisher Beach.
Okay.
Let's go.
Why is there no one here?
I think it's a
cancel-your-beach-trip
kind of day today.
Psst... keep your eyes peeled
for anyone or anything
who might not want us here.
Is that phone wire?
Are phones generally used
underwater?
I think we got a lead.
Lifeguard station 17.
That's the same track
Margo was on.
This didn't go well for her,
so perhaps we should discuss
before going in there, okay?
Ovary up, Charlton.
Uh...
I guess...
off and whales?
What is the
purpose of this distraction?
With whom are we speaking?
We are the whales.
Like...
all of them?
Of course.
Why do you speak through a TV?
Why do you?
What is the nature
of your query?
Okay, I don't really know
how to explain this.
Um...
okay, so you probably don't
know this but we...
we are in a time loop.
We are aware of the disturbance.
Oh, huh.
Whales grok time loops.
So do you happen to remember
if a woman named Margo
came to see you?
Uh, brilliant, about yea high,
maybe a little brusque.
A contemptuous creature.
We were compelled to wash away
her temporal immunity.
You took her Permanence off.
Why?
Her manner was appalling.
That...
does sound like Margo, okay.
I apologize for her bedside
manner, and I just...
I humbly and I respectfully
ask, do you...
do you have any insight
into this loop that we're in?
Our magic caused it.
You're... magicians?
- Pay attention!
- We will explain once.
Our ancestors made a pact
with the Old Gods
and so we spend our lives
tracing sigils
into the ocean floor.
This task is crucial.
Why?
To ensure the Kraken
stays dormant.
Like the...
the Kraken-kraken?
What's a Kraken-kraken?
Should the Kraken ever awaken
it would soon consume the world.
Okay, got it.
So, the loops.
Why?
The moon colliding with Earth
obliterated
our protective sigils
causing the Kraken to rise.
Kinda seems like a hat on a hat
when you've already
got a moon apocalypse.
A bit flippant for a creature
who caused said apocalypse.
Fortunately, our ancestors
implemented a failsafe.
If the Kraken awakens,
it sends Earth back 12 hours
to allow another chance
to avert catastrophe.
Whereupon it'll
all just keep happening
because the fucking moon
is broken.
So it would seem.
Well... uh... well,
if you're... if you're magicians,
then maybe you can help
fix the moon?
We cannot.
We must maintain our sigils.
Okay.
If you don't fix the moon,
the Kraken's just...
just gonna keep krakening.
This distraction
has gone on too long.
Wait... no, no, no.
We must attend to the sigils.
- Hold on.
- Do not contact us again.
No, no, no, no, no.
No!
Uh...
oh, shit.
Feeling the wrong kind
of boned right now.
Oh, okay.
Bye, I guess.
What am I supposed to do?
I can't fix the moon.
That won't work.
You can't help,
you're non-corporeal.
True.
But...
you're not alone.
So whales really are
powerful magicians.
I knew they did weird stuff
on the ocean floor,
I just didn't realize it was...
- Wait.
- Yes, Alice...
tell me what else
you know about whales.
Um...
their closest cousin
is the hippo.
Um, their mating season
is in the fall.
That is so sad for them.
What if they never get
to make love again?
Though I am one to talk.
I mean, it's been
over a thousand years.
That's not exactly
what I needed.
Well, you asked me what I knew.
Is there any info
about the Kraken
that might point us
in a direction?
- Whoa-ho-ho!
- Okay.
Well, you have your
Lovecraftian god-Krakens.
Uh, and then there's the
D&D Kraken
which is sort of six-of-one.
And then, of course,
there's "Clash of the Titans",
both the original
- and the remake.
- Thank you.
With the very famous line...
Thank you, Josh.
Every time the Kraken awakens,
time jumps back 12 hours.
Which would be great
if it took us back
to before the moon broke.
What if we
get the time loop spell to
trigger a couple hours early?
Why don't we
just kill all the damn whales?
Well, that's clearly
what you tried to do
when they took away
your Permanence.
But she's right.
Maybe we need to let out
the thing that scares us.
Maybe we need to, uh, to...
Release the Kraken!
Exactly, yeah.
But earlier.
Early... early enough
to a time before the heist.
Shit, we're almost out of time.
Look, if the whales
have the power
to take away your Permanence,
this could be your last shot.
No presh,
but you're our only hope.
I will do my very best.
Surely, you jest.
I know, I know.
It goes against everything
you've ever believed in,
and I fully respect that,
but the only way to fix this
is to release the Kraken
right now.
Well, I don't think
they liked that.
- What?
- No.
Damn it!
Eliot?
Please be careful.
Uh, you don't know
what they will do.
Hey!
You know I'm right!
I know you're listening.
You know, I have it
on good authority
that mating season
is in the fall.
Do you never wanna fuck again?
Eliot, that was too personal.
Uh...
okay, uh, sorry.
Look, I get it.
Look, I get it...
your ancestors made a deal,
but special circumstances, okay?
Just let it out for 30 seconds.
I will fix this
and then, you know, uh,
the Kraken will be back
in its safe little sea bed
and, uh, you can maintain your
sigils for all of eternity.
You gotta trust me.
Just release the goddamn Kraken.
Please, please, please,
please, please.
Look.
Hi there!
Uh...
are you the Kraken?
No.
Josh, Margo, Penny.
You guys go inside,
loop all the cameras,
open the side door for Natasha.
I'll be outside waiting
with Eliot and Alice.
Holy shit.
This is before the moon broke.
It worked.
- Okay, break.
- Sorry.
Um, could you just, uh...
could you...
You're freaking out, aren't you?
- No.
- Look, you can pull
the ripcord now.
Get out, we'll handle this.
Margo.
Credenza.
Don't ask questions,
just do what you say?
Mm-hmm.
Fine.
Okay.
Slight change of plans.
We are so close
to saving everyone.
You can't take that away
from us now.
Look, whatever it is
you're after
what's the point
if there's no world left?
There'll still be a world,
just not as many people.
Have you met people?
I've met people, many people.
How many people have you met?
Because I bet
I've met more people.
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Hi.
What the hell did...
Hell, yes.
What the... how did you...
Julia, now.
Hey!
Hot pizza!
That's one pizza
we definitely can enjoy.
All right.
Oh, nice pour right there.
Yes, cheers, cheers, yes.
Bam!
- All right, Emeril.
- Fresco pizza!
Yes, cheers.
Whoo!
You don't want a drink?
Actually, I desperately do not.
- That's concerning.
- Those time loops
must've really did
a number on you.
So...
You're right,
I have been pushing you away.
Yeah, no shit.
It's just...
I do remember the Monster.
It was bad and bloody and, um...
Those memories are, like,
right here.
And, um...
you know, maybe I really do
need that drink.
I don't get why you feel like
you have to go it alone.
I don't either.
My logical brain
knows without a doubt
that I'm better with you.
Yes, and same.
Tell your coping mechanisms
to back off...
Or I'll punch 'em in the dick.
During the loops,
we were in it together
and then you were gone, and...
shocking revelation...
I am utterly miserable
when you're not around.
Yeah, I know.
I don't know
if that's fair to you.
What are you talking about?
The other thing I learned
being in the loops
with you for so long...
you're not exactly
who you used to be.
You've...
Please don't say aged.
You've evolved, Margo Hanson.
You've become more
of your true self.
You've earned it.
And I don't want to ask you
to take a step back
just so I can try and catch up.
Oh.
I was a mess you had
to untangle in there
just so you could soldier on,
and... once you did,
you figured out
how to fix all of this.
And then you picked up the baton
and actually did the thing.
- I got lucky.
- No.
It's 'cause you understand me
better than anyone.
Mm-hmm.
So quit acting
like you're the screw-up
and get on my level, El.
You did it.
You did when the world
was on the line,
now do it for yourself.
I don't know
if I want to get on your level
knowing that you
jacked off Todd.
- I did not.
- Yeah, you did.
I did not.
The hell?
Coming.
Oh, thank God!
I've tried every other
magical Penthouse
in the city and...
- Todd.
- Wh... uh, what...
Why are you here?
I need your help.
Something just happened that
feels way above my pay grade,
and you were the first
person I thought of
who could help me handle it.
Okay, it's a weird one.
Just hear me out, okay?
So this pig dude
who kind of looks like
that one guy
Paul Giamatti played
in that one show
with all the wigs
told me I'm supposed
to do a quest.
Seriously?
That asshole went to you?
Wow. Ha.
Yeah, he's extremely committed
to finding a dude.
Yeah, it's fine, Todd.
We fixed it.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, yes, I'm sure.
The Harmonic Convergence
isn't happening anymore.
The who now?
The end of the world?
Uh, no.
He did say the end of something
but not that.
He was talking about Fillory.
Remind me, is Fillory real?
The end of Fillory?
So...
so we saved the wrong world?
So we're not done.
Of course.