Previously on The Magicians...
I'll send you on an epic quest.
Q, I think this is it.
"The Tale of the Seven Keys."
Okay, if fixing magic is,
like, so important to you,
then you should just
talk to this crazy guy
that I met back in
Athens one time.
You mean Prometheus? He's dead.
Damn it!
He told me this
crazy story one time
about how there was,
like, a secret back door
to magic.
I have...
Magic.
I have to be able to
do something with it.
I planted a seed
for you to grow.
It doesn't matter
where it comes from.
It matters what you do with it.
"The Tale of the Seven Keys,"
chapter eight.
The knight remained imprisoned
at the Castle at the
End of the World.
Not even a warrior
as great as he
could break the
bonds placed on him
by the witch.
He could not escape.
But his daughter, now every bit
the knight her father was,
and more so, never gave up.
She fought monsters,
real and imagined,
without as well as within.
She had won all seven keys,
and now she set sail
for the Castle at
the End of the World.
Okay, tick-tock.
Does it say where the castle is?
Shh! Bambi. Let him read.
Just saying, ándale.
Okay, so she faces
the door of the castle.
In the door, there
were seven keyholes.
The door swallowed
the keys whole
and slowly opened.
Up ahead, she saw her
father, bound by seven chains.
"Father," she cried,
"I'm here to save you."
She placed the
keys into the locks,
and when she
turned the seventh...
Sorry, time out.
I thought the weird
door swallowed the keys.
Yeah, no, it did, but then...
But then she has them again?
I'm not that drunk.
This is sloppy plotting.
Or it's a paradox.
That's a clue.
Oh, we're fucked.
The fucking Library
is ready to swoop in
with a... What's it called?
Siphon, and it's
not that simple.
Takes a lot of
power to charge it,
and they don't have those kind
of reserves just lying around,
thanks to Julia
freeing those fairies.
Yeah, well, it's the Library.
They'll think of something.
All we gotta do
is beat them to it.
I mean, their window of time
to even use the whatchamacallit
is super short, right?
Less than a minute,
once we turn the key.
There you go. Get
all this done before...
Our Lady of the Tree, help us.
Please, help me!
Hi, Julia.
Pleasure to finally meet you.
I'm Iris, messenger goddess,
bon vivant, rainbow aficionado.
Let's chat.
Who's...
Our Lady of the Tree?
You are.
I presume they mean the
trees you brought back in Fillory.
Lovely act of penance.
Good moniker for you.
Just what are you saying?
You fulfilled the task Our
Lady Underground gave you...
To grow the spark...
And now you are the flame.
So I'm...
A full-on goddess, correct.
Holy shit.
Shall we go? We
have a lot of work
to do, love, all very exciting.
I'm sort of in the
middle of this quest.
Oh, that. They can
take it from here.
Your concerns are greater now.
Your duty to them is over.
And by the way,
so is all that pain.
You can put it down.
Okay.
I mean, should I, like, bow?
No. I mean, I'm still me.
Well, you're clearly not.
I mean, it's been kind of hard
to ignore the nuclear power plant
radiating off you the
last couple weeks.
I don't know, just...
Wanted us to finish
this together, you know?
Mmm. Me too, but...
I mean, let's be honest, like,
you deserve this.
Why me?
Life is unfair,
but I'm good with it
occasionally working out
for people that I actually love.
Our Lady of the Tree.
No, it's good.
Yeah, it's good.
It's formal.
Very formal.
I'm gonna miss you too.
What was that?
It's enough juice
for a one-off spell.
You know, just in case, like,
a giant Indiana Jones
boulder comes hurtling at you.
You can fight it off.
I love you, Jules.
I love you too.
Goodbye, Quentin.
Any headway?
Well, wasted a few hours
looking at castles, but...
Think I'm onto something,
or someone, who could help us.
I've been tripping
on this, hard.
It's the witch, in the
castle, sitting at a table,
on which another,
smaller, castle...
Yeah? Well, either this is some
M.C. Escher, "the castle
goes on forever" shit,
or that picture means something.
Do you see these?
These are drafting tools
for architects.
Right, she's the
architect that...
That Reynard talked about,
that she's... Oh, my God,
she's the one that,
she made the prison
for the mistakes of the gods,
and she hid it.
She knows where it is.
We need to find her, Q.
There are, like, 50 minor gods
of architecture and the arts.
Well, come at me.
Let's get 'em all down here.
I mean, full-on goddess, huh?
Look, I mean, I get that Julia
has been through some shit,
but seriously, it
just seems random.
So it's like life, then?
I don't know. I'm happy for her.
Me too. Might as well be.
Well, I'd be happier if she
stayed, so she could help us.
Look, she seemed pretty positive
that we could do
this without her, so...
You forgot Calypso.
Like the musical style?
The witch that
imprisoned Odysseus.
And I love you, El,
but how the hell
did you pass AP Lit
without ever reading? I didn't.
So, according to the story,
she was a nymph, which...
Not a god, but I assume
a pretty powerful creature,
considering she
had him in lockdown
for, like, seven full years
on an island called Ogai...
Ogiji?
Ogijia?
Ogygia. KADY: However
that's pronounced.
Cool. Great.
So do we book tickets?
No, it's not a real place.
Hold on, okay, so...
Ogai, ogaiga,
or however you
say it, is a island
in the fictional tale
of "The Odyssey."
It's a clothing label,
a Eurovision band,
a tech company. They make games.
Oh, my God.
I know them. I worship them.
They're the Candy
Collider people.
I nearly spent
$600 on level 593.
It took me 12 straight days.
There are prisons,
and there are prisons.
Right?
We're all just 24/7,
"Like my post."
Beep-boop. Selfie!
Right?
No one's... No one...
Okay, so the CEO
is a woman named Callie.
Great. Vámonos.
Okay, look, I'll talk to you
because I promised
Prometheus I would,
and I would never
break my word to him,
but for the record,
I'm not a fan.
Of you, this big magic
quest, the whole fucking thing.
It's the reason
Prometheus is dead.
So as far as I'm concerned,
you're a big part
of why he's dead.
No, I... We don't...
Yeah, of course you don't.
You're humans.
Little human Magicians.
He loved you so.
All right, here it is.
The Castle was the greatest
commission of my career.
To design a prison that secure
for clients of that caliber...
When I explained that I would
need the most steadfast jailors,
Prometheus offered
to help find them,
create them with a quest.
Always was good at quests.
So you trapped some poor girl
into being your slave
for the rest of her life.
She's there of her own will,
as was her father,
who offered himself
as, well, bait, really.
A sort of damsel in distress
for his daughter to save.
I gave them each an opportunity
to perform a sacred task
to keep the world safe.
I assure you,
she can leave if she wishes.
I wouldn't have
it any other way.
Surely the quest has taught you,
sacrifice is part of everything.
So when Prometheus
was looking to
hide his back door...
I had already designed
the perfect place.
A place full of monsters
where no one wants to look.
He promised he would
make his quest difficult,
so no quester could get
anywhere near my prison
who couldn't ensure
it remained secure.
He channeled every atom of power
into the keys.
So he, like, Horcruxed himself?
Jesus.
Someone got bit
hard by the martyr bug.
All I can say is
he believed in you.
He said he saw a time to come
when you would save us
if you had magic.
He believed this completely.
What does that mean?
Guess we'll find out,
if you get to the end.
He gave everything for you,
and then his enemies came,
knowing he was weak.
With his power gone,
he couldn't stop them,
and they were strong.
Sorry, uh...
It was a long time ago.
So you don't suppose
you want to tell us
where your prison's at,
and/or how to get in?
I've been waiting to tell you
since the day he made the keys.
Wait, this looks like...
Is that Fillory?
It's upside-down.
Looked like that before
Ember and Umber got there
when it was just a
distant, wild little world.
Oh, my God.
There's a...
A theory about Castle Whitespire,
that the dwarves based it on
the most perfect design
that they'd ever seen,
a castle called...
Blackspire, but
Ember destroyed it.
More like flipped
the whole thing over
and started over
on the other side.
So my castle is
based on your prison?
What can I say?
I'm constitutionally incapable
of designing an ugly building.
So Blackspire's still there,
it's just underneath.
Yes.
Good luck with your quest.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey, lady, come on.
How do we get in?
The key paradox.
Let me get one thing clear:
Everything I put
the girl through,
I did to prepare her
for what's locked inside.
You'll find your way in,
and you'll find a way to
do it safely and securely,
but whatever you do,
there's one simple thing
you need to understand
above everything else.
What's locked
inside that castle...
Can never, ever be
allowed to escape.
Begging pardon, we need
your official permission.
As acting High King.
Oh.
You have my permission to
implement the new schedule.
Excellent, Your acting Majesty.
And if it's no trouble,
bring the tax collector's
latest expense reports.
I would like to
double-check them.
Sorry.
Of course. Right away.
You need to stop apologizing.
You'd do well to remember, that
power comes from High King Margo,
but it flows through you.
Is there something you need?
Yes.
Six fairies have
disappeared in two days.
And how are you
certain this is...
I found this.
I believe it's a part
of a magical device
imparting night vision
to paltry human eyes.
There is no magic.
Someone's hunting my people.
What is this?
My lab,
where I come to think,
answer texts, create worlds.
Wait, do I get to create worlds?
I mean, we'll start with one.
You'll split your
time between the lab
and answering the
prayers of your choice.
But I'll be blunt.
The work we do here is much
more vital to the big picture,
but we find that
morale stays higher
if we heal a kid or two
a few times a week.
One more thing.
My friends...
How come I can still feel them?
Takes a bit for those
connections to dissolve.
Q is stressing, and Fen...
I know that she wants to help
save these fairies' lives but...
This is the discipline.
You need to keep
from being seduced.
You're wasted if you
expend too much energy
trying to look after
every last fairy
when you could be
building and shaping worlds
where no fairy
ever comes to harm.
Why don't I show you?
So do we think the knight chick
is somehow still in there?
It's god magic, so
anything's possible.
We really don't know
what could be in there.
I'll travel in.
Excuse us for caring, but, no.
We don't know what
you'd be blipping into,
and we still have enough
Penny blood on our hands
from the last Penny.
Okay.
Say we do find some window.
We know this knight
is gonna help us?
Hi. You're asleep.
I'm in your head, not his.
It's a dream.
You have magic.
Had.
It's sort of a one-off.
Listen... Ora.
I'm Quentin.
I need your help.
You're here about the fountain?
The back door to magic?
Yeah. I can't help.
Because you're
guarding all the...
No. They're all gone.
He's the only one left.
Did they all die, or?
He killed them all.
You can't imagine
what he's capable of.
That's why I can't
do anything for you.
I cannot risk the
security of my charge.
I get that.
I have something
to offer you too.
Julia gave you a hit of
magic, and you did what?
Incepted the
knight in the castle.
That magic was
for killing a monster.
Why waste it on
chatting with the help?
When Calypso told us that Ora
was there on her own accord,
I figured she must
know more than one way
in and out of the
castle, and she does,
and she's going
to open it for us.
In exchange for... All
you have to do is get in,
turn the key, and get out fast.
Um, what about the monster?
Ora will take care
of the monster.
What about you?
I stay in the castle.
It's a fair deal.
She's been there for
centuries, and she's tired,
and I'm... I'm strong enough,
thanks to the quest,
so I'm the new jailor.
This isn't the
solution. I second that.
Alice, who's the
one that died for us?
You were willing to stay in Fillory
for forever. How is this different?
Someone has to step up.
Quick alternative pitch:
Take the gun with
the god-killing bullet
and shoot the fucking
monster in the face.
Second second that, yes.
No.
I promised, no clever stuff.
It's more bloody
and straightforward.
Look, this monster,
it's not a joke.
We cannot let it escape,
and the only way to
make sure that it doesn't
is to do this the hard way.
The quest taught us that
it's like that sometimes.
I don't like this.
Me neither, but
I'm going to do it.
Hello, love.
Oh, shit.
It's a human.
It's also the current
ruler of Fillory.
Hello.
We've met, so we
can get right to the part
where I tell you to stop
stealing fairies to chop up.
They are full
citizens of Fillory.
You will cease at once.
Full citizens. Well, la di da.
Escort them to the...
Uh-uh, uh. Know
what a Traveler is?
We can blip on out of here
and go about our beeswax
anytime we please.
I have something
you very much need
in the castle.
They won't be but a moment.
And may I say, sir,
how much I admire your suit.
I've been passing
bunnies with Margo.
They are very close to
turning magic back on.
Hooray for them.
And you must know
the reason Irene
is poaching fairies
is she needs a huge
amount of energy
to power a thing
that must be placed
just as it's connected,
within seconds, in order to...
Let me save your breath.
I don't care.
You should.
If we keep her long enough,
we can stop her
from derailing magic
and taking it for herself
and for the Library.
This is the future
we're talking about.
Not our future.
I cannot risk another soul.
I know exactly how
to deal with this.
So, what are you
offering, exactly?
I broke a deal.
It's my fault we're vulnerable.
I offer you the
magic of 50 fairies
with a single body.
You know the power
of royal marrow.
You're volunteering to die?
In exchange for a new agreement.
Wait. No fairy will be hunted
by a non-fairy anywhere, ever,
and this deal cannot be broken,
for any reason,
by any being, ever.
Swear to that, and you have me.
Time is of the essence.
My offer expires in one minute.
I'm gonna need a table
with restraints, a bone saw,
knives, and a grinder.
There must be another way.
The deal I struck with Irene
will finally make it possible
for my people to
be safe and free.
Tears for your enemy?
Any day now.
My God.
Where did it turn
out to be, Alice?
This Castle at the
End of the World?
Fillory. Underneath.
Castle Blackspire.
How did you... I
was a fan, too, once.
I need a favor.
I have this,
and I know it's wrong,
and I'll never use it again,
but I need it.
To?
I hear you have an
experimental potion
that not only wipes your memory,
but creates a whole new persona.
I do, but what?
I'll always be tempted.
Once I can feel it
everywhere again, and...
Unless I have no memory.
Alice,
you are...
You are one of the
most brilliant Magicians
I've ever seen.
I didn't choose to be!
I want to live my life,
not how my parents
raised me to think,
or what you taught me,
or what the Library
wants me to do.
I'm not sure if that's the
best path to happiness.
What if there is
no best path, huh?
I don't know.
All I know is the one
I'm on is a bad one...
And I'm stepping off.
Once you've...
Yes?
Drink this.
Give it about a full day
for everything to get rebooted.
After that,
you are on your own.
Thank you.
So?
We need to talk
about our arrangement.
You tell anyone else?
Please don't.
Of course not.
You're the only one that I...
Wanted... Had to tell.
Look, I know that I don't
show it or act like it all the time,
but you're...
You're the one that I love, Q.
You're the one.
And the only thing I'm going to
regret is not remembering that.
Well...
Well, I'll remember
for the both of us.
You made a deal you will regret.
You'll never know.
True.
But I'll die a queen,
not some mediocre,
power-hungry girl.
As I said, I'm only alive
because I fulfill its need.
To be entertained.
Served, coddled.
Loved.
Loved, like...
A child.
Okay, that's better
than my first thought.
Right now, he thinks
we're playing a game.
Hide and seek.
It's the only way to ensure
he'd stay diverted long enough
to let you in, and right
now, he's getting bored.
What's up?
In case I get held up.
Don't. Hear me?
You got this, okay?
My love?
I found you! I tag you!
Give it a moment.
Does it have a name?
No.
What makes it so dangerous?
The gods created
something that simply wants.
So it has to know one secure
place and constant love.
If not, if its
appetite goes unfed
and it's unleashed,
even the gods can't stop it.
Love?
Come out! Did you fall asleep?
Yeah, but what can it do?
Will you play with me?
Eliot! No!
Fuck, Eliot... How?
God-killing bullet.
This is not what we agreed on.
I didn't actually
agree on anything,
but I did decide that
one of my best friends
wouldn't spend the rest of
his life locked in a prison,
guarding what turns out to be
a really not-so-scary monster.
Wait, where'd she go?
Anyway, it's done.
You spent a little bit
too much time as a king.
Well, that's really not
the issue now, is it?
Could've used some Goo
Gone and a toothbrush,
but I think we're good
to go. All right, let's go.
Let's go. Come on, come on.
All right, bitches,
everyone grab a key.
Alice, what are you doing?
Nothing good.
No! ELIOT: Margo!
She's destroying the keys!
I have to.
You don't get to decide that the
whole universe doesn't have magic.
I'll never remember this.
Alice...
Why?
You...
You talked me out of
working for the Library.
I realize there's no good side.
Magic just makes people
different shades of bad,
selfish and irresponsible.
We can't handle it!
You can't handle it.
It's wrong.
We're wrong.
And it stops now!
What are you doing?
I'm gonna cut the bitch,
grab her fairy coke power-up,
and fix this.
So, where shall we start?
Ocean?
Cute little landmass?
Dealer's choice.
I know you can still feel them.
You need to let them go.
I know, but it's bad.
In a blink, it'll be good again,
and in two blinks,
they'll be long gone.
He's on the floor. He's...
He's not getting up.
He'll die, not giving up.
Can't you feel his heart?
No,
'cause I don't do
what you're doing.
You need to let them go.
Remember the
future we're creating.
Will you play with me?
Hey!
You think you can cast
faster than I can stab? Go!
Please, just listen
to me. The knight...
Ah, shut up the fuck up...
Fix this. Now.
There's no point.
The magic's gone. It's done.
He's right.
Jules.
None of your pain is
what we'd call quiet,
especially yours.
I know you thought this
was for everyone's good.
You'll see someday,
it wasn't.
For now, I need you
to stay out of the way.
I want you to know,
it's your bravery...
Made me see.
See what?
What I need to do.
What are you doing?
What Prometheus did.
Whore-crotching.
Horcruxing. Oh.
Look, Jules, are you sure?
Julia, you could
lose your power.
Hurry. PENNY: You okay?
Okay, okay.
Hey, I got you. I got you.
Come on.
Are you okay?
It hurt.
And I'm not connected
to anything anymore.
I got you. MARGO:
Are you guys ready?
Match it with the key.
Let's do this.
Dean Fogg?
Travel, Penny, I kill them all.
Irene...
We do have a deal.
Unless you want to have
a problem with the Library.
The very essence is altered
by the slightest
deviation in finger position.
Watch closely.
The difference is in the
position of the right middle finger.
Sorry, looks like
we're having another...
Power issue.
The rations are
wholly inadequate.
I can't even assign homework!
Do the best you can.
I'll attempt to
renegotiate for our supply.
How?
I'm afraid we can't revisit
your supply until next quarter.
I've spoken to the Board.
Which Board?
North American Fourth District.
Calgary enrollment
hasn't bounced back
the way we have.
They're barely using
2/3 of their allotment,
and they've offered it to us.
Both you and they need to
bring a written request to...
In triplicate.
You'll have a
decision by the 31st.
Excellent.
There's just one more request.
My answer hasn't changed.
She made a deal
with us, then broke it.
Unlike the others,
she belongs to the Library.
I just would like to see her.
Please.
Where are they?
Per the deal, as
struck with The Order,
safe.
No, no, no, no, no, they're not.
Alice, the McAllistairs
can't find them,
and if they try,
the Library's
retribution will be swift.
Not the McAllistairs!
That thing!
It can jump bodies, I told you.
You should know,
that alone is a very
dangerous ability.
If they don't know who they are,
if they don't have magic,
they can't protect themselves.
Okay.
Hypothetically,
this thing gets loose.
Why would it go after them?
It's seen them.
It knows magic is back.
It knows they're
Magicians, even if they don't.
Mmm-hmm. Mmm-hmm.
Sophie, hit pause on
your idiocy for a sec.
Janet?
Hi, I'm Isaac.
You're late. Me, too.
Uh, luckily, I don't recognize
the legality of red lights.
Quentin.
I found you.
Oh, uh...
No, sorry, I'm Brian.
Do a card trick for me, Quentin.
Come on.
Will you play with me?
Uh, I'm sorry, I
think you've got me
mistaken for somebody else,
but I... You know...
I saw it.
I've felt it!
Even the gods are afraid of it.
This is your fault, just
as much as it is mine.
Get me out of here!
Help me stop it.
Don't be scared.
This is great!
There's so much
for us to do together.
I can't wait to get started
on all the people
who really deserve our wrath.
Um, no, look, please, I'm not...
This is gonna be so fun.
I think anything is more fun
when you do it with a friend.