Previously on "The Magicians"...
I'll send you on an epic quest.
Q, I think this is it.
"The Tale of the Seven Keys."
Okay, if fixing magic is,
like, so important to you,
then you should just talk
to this crazy guy
that I met back in Athens one time.
You mean Prometheus? He's dead.
Damn it!
He told me this crazy story one time
about how there was, like,
a secret back door
to magic.
I have...
magic.
I have to be able
to do something with it.
I planted a seed for you to grow.
It doesn't matter where it comes from.
It matters what you do with it.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪ ♪
"The Tale of the Seven Keys,"
chapter eight.
[MYSTERIOUS MUSIC]
The Knight remained imprisoned
at the Castle at the End of the World.
Not even a warrior as great as he
could break the bonds placed on him
by the Witch.
He could not escape.
But his daughter, now every bit
the knight her father was,
and more so, never gave up.
She fought monsters, real and imagined,
without as well as within.
She had won all seven keys,
and now she set sail for the
Castle at the End of the World.
Okay, tick-tock.
Does it say where the castle is?
Shh, Bambi. Let him read.
Just saying, andale.
Okay, so she faces the door
of the castle.
In the door, there were seven keyholes.
The door swallowed the keys whole
and slowly opened.
Up ahead, she saw her father,
bound by seven chains.
"Father," she cried,
"I'm here to save you."
She placed the keys into the locks,
- and when she turned the seventh...
- Sorry, time out.
I thought the weird door
swallowed the keys.
Yeah, no, it did, but then...
But then she has them again?
I'm not that drunk.
This is sloppy plotting.
Or it's a paradox.
- Hmm.
- That's a clue.
Oh, we're... ed.
The... ing Library is ready to swoop in
with a... what's it called?
Siphon, and it's not that simple.
Takes a lot of power to charge it,
and they don't have those kind
of reserves just lying around,
thanks to Julia freeing those fairies.
Yeah, well, it's the Library.
They'll think of something.
All we gotta do is beat them to it.
I mean, their window of time
to even use the, uh, whatchamacallit
- is super short, right?
- [INDISTINCT VOICES]
Less than a minute,
once we turn the key.
There you go.
Get all this done before...
Our Lady of the Tree, help us.
Please, help me!
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
Hi, Julia.
Pleasure to finally meet you.
I'm Iris, messenger goddess,
bon vivant, rainbow aficionado.
Let's chat.
Who's...
Our Lady of the Tree?
You are.
I presume they mean
the trees you brought back in Fillory.
Lovely act of penance.
Good moniker for you.
Just what are you saying?
You fulfilled the task
Our Lady Underground gave you...
to grow the spark...
and now you are the flame.
So I'm...
A full-on goddess, correct.
[GASPS]
Holy shit.
Shall we go? We have a lot of work
to do, love, all very exciting.
I'm sort of in the middle of this quest.
Oh, that. They can take it from here.
Your concerns are greater now.
Your duty to them is over.
[ETHEREAL MUSIC]
And by the way, so is all that pain.
You can put it down.
♪ ♪
Okay.
I mean, should I, like, bow?
No. I mean, I'm still me.
Well, you're clearly not.
I mean, it's been kind of hard
to ignore the nuclear power plant
radiating off you the last couple weeks.
[LAUGHS]
I don't know, just...
wanted us to finish this
together, you know?
Mm, me too, but...
I mean, let's be honest, like,
you deserve this.
Why me?
Life is unfair,
but I'm good with it
occasionally working out
for people that I actually love.
Our Lady of the Tree.
[LAUGHTER]
No, it's good.
Yeah, it's good.
It's formal.
Very formal.
[TENDER MUSIC]
♪ ♪
I'm gonna miss you too.
What was that?
It's enough juice for a one-off spell.
You know, just in case, like,
a giant "Indiana Jones" boulder
comes hurtling at you.
You can fight it off.
♪ ♪
I love you, Jules.
I love you too.
♪ ♪
Goodbye, Quentin.
[WHOOSH]
♪ ♪
[SIGHS]
[DARK MUSIC]
♪ ♪
- Synced and corrected by Shazi89 -
- WEBRip resynced by lonewolf -
- www.addic7ed.com -
- Any headway?
Well, wasted a few hours
looking at castles, but...
think I'm onto something,
or someone,
who could help us.
I've been tripping on this, hard.
It's the witch, in the castle,
sitting at a table,
on which another, smaller, castle...
- Yeah?
- Well, either this is some.
M.C. Escher, "the castle
goes on forever" shit,
or that picture means something.
Do you see these?
These are drafting tools
for architects.
Right, she's the architect that...
that Reynard talked about,
that she's... oh, my God,
she's the one that, uh...
she made the prison
for the mistakes of the gods,
and she... she hid it.
She knows where it is.
We need to find her, Q.
There are, like, 50 minor gods
of architecture and the arts.
Well, come at me. Let's
get 'em all down here.
I mean, full-on goddess, huh?
Look, I mean, I get that
Julia has been through some shit,
but seriously, it just seems random.
So it's like life, then?
I don't know. I'm happy for her.
Me too. Might as well be.
Well, I'd be happier if she
stayed, so she could help us.
Look, she seemed pretty positive that
we could do this without her, so...
You forgot Calypso.
Like the musical style?
The witch that imprisoned Odysseus.
And I love you, El, but how
the hell did you pass AP Lit
- without ever reading?
- I didn't.
So, according to the story,
she was a nymph, which...
not a god, but I assume
a pretty powerful creature,
considering she had him in lockdown
for, like, seven full years
on an island called Ogai...
Ogiji?
- Ogijia?
- [SOFTLY] Ogygia.
However that's pronounced.
Cool. Great.
So do we book tickets?
No, it's not...
it's not a real place.
Hold on, okay, so...
Ogai... ogaiga,
or however you say it,
is a island
um, in the fictional tale
of "The Odyssey."
It's a clothing label,
a Eurovision band,
a tech company... they make games.
Oh, my God.
I know them. I worship them.
They're the Candy Collider people.
I nearly spent $600 on level 593.
It took me 12 straight days.
There are prisons, and
there are prisons.
Right?
We're all just 24/7, "Like my post."
Beep-boop! Selfie!
[LAUGHS] Right?
No one's... No one...
Okay, so the CEO
is a woman named Callie.
Great. Vámonos.
Okay, look, I'll talk to you
because I promised Prometheus I would,
and I would never break my word to him,
but for the record, I'm not a fan.
Of you, this big magic quest,
the whole... ing thing.
It's the reason Prometheus is dead.
So as far as I'm concerned,
you're a big part of why he's dead.
No, I... we don't...
Yeah, of course you don't.
You're humans.
Little human Magicians.
He loved you so.
All right, here it is.
The Castle was the greatest
commission of my career.
To design a prison that secure
for clients of that caliber...
[HOLLOW MUSICAL TONE]
♪ ♪
When I explained that I would
need the most steadfast jailors,
Prometheus offered to help find them,
create them with a quest.
Always was good at quests.
♪ ♪
So you trapped some poor girl
into being your slave
for the rest of her life.
She's there of her own will,
as was her father,
who offered himself
as, well, bait, really.
A sort of damsel in distress
for his daughter to save.
I gave them each an opportunity
to perform a sacred task
to keep the world safe.
I assure you,
she can leave if she wishes.
I wouldn't have it any other way.
Surely the quest has taught you,
sacrifice is part of everything.
Um, so when, uh, Prometheus
was looking to hide his back door...
I had already designed
the perfect place.
A place full of monsters
where no one wants to look.
He promised he would
make his quest difficult,
so no quester could get
anywhere near my prison
who couldn't ensure it remained secure.
♪ ♪
He channeled every atom of power
into the keys.
So he, like, Horcruxed himself?
Jesus.
Someone got bit hard by the martyr bug.
All I can say is he believed in you.
He said he saw a time to come
when you would save us
if you had magic.
He believed this completely.
What... what does that mean?
Guess we'll find out,
if you get to the end.
He gave everything for you,
and then his enemies came,
knowing he was weak.
With his power gone,
he couldn't stop them,
and they were strong.
♪ ♪
[SIGHS]
Sorry.
It was a long time ago.
So you don't suppose
you want to tell us
where your prison's at,
and/or how to get in? [LAUGHS]
I've waiting to tell you
since the day he made the keys.
[UNEASY MUSIC]
♪ ♪
Wait, this looks like...
is that Fillory?
It's upside-down.
Looked like that before
Ember and Umber got there,
when it was just a distant,
wild little world.
Oh, my God.
There's a...
a theory about Castle Whitespire,
that the dwarves based it on
the most perfect design
that they'd ever seen,
a castle called...
Blackspire, but Ember destroyed it.
More like flipped the whole thing over
and started over on the other side.
So my castle is based on your prison?
What can I say?
I'm constitutionally incapable
of designing an ugly building.
So Blackspire's still there,
it's just... underneath.
Yes.
Good luck with your quest.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Hey, lady, come on.
- How do we get in? The key paradox.
- Let me get one thing clear:
everything I put the girl through,
I did to prepare her
for what's locked inside.
You'll find your way in,
and you'll find a way to do it safely
and securely, but whatever you do,
there's one simple thing
you need to understand
above everything else.
What's locked inside that castle...
[HAUNTING MUSIC]
Can never, ever be allowed to escape.
♪ ♪
Begging pardon,
we need your official permission.
As acting High King.
Oh.
You have my permission
to implement the new schedule.
Excellent, Your acting Majesty.
And if it's no trouble,
bring the tax collector's
latest expense reports.
I would like to double-check them.
Sorry.
Of course. Right away.
[SYNTH MUSIC]
♪ ♪
You need to stop apologizing.
You'd do well to remember,
that power comes from High King Margo,
but it flows through you.
Is there something you need?
Yes.
Six fairies have disappeared
in two days.
And how are you certain this is...
I found this.
I believe it's a part
of a magical device
imparting night vision
to paltry human eyes.
There is no magic.
Someone's hunting my people.
[OTHERWORLDLY MUSIC]
♪ ♪
What is this?
My lab,
where I come to think,
answer texts, create worlds.
Wait, do I get to create worlds?
I mean, we'll start with one.
You'll split your time between the lab
and answering the prayers
of your choice.
But I'll be blunt.
The work we do here
is much more vital to the big picture,
but we find that morale stays higher
if we heal a kid or two
a few times a week.
♪ ♪
One more thing.
My friends...
How come I can still feel them?
♪ ♪
Takes a bit for those
connections to dissolve.
Q is stressing, and Fen...
I know that she wants to help
save these fairies' lives but...
This is the discipline.
You need to keep from being seduced.
You're wasted if you expend
too much energy
trying to look after every last fairy
when you could be building
and shaping worlds
where no fairy ever comes to harm.
Why don't I show you?
♪ ♪
So do we think the knight chick
is somehow still in there?
It's god magic,
so anything's possible.
We really don't know
what could be in there.
I'll Travel in.
Excuse us for caring, but no.
We don't know what
you'd be blipping into,
and we still have enough
Penny blood on our hands
from the last Penny.
Okay.
Say we do find some window.
We know this knight is gonna help us?
[MELANCHOLY MUSIC]
♪ ♪
[THUNDERCLAPS]
[OMINOUS DRONE]
Hi.
- [GASPS]
- You're asleep.
I'm in your head, not his.
[TENDER MUSIC]
It's a dream.
♪ ♪
You have magic.
Had.
Uh, it's sort of a one-off.
- Listen...
- Ora.
I'm Quentin.
♪ ♪
I need your help.
You're here about the fountain?
The back door to magic?
Yeah.
I can't help.
Uh, because you're
- guarding all the...
- No.
They're all gone.
♪ ♪
He's the only one left.
Did they all die, or?
He killed them all.
You can't imagine what he's capable of.
That's why I can't do anything for you.
I cannot risk the security of my charge.
I get that.
I have something to offer you too.
♪ ♪
Julia gave you a hit
of magic, and you did what?
Incepted the knight in the castle.
That magic was for killing a monster.
Why waste it on chatting with the help?
When Calypso told us that Ora
was there on her own accord,
I... I figured she must know
more than one way
in and out of the castle, and she does,
and she's going to open it for us.
In exchange for...
All you have to do is get in,
turn the key,
and get out fast.
Um, what about the monster?
- Ora will take care of the monster.
- What about you?
I stay in the castle.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
It's a fair deal.
She's been there for centuries,
and she's tired,
and I'm... I'm strong enough,
thanks to the quest,
so I'm the new jailor.
- This isn't the solution.
- I second that.
Alice, who's the one that died for us?
♪ ♪
You were willing to stay in Fillory
for forever. How is this different?
♪ ♪
Someone has to step up.
Quick alternative pitch: take the
gun with the god-killing bullet
and shoot the... ing monster
in the face.
Second second that, yes.
No.
I promised, no clever stuff.
It's more bloody and straightforward.
Look, this monster,
it's not a joke.
We cannot let it escape, and the only
way to make sure that it doesn't
is to do this the hard way.
The quest taught us
that it's like that sometimes.
♪ ♪
I don't like this.
Me neither,
but I'm going to do it.
♪ ♪
Hello, love. [LAUGHS]
Oh, shit.
- It's a human.
- [SIGHS]
It's also the current ruler of Fillory.
Hello.
We've met,
so we can get right to the part
where I tell you to stop
stealing fairies to chop up.
They are full citizens of Fillory.
You will cease at once.
Full citizens. Well, la Di da. [LAUGHS]
♪ ♪
- Escort them to the...
- Ah, ah, ah.
Know what a traveler is?
We can blip on out of here and go
about our beeswax anytime we please.
I have something you very much need
in the castle.
[SOFT PIANO MUSIC]
♪ ♪
They won't be but a moment.
And may I say, sir,
how much I admire your suit.
I've been passing bunnies with Margo.
They are very close
to turning magic back on.
Hooray for them.
And you must know
the reason Irene is poaching fairies
is she needs a huge amount of energy
to power a... a thing
that must be placed
just as it's connected,
within seconds, in order to...
Let me save your breath.
I don't care.
You should.
If we keep her long enough, we can
stop her from derailing magic
and taking it for herself
and for the Library.
This is the future we're talking about.
Not our future.
I cannot risk another soul.
I know exactly how to deal with this.
So, what are you offering, exactly?
I broke a deal.
It's my fault we're vulnerable.
[UNEASY MUSIC]
I offer you the magic of 50 fairies
with a single body.
♪ ♪
You know the power of royal marrow.
You're volunteering to die?
In exchange for a new agreement.
- Wait.
- No fairy will be hunted
by a non-fairy anywhere, ever,
and this deal cannot be broken,
for any reason,
by any being, ever.
Swear to that,
and you have me.
Time is of the essence.
My offer expires in one minute.
♪ ♪
I'm gonna need a table
with restraints,
uh, a bone saw, knives, and a grinder.
♪ ♪
There must be another way.
The deal I struck with Irene
will finally make it possible
for my people to be safe and free.
♪ ♪
Tears for your enemy?
Any day now.
My God.
Where did it turn out to be? Alice?
This Castle at the End of the World?
Fillory. Underneath.
Castle Blackspire.
- How did you...
- I was a fan, too, once.
Hmm.
I need a favor.
I have this,
and I know it's wrong,
and I'll never use it again,
but I need it.
To?
I hear you have an experimental potion
that not only wipes your memory,
but creates a whole new persona.
I do, but what?
I'll always be tempted.
Once I can feel it
everywhere again, and...
unless I have no memory.
Alice,
you are...
you are one of the most
brilliant Magicians
I've ever seen.
I didn't choose to be!
I want to live my life,
not how my parents raised me to think,
or what you taught me,
or what the Library wants me to do.
I'm not sure if that's
the best path to happiness.
What if there is no best path?
Huh?
I don't know.
[MELANCHOLY MUSIC]
All I know is the one I'm on
is a bad one...
♪ ♪
And I'm stepping off.
Once you've... [SNIFFS]
Yes?
Drink this.
Give it about a full day
for everything to get rebooted.
After that,
you are on your own.
♪ ♪
Thank you.
[UNEASY MUSIC]
So?
We need to talk
about our arrangement.
♪ ♪
You tell anyone else?
Please don't.
Of course not.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
You're the only one that I...
wanted... had to tell.
♪ ♪
Look, I know that I don't show it
or act like it all the time,
but...
but you're...
you're the one that I love, Q.
You're the one.
♪ ♪
And the only thing I'm going to
regret is not remembering that.
♪ ♪
Well...
Well, I'll remember for the both of us.
♪ ♪
[EXHALES DEEPLY]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[SIGHS]
You made a deal you will regret.
You'll never know.
True.
But I'll die a queen,
not some mediocre, power-hungry girl.
[KNIFE SQUELCHES]
["JAGWAR" BY SHELLS PLAYING]
♪ ♪
♪ Give a little, get it all ♪
♪ Honey and gold for the taking ♪
♪ Fire up my ember heart ♪
♪ Can you feel the ground beneath ♪
♪ I wouldn't hold you ♪
♪ Make you my captive ♪
♪ Don't hold me too ♪
♪ And the tighter your grip ♪
♪ Yeah the harder I'm pulling ♪
♪ Till we fall through ♪
♪ ♪
♪ I'm the jagwar calling ♪
♪ I make a bad, bad prisoner ♪
♪ I'm a bird free falling ♪
♪ Wasn't born just to please you ♪
♪ If you love it let it go ♪
♪ ♪
♪ If you love it ♪
♪ If you love it let it go ♪
♪ ♪
♪ If you love it ♪
♪ Throw ♪
♪ Throw a kiss into the wind ♪
As I said, I'm only alive
because I fulfill its need.
To be entertained.
Served, coddled.
Loved.
Loved, like...
A child.
Okay, that's better
than my first thought.
Right now, he thinks
we're playing a game.
Hide and seek.
It's the only way to ensure
he'd stay diverted long enough
to let you in, and right
now, he's getting bored.
♪ ♪
What's up?
In case I get held up.
Don't.
Hear me?
♪ ♪
You got this, okay?
[THUNDERCLAP]
My love?
[CHEERFULLY] I found you! I tag you!
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
[QUIETLY] Give it a moment.
♪ ♪
Does it have a name?
No.
♪ ♪
What makes it so dangerous?
The gods created something
that simply...
wants.
So it has to know one secure place
and constant love.
If not,
if its appetite goes unfed
and it's unleashed,
even the gods can't stop it.
♪ ♪
Love?
Come out!
Did you fall asleep?
Yeah, but what can it do?
[CHUCKLE]
♪ ♪
Will you play with me?
[OMINOUS MUSIC]
Eliot! No!
♪ ♪
- Fuck, Eliot...
- How?
God-killing bullet.
This is not what we agreed on.
I didn't actually agree on anything,
but I did decide that
one of my best friends
wouldn't spend the rest of
his life locked in a prison,
guarding what turns out to be a
really not-so-scary monster.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
Wait, where'd she go?
♪ ♪
Anyway, it's done.
You spent a little bit
too much time as a king.
Well, that's really not
the issue now, is it?
♪ ♪
Could've used some Goo
Gone and a toothbrush,
- but I think we're good to go.
- All right, let's go.
- Let's go. Come on, come on.
- All right bitches,
everyone grab a key.
♪ ♪
Alice, what are you doing?
Nothing good.
- No!
- Margo!
[HUMMING]
[SIZZLING]
She's destroying the keys!
I have to.
You don't get to decide that the
whole universe doesn't have magic.
I'll never remember this.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪ ♪
Alice...
why?
You...
you talked me out of
working for the Library.
I realize there's no good side.
Magic just makes people
different shades of bad,
selfish and irresponsible.
We can't handle it!
You can't handle it.
It's wrong.
We're wrong.
And it stops now!
[SIZZLING]
ALL: Ah!
What are you doing?
I'm gonna cut the bitch,
grab her fairy coke
power-up, and fix this.
So, where shall we start?
Ocean?
Cute little landmass?
Dealer's choice.
[ETHEREAL CHIMING]
I know you can still feel them.
You need to let them go.
I know, but it's bad.
In a blink, it'll be good again,
and in two blinks, they'll be long gone.
♪ ♪
He's on the floor. He's...
He's not getting up.
He'll die, not giving up.
Can't you feel his heart?
[MELANCHOLY MUSIC]
No,
'cause I don't do what you're doing.
♪ ♪
You need to let them go.
Remember the future we're creating.
♪ ♪
[UNEASY DRONE]
Will you play with me?
[LAUGHS]
[THUNDERCLAP]
- Hey!
- Ah!
You think you can cast
faster than I can stab? Go!
- Please, listen to me. The knight...
- Ah, shut the... up and...
♪ ♪
- Fix this.
- Now.
Uh-uh.
There's no point.
The magic's gone. It's done.
♪ ♪
He's right.
[TENDER MUSIC]
Jules.
None of your pain
is what we'd call quiet,
especially yours.
♪ ♪
I know you thought
this was for everyone's good.
♪ ♪
You'll see someday,
it wasn't.
♪ ♪
For now,
I need you to stay out of the way.
[UNEASY MUSIC]
[BREATHING RAPIDLY]
♪ ♪
I want you to know, it's your bravery...
made me see.
See what?
What I need to do.
♪ ♪
[BREATHES DEEPLY]
What are you doing?
What Prometheus did.
Whore-crotching.
- Horcruxing.
- Oh.
- Look, Jules, are you sure?
- Shh.
Julia, you could lose your power.
[BUILDING ORCHESTRAL MUSIC]
♪ ♪
[GASPING]
[GASPS]
♪ ♪
[SCREAMS]
- Hurry.
- You okay?
[ROUSING ORCHESTRAL MUSIC]
♪ ♪
- [GRUNTS]
- Okay, okay.
Hey, I got you. I got you.
Come on.
Are you okay?
It hurt.
And I'm not con...
connected to anything anymore.
- I got you.
- Are you guys ready?
[INDISTINCT SPEECH]
Let's do this.
[LOUD CLICKS]
[UNEASY MUSIC]
♪ ♪
[RUMBLING]
[GURGLING]
[WATER RUSHING]
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
♪ ♪
[QUIET WHOOSH]
[UNEASY DRONE]
Dean Fogg?
[GASPS, CHOKING]
Travel, Penny,
I kill them all.
♪ ♪
[CHUCKLES]
[ALL CHOKING] Irene...
We do have a deal.
Unless you want to have
a problem with the Library.
♪ ♪
[ALL GASPING FOR AIR]
The very essence is altered
by the slightest deviation in
finger position. Watch closely.
♪ ♪
The difference is in the position
of the right middle finger.
[MUSIC STUTTERING]
[SIGHS]
Sorry, looks like we're
having another...
power issue.
The rations are wholly inadequate.
I can't even assign homework!
Do the best you can.
I'll attempt to renegotiate
for our supply.
How?
I'm afraid we can't revisit
your supply until next quarter.
I've spoken to the Board.
- Which Board?
- North American Fourth District.
Calgary enrollment hasn't
bounced back the way we have.
They're barely using
2/3 of their allotment,
and they've offered it to us.
Both you and they need
to bring a written request to...
In triplicate.
You'll have a decision by the 31st.
Excellent.
There's just one more request.
My answer hasn't changed.
She made a deal with us, then broke it.
Unlike the others,
she belongs to the Library.
I just would like to see her.
Please.
Where are they?
Per the... deal,
as struck with the Order,
safe.
No, no, no, no, no, they're not.
Alice, the McAllistairs can't find them,
and if they try,
the Library's retribution will be swift.
Not the McAllistairs!
That thing!
It can jump bodies, I told you.
You should know,
that alone is a very dangerous ability.
If they don't know who they
are, if they don't have magic,
they can't protect themselves.
Okay.
Hypothetically,
this thing gets loose.
Why would it go after them?
It's seen them.
It knows magic is back.
It knows they're Magicians,
even if they don't.
Mm-hmm.
Sophie, hit pause
on your idiocy for a sec.
Janet?
Hi, I'm Isaac.
You're late. Me, too.
Uh, luckily, I don't recognize
the legality of red lights.
[SOMBER MUSIC]
♪ ♪
♪ One way or another ♪
♪ I'm gonna find you ♪
♪ I'm gonna get you ♪
♪ One way or another ♪
♪ I'm gonna win you ♪
♪ I'm gonna get you, get you ♪
♪ One way or another ♪
♪ I'm gonna see you ♪
♪ Gonna meet you ♪
♪ One day maybe next week ♪
♪ Gonna meet you Gonna meet you ♪
♪ But I will ♪
♪ Drive by your house ♪
♪ And if ♪
♪ The lights are all out ♪
♪ I'll see ♪
Quentin.
I found you.
Oh, uh,
no, sorry, I'm Brian.
♪ ♪
Do a card trick for me, Quentin.
[LAUGHS]
Come on.
Will you play with me?
I'm sorry, I think you've got me
mistaken for somebody else,
but I... you know...
I saw it.
I've felt it!
Even the gods are afraid of it.
♪ ♪
This is your fault,
just as much as it is mine.
Get me out of here!
♪ ♪
Help me stop it.
♪ One way or another ♪
♪ I'm gonna win you ♪
♪ I'm gonna get you, get you ♪
♪ One way or another ♪
♪ I'm gonna see you ♪
♪ Gonna meet you ♪
♪ One day ♪
Don't be scared.
This is great!
There's so much for us to do together.
I can't wait to get started
on all the people
who really deserve our wrath.
Um, no, look, please, I'm not... I...
This is gonna be so fun.
I think anything is more fun
when you do it with a friend.
♪ ♪
- Synced and corrected by Shazi89 -
- WEBRip resynced by lonewolf -
- www.addic7ed.com -